<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><section_number>103.301.1</section_number><edition_id>1</edition_id><section_id>1483</section_id><structure_id>33</structure_id><catch_line>Antique Show Or Collectors Exchange Show.</catch_line><history></history><full_text>&#xA0; ANTIQUE SHOW OR COLLECTORS EXCHANGE SHOW.
	(Added by Ord. No. 147,883, Eff. 1/1/76.)

	(a)	Definitions.&#xA0; As used in this article.

	1.	&#x201C;ANTIQUE SHOW&#x201D; Means an occasional display-type show consisting of booths, rooms or display areas wherein antique merchandise is displayed, exhibited or offered for sale or exchange. For the purpose of this section the merchandise must be displayed, exhibited or offered for sale or exchange upon the basis, express or implied, that the value of the property, in whole or in substantial part is derived from its age or from its historical associations. For the purposes of this section, merchandise shall be considered antique because of age if it is at least 50 years old. (Amended by Ord. No. 149,484, Eff. 5/19/77.)

	2.	&#x201C;COLLECTORS EXCHANGE SHOW&#x201D; means an occasional display type show consisting of booths, rooms or display areas wherein a single, specific category of secondhand collector&#x2019;s personal property, of a like or similar character, is displayed, exhibited or offered for sale or exchange to the general public or other participating collectors or exhibitors. (Added by Ord. No. 147,883, Eff. 1/2/76.)

	3.	&#x201C;LIKE OR SIMILAR CHARACTER&#x201D; means a particular identifying characteristic of specific items which places them in a class by themselves, such as dolls, electric trains, miniature furniture, chinaware, musical instruments, vases, lamps, clocks, or other similar items collected because of such similarity. (Added by Ord. No 147,833, Eff. 1/2/76.)

	4.	For the purposes of this section, the terms &#x201C;promoter&#x201D; and &#x201C;exhibitor&#x201D; do not include promoters of, or exhibitors at shows or events billed or conducted exclusively as &#x201C;coin&#x201D; and/or &#x201C;stamp&#x201D; shows, events or exhibits where numismatic or philatelic objects and related supplies and materials are displayed, exhibited or offered for sale or exchange. (Added by Ord. No. 149,484, Eff. 5/19/77. )

	(b)	Permit Required.

	1.	Promoter.&#xA0; No person shall arrange, advertise or promote an antique show or a collectors exchange show without a written permit from the Board. (Added by Ord. No. 147,883, Eff. 1/2/76.)

	2.	Exhibitor.&#xA0; For the purposes of this section, the term &#x201C;exhibitor&#x201D; shall mean any person who displays, exhibits or offers for sale or exchange any secondhand personal property at an antique show or at a collector&#x2019;s exchange show. (Amended by Ord. No. 161,524, Eff. 8/17/86.)

	3.	Professional Societies. (Added by Ord. No. 156,264, Eff. 2/6/82.)

	(i)	Upon written application, the Board may grant to a professional society or association of bona fide collectors and to its bona fide collector members named in the application, a single event exemption from the requirements of this section in order that it may conduct an antique show or a collectors exchange show, provided that the Board is first informed and determines that the society or association:

	a.	holds such an event in the City of Los Angeles no more frequently than annually;

	b.	deals solely in, and is limiting this event to, personal property one of the types referred to in Subsections (a)1, (a)2, or (a)3 of this section;

	c.	has, and for the event will employ, procedures competent to prevent the exhibition, display for sale, or sale of stolen property; and

	d.	will amend its application not less than 7 days before the beginning of the event applied for to set forth the names of any additional members of the society or organization who are bona fide collectors who will participate in the event.

	(ii)	The display for sale, or sale of stolen property at any event for which there has been a grant of exemption under (i) shall cause said grant of exemption to have no further force or effect as to the collector or collectors involved.

	4.	The provisions of this section shall not apply to or preclude the sale of donated property wherein all the proceeds or profits from such sale are to be donated to any religious, charitable, benevolent, civic or other nonprofit organization which has a valid social services permit issued by the Police Department. (Amended by Ord. No. 173,300, Eff. 6/30/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)

	(c)	Conditions of Issuance of Permits. (Amended by Ord. No. 149,484, Eff. 5/19/77.)&#xA0; The Board may issue permits for collector&#x2019;s exchange shows and antique shows subject to the following conditions with respect to application for permits and the promoting of and participation in such shows:

	1.	When the Board has determined that the cost of police investigation services will be increased because of the conduct of an antique or collectors&#x2019; exchange show, the Board may require the promoter to make payment into the general fund of the City of Los Angeles an amount calculated at the current hourly rate of a Detective II for each hour of investigation on a weekday and 150% of the current hourly rate of a Detective II for each hour of investigation on a Saturday, Sunday or holiday involving the show, up to a maximum of 16 hours per day of show operation, plus 23.1% of such amount for administrative costs. The promoter shall pay the amount due to the Office of Finance within 30 days after the bill is mailed to the promoter by the Board. (Amended by Ord. No. 173,300, Eff. 6/30/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)

	2.	The promoter, prior to the event, shall verify to the Police Department that all exhibitors will display only the unique type of merchandise permitted to be displayed, exhibited, or entered for sale or exchange at such show and that each exhibitor has submitted his catalog or inventory list to the Police Department, as required by this subsection, and has consented to an inspection by a police officer of all goods under such exhibitor&#x2019;s control at the show before permitting any exhibitor to participate in such show. Failure on the part of the promoter to verify the above information is grounds for the Police Department to close the show or event.. (Amended by Ord. No. 161,524, Eff. 8/17/86.)

	3.	(None)

	4.	(None)

	5.	An antique show or collector&#x2019;s exchange show shall be conducted in a building or other structure at a location which meets and complies with all current zoning, health, safety and fire regulations and standards of the laws of the State of California and ordinances of the City of Los Angeles applicable to such an operation. The promoter shall be responsible for obtaining all necessary permits and approvals under this requirement. (Amended by Ord. No. 149,484, Eff. 5/18/77.)

	6.	Each exhibitor shall file a written notice of intent to participate in an antique or collector&#x2019;s exchange show with the promoter at least 14 days prior to the scheduled date of the show or event. The promoter shall deliver all such notices to the Board at least 14 days prior to the scheduled date of the show or event. Upon application by the promoter and the exhibitor, the Board may approve the participation of an exhibitor who has not filed an application 14 days prior to the scheduled date of the show or event if it determines that such exhibitor has failed to comply with the provisions herein for reasons beyond the exhibitor&#x2019;s control and that strict application of the 14 day provision herein shall result in practical difficulties or unnecessary hardships inconsistent with the purpose and intent of that time limitation. (Amended by Ord. No. 149,484, Eff. 5/19/77.)

	7.	Each exhibitor shall provide the Police Department with a catalog or inventory listing all items intended to be displayed, exhibited or offered for sale or exchange at the event or show at least 7 days prior to the scheduled date thereof, except that any exhibitor whose application for participation in a show or event has been approved by the Board pursuant to the provisions of Subdivision 6 of this subsection within 7 days prior to the scheduled date thereof shall submit said catalog or inventory on the date of the Board&#x2019;s approval. Each exhibitor shall make available for inspection by the Department on each day of the event or show a list of all modifications and changes to the original list. The catalog or inventory need not include items previously reported to the Department and held pursuant to departmental rules and regulations for the handling of secondhand merchandise, nor need it include items imported into the United States which are received by the exhibitor subsequent to the submission of said inventory listing, provided, however, that proof of importation must be presented to the Department upon request. Any catalog or inventory prepared for submission to the Department may, for convenience, group together or otherwise categorize items, provided that unique markings, serial numbers or other specific identifying characteristics, where available, shall be detailed and listed therein. (Amended by Ord. No. 161,524, Eff. 8/17/86.)

	(d)	Identification of Buyer or Recipient.&#xA0; Each exhibitor shall give to each buyer or recipient of any item set forth in a catalog or inventory list required by this section and sold or disposed of at the show or event, a written invoice for any sale over $5.00. The invoice shall contain a description of the article, the selling price thereof, and the name and address of the purchaser. The copies of all such invoices shall be kept by the exhibitor for 6 months after the sale or disposition and shall be available for inspection by a police officer or other representative of the Board. (Amended by Ord. No. 149,484, Eff. 5/19/77.)

	(e)	Mixing of Personal Property.&#xA0; The display, exhibition, offer, sale or exchange of dissimilar items of secondhand personal property or general merchandise shall not be allowed or permitted under this section. Such shall be governed by applicable ordinances regulating sales of secondhand goods; wares and merchandise. (Added by Ord. No. 147,883, Eff. 1/2/76.)</full_text><order_by>301.1</order_by><ancestry><unit id="33" label="article"><name>Police Permit Regulation</name><identifier>3</identifier><url>/10/3/</url></unit><unit id="29" label="chapter"><name>Business Regulations</name><identifier>10</identifier><url>/10/</url></unit></ancestry><structure_contents><unit id="1971"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.00</section_number><catch_line>Scope.</catch_line><url>/103.00/</url><token>103.00</token></unit><unit id="2728"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.01</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/103.01/</url><token>103.01</token></unit><unit id="3947"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.02</section_number><catch_line>Permit Required.</catch_line><url>/103.02/</url><token>103.02</token></unit><unit id="1237"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.02.1</section_number><catch_line>Permit Applications.</catch_line><url>/103.02.1/</url><token>103.02.1</token></unit><unit id="3529"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.03</section_number><catch_line>Public Hearings.</catch_line><url>/103.03/</url><token>103.03</token></unit><unit id="1633"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.04</section_number><catch_line>False Statements.</catch_line><url>/103.04/</url><token>103.04</token></unit><unit id="3757"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.05</section_number><catch_line>Overlapping Business.</catch_line><url>/103.05/</url><token>103.05</token></unit><unit id="3124"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.06</section_number><catch_line>Permits &#x2013; Duration.</catch_line><url>/103.06/</url><token>103.06</token></unit><unit id="2153"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.06.1</section_number><catch_line>Permits &#x2013; Renewal.</catch_line><url>/103.06.1/</url><token>103.06.1</token></unit><unit id="626"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.06.2</section_number><catch_line>Temporary Permits.</catch_line><url>/103.06.2/</url><token>103.06.2</token></unit><unit id="2080"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.07</section_number><catch_line>Permits &#x2013; Annual Fee.</catch_line><url>/103.07/</url><token>103.07</token></unit><unit id="935"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.08</section_number><catch_line>Permits Non-Transferable.</catch_line><url>/103.08/</url><token>103.08</token></unit><unit id="1789"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.09</section_number><catch_line>Permit For Each Location.</catch_line><url>/103.09/</url><token>103.09</token></unit><unit id="1610"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.10</section_number><catch_line>Change Of Location.</catch_line><url>/103.10/</url><token>103.10</token></unit><unit id="2237"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.11</section_number><catch_line>Additional Locations.</catch_line><url>/103.11/</url><token>103.11</token></unit><unit id="4168"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.12</section_number><catch_line>Fees.</catch_line><url>/103.12/</url><token>103.12</token></unit><unit id="2834"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.13</section_number><catch_line>Records.</catch_line><url>/103.13/</url><token>103.13</token></unit><unit id="1926"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.14</section_number><catch_line>Inspection.</catch_line><url>/103.14/</url><token>103.14</token></unit><unit id="3867"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.15</section_number><catch_line>Reports.</catch_line><url>/103.15/</url><token>103.15</token></unit><unit id="1179"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.16</section_number><catch_line>Property.</catch_line><url>/103.16/</url><token>103.16</token></unit><unit id="2714"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.17</section_number><catch_line>Advertising.</catch_line><url>/103.17/</url><token>103.17</token></unit><unit id="4164"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.18</section_number><catch_line>Permittee &#x2013; Responsibility.</catch_line><url>/103.18/</url><token>103.18</token></unit><unit id="1396"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.19</section_number><catch_line>Signs Required.</catch_line><url>/103.19/</url><token>103.19</token></unit><unit id="3238"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.20</section_number><catch_line>Display Of Permit.</catch_line><url>/103.20/</url><token>103.20</token></unit><unit id="663"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.21</section_number><catch_line>Change In Owner Information.</catch_line><url>/103.21/</url><token>103.21</token></unit><unit id="1862"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.22</section_number><catch_line>Identification Cards.</catch_line><url>/103.22/</url><token>103.22</token></unit><unit id="57"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.23</section_number><catch_line>Surrender Of Permits.</catch_line><url>/103.23/</url><token>103.23</token></unit><unit id="1606"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.24</section_number><catch_line>Hours Of Business.</catch_line><url>/103.24/</url><token>103.24</token></unit><unit id="3896"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.25</section_number><catch_line>Doing Business With Minor.</catch_line><url>/103.25/</url><token>103.25</token></unit><unit id="3138"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.26</section_number><catch_line>True Name, Age And Address.</catch_line><url>/103.26/</url><token>103.26</token></unit><unit id="233"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.27</section_number><catch_line>Administration.</catch_line><url>/103.27/</url><token>103.27</token></unit><unit id="2008"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.28</section_number><catch_line>Investigation By Board.</catch_line><url>/103.28/</url><token>103.28</token></unit><unit id="3636"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.29</section_number><catch_line>Timing Of Action On Application.</catch_line><url>/103.29/</url><token>103.29</token></unit><unit id="1985"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.29.01</section_number><catch_line>Executive Director Action On Application.</catch_line><url>/103.29.01/</url><token>103.29.01</token></unit><unit id="3913"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.30</section_number><catch_line>Effect Of Granting Permit.</catch_line><url>/103.30/</url><token>103.30</token></unit><unit id="1563"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.31</section_number><catch_line>Denial Of Application.</catch_line><url>/103.31/</url><token>103.31</token></unit><unit id="608"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.31.1</section_number><catch_line>Final Decisions.</catch_line><url>/103.31.1/</url><token>103.31.1</token></unit><unit id="2525"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.31.2</section_number><catch_line>Effective Date Of Notices.</catch_line><url>/103.31.2/</url><token>103.31.2</token></unit><unit id="3821"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.32</section_number><catch_line>Denial &#x2013;Notice To Applicant.</catch_line><url>/103.32/</url><token>103.32</token></unit><unit id="569"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.33</section_number><catch_line>Hearing On Denial &#x2013; Request By Applicant.</catch_line><url>/103.33/</url><token>103.33</token></unit><unit id="3240"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.34</section_number><catch_line>Suspension Or Revocation Of Permits Issued Under This Article.</catch_line><url>/103.34/</url><token>103.34</token></unit><unit id="3508"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.34.1</section_number><catch_line>Suspension Or Revocation Of Permits Issued Pursuant To Sections 103.101.1, 103.102 And 103.109.</catch_line><url>/103.34.1/</url><token>103.34.1</token></unit><unit id="3371"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.34.2</section_number><catch_line>Judicial Review Of Board Action On Applications And Permits Subject To Sections 103.101.1, 103.102 And 103.109.</catch_line><url>/103.34.2/</url><token>103.34.2</token></unit><unit id="2882"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.35</section_number><catch_line>Disciplinary Action &#x2013; Grounds.</catch_line><url>/103.35/</url><token>103.35</token></unit><unit id="214"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.36</section_number><catch_line>Suspension Or Revocation Without Hearing.</catch_line><url>/103.36/</url><token>103.36</token></unit><unit id="2189"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.37</section_number><catch_line>Suspension Or Revocation &#x2013; Effect On Other Permits.</catch_line><url>/103.37/</url><token>103.37</token></unit><unit id="4000"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.38</section_number><catch_line>New Permit Application After Denial Or Revocation.</catch_line><url>/103.38/</url><token>103.38</token></unit><unit id="755"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.39</section_number><catch_line>Cancelled Or Suspended Permit &#x2013; Jurisdiction Of The Board.</catch_line><url>/103.39/</url><token>103.39</token></unit><unit id="3036"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.40</section_number><catch_line>Pending Revocation Or Suspension Proceedings &#x2013; Effect On Permittee.</catch_line><url>/103.40/</url><token>103.40</token></unit><unit id="2541"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.40.1</section_number><catch_line>Power Of Board To Limit And/Or Condition A Permit.</catch_line><url>/103.40.1/</url><token>103.40.1</token></unit><unit id="3520"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.40.2</section_number><catch_line>Subject Matter Of Limitations And/Or Conditions To A Permit.</catch_line><url>/103.40.2/</url><token>103.40.2</token></unit><unit id="982"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.41</section_number><catch_line>Prior Acts No Bar To Board Action.</catch_line><url>/103.41/</url><token>103.41</token></unit><unit id="911"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.42</section_number><catch_line>Stolen Property &#x2013; Investigation.</catch_line><url>/103.42/</url><token>103.42</token></unit><unit id="2845"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.43</section_number><catch_line>Record Search &#x2013; Charge Authorized.</catch_line><url>/103.43/</url><token>103.43</token></unit><unit id="102"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.44</section_number><catch_line>Instructional Materials &#x2013; Custody &#x2013; Fees For Rental Or Sale.</catch_line><url>/103.44/</url><token>103.44</token></unit><unit id="2184"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101</section_number><catch_line>Picture Arcade.</catch_line><url>/103.101/</url><token>103.101</token></unit><unit id="845"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101.1</section_number><catch_line>Picture Arcade Permits And Regulations.</catch_line><url>/103.101.1/</url><token>103.101.1</token></unit><unit id="3778"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101.2</section_number><catch_line>Compliance By Existing Permittees.</catch_line><url>/103.101.2/</url><token>103.101.2</token></unit><unit id="445"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101.3</section_number><catch_line>Game Arcade.</catch_line><url>/103.101.3/</url><token>103.101.3</token></unit><unit id="3234"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101.4</section_number><catch_line>Cyber Caf&#xC9;S.</catch_line><url>/103.101.4/</url><token>103.101.4</token></unit><unit id="1486"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.102</section_number><catch_line>Cafe Entertainment And Shows.</catch_line><url>/103.102/</url><token>103.102</token></unit><unit id="3379"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.102.1</section_number><catch_line>Additional Regulations.</catch_line><url>/103.102.1/</url><token>103.102.1</token></unit><unit id="3638"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.102.2</section_number><catch_line>Compliance By Existing Permittees And Effect Of Noncompliance.</catch_line><url>/103.102.2/</url><token>103.102.2</token></unit><unit id="2551"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.103</section_number><catch_line>Card Club &#x2013; Social Card Club &#x2013; Card School.</catch_line><url>/103.103/</url><token>103.103</token></unit><unit id="2151"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.104</section_number><catch_line>Carnivals.</catch_line><url>/103.104/</url><token>103.104</token></unit><unit id="1602"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.105</section_number><catch_line>Dancing Academies.</catch_line><url>/103.105/</url><token>103.105</token></unit><unit id="1052"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.106</section_number><catch_line>Dance Halls, Dancing Clubs, Public Dances.</catch_line><url>/103.106/</url><token>103.106</token></unit><unit id="2839"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.106.1</section_number><catch_line>Hostess Dance Hall.</catch_line><url>/103.106.1/</url><token>103.106.1</token></unit><unit id="3668"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.107</section_number><catch_line>Escort Bureaus.</catch_line><url>/103.107/</url><token>103.107</token></unit><unit id="268"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.107.1</section_number><catch_line>Escort &#x2013; Permit Required.</catch_line><url>/103.107.1/</url><token>103.107.1</token></unit><unit id="1084"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.109</section_number><catch_line>Motion Picture Shows.</catch_line><url>/103.109/</url><token>103.109</token></unit><unit id="94"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.111</section_number><catch_line>Parades And Assemblies.</catch_line><url>/103.111/</url><token>103.111</token></unit><unit id="3445"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.112</section_number><catch_line>Billiard Rooms, Poolrooms, Bowling Alleys.</catch_line><url>/103.112/</url><token>103.112</token></unit><unit id="3049"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.112.1</section_number><catch_line>Family Billiard Rooms.</catch_line><url>/103.112.1/</url><token>103.112.1</token></unit><unit id="277"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.113</section_number><catch_line>Rides.</catch_line><url>/103.113/</url><token>103.113</token></unit><unit id="442"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.115</section_number><catch_line>Skating Rinks.</catch_line><url>/103.115/</url><token>103.115</token></unit><unit id="2194"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.116</section_number><catch_line>Games Of Skill And Science.</catch_line><url>/103.116/</url><token>103.116</token></unit><unit id="384"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.117</section_number><catch_line>Rifle Range &#x2013; Shooting Gallery.</catch_line><url>/103.117/</url><token>103.117</token></unit><unit id="1306"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.118</section_number><catch_line>Teenage Dances.</catch_line><url>/103.118/</url><token>103.118</token></unit><unit id="2754"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.120</section_number><catch_line>Soundproofing Of Places Of Amusement &#x2013; When Required.</catch_line><url>/103.120/</url><token>103.120</token></unit><unit id="2832"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.202</section_number><catch_line>Automobile Parking Lots.</catch_line><url>/103.202/</url><token>103.202</token></unit><unit id="2880"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.204</section_number><catch_line>Towing Operation.</catch_line><url>/103.204/</url><token>103.204</token></unit><unit id="4074"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.204.1</section_number><catch_line>Tow Unit Operators.</catch_line><url>/103.204.1/</url><token>103.204.1</token></unit><unit id="448"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.205</section_number><catch_line>Massage Therapy.</catch_line><url>/103.205/</url><token>103.205</token></unit><unit id="3536"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.205.1</section_number><catch_line>Massage Therapists.</catch_line><url>/103.205.1/</url><token>103.205.1</token></unit><unit id="2047"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.205.2</section_number><catch_line>Baths.</catch_line><url>/103.205.2/</url><token>103.205.2</token></unit><unit id="687"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.206</section_number><catch_line>Alarm Systems.</catch_line><url>/103.206/</url><token>103.206</token></unit><unit id="2780"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.206.1</section_number><catch_line>Alarm Company Operators.</catch_line><url>/103.206.1/</url><token>103.206.1</token></unit><unit id="3551"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.206.2</section_number><catch_line>Commercial Unsecured Buildings.</catch_line><url>/103.206.2/</url><token>103.206.2</token></unit><unit id="2339"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.208</section_number><catch_line>Key Duplicator.</catch_line><url>/103.208/</url><token>103.208</token></unit><unit id="2609"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.211</section_number><catch_line>Handbill Distribution.</catch_line><url>/103.211/</url><token>103.211</token></unit><unit id="1701"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.212</section_number><catch_line>Soliciting &#x2013; Peace Officers&#x2019; And Firefighters&#x2019; Organizations &#x2013; Permits.</catch_line><url>/103.212/</url><token>103.212</token></unit><unit id="3677"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.213</section_number><catch_line>Figure Studios.</catch_line><url>/103.213/</url><token>103.213</token></unit><unit id="966"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.301</section_number><catch_line>Antique Shops.</catch_line><url>/103.301/</url><token>103.301</token></unit><unit id="1483"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.301.1</section_number><catch_line>Antique Show Or Collectors Exchange Show.</catch_line><url>/103.301.1/</url><token>103.301.1</token></unit><unit id="3136"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.304</section_number><catch_line>Junk Collectors.</catch_line><url>/103.304/</url><token>103.304</token></unit><unit id="3016"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.305</section_number><catch_line>Junk Dealers.</catch_line><url>/103.305/</url><token>103.305</token></unit><unit id="3600"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.306</section_number><catch_line>Pawnbroker.</catch_line><url>/103.306/</url><token>103.306</token></unit><unit id="1834"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.307</section_number><catch_line>Rummage Sale.</catch_line><url>/103.307/</url><token>103.307</token></unit><unit id="1830"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.308</section_number><catch_line>Sales &#x2013; Fire And Closing Out.</catch_line><url>/103.308/</url><token>103.308</token></unit><unit id="236"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.309</section_number><catch_line>Secondhand Auto Parts Dealer.</catch_line><url>/103.309/</url><token>103.309</token></unit><unit id="3361"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.310</section_number><catch_line>Secondhand Book Dealers.</catch_line><url>/103.310/</url><token>103.310</token></unit><unit id="3558"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.311</section_number><catch_line>Secondhand Dealers.</catch_line><url>/103.311/</url><token>103.311</token></unit><unit id="3738"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.311.1</section_number><catch_line>Firearms Sales By Secondhand Dealers Prohibited.</catch_line><url>/103.311.1/</url><token>103.311.1</token></unit><unit id="2476"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.314</section_number><catch_line>Sellers Of Firearms.</catch_line><url>/103.314/</url><token>103.314</token></unit><unit id="3698"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.314.1</section_number><catch_line>Sellers Of Firearm Ammunition.</catch_line><url>/103.314.1/</url><token>103.314.1</token></unit></structure_contents><next_section id="3136"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.304</section_number><catch_line>Junk Collectors.</catch_line><url>/103.304/</url><token>103.304</token></next_section><metadata></metadata><references></references><url>/103.301.1/</url><token>103.301.1</token><formats><txt>/103.301.1.txt</txt><json>/103.301.1.xml</json></formats><dublin_core><Title>Antique Show Or Collectors Exchange Show.</Title><Type>Text</Type><Format>text/html</Format><Identifier>&#xA7; 103.301.1</Identifier><Relation>Los Angeles Municipal Code</Relation></dublin_core><plain_text>                            LOS ANGELES MUNICIPAL CODE

ANTIQUE SHOW OR COLLECTORS EXCHANGE SHOW. (&#xA7; 103.301.1)

&#xA0; ANTIQUE SHOW OR COLLECTORS EXCHANGE SHOW.
	(Added by Ord. No. 147,883, Eff. 1/1/76.)	(a)	Definitions.&#xA0; As used in this
article.	1.	&#x201C;ANTIQUE SHOW&#x201D; Means an occasional display-type show consisting
of booths, rooms or display areas wherein antique merchandise is displayed,
exhibited or offered for sale or exchange. For the purpose of this section the
merchandise must be displayed, exhibited or offered for sale or exchange upon
the basis, express or implied, that the value of the property, in whole or in
substantial part is derived from its age or from its historical associations.
For the purposes of this section, merchandise shall be considered antique
because of age if it is at least 50 years old. (Amended by Ord. No. 149,484,
Eff. 5/19/77.)	2.	&#x201C;COLLECTORS EXCHANGE SHOW&#x201D; means an occasional display
type show consisting of booths, rooms or display areas wherein a single,
specific category of secondhand collector&#x2019;s personal property, of a like or
similar character, is displayed, exhibited or offered for sale or exchange to
the general public or other participating collectors or exhibitors. (Added by
Ord. No. 147,883, Eff. 1/2/76.)	3.	&#x201C;LIKE OR SIMILAR CHARACTER&#x201D; means a
particular identifying characteristic of specific items which places them in a
class by themselves, such as dolls, electric trains, miniature furniture,
chinaware, musical instruments, vases, lamps, clocks, or other similar items
collected because of such similarity. (Added by Ord. No 147,833, Eff.
1/2/76.)	4.	For the purposes of this section, the terms &#x201C;promoter&#x201D; and
&#x201C;exhibitor&#x201D; do not include promoters of, or exhibitors at shows or events
billed or conducted exclusively as &#x201C;coin&#x201D; and/or &#x201C;stamp&#x201D; shows, events
or exhibits where numismatic or philatelic objects and related supplies and
materials are displayed, exhibited or offered for sale or exchange. (Added by
Ord. No. 149,484, Eff. 5/19/77. )	(b)	Permit Required.	1.	Promoter.&#xA0; No person
shall arrange, advertise or promote an antique show or a collectors exchange
show without a written permit from the Board. (Added by Ord. No. 147,883, Eff.
1/2/76.)	2.	Exhibitor.&#xA0; For the purposes of this section, the term
&#x201C;exhibitor&#x201D; shall mean any person who displays, exhibits or offers for sale
or exchange any secondhand personal property at an antique show or at a
collector&#x2019;s exchange show. (Amended by Ord. No. 161,524, Eff.
8/17/86.)	3.	Professional Societies. (Added by Ord. No. 156,264, Eff.
2/6/82.)	(i)	Upon written application, the Board may grant to a professional
society or association of bona fide collectors and to its bona fide collector
members named in the application, a single event exemption from the requirements
of this section in order that it may conduct an antique show or a collectors
exchange show, provided that the Board is first informed and determines that the
society or association:	a.	holds such an event in the City of Los Angeles no
more frequently than annually;	b.	deals solely in, and is limiting this event
to, personal property one of the types referred to in Subsections (a)1, (a)2, or
(a)3 of this section;	c.	has, and for the event will employ, procedures
competent to prevent the exhibition, display for sale, or sale of stolen
property; and	d.	will amend its application not less than 7 days before the
beginning of the event applied for to set forth the names of any additional
members of the society or organization who are bona fide collectors who will
participate in the event.	(ii)	The display for sale, or sale of stolen property
at any event for which there has been a grant of exemption under (i) shall cause
said grant of exemption to have no further force or effect as to the collector
or collectors involved.	4.	The provisions of this section shall not apply to or
preclude the sale of donated property wherein all the proceeds or profits from
such sale are to be donated to any religious, charitable, benevolent, civic or
other nonprofit organization which has a valid social services permit issued by
the Police Department. (Amended by Ord. No. 173,300, Eff. 6/30/00, Oper.
7/1/00.)	(c)	Conditions of Issuance of Permits. (Amended by Ord. No. 149,484,
Eff. 5/19/77.)&#xA0; The Board may issue permits for collector&#x2019;s exchange shows
and antique shows subject to the following conditions with respect to
application for permits and the promoting of and participation in such
shows:	1.	When the Board has determined that the cost of police investigation
services will be increased because of the conduct of an antique or collectors&#x2019;
exchange show, the Board may require the promoter to make payment into the
general fund of the City of Los Angeles an amount calculated at the current
hourly rate of a Detective II for each hour of investigation on a weekday and
150% of the current hourly rate of a Detective II for each hour of investigation
on a Saturday, Sunday or holiday involving the show, up to a maximum of 16 hours
per day of show operation, plus 23.1% of such amount for administrative costs.
The promoter shall pay the amount due to the Office of Finance within 30 days
after the bill is mailed to the promoter by the Board. (Amended by Ord. No.
173,300, Eff. 6/30/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)	2.	The promoter, prior to the event, shall
verify to the Police Department that all exhibitors will display only the unique
type of merchandise permitted to be displayed, exhibited, or entered for sale or
exchange at such show and that each exhibitor has submitted his catalog or
inventory list to the Police Department, as required by this subsection, and has
consented to an inspection by a police officer of all goods under such
exhibitor&#x2019;s control at the show before permitting any exhibitor to participate
in such show. Failure on the part of the promoter to verify the above
information is grounds for the Police Department to close the show or event..
(Amended by Ord. No. 161,524, Eff. 8/17/86.)	3.	(None)	4.	(None)	5.	An antique
show or collector&#x2019;s exchange show shall be conducted in a building or other
structure at a location which meets and complies with all current zoning,
health, safety and fire regulations and standards of the laws of the State of
California and ordinances of the City of Los Angeles applicable to such an
operation. The promoter shall be responsible for obtaining all necessary permits
and approvals under this requirement. (Amended by Ord. No. 149,484, Eff.
5/18/77.)	6.	Each exhibitor shall file a written notice of intent to participate
in an antique or collector&#x2019;s exchange show with the promoter at least 14 days
prior to the scheduled date of the show or event. The promoter shall deliver all
such notices to the Board at least 14 days prior to the scheduled date of the
show or event. Upon application by the promoter and the exhibitor, the Board may
approve the participation of an exhibitor who has not filed an application 14
days prior to the scheduled date of the show or event if it determines that such
exhibitor has failed to comply with the provisions herein for reasons beyond the
exhibitor&#x2019;s control and that strict application of the 14 day provision herein
shall result in practical difficulties or unnecessary hardships inconsistent
with the purpose and intent of that time limitation. (Amended by Ord. No.
149,484, Eff. 5/19/77.)	7.	Each exhibitor shall provide the Police Department
with a catalog or inventory listing all items intended to be displayed,
exhibited or offered for sale or exchange at the event or show at least 7 days
prior to the scheduled date thereof, except that any exhibitor whose application
for participation in a show or event has been approved by the Board pursuant to
the provisions of Subdivision 6 of this subsection within 7 days prior to the
scheduled date thereof shall submit said catalog or inventory on the date of the
Board&#x2019;s approval. Each exhibitor shall make available for inspection by the
Department on each day of the event or show a list of all modifications and
changes to the original list. The catalog or inventory need not include items
previously reported to the Department and held pursuant to departmental rules
and regulations for the handling of secondhand merchandise, nor need it include
items imported into the United States which are received by the exhibitor
subsequent to the submission of said inventory listing, provided, however, that
proof of importation must be presented to the Department upon request. Any
catalog or inventory prepared for submission to the Department may, for
convenience, group together or otherwise categorize items, provided that unique
markings, serial numbers or other specific identifying characteristics, where
available, shall be detailed and listed therein. (Amended by Ord. No. 161,524,
Eff. 8/17/86.)	(d)	Identification of Buyer or Recipient.&#xA0; Each exhibitor shall
give to each buyer or recipient of any item set forth in a catalog or inventory
list required by this section and sold or disposed of at the show or event, a
written invoice for any sale over $5.00. The invoice shall contain a description
of the article, the selling price thereof, and the name and address of the
purchaser. The copies of all such invoices shall be kept by the exhibitor for 6
months after the sale or disposition and shall be available for inspection by a
police officer or other representative of the Board. (Amended by Ord. No.
149,484, Eff. 5/19/77.)	(e)	Mixing of Personal Property.&#xA0; The display,
exhibition, offer, sale or exchange of dissimilar items of secondhand personal
property or general merchandise shall not be allowed or permitted under this
section. Such shall be governed by applicable ordinances regulating sales of
secondhand goods; wares and merchandise. (Added by Ord. No. 147,883, Eff.
1/2/76.)
</plain_text><html>
					&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#xA0; ANTIQUE SHOW OR COLLECTORS EXCHANGE SHOW.
	(Added by Ord. No. 147,883, Eff. 1/1/76.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(a)	Definitions.&#xA0; As used in this article.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	&#x201C;ANTIQUE SHOW&#x201D; Means an occasional display-type show consisting of booths, rooms or display areas wherein antique merchandise is displayed, exhibited or offered for sale or exchange. For the purpose of this section the merchandise must be displayed, exhibited or offered for sale or exchange upon the basis, express or implied, that the value of the property, in whole or in substantial part is derived from its age or from its historical associations. For the purposes of this section, merchandise shall be considered antique because of age if it is at least 50 years old. (Amended by Ord. No. 149,484, Eff. 5/19/77.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	&#x201C;COLLECTORS EXCHANGE SHOW&#x201D; means an occasional display type show consisting of booths, rooms or display areas wherein a single, specific category of secondhand collector&#x2019;s personal property, of a like or similar character, is displayed, exhibited or offered for sale or exchange to the general public or other participating collectors or exhibitors. (Added by Ord. No. 147,883, Eff. 1/2/76.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	&#x201C;LIKE OR SIMILAR CHARACTER&#x201D; means a particular identifying characteristic of specific items which places them in a class by themselves, such as dolls, electric trains, miniature furniture, chinaware, musical instruments, vases, lamps, clocks, or other similar items collected because of such similarity. (Added by Ord. No 147,833, Eff. 1/2/76.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	4.	For the purposes of this section, the terms &#x201C;promoter&#x201D; and &#x201C;exhibitor&#x201D; do not include promoters of, or exhibitors at shows or events billed or conducted exclusively as &#x201C;coin&#x201D; and/or &#x201C;stamp&#x201D; shows, events or exhibits where numismatic or philatelic &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;objects&lt;/span&gt; and related supplies and &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;materials&lt;/span&gt; are displayed, exhibited or offered for sale or exchange. (Added by Ord. No. 149,484, Eff. 5/19/77. )&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(b)	Permit Required.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	Promoter.&#xA0; No person shall arrange, advertise or promote an antique show or a collectors exchange show without a written permit from the Board. (Added by Ord. No. 147,883, Eff. 1/2/76.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	Exhibitor.&#xA0; For the purposes of this section, the term &#x201C;exhibitor&#x201D; shall mean any person who displays, exhibits or offers for sale or exchange any secondhand personal property at an antique show or at a collector&#x2019;s exchange show. (Amended by Ord. No. 161,524, Eff. 8/17/86.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	Professional Societies. (Added by Ord. No. 156,264, Eff. 2/6/82.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(i)	Upon written application, the Board may grant to a professional society or association of bona fide collectors and to its bona fide collector members named in the application, a single event exemption from the requirements of this section in &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; that it may conduct an antique show or a collectors exchange show, provided that the Board is first informed and determines that the society or association:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	a.	holds such an event in the City of Los Angeles no more frequently than annually;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	b.	deals solely in, and is limiting this event to, personal property one of the types referred to in Subsections (a)1, (a)2, or (a)3 of this section;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	c.	has, and for the event will employ, procedures competent to prevent the exhibition, display for sale, or sale of stolen property; and&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	d.	will &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;amend&lt;/span&gt; its application not less than 7 days before the beginning of the event applied for to set forth the names of any additional members of the society or organization who are bona fide collectors who will participate in the event.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(ii)	The display for sale, or sale of stolen property at any event for which there has been a grant of exemption under (i) shall cause said grant of exemption to have no further force or effect as to the collector or collectors involved.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	4.	The provisions of this section shall not apply to or preclude the sale of donated property wherein all the proceeds or profits from such sale are to be donated to any religious, charitable, benevolent, civic or other nonprofit organization which has a valid social services permit issued by the Police Department. (Amended by Ord. No. 173,300, Eff. 6/30/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(c)	Conditions of Issuance of Permits. (Amended by Ord. No. 149,484, Eff. 5/19/77.)&#xA0; The Board may &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;issue&lt;/span&gt; permits for collector&#x2019;s exchange shows and antique shows subject to the following conditions with respect to application for permits and the promoting of and participation in such shows:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	When the Board has determined that the cost of police investigation services will be increased because of the conduct of an antique or collectors&#x2019; exchange show, the Board may require the promoter to make payment into the general fund of the City of Los Angeles an amount calculated at the current hourly rate of a Detective II for each hour of investigation on a weekday and 150% of the current hourly rate of a Detective II for each hour of investigation on a Saturday, Sunday or holiday involving the show, up to a maximum of 16 hours per day of show operation, plus 23.1% of such amount for administrative costs. The promoter shall pay the amount due to the Office of Finance within 30 days after the bill is mailed to the promoter by the Board. (Amended by Ord. No. 173,300, Eff. 6/30/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	The promoter, prior to the event, shall verify to the Police Department that all exhibitors will display only the unique type of merchandise permitted to be displayed, exhibited, or entered for sale or exchange at such show and that each exhibitor has submitted his catalog or inventory list to the Police Department, as required by this subsection, and has consented to an inspection by a police officer of all goods under such exhibitor&#x2019;s control at the show before permitting any exhibitor to participate in such show. Failure on the part of the promoter to verify the above information is grounds for the Police Department to close the show or event.. (Amended by Ord. No. 161,524, Eff. 8/17/86.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	(None)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	4.	(None)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	5.	An antique show or collector&#x2019;s exchange show shall be conducted in a building or other structure at a location which meets and complies with all current zoning, health, safety and fire regulations and standards of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;laws&lt;/span&gt; of the State of California and &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinances&lt;/span&gt; of the City of Los Angeles applicable to such an operation. The promoter shall be responsible for obtaining all necessary permits and approvals under this requirement. (Amended by Ord. No. 149,484, Eff. 5/18/77.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	6.	Each exhibitor shall file a written notice of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;intent&lt;/span&gt; to participate in an antique or collector&#x2019;s exchange show with the promoter at least 14 days prior to the scheduled date of the show or event. The promoter shall deliver all such notices to the Board at least 14 days prior to the scheduled date of the show or event. Upon application by the promoter and the exhibitor, the Board may approve the participation of an exhibitor who has not filed an application 14 days prior to the scheduled date of the show or event if it determines that such exhibitor has failed to comply with the provisions herein for reasons beyond the exhibitor&#x2019;s control and that strict application of the 14 day provision herein shall result in practical difficulties or unnecessary hardships inconsistent with the purpose and &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;intent&lt;/span&gt; of that time limitation. (Amended by Ord. No. 149,484, Eff. 5/19/77.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	7.	Each exhibitor shall provide the Police Department with a catalog or inventory listing all items intended to be displayed, exhibited or offered for sale or exchange at the event or show at least 7 days prior to the scheduled date thereof, except that any exhibitor whose application for participation in a show or event has been approved by the Board pursuant to the provisions of Subdivision 6 of this subsection within 7 days prior to the scheduled date thereof shall submit said catalog or inventory on the date of the Board&#x2019;s approval. Each exhibitor shall make available for inspection by the Department on each day of the event or show a list of all modifications and changes to the original list. The catalog or inventory need not include items previously reported to the Department and held pursuant to departmental rules and regulations for the handling of secondhand merchandise, nor need it include items imported into the United States which are received by the exhibitor subsequent to the submission of said inventory listing, provided, however, that proof of importation must be presented to the Department upon request. Any catalog or inventory prepared for submission to the Department may, for convenience, group together or otherwise categorize items, provided that unique markings, serial numbers or other specific identifying characteristics, where available, shall be detailed and listed therein. (Amended by Ord. No. 161,524, Eff. 8/17/86.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(d)	Identification of Buyer or Recipient.&#xA0; Each exhibitor shall give to each buyer or recipient of any item set forth in a catalog or inventory list required by this section and sold or disposed of at the show or event, a written invoice for any sale over $5.00. The invoice shall contain a description of the article, the selling price thereof, and the name and address of the purchaser. The copies of all such invoices shall be kept by the exhibitor for 6 months after the sale or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;disposition&lt;/span&gt; and shall be available for inspection by a police officer or other representative of the Board. (Amended by Ord. No. 149,484, Eff. 5/19/77.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(e)	Mixing of Personal Property.&#xA0; The display, exhibition, offer, sale or exchange of dissimilar items of secondhand personal property or general merchandise shall not be allowed or permitted under this section. Such shall be governed by applicable &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinances&lt;/span&gt; regulating sales of secondhand goods; wares and merchandise. (Added by Ord. No. 147,883, Eff. 1/2/76.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</html><previous_section id="966"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.301</section_number><catch_line>Antique Shops.</catch_line><url>/103.301/</url><token>103.301</token></previous_section><text><unit id="1469" prefix=""><text>&#xA0; ANTIQUE SHOW OR COLLECTORS EXCHANGE SHOW.
	(Added by Ord. No. 147,883, Eff. 1/1/76.)	(a)	Definitions.&#xA0; As used in this article.	1.	&#x201C;ANTIQUE SHOW&#x201D; Means an occasional display-type show consisting of booths, rooms or display areas wherein antique merchandise is displayed, exhibited or offered for sale or exchange. For the purpose of this section the merchandise must be displayed, exhibited or offered for sale or exchange upon the basis, express or implied, that the value of the property, in whole or in substantial part is derived from its age or from its historical associations. For the purposes of this section, merchandise shall be considered antique because of age if it is at least 50 years old. (Amended by Ord. No. 149,484, Eff. 5/19/77.)	2.	&#x201C;COLLECTORS EXCHANGE SHOW&#x201D; means an occasional display type show consisting of booths, rooms or display areas wherein a single, specific category of secondhand collector&#x2019;s personal property, of a like or similar character, is displayed, exhibited or offered for sale or exchange to the general public or other participating collectors or exhibitors. (Added by Ord. No. 147,883, Eff. 1/2/76.)	3.	&#x201C;LIKE OR SIMILAR CHARACTER&#x201D; means a particular identifying characteristic of specific items which places them in a class by themselves, such as dolls, electric trains, miniature furniture, chinaware, musical instruments, vases, lamps, clocks, or other similar items collected because of such similarity. (Added by Ord. No 147,833, Eff. 1/2/76.)	4.	For the purposes of this section, the terms &#x201C;promoter&#x201D; and &#x201C;exhibitor&#x201D; do not include promoters of, or exhibitors at shows or events billed or conducted exclusively as &#x201C;coin&#x201D; and/or &#x201C;stamp&#x201D; shows, events or exhibits where numismatic or philatelic objects and related supplies and materials are displayed, exhibited or offered for sale or exchange. (Added by Ord. No. 149,484, Eff. 5/19/77. )	(b)	Permit Required.	1.	Promoter.&#xA0; No person shall arrange, advertise or promote an antique show or a collectors exchange show without a written permit from the Board. (Added by Ord. No. 147,883, Eff. 1/2/76.)	2.	Exhibitor.&#xA0; For the purposes of this section, the term &#x201C;exhibitor&#x201D; shall mean any person who displays, exhibits or offers for sale or exchange any secondhand personal property at an antique show or at a collector&#x2019;s exchange show. (Amended by Ord. No. 161,524, Eff. 8/17/86.)	3.	Professional Societies. (Added by Ord. No. 156,264, Eff. 2/6/82.)	(i)	Upon written application, the Board may grant to a professional society or association of bona fide collectors and to its bona fide collector members named in the application, a single event exemption from the requirements of this section in order that it may conduct an antique show or a collectors exchange show, provided that the Board is first informed and determines that the society or association:	a.	holds such an event in the City of Los Angeles no more frequently than annually;	b.	deals solely in, and is limiting this event to, personal property one of the types referred to in Subsections (a)1, (a)2, or (a)3 of this section;	c.	has, and for the event will employ, procedures competent to prevent the exhibition, display for sale, or sale of stolen property; and	d.	will amend its application not less than 7 days before the beginning of the event applied for to set forth the names of any additional members of the society or organization who are bona fide collectors who will participate in the event.	(ii)	The display for sale, or sale of stolen property at any event for which there has been a grant of exemption under (i) shall cause said grant of exemption to have no further force or effect as to the collector or collectors involved.	4.	The provisions of this section shall not apply to or preclude the sale of donated property wherein all the proceeds or profits from such sale are to be donated to any religious, charitable, benevolent, civic or other nonprofit organization which has a valid social services permit issued by the Police Department. (Amended by Ord. No. 173,300, Eff. 6/30/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)	(c)	Conditions of Issuance of Permits. (Amended by Ord. No. 149,484, Eff. 5/19/77.)&#xA0; The Board may issue permits for collector&#x2019;s exchange shows and antique shows subject to the following conditions with respect to application for permits and the promoting of and participation in such shows:	1.	When the Board has determined that the cost of police investigation services will be increased because of the conduct of an antique or collectors&#x2019; exchange show, the Board may require the promoter to make payment into the general fund of the City of Los Angeles an amount calculated at the current hourly rate of a Detective II for each hour of investigation on a weekday and 150% of the current hourly rate of a Detective II for each hour of investigation on a Saturday, Sunday or holiday involving the show, up to a maximum of 16 hours per day of show operation, plus 23.1% of such amount for administrative costs. The promoter shall pay the amount due to the Office of Finance within 30 days after the bill is mailed to the promoter by the Board. (Amended by Ord. No. 173,300, Eff. 6/30/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)	2.	The promoter, prior to the event, shall verify to the Police Department that all exhibitors will display only the unique type of merchandise permitted to be displayed, exhibited, or entered for sale or exchange at such show and that each exhibitor has submitted his catalog or inventory list to the Police Department, as required by this subsection, and has consented to an inspection by a police officer of all goods under such exhibitor&#x2019;s control at the show before permitting any exhibitor to participate in such show. Failure on the part of the promoter to verify the above information is grounds for the Police Department to close the show or event.. (Amended by Ord. No. 161,524, Eff. 8/17/86.)	3.	(None)	4.	(None)	5.	An antique show or collector&#x2019;s exchange show shall be conducted in a building or other structure at a location which meets and complies with all current zoning, health, safety and fire regulations and standards of the laws of the State of California and ordinances of the City of Los Angeles applicable to such an operation. The promoter shall be responsible for obtaining all necessary permits and approvals under this requirement. (Amended by Ord. No. 149,484, Eff. 5/18/77.)	6.	Each exhibitor shall file a written notice of intent to participate in an antique or collector&#x2019;s exchange show with the promoter at least 14 days prior to the scheduled date of the show or event. The promoter shall deliver all such notices to the Board at least 14 days prior to the scheduled date of the show or event. Upon application by the promoter and the exhibitor, the Board may approve the participation of an exhibitor who has not filed an application 14 days prior to the scheduled date of the show or event if it determines that such exhibitor has failed to comply with the provisions herein for reasons beyond the exhibitor&#x2019;s control and that strict application of the 14 day provision herein shall result in practical difficulties or unnecessary hardships inconsistent with the purpose and intent of that time limitation. (Amended by Ord. No. 149,484, Eff. 5/19/77.)	7.	Each exhibitor shall provide the Police Department with a catalog or inventory listing all items intended to be displayed, exhibited or offered for sale or exchange at the event or show at least 7 days prior to the scheduled date thereof, except that any exhibitor whose application for participation in a show or event has been approved by the Board pursuant to the provisions of Subdivision 6 of this subsection within 7 days prior to the scheduled date thereof shall submit said catalog or inventory on the date of the Board&#x2019;s approval. Each exhibitor shall make available for inspection by the Department on each day of the event or show a list of all modifications and changes to the original list. The catalog or inventory need not include items previously reported to the Department and held pursuant to departmental rules and regulations for the handling of secondhand merchandise, nor need it include items imported into the United States which are received by the exhibitor subsequent to the submission of said inventory listing, provided, however, that proof of importation must be presented to the Department upon request. Any catalog or inventory prepared for submission to the Department may, for convenience, group together or otherwise categorize items, provided that unique markings, serial numbers or other specific identifying characteristics, where available, shall be detailed and listed therein. (Amended by Ord. No. 161,524, Eff. 8/17/86.)	(d)	Identification of Buyer or Recipient.&#xA0; Each exhibitor shall give to each buyer or recipient of any item set forth in a catalog or inventory list required by this section and sold or disposed of at the show or event, a written invoice for any sale over $5.00. The invoice shall contain a description of the article, the selling price thereof, and the name and address of the purchaser. The copies of all such invoices shall be kept by the exhibitor for 6 months after the sale or disposition and shall be available for inspection by a police officer or other representative of the Board. (Amended by Ord. No. 149,484, Eff. 5/19/77.)	(e)	Mixing of Personal Property.&#xA0; The display, exhibition, offer, sale or exchange of dissimilar items of secondhand personal property or general merchandise shall not be allowed or permitted under this section. Such shall be governed by applicable ordinances regulating sales of secondhand goods; wares and merchandise. (Added by Ord. No. 147,883, Eff. 1/2/76.)</text><type>section</type><prefixes><unit></unit></prefixes><entire_prefix></entire_prefix><prefix_anchor></prefix_anchor><level>1</level></unit></text></law>
