<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><section_number>103.118</section_number><edition_id>1</edition_id><section_id>1306</section_id><structure_id>33</structure_id><catch_line>Teenage Dances.</catch_line><history></history><full_text>&#xA0; TEENAGE DANCES.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 160,203, Eff. 9/2/85.)

	(a)	Definitions.&#xA0; As used in this article, the term &#x201C;premises&#x201D; shall mean any facility open to the public where activity regulated hereunder is occurring, the room or rooms where such activity is occurring and the area adjacent thereto to which direct access is available from such room and the term &#x201C;Teenager&#x201D; shall mean any person over the age of 13 years and under the age of 18 years.

	(b)	Permit Required.

	1.	No person, dancing club or other association shall, without first obtaining a permit from the Board, operate, manage or maintain any dance hall, &#x201C;disco&#x201D;, nightclub or hostess hall, or conduct any public dance or dances wherein teenagers are permitted to be present, except as herein provided.

	2.	Such permit shall be in addition to any other dance permit required by this article.

	(c)	Permit &#x2013; Application &#x2013; Contents of.&#xA0; An application for a permit shall be accompanied by certification that the premises where a dance is to be held or dancing activity is to occur is adequate for the purpose, and that the premises conform with the existing health, safety, fire and zoning ordinances of the City of Los Angeles. The certification shall also specify the maximum number of persons that may safely be accommodated at the location where the dance or dancing activity is to take place.

	(d)	Exceptions.

	1.	A permit shall not be required for any agency or department of the City of Los Angeles, County of Los Angeles, Board of Education, or other political subdivision of the State of California, or for any religious or charitable organization holding a valid tax exempt registration certificate under Section 21.22 of this Code and which is normally engaged in youth or child-serving activities.

	2.	A permit shall not be required for any hotel, cafe, restaurant, banquet hall or catering facility which does not predominantly cater to the patronage of teenagers and where no charge or admission is imposed for the privilege of entering or dancing.

	(e)	Investigation.&#xA0; Upon the filing of an application, the Board shall cause that investigation to be made which it deems necessary. The Board shall issue no permit to the applicant unless the following conditions are satisfied:

	1.	The dance or dancing activity for which an application has been filed conforms to the laws of the City of Los Angeles and of the State of California, and will not constitute a menace to the health, peace or safety of the community;

	2.	A sufficient number of adult supervisors who are employees of the location will be provided to insure compliance with the provisions of this section and any rules or regulations promulgated by the Board with respect thereto. For purposes herein, a sufficient number shall constitute, at a minimum, a ratio of one adult to every 35 teenagers in attendance at the teenage dance premises.

	(f)	Lighting in Hall.&#xA0; Each of the premises where any dance or dancing activity regulated under this section is held, shall be adequately lighted at all times when open for dancing. For purposes herein, the volume of illumination shall at no time be less than one foot-candle in any part of the building and premises accessible to participants.

	(g)	Parking &#x2013; Lighting.&#xA0; All off-street parking facilities under the direct or indirect control of a permittee shall be adequately lighted and supervised so as to ensure that violations of this article or other laws do not occur. For purposes herein, adequate lighting and supervision will be established by the Board at the time of the granting or reviewing a permit.

	(h)	Use of Drugs or Alcoholic Beverages &#x2013; Prohibited.&#xA0; No alcoholic beverages shall be sold, consumed or be available on the premises where there is a dance or dancing activity is being held which is regulated by this section. Admission to the premises shall be denied to any person showing evidence of drinking any alcoholic beverages or showing symptoms of being intoxicated as a result of the ingestion of any chemical substance.

	(i)	Time Limit for Dances.&#xA0; Teenage dancing regulated hereunder shall not be permitted after 1:00 a.m. on Saturdays, Sundays, and local public school holidays. On all other days, except Fridays, Saturdays, and the day before a legal holiday, teenage dancing regulated hereunder shall be prohibited after the hour of 10:00 p.m., provided however that permission to continue dancing after 10:00 p.m. on such other days may be granted by the Board during public school vacation periods if the Board finds the continuation of dancing after 10:00 p.m. does not unreasonably disturb the peace and quiet of the surrounding neighborhood. In no event shall such an establishment be permitted to continue such teenage dances or dancing activity later than 1:00 a.m.

	(j)	Teenagers Under the Age of 15 Years.&#xA0; No person under the age of 15 years shall be permitted to enter any premises where there is dancing activity regulated under this section unless such person is accompanied by a parent or legal guardian unless the parent or legal guardian of such person has signed and filed with the owner, manager or operator of the facility a consent form for such minor to be there unaccompanied by said parent or guardian. The consent shall be set forth on a form approved by the Board. Such form must be signed by the parent or legal guardian in the presence of the owner, manager or operator of the facility and shall contain the minor&#x2019;s name, date of birth, address, and the parent or legal guardian&#x2019;s telephone number for use in case of an emergency. In the event no such consent form has been so completed and filed, such teenagers shall not be permitted to enter into or remain at the premises unless accompanied or escorted by his or her parent or legal guardian. Any teenager admitted and accompanied by a parent or legal guardian shall have the rights and privileges of other legally admitted teenagers. Any teenager entering pursuant to a consent form filed by his or her parent or legal guardian must present valid identification as defined in Subsection (n).

	(k)	Persons Under the Age of 13 Years.&#xA0; In no event shall any person under the age of 13 years be permitted to enter the premises where there is a dance or dancing activity being held which is regulated under this section.

	(l)	Persons Over the Age of 20 Years.&#xA0; No person over the age of 20 years shall be permitted to enter the premises where there is a dance or dancing activity being held which is regulated under this section unless that person is a parent or legal guardian accompanying a child as required by Subsections (j) and (m) herein.

	(m)	Teenagers Between the Age of 15 and 18 Years.&#xA0; No person between the ages of 15 and 18 years may be present at premises regulated under this section unless he or she (1) is accompanied by a parent or legal guardian, or, if unaccompanied, the parent or legal guardian of such person has signed and filed a consent form similar to that required by Subsection (j) herein; or (2) presents valid proof of age as defined in Subsection (n) herein.

	(n)	Proof of Age. &#xA0; Proof of age shall be required of each patron entering the establishment. Such proof may be established by identification issued by a governmental agency, the patron&#x2019;s school, or the Department of Motor Vehicles, and must contain the patron&#x2019;s name, date of birth, and a picture that has been taken within the preceding two years.

	(o)	Denial of Entry on Request of Parent.&#xA0; No person having charge or control of any premises regulated under this section shall allow a teenager to enter or remain at the premises after receiving a written notice signed by the parent or legal guardian of such teenager which requests that said teenager be prevented from entering the premises.

	(p)	Attendance.&#xA0; Except in emergency situations, no patron shall be permitted to leave the premises at which any dance or dancing activity regulated by this section is being held and thereafter re-enter prior to the conclusion of such dance or dancing activity. No pass or other indicia permitting re-entry shall be issued.

	(q)	Criminal History of Supervisory Staff.&#xA0; No person, dancing club, or other association or entity obtaining a permit under this section shall employ any person as a supervisory employee at the premises at the time of any dancing activity regulated hereunder who has been convicted of a misdemeanor or a felony in the last five (5) years, nor shall such permittee employ any person who has been arrested and is out on bail or on his or her own recognizance pending trial. As permitted by California Labor Code Section 432.7, such permittee shall ask all applicants for such employment at the premises about any conviction, as that term is used in said Labor Code Section, and about any arrest for which the applicant is out on bail or on his or her own recognizance pending trial. Copies of the employment applications of all persons hired shall be filed with the Board. Upon a showing of just causes a permittee may apply to the Board for a waiver of this provision. Just cause, as used in this subsection, shall include but is not limited to a demonstration that the prior conviction, or arrest as described herein, would not have an adverse effect on the employee&#x2019;s ability to supervise teenagers at a location as described within this section. While teenagers are present, all employees also present within the premises, as that term is defined by this section, shall be considered supervisory employees.

	(r)	Duty of Management.&#xA0; If a teenager is discovered inside the premises showing evidence or symptoms of being intoxicated as a result of the ingestion of alcohol or any chemical substance, that teenager shall be reported by management to local police authorities and to his or her parent or legal guardian. Management shall attempt to separate the teenager from other teenagers at the premises pending the arrival of police or the parent or legal guardian of the teenager. A notice shall be posted by all pay phones containing the local police telephone number and shall request all patrons to call the police if management neglects to take action to report a violation of this subsection.

	(s)	Operation After 1:00 a.m. &#x2013; 18 Year Olds.&#xA0; If the premises intends to operate after the closing time set forth in Subsection (i) herein, the premises must first be vacated by all customers, and thereafter only those persons 18 years of age or older who present valid identification containing proof of age established as set forth in Subsection (n) herein may be permitted to enter the premises.

	(t)	Additional Restrictions by the Board.&#xA0; The Board may promulgate additional rules as necessary with respect thereto.

	(u)	Regulation by Permittee.&#xA0; Nothing herein is intended to preclude the imposition of more restrictive regulations by any permittee so long as the regulations are not in conflict with any provision of this section.</full_text><order_by>118</order_by><ancestry><unit id="33" label="article"><name>Police Permit Regulation</name><identifier>3</identifier><url>/10/3/</url></unit><unit id="29" label="chapter"><name>Business Regulations</name><identifier>10</identifier><url>/10/</url></unit></ancestry><structure_contents><unit id="1971"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.00</section_number><catch_line>Scope.</catch_line><url>/103.00/</url><token>103.00</token></unit><unit id="2728"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.01</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/103.01/</url><token>103.01</token></unit><unit id="3947"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.02</section_number><catch_line>Permit Required.</catch_line><url>/103.02/</url><token>103.02</token></unit><unit id="1237"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.02.1</section_number><catch_line>Permit Applications.</catch_line><url>/103.02.1/</url><token>103.02.1</token></unit><unit id="3529"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.03</section_number><catch_line>Public Hearings.</catch_line><url>/103.03/</url><token>103.03</token></unit><unit id="1633"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.04</section_number><catch_line>False Statements.</catch_line><url>/103.04/</url><token>103.04</token></unit><unit id="3757"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.05</section_number><catch_line>Overlapping Business.</catch_line><url>/103.05/</url><token>103.05</token></unit><unit id="3124"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.06</section_number><catch_line>Permits &#x2013; Duration.</catch_line><url>/103.06/</url><token>103.06</token></unit><unit id="2153"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.06.1</section_number><catch_line>Permits &#x2013; Renewal.</catch_line><url>/103.06.1/</url><token>103.06.1</token></unit><unit id="626"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.06.2</section_number><catch_line>Temporary Permits.</catch_line><url>/103.06.2/</url><token>103.06.2</token></unit><unit id="2080"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.07</section_number><catch_line>Permits &#x2013; Annual Fee.</catch_line><url>/103.07/</url><token>103.07</token></unit><unit id="935"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.08</section_number><catch_line>Permits Non-Transferable.</catch_line><url>/103.08/</url><token>103.08</token></unit><unit id="1789"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.09</section_number><catch_line>Permit For Each Location.</catch_line><url>/103.09/</url><token>103.09</token></unit><unit id="1610"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.10</section_number><catch_line>Change Of Location.</catch_line><url>/103.10/</url><token>103.10</token></unit><unit id="2237"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.11</section_number><catch_line>Additional Locations.</catch_line><url>/103.11/</url><token>103.11</token></unit><unit id="4168"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.12</section_number><catch_line>Fees.</catch_line><url>/103.12/</url><token>103.12</token></unit><unit id="2834"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.13</section_number><catch_line>Records.</catch_line><url>/103.13/</url><token>103.13</token></unit><unit id="1926"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.14</section_number><catch_line>Inspection.</catch_line><url>/103.14/</url><token>103.14</token></unit><unit id="3867"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.15</section_number><catch_line>Reports.</catch_line><url>/103.15/</url><token>103.15</token></unit><unit id="1179"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.16</section_number><catch_line>Property.</catch_line><url>/103.16/</url><token>103.16</token></unit><unit id="2714"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.17</section_number><catch_line>Advertising.</catch_line><url>/103.17/</url><token>103.17</token></unit><unit id="4164"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.18</section_number><catch_line>Permittee &#x2013; Responsibility.</catch_line><url>/103.18/</url><token>103.18</token></unit><unit id="1396"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.19</section_number><catch_line>Signs Required.</catch_line><url>/103.19/</url><token>103.19</token></unit><unit id="3238"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.20</section_number><catch_line>Display Of Permit.</catch_line><url>/103.20/</url><token>103.20</token></unit><unit id="663"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.21</section_number><catch_line>Change In Owner Information.</catch_line><url>/103.21/</url><token>103.21</token></unit><unit id="1862"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.22</section_number><catch_line>Identification Cards.</catch_line><url>/103.22/</url><token>103.22</token></unit><unit id="57"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.23</section_number><catch_line>Surrender Of Permits.</catch_line><url>/103.23/</url><token>103.23</token></unit><unit id="1606"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.24</section_number><catch_line>Hours Of Business.</catch_line><url>/103.24/</url><token>103.24</token></unit><unit id="3896"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.25</section_number><catch_line>Doing Business With Minor.</catch_line><url>/103.25/</url><token>103.25</token></unit><unit id="3138"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.26</section_number><catch_line>True Name, Age And Address.</catch_line><url>/103.26/</url><token>103.26</token></unit><unit id="233"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.27</section_number><catch_line>Administration.</catch_line><url>/103.27/</url><token>103.27</token></unit><unit id="2008"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.28</section_number><catch_line>Investigation By Board.</catch_line><url>/103.28/</url><token>103.28</token></unit><unit id="3636"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.29</section_number><catch_line>Timing Of Action On Application.</catch_line><url>/103.29/</url><token>103.29</token></unit><unit id="1985"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.29.01</section_number><catch_line>Executive Director Action On Application.</catch_line><url>/103.29.01/</url><token>103.29.01</token></unit><unit id="3913"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.30</section_number><catch_line>Effect Of Granting Permit.</catch_line><url>/103.30/</url><token>103.30</token></unit><unit id="1563"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.31</section_number><catch_line>Denial Of Application.</catch_line><url>/103.31/</url><token>103.31</token></unit><unit id="608"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.31.1</section_number><catch_line>Final Decisions.</catch_line><url>/103.31.1/</url><token>103.31.1</token></unit><unit id="2525"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.31.2</section_number><catch_line>Effective Date Of Notices.</catch_line><url>/103.31.2/</url><token>103.31.2</token></unit><unit id="3821"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.32</section_number><catch_line>Denial &#x2013;Notice To Applicant.</catch_line><url>/103.32/</url><token>103.32</token></unit><unit id="569"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.33</section_number><catch_line>Hearing On Denial &#x2013; Request By Applicant.</catch_line><url>/103.33/</url><token>103.33</token></unit><unit id="3240"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.34</section_number><catch_line>Suspension Or Revocation Of Permits Issued Under This Article.</catch_line><url>/103.34/</url><token>103.34</token></unit><unit id="3508"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.34.1</section_number><catch_line>Suspension Or Revocation Of Permits Issued Pursuant To Sections 103.101.1, 103.102 And 103.109.</catch_line><url>/103.34.1/</url><token>103.34.1</token></unit><unit id="3371"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.34.2</section_number><catch_line>Judicial Review Of Board Action On Applications And Permits Subject To Sections 103.101.1, 103.102 And 103.109.</catch_line><url>/103.34.2/</url><token>103.34.2</token></unit><unit id="2882"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.35</section_number><catch_line>Disciplinary Action &#x2013; Grounds.</catch_line><url>/103.35/</url><token>103.35</token></unit><unit id="214"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.36</section_number><catch_line>Suspension Or Revocation Without Hearing.</catch_line><url>/103.36/</url><token>103.36</token></unit><unit id="2189"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.37</section_number><catch_line>Suspension Or Revocation &#x2013; Effect On Other Permits.</catch_line><url>/103.37/</url><token>103.37</token></unit><unit id="4000"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.38</section_number><catch_line>New Permit Application After Denial Or Revocation.</catch_line><url>/103.38/</url><token>103.38</token></unit><unit id="755"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.39</section_number><catch_line>Cancelled Or Suspended Permit &#x2013; Jurisdiction Of The Board.</catch_line><url>/103.39/</url><token>103.39</token></unit><unit id="3036"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.40</section_number><catch_line>Pending Revocation Or Suspension Proceedings &#x2013; Effect On Permittee.</catch_line><url>/103.40/</url><token>103.40</token></unit><unit id="2541"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.40.1</section_number><catch_line>Power Of Board To Limit And/Or Condition A Permit.</catch_line><url>/103.40.1/</url><token>103.40.1</token></unit><unit id="3520"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.40.2</section_number><catch_line>Subject Matter Of Limitations And/Or Conditions To A Permit.</catch_line><url>/103.40.2/</url><token>103.40.2</token></unit><unit id="982"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.41</section_number><catch_line>Prior Acts No Bar To Board Action.</catch_line><url>/103.41/</url><token>103.41</token></unit><unit id="911"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.42</section_number><catch_line>Stolen Property &#x2013; Investigation.</catch_line><url>/103.42/</url><token>103.42</token></unit><unit id="2845"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.43</section_number><catch_line>Record Search &#x2013; Charge Authorized.</catch_line><url>/103.43/</url><token>103.43</token></unit><unit id="102"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.44</section_number><catch_line>Instructional Materials &#x2013; Custody &#x2013; Fees For Rental Or Sale.</catch_line><url>/103.44/</url><token>103.44</token></unit><unit id="2184"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101</section_number><catch_line>Picture Arcade.</catch_line><url>/103.101/</url><token>103.101</token></unit><unit id="845"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101.1</section_number><catch_line>Picture Arcade Permits And Regulations.</catch_line><url>/103.101.1/</url><token>103.101.1</token></unit><unit id="3778"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101.2</section_number><catch_line>Compliance By Existing Permittees.</catch_line><url>/103.101.2/</url><token>103.101.2</token></unit><unit id="445"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101.3</section_number><catch_line>Game Arcade.</catch_line><url>/103.101.3/</url><token>103.101.3</token></unit><unit id="3234"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101.4</section_number><catch_line>Cyber Caf&#xC9;S.</catch_line><url>/103.101.4/</url><token>103.101.4</token></unit><unit id="1486"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.102</section_number><catch_line>Cafe Entertainment And Shows.</catch_line><url>/103.102/</url><token>103.102</token></unit><unit id="3379"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.102.1</section_number><catch_line>Additional Regulations.</catch_line><url>/103.102.1/</url><token>103.102.1</token></unit><unit id="3638"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.102.2</section_number><catch_line>Compliance By Existing Permittees And Effect Of Noncompliance.</catch_line><url>/103.102.2/</url><token>103.102.2</token></unit><unit id="2551"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.103</section_number><catch_line>Card Club &#x2013; Social Card Club &#x2013; Card School.</catch_line><url>/103.103/</url><token>103.103</token></unit><unit id="2151"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.104</section_number><catch_line>Carnivals.</catch_line><url>/103.104/</url><token>103.104</token></unit><unit id="1602"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.105</section_number><catch_line>Dancing Academies.</catch_line><url>/103.105/</url><token>103.105</token></unit><unit id="1052"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.106</section_number><catch_line>Dance Halls, Dancing Clubs, Public Dances.</catch_line><url>/103.106/</url><token>103.106</token></unit><unit id="2839"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.106.1</section_number><catch_line>Hostess Dance Hall.</catch_line><url>/103.106.1/</url><token>103.106.1</token></unit><unit id="3668"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.107</section_number><catch_line>Escort Bureaus.</catch_line><url>/103.107/</url><token>103.107</token></unit><unit id="268"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.107.1</section_number><catch_line>Escort &#x2013; Permit Required.</catch_line><url>/103.107.1/</url><token>103.107.1</token></unit><unit id="1084"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.109</section_number><catch_line>Motion Picture Shows.</catch_line><url>/103.109/</url><token>103.109</token></unit><unit id="94"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.111</section_number><catch_line>Parades And Assemblies.</catch_line><url>/103.111/</url><token>103.111</token></unit><unit id="3445"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.112</section_number><catch_line>Billiard Rooms, Poolrooms, Bowling Alleys.</catch_line><url>/103.112/</url><token>103.112</token></unit><unit id="3049"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.112.1</section_number><catch_line>Family Billiard Rooms.</catch_line><url>/103.112.1/</url><token>103.112.1</token></unit><unit id="277"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.113</section_number><catch_line>Rides.</catch_line><url>/103.113/</url><token>103.113</token></unit><unit id="442"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.115</section_number><catch_line>Skating Rinks.</catch_line><url>/103.115/</url><token>103.115</token></unit><unit id="2194"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.116</section_number><catch_line>Games Of Skill And Science.</catch_line><url>/103.116/</url><token>103.116</token></unit><unit id="384"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.117</section_number><catch_line>Rifle Range &#x2013; Shooting Gallery.</catch_line><url>/103.117/</url><token>103.117</token></unit><unit id="1306"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.118</section_number><catch_line>Teenage Dances.</catch_line><url>/103.118/</url><token>103.118</token></unit><unit id="2754"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.120</section_number><catch_line>Soundproofing Of Places Of Amusement &#x2013; When Required.</catch_line><url>/103.120/</url><token>103.120</token></unit><unit id="2832"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.202</section_number><catch_line>Automobile Parking Lots.</catch_line><url>/103.202/</url><token>103.202</token></unit><unit id="2880"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.204</section_number><catch_line>Towing Operation.</catch_line><url>/103.204/</url><token>103.204</token></unit><unit id="4074"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.204.1</section_number><catch_line>Tow Unit Operators.</catch_line><url>/103.204.1/</url><token>103.204.1</token></unit><unit id="448"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.205</section_number><catch_line>Massage Therapy.</catch_line><url>/103.205/</url><token>103.205</token></unit><unit id="3536"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.205.1</section_number><catch_line>Massage Therapists.</catch_line><url>/103.205.1/</url><token>103.205.1</token></unit><unit id="2047"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.205.2</section_number><catch_line>Baths.</catch_line><url>/103.205.2/</url><token>103.205.2</token></unit><unit id="687"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.206</section_number><catch_line>Alarm Systems.</catch_line><url>/103.206/</url><token>103.206</token></unit><unit id="2780"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.206.1</section_number><catch_line>Alarm Company Operators.</catch_line><url>/103.206.1/</url><token>103.206.1</token></unit><unit id="3551"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.206.2</section_number><catch_line>Commercial Unsecured Buildings.</catch_line><url>/103.206.2/</url><token>103.206.2</token></unit><unit id="2339"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.208</section_number><catch_line>Key Duplicator.</catch_line><url>/103.208/</url><token>103.208</token></unit><unit id="2609"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.211</section_number><catch_line>Handbill Distribution.</catch_line><url>/103.211/</url><token>103.211</token></unit><unit id="1701"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.212</section_number><catch_line>Soliciting &#x2013; Peace Officers&#x2019; And Firefighters&#x2019; Organizations &#x2013; Permits.</catch_line><url>/103.212/</url><token>103.212</token></unit><unit id="3677"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.213</section_number><catch_line>Figure Studios.</catch_line><url>/103.213/</url><token>103.213</token></unit><unit id="966"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.301</section_number><catch_line>Antique Shops.</catch_line><url>/103.301/</url><token>103.301</token></unit><unit id="1483"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.301.1</section_number><catch_line>Antique Show Or Collectors Exchange Show.</catch_line><url>/103.301.1/</url><token>103.301.1</token></unit><unit id="3136"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.304</section_number><catch_line>Junk Collectors.</catch_line><url>/103.304/</url><token>103.304</token></unit><unit id="3016"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.305</section_number><catch_line>Junk Dealers.</catch_line><url>/103.305/</url><token>103.305</token></unit><unit id="3600"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.306</section_number><catch_line>Pawnbroker.</catch_line><url>/103.306/</url><token>103.306</token></unit><unit id="1834"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.307</section_number><catch_line>Rummage Sale.</catch_line><url>/103.307/</url><token>103.307</token></unit><unit id="1830"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.308</section_number><catch_line>Sales &#x2013; Fire And Closing Out.</catch_line><url>/103.308/</url><token>103.308</token></unit><unit id="236"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.309</section_number><catch_line>Secondhand Auto Parts Dealer.</catch_line><url>/103.309/</url><token>103.309</token></unit><unit id="3361"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.310</section_number><catch_line>Secondhand Book Dealers.</catch_line><url>/103.310/</url><token>103.310</token></unit><unit id="3558"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.311</section_number><catch_line>Secondhand Dealers.</catch_line><url>/103.311/</url><token>103.311</token></unit><unit id="3738"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.311.1</section_number><catch_line>Firearms Sales By Secondhand Dealers Prohibited.</catch_line><url>/103.311.1/</url><token>103.311.1</token></unit><unit id="2476"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.314</section_number><catch_line>Sellers Of Firearms.</catch_line><url>/103.314/</url><token>103.314</token></unit><unit id="3698"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.314.1</section_number><catch_line>Sellers Of Firearm Ammunition.</catch_line><url>/103.314.1/</url><token>103.314.1</token></unit></structure_contents><next_section id="2754"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.120</section_number><catch_line>Soundproofing Of Places Of Amusement &#x2013; When Required.</catch_line><url>/103.120/</url><token>103.120</token></next_section><metadata></metadata><references></references><url>/103.118/</url><token>103.118</token><formats><txt>/103.118.txt</txt><json>/103.118.xml</json></formats><dublin_core><Title>Teenage Dances.</Title><Type>Text</Type><Format>text/html</Format><Identifier>&#xA7; 103.118</Identifier><Relation>Los Angeles Municipal Code</Relation></dublin_core><plain_text>                            LOS ANGELES MUNICIPAL CODE

TEENAGE DANCES. (&#xA7; 103.118)

&#xA0; TEENAGE DANCES.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 160,203, Eff. 9/2/85.)	(a)	Definitions.&#xA0; As used in this
article, the term &#x201C;premises&#x201D; shall mean any facility open to the public
where activity regulated hereunder is occurring, the room or rooms where such
activity is occurring and the area adjacent thereto to which direct access is
available from such room and the term &#x201C;Teenager&#x201D; shall mean any person over
the age of 13 years and under the age of 18 years.	(b)	Permit Required.	1.	No
person, dancing club or other association shall, without first obtaining a
permit from the Board, operate, manage or maintain any dance hall, &#x201C;disco&#x201D;,
nightclub or hostess hall, or conduct any public dance or dances wherein
teenagers are permitted to be present, except as herein provided.	2.	Such permit
shall be in addition to any other dance permit required by this
article.	(c)	Permit &#x2013; Application &#x2013; Contents of.&#xA0; An application for a
permit shall be accompanied by certification that the premises where a dance is
to be held or dancing activity is to occur is adequate for the purpose, and that
the premises conform with the existing health, safety, fire and zoning
ordinances of the City of Los Angeles. The certification shall also specify the
maximum number of persons that may safely be accommodated at the location where
the dance or dancing activity is to take place.	(d)	Exceptions.	1.	A permit
shall not be required for any agency or department of the City of Los Angeles,
County of Los Angeles, Board of Education, or other political subdivision of the
State of California, or for any religious or charitable organization holding a
valid tax exempt registration certificate under Section 21.22 of this Code and
which is normally engaged in youth or child-serving activities.	2.	A permit
shall not be required for any hotel, cafe, restaurant, banquet hall or catering
facility which does not predominantly cater to the patronage of teenagers and
where no charge or admission is imposed for the privilege of entering or
dancing.	(e)	Investigation.&#xA0; Upon the filing of an application, the Board shall
cause that investigation to be made which it deems necessary. The Board shall
issue no permit to the applicant unless the following conditions are
satisfied:	1.	The dance or dancing activity for which an application has been
filed conforms to the laws of the City of Los Angeles and of the State of
California, and will not constitute a menace to the health, peace or safety of
the community;	2.	A sufficient number of adult supervisors who are employees of
the location will be provided to insure compliance with the provisions of this
section and any rules or regulations promulgated by the Board with respect
thereto. For purposes herein, a sufficient number shall constitute, at a
minimum, a ratio of one adult to every 35 teenagers in attendance at the teenage
dance premises.	(f)	Lighting in Hall.&#xA0; Each of the premises where any dance or
dancing activity regulated under this section is held, shall be adequately
lighted at all times when open for dancing. For purposes herein, the volume of
illumination shall at no time be less than one foot-candle in any part of the
building and premises accessible to participants.	(g)	Parking &#x2013; Lighting.&#xA0;
All off-street parking facilities under the direct or indirect control of a
permittee shall be adequately lighted and supervised so as to ensure that
violations of this article or other laws do not occur. For purposes herein,
adequate lighting and supervision will be established by the Board at the time
of the granting or reviewing a permit.	(h)	Use of Drugs or Alcoholic Beverages
&#x2013; Prohibited.&#xA0; No alcoholic beverages shall be sold, consumed or be available
on the premises where there is a dance or dancing activity is being held which
is regulated by this section. Admission to the premises shall be denied to any
person showing evidence of drinking any alcoholic beverages or showing symptoms
of being intoxicated as a result of the ingestion of any chemical
substance.	(i)	Time Limit for Dances.&#xA0; Teenage dancing regulated hereunder
shall not be permitted after 1:00 a.m. on Saturdays, Sundays, and local public
school holidays. On all other days, except Fridays, Saturdays, and the day
before a legal holiday, teenage dancing regulated hereunder shall be prohibited
after the hour of 10:00 p.m., provided however that permission to continue
dancing after 10:00 p.m. on such other days may be granted by the Board during
public school vacation periods if the Board finds the continuation of dancing
after 10:00 p.m. does not unreasonably disturb the peace and quiet of the
surrounding neighborhood. In no event shall such an establishment be permitted
to continue such teenage dances or dancing activity later than 1:00
a.m.	(j)	Teenagers Under the Age of 15 Years.&#xA0; No person under the age of 15
years shall be permitted to enter any premises where there is dancing activity
regulated under this section unless such person is accompanied by a parent or
legal guardian unless the parent or legal guardian of such person has signed and
filed with the owner, manager or operator of the facility a consent form for
such minor to be there unaccompanied by said parent or guardian. The consent
shall be set forth on a form approved by the Board. Such form must be signed by
the parent or legal guardian in the presence of the owner, manager or operator
of the facility and shall contain the minor&#x2019;s name, date of birth, address,
and the parent or legal guardian&#x2019;s telephone number for use in case of an
emergency. In the event no such consent form has been so completed and filed,
such teenagers shall not be permitted to enter into or remain at the premises
unless accompanied or escorted by his or her parent or legal guardian. Any
teenager admitted and accompanied by a parent or legal guardian shall have the
rights and privileges of other legally admitted teenagers. Any teenager entering
pursuant to a consent form filed by his or her parent or legal guardian must
present valid identification as defined in Subsection (n).	(k)	Persons Under the
Age of 13 Years.&#xA0; In no event shall any person under the age of 13 years be
permitted to enter the premises where there is a dance or dancing activity being
held which is regulated under this section.	(l)	Persons Over the Age of 20
Years.&#xA0; No person over the age of 20 years shall be permitted to enter the
premises where there is a dance or dancing activity being held which is
regulated under this section unless that person is a parent or legal guardian
accompanying a child as required by Subsections (j) and (m)
herein.	(m)	Teenagers Between the Age of 15 and 18 Years.&#xA0; No person between
the ages of 15 and 18 years may be present at premises regulated under this
section unless he or she (1) is accompanied by a parent or legal guardian, or,
if unaccompanied, the parent or legal guardian of such person has signed and
filed a consent form similar to that required by Subsection (j) herein; or (2)
presents valid proof of age as defined in Subsection (n) herein.	(n)	Proof of
Age. &#xA0; Proof of age shall be required of each patron entering the
establishment. Such proof may be established by identification issued by a
governmental agency, the patron&#x2019;s school, or the Department of Motor Vehicles,
and must contain the patron&#x2019;s name, date of birth, and a picture that has been
taken within the preceding two years.	(o)	Denial of Entry on Request of
Parent.&#xA0; No person having charge or control of any premises regulated under
this section shall allow a teenager to enter or remain at the premises after
receiving a written notice signed by the parent or legal guardian of such
teenager which requests that said teenager be prevented from entering the
premises.	(p)	Attendance.&#xA0; Except in emergency situations, no patron shall be
permitted to leave the premises at which any dance or dancing activity regulated
by this section is being held and thereafter re-enter prior to the conclusion of
such dance or dancing activity. No pass or other indicia permitting re-entry
shall be issued.	(q)	Criminal History of Supervisory Staff.&#xA0; No person, dancing
club, or other association or entity obtaining a permit under this section shall
employ any person as a supervisory employee at the premises at the time of any
dancing activity regulated hereunder who has been convicted of a misdemeanor or
a felony in the last five (5) years, nor shall such permittee employ any person
who has been arrested and is out on bail or on his or her own recognizance
pending trial. As permitted by California Labor Code Section 432.7, such
permittee shall ask all applicants for such employment at the premises about any
conviction, as that term is used in said Labor Code Section, and about any
arrest for which the applicant is out on bail or on his or her own recognizance
pending trial. Copies of the employment applications of all persons hired shall
be filed with the Board. Upon a showing of just causes a permittee may apply to
the Board for a waiver of this provision. Just cause, as used in this
subsection, shall include but is not limited to a demonstration that the prior
conviction, or arrest as described herein, would not have an adverse effect on
the employee&#x2019;s ability to supervise teenagers at a location as described
within this section. While teenagers are present, all employees also present
within the premises, as that term is defined by this section, shall be
considered supervisory employees.	(r)	Duty of Management.&#xA0; If a teenager is
discovered inside the premises showing evidence or symptoms of being intoxicated
as a result of the ingestion of alcohol or any chemical substance, that teenager
shall be reported by management to local police authorities and to his or her
parent or legal guardian. Management shall attempt to separate the teenager from
other teenagers at the premises pending the arrival of police or the parent or
legal guardian of the teenager. A notice shall be posted by all pay phones
containing the local police telephone number and shall request all patrons to
call the police if management neglects to take action to report a violation of
this subsection.	(s)	Operation After 1:00 a.m. &#x2013; 18 Year Olds.&#xA0; If the
premises intends to operate after the closing time set forth in Subsection (i)
herein, the premises must first be vacated by all customers, and thereafter only
those persons 18 years of age or older who present valid identification
containing proof of age established as set forth in Subsection (n) herein may be
permitted to enter the premises.	(t)	Additional Restrictions by the Board.&#xA0; The
Board may promulgate additional rules as necessary with respect
thereto.	(u)	Regulation by Permittee.&#xA0; Nothing herein is intended to preclude
the imposition of more restrictive regulations by any permittee so long as the
regulations are not in conflict with any provision of this section.
</plain_text><html>
					&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#xA0; TEENAGE DANCES.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 160,203, Eff. 9/2/85.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(a)	Definitions.&#xA0; As used in this article, the term &#x201C;premises&#x201D; shall mean any facility open to the public where activity regulated hereunder is occurring, the room or rooms where such activity is occurring and the area adjacent thereto to which direct access is available from such room and the term &#x201C;Teenager&#x201D; shall mean any person over the age of 13 years and under the age of 18 years.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(b)	Permit Required.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	No person, dancing club or other association shall, without first obtaining a permit from the Board, operate, manage or maintain any dance hall, &#x201C;disco&#x201D;, nightclub or hostess hall, or conduct any public dance or dances wherein teenagers are permitted to be present, except as herein provided.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	Such permit shall be in addition to any other dance permit required by this article.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(c)	Permit &#x2013; Application &#x2013; Contents of.&#xA0; An application for a permit shall be accompanied by certification that the premises where a dance is to be held or dancing activity is to occur is adequate for the purpose, and that the premises conform with the existing health, safety, fire and zoning &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinances&lt;/span&gt; of the City of Los Angeles. The certification shall also specify the maximum number of persons that may safely be accommodated at the location where the dance or dancing activity is to take place.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(d)	Exceptions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	A permit shall not be required for any agency or department of the City of Los Angeles, County of Los Angeles, Board of Education, or other political subdivision of the State of California, or for any religious or charitable organization holding a valid tax exempt registration certificate under Section 21.22 of this Code and which is normally engaged in youth or child-serving activities.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	A permit shall not be required for any hotel, cafe, restaurant, banquet hall or catering facility which does not predominantly cater to the patronage of teenagers and where no charge or admission is imposed for the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;privilege&lt;/span&gt; of entering or dancing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(e)	Investigation.&#xA0; Upon the filing of an application, the Board shall cause that investigation to be made which it deems necessary. The Board shall &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;issue&lt;/span&gt; no permit to the applicant unless the following conditions are satisfied:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	The dance or dancing activity for which an application has been filed conforms to the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;laws&lt;/span&gt; of the City of Los Angeles and of the State of California, and will not constitute a menace to the health, peace or safety of the community;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	A sufficient number of adult supervisors who are employees of the location will be provided to insure compliance with the provisions of this section and any rules or regulations promulgated by the Board with respect thereto. For purposes herein, a sufficient number shall constitute, at a minimum, a ratio of one adult to every 35 teenagers in attendance at the teenage dance premises.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(f)	Lighting in Hall.&#xA0; Each of the premises where any dance or dancing activity regulated under this section is held, shall be adequately lighted at all times when open for dancing. For purposes herein, the volume of illumination shall at no time be less than one foot-candle in any part of the building and premises accessible to participants.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(g)	Parking &#x2013; Lighting.&#xA0; All off-street parking facilities under the direct or indirect control of a permittee shall be adequately lighted and supervised so as to ensure that violations of this article or other &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;laws&lt;/span&gt; do not occur. For purposes herein, adequate lighting and supervision will be established by the Board at the time of the granting or reviewing a permit.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(h)	Use of Drugs or Alcoholic Beverages &#x2013; Prohibited.&#xA0; No alcoholic beverages shall be sold, consumed or be available on the premises where there is a dance or dancing activity is being held which is regulated by this section. Admission to the premises shall be denied to any person showing &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;evidence&lt;/span&gt; of drinking any alcoholic beverages or showing symptoms of being intoxicated as a result of the ingestion of any chemical substance.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(i)	Time Limit for Dances.&#xA0; Teenage dancing regulated hereunder shall not be permitted after 1:00 a.m. on Saturdays, Sundays, and local public school holidays. On all other days, except Fridays, Saturdays, and the day before a legal holiday, teenage dancing regulated hereunder shall be prohibited after the hour of 10:00 p.m., provided however that permission to continue dancing after 10:00 p.m. on such other days may be granted by the Board during public school vacation periods if the Board finds the continuation of dancing after 10:00 p.m. does not unreasonably disturb the peace and quiet of the surrounding neighborhood. In no event shall such an establishment be permitted to continue such teenage dances or dancing activity later than 1:00 a.m.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(j)	Teenagers Under the Age of 15 Years.&#xA0; No person under the age of 15 years shall be permitted to enter any premises where there is dancing activity regulated under this section unless such person is accompanied by a parent or legal guardian unless the parent or legal guardian of such person has signed and filed with the owner, manager or operator of the facility a consent form for such &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt; to be there unaccompanied by said parent or guardian. The consent shall be set forth on a form approved by the Board. Such form must be signed by the parent or legal guardian in the presence of the owner, manager or operator of the facility and shall contain the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt;&#x2019;s name, date of birth, address, and the parent or legal guardian&#x2019;s telephone number for use in case of an emergency. In the event no such consent form has been so completed and filed, such teenagers shall not be permitted to enter into or remain at the premises unless accompanied or escorted by his or her parent or legal guardian. Any teenager admitted and accompanied by a parent or legal guardian shall have the rights and &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;privileges&lt;/span&gt; of other legally admitted teenagers. Any teenager entering pursuant to a consent form filed by his or her parent or legal guardian must present valid identification as defined in Subsection (n).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(k)	Persons Under the Age of 13 Years.&#xA0; In no event shall any person under the age of 13 years be permitted to enter the premises where there is a dance or dancing activity being held which is regulated under this section.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(l)	Persons Over the Age of 20 Years.&#xA0; No person over the age of 20 years shall be permitted to enter the premises where there is a dance or dancing activity being held which is regulated under this section unless that person is a parent or legal guardian accompanying a child as required by Subsections (j) and (m) herein.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(m)	Teenagers Between the Age of 15 and 18 Years.&#xA0; No person between the ages of 15 and 18 years may be present at premises regulated under this section unless he or she (1) is accompanied by a parent or legal guardian, or, if unaccompanied, the parent or legal guardian of such person has signed and filed a consent form similar to that required by Subsection (j) herein; or (2) presents valid proof of age as defined in Subsection (n) herein.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(n)	Proof of Age. &#xA0; Proof of age shall be required of each patron entering the establishment. Such proof may be established by identification issued by a governmental agency, the patron&#x2019;s school, or the Department of Motor Vehicles, and must contain the patron&#x2019;s name, date of birth, and a picture that has been taken within the preceding two years.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(o)	Denial of Entry on Request of Parent.&#xA0; No person having charge or control of any premises regulated under this section shall allow a teenager to enter or remain at the premises after receiving a written notice signed by the parent or legal guardian of such teenager which requests that said teenager be prevented from entering the premises.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(p)	Attendance.&#xA0; Except in emergency situations, no patron shall be permitted to leave the premises at which any dance or dancing activity regulated by this section is being held and thereafter re-enter prior to the conclusion of such dance or dancing activity. No pass or other indicia permitting re-entry shall be issued.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(q)	Criminal History of Supervisory Staff.&#xA0; No person, dancing club, or other association or entity obtaining a permit under this section shall employ any person as a supervisory employee at the premises at the time of any dancing activity regulated hereunder who has been convicted of a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;misdemeanor&lt;/span&gt; or a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;felony&lt;/span&gt; in the last five (5) years, nor shall such permittee employ any person who has been arrested and is out on &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;bail&lt;/span&gt; or on his or her own &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;recognizance&lt;/span&gt; pending &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;trial&lt;/span&gt;. As permitted by California Labor Code Section 432.7, such permittee shall ask all applicants for such employment at the premises about any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;conviction&lt;/span&gt;, as that term is used in said Labor Code Section, and about any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;arrest&lt;/span&gt; for which the applicant is out on &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;bail&lt;/span&gt; or on his or her own &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;recognizance&lt;/span&gt; pending &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;trial&lt;/span&gt;. Copies of the employment applications of all persons hired shall be filed with the Board. Upon a showing of just causes a permittee may apply to the Board for a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;waiver&lt;/span&gt; of this provision. Just cause, as used in this subsection, shall include but is not limited to a demonstration that the prior &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;conviction&lt;/span&gt;, or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;arrest&lt;/span&gt; as described herein, would not have an adverse effect on the employee&#x2019;s ability to supervise teenagers at a location as described within this section. While teenagers are present, all employees also present within the premises, as that term is defined by this section, shall be considered supervisory employees.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(r)	Duty of Management.&#xA0; If a teenager is discovered inside the premises showing &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;evidence&lt;/span&gt; or symptoms of being intoxicated as a result of the ingestion of alcohol or any chemical substance, that teenager shall be reported by management to local police authorities and to his or her parent or legal guardian. Management shall attempt to separate the teenager from other teenagers at the premises pending the arrival of police or the parent or legal guardian of the teenager. A notice shall be posted by all pay phones containing the local police telephone number and shall request all patrons to call the police if management neglects to take action to report a violation of this subsection.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(s)	Operation After 1:00 a.m. &#x2013; 18 Year Olds.&#xA0; If the premises intends to operate after the closing time set forth in Subsection (i) herein, the premises must first be vacated by all customers, and thereafter only those persons 18 years of age or older who present valid identification containing proof of age established as set forth in Subsection (n) herein may be permitted to enter the premises.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(t)	Additional Restrictions by the Board.&#xA0; The Board may promulgate additional rules as necessary with respect thereto.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(u)	Regulation by Permittee.&#xA0; Nothing herein is intended to preclude the imposition of more restrictive regulations by any permittee so long as the regulations are not in conflict with any provision of this section.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</html><previous_section id="384"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.117</section_number><catch_line>Rifle Range &#x2013; Shooting Gallery.</catch_line><url>/103.117/</url><token>103.117</token></previous_section><text><unit id="1292" prefix=""><text>&#xA0; TEENAGE DANCES.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 160,203, Eff. 9/2/85.)	(a)	Definitions.&#xA0; As used in this article, the term &#x201C;premises&#x201D; shall mean any facility open to the public where activity regulated hereunder is occurring, the room or rooms where such activity is occurring and the area adjacent thereto to which direct access is available from such room and the term &#x201C;Teenager&#x201D; shall mean any person over the age of 13 years and under the age of 18 years.	(b)	Permit Required.	1.	No person, dancing club or other association shall, without first obtaining a permit from the Board, operate, manage or maintain any dance hall, &#x201C;disco&#x201D;, nightclub or hostess hall, or conduct any public dance or dances wherein teenagers are permitted to be present, except as herein provided.	2.	Such permit shall be in addition to any other dance permit required by this article.	(c)	Permit &#x2013; Application &#x2013; Contents of.&#xA0; An application for a permit shall be accompanied by certification that the premises where a dance is to be held or dancing activity is to occur is adequate for the purpose, and that the premises conform with the existing health, safety, fire and zoning ordinances of the City of Los Angeles. The certification shall also specify the maximum number of persons that may safely be accommodated at the location where the dance or dancing activity is to take place.	(d)	Exceptions.	1.	A permit shall not be required for any agency or department of the City of Los Angeles, County of Los Angeles, Board of Education, or other political subdivision of the State of California, or for any religious or charitable organization holding a valid tax exempt registration certificate under Section 21.22 of this Code and which is normally engaged in youth or child-serving activities.	2.	A permit shall not be required for any hotel, cafe, restaurant, banquet hall or catering facility which does not predominantly cater to the patronage of teenagers and where no charge or admission is imposed for the privilege of entering or dancing.	(e)	Investigation.&#xA0; Upon the filing of an application, the Board shall cause that investigation to be made which it deems necessary. The Board shall issue no permit to the applicant unless the following conditions are satisfied:	1.	The dance or dancing activity for which an application has been filed conforms to the laws of the City of Los Angeles and of the State of California, and will not constitute a menace to the health, peace or safety of the community;	2.	A sufficient number of adult supervisors who are employees of the location will be provided to insure compliance with the provisions of this section and any rules or regulations promulgated by the Board with respect thereto. For purposes herein, a sufficient number shall constitute, at a minimum, a ratio of one adult to every 35 teenagers in attendance at the teenage dance premises.	(f)	Lighting in Hall.&#xA0; Each of the premises where any dance or dancing activity regulated under this section is held, shall be adequately lighted at all times when open for dancing. For purposes herein, the volume of illumination shall at no time be less than one foot-candle in any part of the building and premises accessible to participants.	(g)	Parking &#x2013; Lighting.&#xA0; All off-street parking facilities under the direct or indirect control of a permittee shall be adequately lighted and supervised so as to ensure that violations of this article or other laws do not occur. For purposes herein, adequate lighting and supervision will be established by the Board at the time of the granting or reviewing a permit.	(h)	Use of Drugs or Alcoholic Beverages &#x2013; Prohibited.&#xA0; No alcoholic beverages shall be sold, consumed or be available on the premises where there is a dance or dancing activity is being held which is regulated by this section. Admission to the premises shall be denied to any person showing evidence of drinking any alcoholic beverages or showing symptoms of being intoxicated as a result of the ingestion of any chemical substance.	(i)	Time Limit for Dances.&#xA0; Teenage dancing regulated hereunder shall not be permitted after 1:00 a.m. on Saturdays, Sundays, and local public school holidays. On all other days, except Fridays, Saturdays, and the day before a legal holiday, teenage dancing regulated hereunder shall be prohibited after the hour of 10:00 p.m., provided however that permission to continue dancing after 10:00 p.m. on such other days may be granted by the Board during public school vacation periods if the Board finds the continuation of dancing after 10:00 p.m. does not unreasonably disturb the peace and quiet of the surrounding neighborhood. In no event shall such an establishment be permitted to continue such teenage dances or dancing activity later than 1:00 a.m.	(j)	Teenagers Under the Age of 15 Years.&#xA0; No person under the age of 15 years shall be permitted to enter any premises where there is dancing activity regulated under this section unless such person is accompanied by a parent or legal guardian unless the parent or legal guardian of such person has signed and filed with the owner, manager or operator of the facility a consent form for such minor to be there unaccompanied by said parent or guardian. The consent shall be set forth on a form approved by the Board. Such form must be signed by the parent or legal guardian in the presence of the owner, manager or operator of the facility and shall contain the minor&#x2019;s name, date of birth, address, and the parent or legal guardian&#x2019;s telephone number for use in case of an emergency. In the event no such consent form has been so completed and filed, such teenagers shall not be permitted to enter into or remain at the premises unless accompanied or escorted by his or her parent or legal guardian. Any teenager admitted and accompanied by a parent or legal guardian shall have the rights and privileges of other legally admitted teenagers. Any teenager entering pursuant to a consent form filed by his or her parent or legal guardian must present valid identification as defined in Subsection (n).	(k)	Persons Under the Age of 13 Years.&#xA0; In no event shall any person under the age of 13 years be permitted to enter the premises where there is a dance or dancing activity being held which is regulated under this section.	(l)	Persons Over the Age of 20 Years.&#xA0; No person over the age of 20 years shall be permitted to enter the premises where there is a dance or dancing activity being held which is regulated under this section unless that person is a parent or legal guardian accompanying a child as required by Subsections (j) and (m) herein.	(m)	Teenagers Between the Age of 15 and 18 Years.&#xA0; No person between the ages of 15 and 18 years may be present at premises regulated under this section unless he or she (1) is accompanied by a parent or legal guardian, or, if unaccompanied, the parent or legal guardian of such person has signed and filed a consent form similar to that required by Subsection (j) herein; or (2) presents valid proof of age as defined in Subsection (n) herein.	(n)	Proof of Age. &#xA0; Proof of age shall be required of each patron entering the establishment. Such proof may be established by identification issued by a governmental agency, the patron&#x2019;s school, or the Department of Motor Vehicles, and must contain the patron&#x2019;s name, date of birth, and a picture that has been taken within the preceding two years.	(o)	Denial of Entry on Request of Parent.&#xA0; No person having charge or control of any premises regulated under this section shall allow a teenager to enter or remain at the premises after receiving a written notice signed by the parent or legal guardian of such teenager which requests that said teenager be prevented from entering the premises.	(p)	Attendance.&#xA0; Except in emergency situations, no patron shall be permitted to leave the premises at which any dance or dancing activity regulated by this section is being held and thereafter re-enter prior to the conclusion of such dance or dancing activity. No pass or other indicia permitting re-entry shall be issued.	(q)	Criminal History of Supervisory Staff.&#xA0; No person, dancing club, or other association or entity obtaining a permit under this section shall employ any person as a supervisory employee at the premises at the time of any dancing activity regulated hereunder who has been convicted of a misdemeanor or a felony in the last five (5) years, nor shall such permittee employ any person who has been arrested and is out on bail or on his or her own recognizance pending trial. As permitted by California Labor Code Section 432.7, such permittee shall ask all applicants for such employment at the premises about any conviction, as that term is used in said Labor Code Section, and about any arrest for which the applicant is out on bail or on his or her own recognizance pending trial. Copies of the employment applications of all persons hired shall be filed with the Board. Upon a showing of just causes a permittee may apply to the Board for a waiver of this provision. Just cause, as used in this subsection, shall include but is not limited to a demonstration that the prior conviction, or arrest as described herein, would not have an adverse effect on the employee&#x2019;s ability to supervise teenagers at a location as described within this section. While teenagers are present, all employees also present within the premises, as that term is defined by this section, shall be considered supervisory employees.	(r)	Duty of Management.&#xA0; If a teenager is discovered inside the premises showing evidence or symptoms of being intoxicated as a result of the ingestion of alcohol or any chemical substance, that teenager shall be reported by management to local police authorities and to his or her parent or legal guardian. Management shall attempt to separate the teenager from other teenagers at the premises pending the arrival of police or the parent or legal guardian of the teenager. A notice shall be posted by all pay phones containing the local police telephone number and shall request all patrons to call the police if management neglects to take action to report a violation of this subsection.	(s)	Operation After 1:00 a.m. &#x2013; 18 Year Olds.&#xA0; If the premises intends to operate after the closing time set forth in Subsection (i) herein, the premises must first be vacated by all customers, and thereafter only those persons 18 years of age or older who present valid identification containing proof of age established as set forth in Subsection (n) herein may be permitted to enter the premises.	(t)	Additional Restrictions by the Board.&#xA0; The Board may promulgate additional rules as necessary with respect thereto.	(u)	Regulation by Permittee.&#xA0; Nothing herein is intended to preclude the imposition of more restrictive regulations by any permittee so long as the regulations are not in conflict with any provision of this section.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><unit></unit></prefixes><entire_prefix></entire_prefix><prefix_anchor></prefix_anchor><level>1</level></unit></text></law>
