<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><section_number>103.205</section_number><edition_id>1</edition_id><section_id>448</section_id><structure_id>33</structure_id><catch_line>Massage Therapy.</catch_line><history></history><full_text>&#xA0; MASSAGE THERAPY. (Amended by Ord. No. 171,994, Eff.
5/31/98.) The City of Los Angeles recognizes that the practice of
massage is therapeutic and the therapist must have a basic
knowledge of anatomy, physiology and an understanding of the
relationship between the structure and the function of the tissues
being treated and the total function of the body.&#xA0; The City
also recognizes that the practice of massage without sufficient
training and standards can be dangerous to the public.&#xA0;
Therefore, the purpose and intent of this Ordinance is to regulate
massage establishments and massage therapy practitioners in order
to protect and promote the public health, safety and welfare by: 1.
Providing appropriate standards for education and training of
massage therapists. 2. Providing a clean, sanitary, healthy and
safe environment in which massage therapy is offered to the public.
3. Recognizing massage therapy as a legitimate business occupation
and promoting the public confidence therein. (a) Definitions.&#xA0;
Unless the context or subject matter clearly indicates that a
different meaning is intended, the following words and phrases
shall have the following meanings when used in this section. (1)
&#x201C;Board&#x201D; means the Board of Police Commissioners. (2) &#x201C;&#xFFFD;&#xFFFD; means any
method of pressure on or friction against, or stroking, kneading,
rubbing, tapping, pounding, or stimulating the external parts of
the body with the hands or other parts of the body,&#xA0; or any
other type system for treating or manipulating the human body with
or without the aid of any mechanical or electrical apparatus or
appliances, or with or without supplementary aids such as rubbing
alcohol, liniments, antiseptics, oils, powder, creams, lotions,
ointments, or other similar preparations commonly used in this
practice. (3) &#x201C;Massage Business&#x201D; means the activity or providing,
for any form of consideration or gratuity, facilities for:&#xA0;
massage therapy, administration of fomentation, massage, electric
or magnetic treatment, or alcohol rub;&#xA0; or any other type
system for treating or manipulating the human body. (4)
&#x201C;Off-Premises Massage&#x201D; means activity of providing massage
services, or massage facilities as defined herein at a location
other than premises licensed by a permit from the Board. (5)
&#x201C;Massage Therapist&#x201D; means any person who, for any form of
consideration whatsoever, gives or administers to another person a
&#x201C;massage&#x201D; as defined in this section. (6) &#x201C;Permit&#x201D; means the permit
required to be obtained from the Board for the operation of a
Massage business, an Off-Premises Massage business, or for
performing the activities of a Massage Therapist, with or without
an off-premises endorsement. (7) &#x201C;Health Department&#x201D; means the
County of Los Angeles Department of Health Services. (b)
On-Premises Massage Business &#x2013; Permit Required.&#xA0; (Amended by
Ord. No. 175,167, Eff. 5/20/03.)&#xA0; No person shall engage in,
promote, advertise, conduct, or carry on, in or upon any premises
within the City of Los Angeles, the operation of a massage business
without a permit duly issued by the Board pursuant to this
subsection for each business location.&#xA0; This required permit
shall be in addition to any business tax license required by
ordinance. (1) Application for Permit. Permit applications shall be
made in accordance with Chapter X, Article 3, Division 3 of this
Code. (2) Additional Requirements.&#xA0; In addition to those
requirements specified in Chapter X, Article 3, Division 3 of this
Code, each applicant for a Massage permit shall furnish the
following information to the Board: (i) Each residence and business
address of the applicant for the five years&#xA0; immediately
preceding the date the application, and in the inclusive dates of
each address. (ii) Written proof that the applicant is at least 18
years of age. (iii) Applicant&#x2019;s height, weight, color of eyes and
hair. (iv) Three photographs of applicant, of a size specified by
the Board, taken within the six months immediately preceding the
date of application. (v) Applicant&#x2019;s business, occupation and
employment history for the five years immediately preceding the
date of application. (vi) The permit history of the
applicant:&#xA0; whether the person has ever had a&#xA0; license or
permit issued by any agency or board, City, County or State revoked
or suspended, or has had any professional or vocational license or
permit revoked or suspended, and the reason for the revocation or
suspension. (vii) Any other identification and information as may
be required by the Board. (viii) If the applicant is a corporation,
the name of the corporation shall be set forth exactly as shown in
its Articles of Incorporation or Charter, together with the State
and date of incorporation and names and residence addresses of each
of its current officers and directors, and each stockholder holding
more than five percent of the stock of the corporation.&#xA0; If
the applicant is a partnership, the application shall set forth the
name and residence addresses of each of the partners, including
limited partnership, and it shall furnish a copy of its certificate
of limited partnership as filed with the County Clerk.&#xA0; If one
or more of the partners is a corporation, the provisions of this
subsection pertaining to corporation applicants shall apply.&#xA0;
The applicant corporation or partnership shall designate a
responsible managing officer.&#xA0; This person shall complete and
sign all application forms required for an individual applicant
under this ordinance, but only one application fee shall be
charged.&#xA0; A change application shall be filed to change the
responsible managing officer but no additional inspection shall be
necessary.&#xA0; The corporation&#x2019;s or partnership&#x2019;s responsible
managing officer must at all times meet all of the requirements set
for permittees by this section or the corporation or partnership
permit shall be suspended until a responsible managing officer who
does meet all these requirements is designated.&#xA0; If no person
is named within 90 days, the corporation or partnership permit is
deemed cancelled and a new initial application for permit must be
filed. (ix) The name and address of the Owner and Lessor of the
Real Property upon or in which the business is to be conducted, and
a copy of the deed, lease or rental agreements. (x) Upon filing of
the application for a Massage permit with the Office of Finance,
the Office of Finance shall notify the Department of Health.&#xA0;
This department shall cause an inspection to be made of the
premises sought to be licensed within 20 days to ascertain if the
premises are in compliance with all applicable health laws.&#xA0;
If the premises are in compliance, the department shall issue a
letter to the Office of Finance so stating, which shall be
forwarded to the Board with the application.&#xA0; If the premises
are not in compliance, the department shall issue a letter to the
applicant setting forth the deficiencies and shall reinspect the
premises no more than twice upon written request of the
applicant.&#xA0; If a letter of full compliance is not issued by
the department within 90 days of the date of the filing of the
application, the application shall be deemed withdrawn and a new
application must be filed.&#xA0; The Office of Finance shall not
forward the application to the Board until the Health Department
has issued a letter of compliance. (xi) All convictions for any
crime involving conduct which requires registration under any state
law similar to and including California Penal Code Section 290, or
of conduct which is a violation of the provisions of any state law
similar to and including California Penal Code Sections 266i, 314,
315, 316, 318, 647(a), 647(b), or any crime involving dishonesty,
fraud, deceit, or moral turpitude. (xii) A complete list of the
names and residence addresses of all of the proposed massage
therapists and employees practicing in the massage establishment or
off-premises massage business and the name of the manager or
managing employee proposed to be principally in charge of the
operation of the massage establishment or off-premises massage
business.&#xA0; (xiii) A statement in writing by the applicant that
he or she certifies under penalty of perjury that all information
contained in the application is true and correct, with the
declaration being duly dated and signed in the City. (c) Public
Hearings. (1) In addition to the requirements of Subsection (a) and
(b) above, and subsequent to compliance with the provisions of (b),
if substantial public protest or adverse information concerning the
applicant is received, the Board or upon its direction, an Examiner
shall hold a public hearing to gather input from the public before
a permit for the operation of a massage business is issued.&#xA0;
All relevant information so obtained shall be used by the Board in
determining whether or not to issue a massage business
permit.&#xA0; Public hearings shall be held in accordance with
Chapter X, Article 2, Division 3 of this Code. (2) (Amended by Ord.
No. 173,300, Eff. 6/30/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)&#xA0; Notice of an
applicant&#x2019;s intent to establish a massage business &#xA0; shall be
given in the following manner: (i) By at least one publication in a
newspaper of general circulation in the City, designated for that
purpose by the Office of Finance, not less than 24 days after
applying for the permit. (ii) When a public hearing is scheduled,
written notice shall be mailed not less than 24 days prior to the
date of such hearing to the applicant, to the owner or owners of
the property within and outside the City that is within 300 feet of
the area proposed to be subject of the permit application as shown
upon the records of the Office of Finance, or in the case of
property outside of the City the records of the County Assessor.
(3) Record &#x2013; The hearing procedure shall be recorded or summarized
as directed by the Board.&#xA0; When proceedings are recorded and
not summarized, they shall be transcribed at the request of any
party or interested person upon the prepayment of a fee, as
required by ordinance.&#xA0; One copy of such transcript shall be
furnished the Commission to be placed in the files. (4) Hearings -
conducted by whom &#x2013; The public hearing may be conducted by the
Board or an Examiner at its direction.&#xA0; After the conclusion
of a public hearing conducted by an Examiner, the Examiner shall
submit his report to the Board within such time, which may be fixed
by the Board, setting forth his conclusions and recommendations in
writing and stating briefly his reasons therefore. (d) Massage
Business &#x2013; Operating Requirements.&#xA0; No person shall engage in,
promote, advertise, conduct, carry on, or permit to be engaged in,
promoted, advertised, conducted or carried on, any Massage business
unless each and all of the following requirements are met. (1) Each
person employed or acting as a Massage Therapist shall have a valid
permit issued by the Board.&#xA0; It shall be unlawful for any
owner, operator, responsible managing employee, manager or
permittee in charge of or in control of a Massage Business to
employ or permit a person to act as a Massage Therapist, as defined
in this section, who is not in possession of a valid, unrevoked
Massage Therapist permit issued pursuant to this Code. (2) The
possession of a valid Massage Business permit does not authorize
the possessor to perform work for which a Massage Therapist permit
is required. (3) Massage operations shall be carried on, and the
premises shall be open, only between the hours of 7:00 a.m. and
10:00 p.m. (4) A list of services available and the cost of such
services shall be posted in an open and conspicuous place on the
premises.&#xA0; The services shall be described in readily
understandable language. (5) The Massage Business permit, and a
copy of the permit of each and every Massage Therapist employed in
the establishment, shall be displayed in an open and conspicuous
place on the premises. (6) Every permittee operating a Massage
Business under a permit issued pursuant to this Section shall keep
a record of the date and hour of each treatment, the name and
address of the patron, the name of the employee administering such
treatment, and the type of treatment administered.&#xA0; Such
record shall be maintained on a professionally printed form
provided by the permittee.&#xA0; Such records shall be open to
inspection only by Public Health Investigators.&#xA0; The
information furnished or secured as a result of any such record
shall be confidential.&#xA0; Any unauthorized disclosure or use of
such information by an employee of the business or the City or
County of Los Angeles shall constitute a misdemeanor, and such
employee shall be subject to the penalty provisions of this Code in
addition to any other penalties provided by law.&#xA0; Such records
shall be maintained for a period of one (1) year. (7) The
Department of Health shall, from time to time, and at least once a
year, make an inspection of each Massage Business in the City for
the purposes of determining that the health provisions of the laws
of the State of California and ordinances of the City and County of
Los Angeles and this section are met (8) The Massage business meets
any or all of the following conditions which may, in the discretion
of the Board, be imposed on such Business. (i) A minimum of one (1)
tub or shower, and one (1) toilet and wash basin shall be provided
for the patrons in every Massage Business location;&#xA0; however,
if male and female patrons are to be served simultaneously at said
establishment, separate toilet facilities shall be provided for
male and female patrons.&#xA0; In those establishments where steam
rooms or sauna baths are provided, if male and female patrons are
to be served simultaneously, separate steam rooms or sauna rooms
shall be provided for male and female patrons.&#xA0; Hot and cold
running water under pressure shall be provided to all wash basins,
bathtubs, showers, and similar equipment.&#xA0; Each wash basin
shall be provided with soap or detergent and sanitary towels placed
in permanently installed dispensers.&#xA0; A trash receptacle shall
be provided in each toilet room.&#xA0; In addition to the wash
basin provided for patrons, a minimum of one separate wash basin
shall be provided in each massage establishment.&#xA0; This basin
shall provide soap or detergent and hot and cold running water at
all times and shall be located within or as close as practicable to
the area devoted to the performing of massage services.&#xA0; In
addition, there shall be provided at each wash basin, sanitary
towels placed in permanently installed dispensers. EXCEPTION: If
the wash basin for the patrons is not in the toilet room but is
adjacent thereto, this wash basin will meet the separate wash basin
requirement if it is reasonably close to the area devoted to the
performing of massage. (ii) Minimum ventilation shall be provided
in accordance with the Building code of the City of Los
Angeles.&#xA0; A light level of no less than 25 watts shall be
maintained in public rooms, walkways, and at any point within each
room or enclosure where massage services are being performed, and
at all times such services are being provided. (iii) All walls,
ceilings, floors, pools, showers, bathtubs, wet and dry heat rooms,
steam or vapor rooms, tables and all other physical facilities
shall be in good repair and maintained in a clean and sanitary
condition.&#xA0; Wet and dry heat rooms, steam or vapor rooms or
cabinets, showers, compartments and toilet rooms shall be
thoroughly cleaned at least once each day the business is in
operation.&#xA0; Bathtubs shall be thoroughly cleaned after each
use. (iv) Clean and sanitary towels, sheets and linens shall be
provided for each patron of the establishment or each patron
receiving massage services.&#xA0; No common use of towels or linens
shall be permitted.&#xA0; Towels, sheets and linens shall be
provided in sufficient quantity and shall not be used by more than
one (1) person unless they have been first relaundered.&#xA0; Heavy
white paper may be substituted for sheets provided that such paper
is used one for each person and then discarded into a sanitary
receptacle.&#xA0; Separate closed cabinets or containers shall be
provided for the storage of clean and soiled linen and shall be
plainly marked:&#xA0; &#x201C;clean linen&#x201D; and &#x201C;soiled linen.&#x201D; (v)
Disinfecting agents and sterilizing equipment approved by the
Health Department shall be provided for any instruments used in
performing any massage. (vi) Pads used on massage tables shall be
covered in a workmanlike manner with durable, washable plastic or
other waterproof material acceptable to the Health Department.
(vii) All exterior and interior massage room doors shall remain
unlocked during business hours. (viii) A separate locker shall be
provided for each patron to be served, such locker shall be capable
of being locked and available at no extra charge. (ix) No person
shall enter, be or remain, in any part of a Massage Business
location while in the possession of, consuming, or using any
alcoholic beverages or drugs except pursuant to a prescription for
such drugs.&#xA0; The owner, operator, responsible managing
employee, manager or permittee shall not permit any such person to
enter or remain upon such premises. (x) All employees including
Massage Therapists, shall be clean, and shall be fully clothed in
clean nontransparent outer garments.&#xA0; As used herein, &#x201C;fully
clothed&#x201D; shall mean the wearing of undergarments such as bras and
underwear as well as the wearing of clothing which is comparable to
the clothing commonly worn by nurses and physical therapists while
performing their respective professional duties. (e) Off-Premises
Massage Business &#x2013; Permit Required.&#xA0; No person shall engage
in, promote, advertise, conduct, carry on, or permit to be engaged
in, promoted, advertised, conducted or carried on, any Off-Premises
Massage Business in the City of Los Angeles, without a permit duly
issued by the Board pursuant to this subsection for each business
location.&#xA0; The permit required hereby shall be in addition to
any business tax license required by ordinance. (1) Application for
Permit.&#xA0; Permit Applications shall be made in accordance with
the requirements of Chapter X, Article 3, and Section 103.205(b)(2)
of this Code. (2) Operating Requirements.&#xA0; The operating
requirements are as set forth in Section 103.205(d) of this Code
and the following additional requirements shall apply: (i) The
owner, operator, responsible managing employee, manager or
permittee of an Off-Premises Massage Business shall display the
permit issued therefore and a true and correct copy of the permit
of each and every Massage Therapist employed by the business in an
open and conspicuous manner on the business premises and to every
customer who requests the information contained in the permits.
(ii) A record of treatment shall be maintained by each Massage
Therapist employed by the business. (iii) No person operating an
Off-Premises Massage Business shall employee or allow a person to
act as an Off-Premises Massage Therapist unless such person has a
valid, unrevoked Massage Therapist permit endorsed by the Board of
Police Commissioners for Off-Premises Massage. (iv) Upon any change
of employees, the permittee shall inform the Board within ten (10)
days of such change. (f) Massage Business/Off-Premises Permit
Issuance and Denial. (1) Upon receipt of a written application for
a permit to conduct a Massage Business or Off-Premises Massage
Business, the Board shall conduct an investigation in order to
ascertain whether such permit should be issued as requested.&#xA0;
The Board shall approve, conditionally approve, set for an
Administrative Hearing or &#x2018;File Without Further Action&#x2019; the
application within ninety (90) days of the filing of an
application.&#xA0; The Board shall issue such permit as requested
unless the Board makes any of the following findings: (a) Any
person, including but not limited to, employees who will be
directly engaged or employed in the massage establishment or
Off-Premises Massage Business has been convicted or a violation of
Health and Safety Code Section 11550 or a violation of Penal Code
Section 266i, 315, 316, 318, 647(a) P.C., 647(b), or has been
convicted in any other State of any offense which if committed or
attempted in this State, would have been punished as one or more of
the above mentioned offenses, or that any such person is required
to register under the provisions of Penal Code Section 290. (b) Any
person, including, but not limited to, employees who will be
directly engaged or employed in the massage establishment or
Off-Premises Massage Business who has been convicted of any felony
offense involving the sale of a controlled substance specified in
Health and Safety Code Sections 11054, 11055, 11056, 11057, or
11058 or has been convicted in any other State of any offense
which, if committed or attempted in this State would have been
punishable as one or more of the above mentioned offenses. (c) Any
person including, but not limited to, employees who will be
directly engaged or employed in the massage establishment or
Off-Premises Massage Business, who has committed an act, which, if
done by a licensee or permittee under this Chapter, would be
grounds for suspension or revocation of a license or permit. (d)
Any person including, but not limited to, employees who will be
directly engaged or employed in the massage establishment or
Off-Premises Massage Business, who has committed an act involving
dishonesty, fraud, or deceit with the intent to substantially
benefit himself, herself, or another or substantially to injure
another, or an act of violence, which act or acts are substantially
related to the qualifications, functions, or duties of the massage
establishment or Off-Premises Massage Business. (e) The operations
of the massage establishment or Off- Premise Massage Business
would, if allowed, constitute a public nuisance. (f) The applicant
has knowingly made a false, misleading, or fraudulent statement of
fact to the City in the permit application process. (g) The
application does not contain the information required by this
section. (h) The applicant has not satisfied the requirements of
this Code. (2) Conditions of Permit Issuance.&#xA0; The Board shall
condition the issuance of an operator&#x2019;s permit to insure compliance
with this section and other applicable laws.&#xA0; Such conditions
shall include, but not be limited to, the following: (a) The front
door of the massage establishment and the doors of the interior
treatment rooms in which massages are being performed must remain
unlocked during all hours of operation.&#xA0; No electronic locking
device may be utilized on any entrance door.&#xA0; No warning
devices such as buzzers may be installed.&#xA0; No locks may be
installed on any of the treatment room doors. (b) No massage
therapist/practitioner or employee shall expose his or her
genitals, buttocks, or, in the case of a female, her breast nor, in
the course of administering a massage, make intentional contact
with the genitals or anus of another person. (c) The massage
establishment or Off-Premises Massage Business shall not refuse
service on the basis of a customer&#x2019;s sex, race, color, religion,
ancestry, national origin or other arbitrary factor proscribed by
the Unruh Civil Rights Act, Civil Code Section 51 et seq. (d) The
Chief of Police or his authorized representative, and the Los
Angeles County Health Department shall have the right to enter each
and every part of the massage establishment for the purpose of
making unscheduled inspections to observe and enforce compliance
with applicable regulations, laws, and provisions of this
ordinance.&#xA0; It shall be unlawful for any permittee to fail to
allow such inspection officers access to the premises or hinder
such officer in any manner.</full_text><order_by>205</order_by><ancestry><unit id="33" label="article"><name>Police Permit Regulation</name><identifier>3</identifier><url>/10/3/</url></unit><unit id="29" label="chapter"><name>Business Regulations</name><identifier>10</identifier><url>/10/</url></unit></ancestry><structure_contents><unit id="1971"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.00</section_number><catch_line>Scope.</catch_line><url>/103.00/</url><token>103.00</token></unit><unit id="2728"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.01</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/103.01/</url><token>103.01</token></unit><unit id="3947"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.02</section_number><catch_line>Permit Required.</catch_line><url>/103.02/</url><token>103.02</token></unit><unit id="1237"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.02.1</section_number><catch_line>Permit Applications.</catch_line><url>/103.02.1/</url><token>103.02.1</token></unit><unit id="3529"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.03</section_number><catch_line>Public Hearings.</catch_line><url>/103.03/</url><token>103.03</token></unit><unit id="1633"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.04</section_number><catch_line>False Statements.</catch_line><url>/103.04/</url><token>103.04</token></unit><unit id="3757"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.05</section_number><catch_line>Overlapping Business.</catch_line><url>/103.05/</url><token>103.05</token></unit><unit id="3124"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.06</section_number><catch_line>Permits &#x2013; Duration.</catch_line><url>/103.06/</url><token>103.06</token></unit><unit id="2153"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.06.1</section_number><catch_line>Permits &#x2013; Renewal.</catch_line><url>/103.06.1/</url><token>103.06.1</token></unit><unit id="626"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.06.2</section_number><catch_line>Temporary Permits.</catch_line><url>/103.06.2/</url><token>103.06.2</token></unit><unit id="2080"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.07</section_number><catch_line>Permits &#x2013; Annual Fee.</catch_line><url>/103.07/</url><token>103.07</token></unit><unit id="935"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.08</section_number><catch_line>Permits Non-Transferable.</catch_line><url>/103.08/</url><token>103.08</token></unit><unit id="1789"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.09</section_number><catch_line>Permit For Each Location.</catch_line><url>/103.09/</url><token>103.09</token></unit><unit id="1610"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.10</section_number><catch_line>Change Of Location.</catch_line><url>/103.10/</url><token>103.10</token></unit><unit id="2237"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.11</section_number><catch_line>Additional Locations.</catch_line><url>/103.11/</url><token>103.11</token></unit><unit id="4168"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.12</section_number><catch_line>Fees.</catch_line><url>/103.12/</url><token>103.12</token></unit><unit id="2834"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.13</section_number><catch_line>Records.</catch_line><url>/103.13/</url><token>103.13</token></unit><unit id="1926"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.14</section_number><catch_line>Inspection.</catch_line><url>/103.14/</url><token>103.14</token></unit><unit id="3867"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.15</section_number><catch_line>Reports.</catch_line><url>/103.15/</url><token>103.15</token></unit><unit id="1179"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.16</section_number><catch_line>Property.</catch_line><url>/103.16/</url><token>103.16</token></unit><unit id="2714"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.17</section_number><catch_line>Advertising.</catch_line><url>/103.17/</url><token>103.17</token></unit><unit id="4164"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.18</section_number><catch_line>Permittee &#x2013; Responsibility.</catch_line><url>/103.18/</url><token>103.18</token></unit><unit id="1396"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.19</section_number><catch_line>Signs Required.</catch_line><url>/103.19/</url><token>103.19</token></unit><unit id="3238"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.20</section_number><catch_line>Display Of Permit.</catch_line><url>/103.20/</url><token>103.20</token></unit><unit id="663"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.21</section_number><catch_line>Change In Owner Information.</catch_line><url>/103.21/</url><token>103.21</token></unit><unit id="1862"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.22</section_number><catch_line>Identification Cards.</catch_line><url>/103.22/</url><token>103.22</token></unit><unit id="57"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.23</section_number><catch_line>Surrender Of Permits.</catch_line><url>/103.23/</url><token>103.23</token></unit><unit id="1606"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.24</section_number><catch_line>Hours Of Business.</catch_line><url>/103.24/</url><token>103.24</token></unit><unit id="3896"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.25</section_number><catch_line>Doing Business With Minor.</catch_line><url>/103.25/</url><token>103.25</token></unit><unit id="3138"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.26</section_number><catch_line>True Name, Age And Address.</catch_line><url>/103.26/</url><token>103.26</token></unit><unit id="233"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.27</section_number><catch_line>Administration.</catch_line><url>/103.27/</url><token>103.27</token></unit><unit id="2008"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.28</section_number><catch_line>Investigation By Board.</catch_line><url>/103.28/</url><token>103.28</token></unit><unit id="3636"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.29</section_number><catch_line>Timing Of Action On Application.</catch_line><url>/103.29/</url><token>103.29</token></unit><unit id="1985"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.29.01</section_number><catch_line>Executive Director Action On Application.</catch_line><url>/103.29.01/</url><token>103.29.01</token></unit><unit id="3913"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.30</section_number><catch_line>Effect Of Granting Permit.</catch_line><url>/103.30/</url><token>103.30</token></unit><unit id="1563"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.31</section_number><catch_line>Denial Of Application.</catch_line><url>/103.31/</url><token>103.31</token></unit><unit id="608"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.31.1</section_number><catch_line>Final Decisions.</catch_line><url>/103.31.1/</url><token>103.31.1</token></unit><unit id="2525"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.31.2</section_number><catch_line>Effective Date Of Notices.</catch_line><url>/103.31.2/</url><token>103.31.2</token></unit><unit id="3821"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.32</section_number><catch_line>Denial &#x2013;Notice To Applicant.</catch_line><url>/103.32/</url><token>103.32</token></unit><unit id="569"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.33</section_number><catch_line>Hearing On Denial &#x2013; Request By Applicant.</catch_line><url>/103.33/</url><token>103.33</token></unit><unit id="3240"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.34</section_number><catch_line>Suspension Or Revocation Of Permits Issued Under This Article.</catch_line><url>/103.34/</url><token>103.34</token></unit><unit id="3508"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.34.1</section_number><catch_line>Suspension Or Revocation Of Permits Issued Pursuant To Sections 103.101.1, 103.102 And 103.109.</catch_line><url>/103.34.1/</url><token>103.34.1</token></unit><unit id="3371"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.34.2</section_number><catch_line>Judicial Review Of Board Action On Applications And Permits Subject To Sections 103.101.1, 103.102 And 103.109.</catch_line><url>/103.34.2/</url><token>103.34.2</token></unit><unit id="2882"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.35</section_number><catch_line>Disciplinary Action &#x2013; Grounds.</catch_line><url>/103.35/</url><token>103.35</token></unit><unit id="214"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.36</section_number><catch_line>Suspension Or Revocation Without Hearing.</catch_line><url>/103.36/</url><token>103.36</token></unit><unit id="2189"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.37</section_number><catch_line>Suspension Or Revocation &#x2013; Effect On Other Permits.</catch_line><url>/103.37/</url><token>103.37</token></unit><unit id="4000"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.38</section_number><catch_line>New Permit Application After Denial Or Revocation.</catch_line><url>/103.38/</url><token>103.38</token></unit><unit id="755"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.39</section_number><catch_line>Cancelled Or Suspended Permit &#x2013; Jurisdiction Of The Board.</catch_line><url>/103.39/</url><token>103.39</token></unit><unit id="3036"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.40</section_number><catch_line>Pending Revocation Or Suspension Proceedings &#x2013; Effect On Permittee.</catch_line><url>/103.40/</url><token>103.40</token></unit><unit id="2541"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.40.1</section_number><catch_line>Power Of Board To Limit And/Or Condition A Permit.</catch_line><url>/103.40.1/</url><token>103.40.1</token></unit><unit id="3520"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.40.2</section_number><catch_line>Subject Matter Of Limitations And/Or Conditions To A Permit.</catch_line><url>/103.40.2/</url><token>103.40.2</token></unit><unit id="982"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.41</section_number><catch_line>Prior Acts No Bar To Board Action.</catch_line><url>/103.41/</url><token>103.41</token></unit><unit id="911"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.42</section_number><catch_line>Stolen Property &#x2013; Investigation.</catch_line><url>/103.42/</url><token>103.42</token></unit><unit id="2845"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.43</section_number><catch_line>Record Search &#x2013; Charge Authorized.</catch_line><url>/103.43/</url><token>103.43</token></unit><unit id="102"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.44</section_number><catch_line>Instructional Materials &#x2013; Custody &#x2013; Fees For Rental Or Sale.</catch_line><url>/103.44/</url><token>103.44</token></unit><unit id="2184"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101</section_number><catch_line>Picture Arcade.</catch_line><url>/103.101/</url><token>103.101</token></unit><unit id="845"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101.1</section_number><catch_line>Picture Arcade Permits And Regulations.</catch_line><url>/103.101.1/</url><token>103.101.1</token></unit><unit id="3778"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101.2</section_number><catch_line>Compliance By Existing Permittees.</catch_line><url>/103.101.2/</url><token>103.101.2</token></unit><unit id="445"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101.3</section_number><catch_line>Game Arcade.</catch_line><url>/103.101.3/</url><token>103.101.3</token></unit><unit id="3234"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101.4</section_number><catch_line>Cyber Caf&#xC9;S.</catch_line><url>/103.101.4/</url><token>103.101.4</token></unit><unit id="1486"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.102</section_number><catch_line>Cafe Entertainment And Shows.</catch_line><url>/103.102/</url><token>103.102</token></unit><unit id="3379"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.102.1</section_number><catch_line>Additional Regulations.</catch_line><url>/103.102.1/</url><token>103.102.1</token></unit><unit id="3638"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.102.2</section_number><catch_line>Compliance By Existing Permittees And Effect Of Noncompliance.</catch_line><url>/103.102.2/</url><token>103.102.2</token></unit><unit id="2551"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.103</section_number><catch_line>Card Club &#x2013; Social Card Club &#x2013; Card School.</catch_line><url>/103.103/</url><token>103.103</token></unit><unit id="2151"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.104</section_number><catch_line>Carnivals.</catch_line><url>/103.104/</url><token>103.104</token></unit><unit id="1602"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.105</section_number><catch_line>Dancing Academies.</catch_line><url>/103.105/</url><token>103.105</token></unit><unit id="1052"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.106</section_number><catch_line>Dance Halls, Dancing Clubs, Public Dances.</catch_line><url>/103.106/</url><token>103.106</token></unit><unit id="2839"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.106.1</section_number><catch_line>Hostess Dance Hall.</catch_line><url>/103.106.1/</url><token>103.106.1</token></unit><unit id="3668"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.107</section_number><catch_line>Escort Bureaus.</catch_line><url>/103.107/</url><token>103.107</token></unit><unit id="268"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.107.1</section_number><catch_line>Escort &#x2013; Permit Required.</catch_line><url>/103.107.1/</url><token>103.107.1</token></unit><unit id="1084"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.109</section_number><catch_line>Motion Picture Shows.</catch_line><url>/103.109/</url><token>103.109</token></unit><unit id="94"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.111</section_number><catch_line>Parades And Assemblies.</catch_line><url>/103.111/</url><token>103.111</token></unit><unit id="3445"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.112</section_number><catch_line>Billiard Rooms, Poolrooms, Bowling Alleys.</catch_line><url>/103.112/</url><token>103.112</token></unit><unit id="3049"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.112.1</section_number><catch_line>Family Billiard Rooms.</catch_line><url>/103.112.1/</url><token>103.112.1</token></unit><unit id="277"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.113</section_number><catch_line>Rides.</catch_line><url>/103.113/</url><token>103.113</token></unit><unit id="442"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.115</section_number><catch_line>Skating Rinks.</catch_line><url>/103.115/</url><token>103.115</token></unit><unit id="2194"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.116</section_number><catch_line>Games Of Skill And Science.</catch_line><url>/103.116/</url><token>103.116</token></unit><unit id="384"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.117</section_number><catch_line>Rifle Range &#x2013; Shooting Gallery.</catch_line><url>/103.117/</url><token>103.117</token></unit><unit id="1306"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.118</section_number><catch_line>Teenage Dances.</catch_line><url>/103.118/</url><token>103.118</token></unit><unit id="2754"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.120</section_number><catch_line>Soundproofing Of Places Of Amusement &#x2013; When Required.</catch_line><url>/103.120/</url><token>103.120</token></unit><unit id="2832"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.202</section_number><catch_line>Automobile Parking Lots.</catch_line><url>/103.202/</url><token>103.202</token></unit><unit id="2880"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.204</section_number><catch_line>Towing Operation.</catch_line><url>/103.204/</url><token>103.204</token></unit><unit id="4074"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.204.1</section_number><catch_line>Tow Unit Operators.</catch_line><url>/103.204.1/</url><token>103.204.1</token></unit><unit id="448"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.205</section_number><catch_line>Massage Therapy.</catch_line><url>/103.205/</url><token>103.205</token></unit><unit id="3536"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.205.1</section_number><catch_line>Massage Therapists.</catch_line><url>/103.205.1/</url><token>103.205.1</token></unit><unit id="2047"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.205.2</section_number><catch_line>Baths.</catch_line><url>/103.205.2/</url><token>103.205.2</token></unit><unit id="687"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.206</section_number><catch_line>Alarm Systems.</catch_line><url>/103.206/</url><token>103.206</token></unit><unit id="2780"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.206.1</section_number><catch_line>Alarm Company Operators.</catch_line><url>/103.206.1/</url><token>103.206.1</token></unit><unit id="3551"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.206.2</section_number><catch_line>Commercial Unsecured Buildings.</catch_line><url>/103.206.2/</url><token>103.206.2</token></unit><unit id="2339"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.208</section_number><catch_line>Key Duplicator.</catch_line><url>/103.208/</url><token>103.208</token></unit><unit id="2609"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.211</section_number><catch_line>Handbill Distribution.</catch_line><url>/103.211/</url><token>103.211</token></unit><unit id="1701"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.212</section_number><catch_line>Soliciting &#x2013; Peace Officers&#x2019; And Firefighters&#x2019; Organizations &#x2013; Permits.</catch_line><url>/103.212/</url><token>103.212</token></unit><unit id="3677"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.213</section_number><catch_line>Figure Studios.</catch_line><url>/103.213/</url><token>103.213</token></unit><unit id="966"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.301</section_number><catch_line>Antique Shops.</catch_line><url>/103.301/</url><token>103.301</token></unit><unit id="1483"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.301.1</section_number><catch_line>Antique Show Or Collectors Exchange Show.</catch_line><url>/103.301.1/</url><token>103.301.1</token></unit><unit id="3136"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.304</section_number><catch_line>Junk Collectors.</catch_line><url>/103.304/</url><token>103.304</token></unit><unit id="3016"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.305</section_number><catch_line>Junk Dealers.</catch_line><url>/103.305/</url><token>103.305</token></unit><unit id="3600"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.306</section_number><catch_line>Pawnbroker.</catch_line><url>/103.306/</url><token>103.306</token></unit><unit id="1834"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.307</section_number><catch_line>Rummage Sale.</catch_line><url>/103.307/</url><token>103.307</token></unit><unit id="1830"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.308</section_number><catch_line>Sales &#x2013; Fire And Closing Out.</catch_line><url>/103.308/</url><token>103.308</token></unit><unit id="236"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.309</section_number><catch_line>Secondhand Auto Parts Dealer.</catch_line><url>/103.309/</url><token>103.309</token></unit><unit id="3361"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.310</section_number><catch_line>Secondhand Book Dealers.</catch_line><url>/103.310/</url><token>103.310</token></unit><unit id="3558"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.311</section_number><catch_line>Secondhand Dealers.</catch_line><url>/103.311/</url><token>103.311</token></unit><unit id="3738"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.311.1</section_number><catch_line>Firearms Sales By Secondhand Dealers Prohibited.</catch_line><url>/103.311.1/</url><token>103.311.1</token></unit><unit id="2476"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.314</section_number><catch_line>Sellers Of Firearms.</catch_line><url>/103.314/</url><token>103.314</token></unit><unit id="3698"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.314.1</section_number><catch_line>Sellers Of Firearm Ammunition.</catch_line><url>/103.314.1/</url><token>103.314.1</token></unit></structure_contents><next_section id="3536"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.205.1</section_number><catch_line>Massage Therapists.</catch_line><url>/103.205.1/</url><token>103.205.1</token></next_section><metadata></metadata><references></references><url>/103.205/</url><token>103.205</token><formats><txt>/103.205.txt</txt><json>/103.205.xml</json></formats><dublin_core><Title>Massage Therapy.</Title><Type>Text</Type><Format>text/html</Format><Identifier>&#xA7; 103.205</Identifier><Relation>Los Angeles Municipal Code</Relation></dublin_core><plain_text>                            LOS ANGELES MUNICIPAL CODE

MASSAGE THERAPY. (&#xA7; 103.205)

&#xA0; MASSAGE THERAPY. (Amended by Ord. No. 171,994, Eff.
5/31/98.) The City of Los Angeles recognizes that the practice of
massage is therapeutic and the therapist must have a basic
knowledge of anatomy, physiology and an understanding of the
relationship between the structure and the function of the tissues
being treated and the total function of the body.&#xA0; The City
also recognizes that the practice of massage without sufficient
training and standards can be dangerous to the public.&#xA0;
Therefore, the purpose and intent of this Ordinance is to regulate
massage establishments and massage therapy practitioners in order
to protect and promote the public health, safety and welfare by: 1.
Providing appropriate standards for education and training of
massage therapists. 2. Providing a clean, sanitary, healthy and
safe environment in which massage therapy is offered to the public.
3. Recognizing massage therapy as a legitimate business occupation
and promoting the public confidence therein. (a) Definitions.&#xA0;
Unless the context or subject matter clearly indicates that a
different meaning is intended, the following words and phrases
shall have the following meanings when used in this section. (1)
&#x201C;Board&#x201D; means the Board of Police Commissioners. (2) &#x201C;&#xFFFD;&#xFFFD; means any
method of pressure on or friction against, or stroking, kneading,
rubbing, tapping, pounding, or stimulating the external parts of
the body with the hands or other parts of the body,&#xA0; or any
other type system for treating or manipulating the human body with
or without the aid of any mechanical or electrical apparatus or
appliances, or with or without supplementary aids such as rubbing
alcohol, liniments, antiseptics, oils, powder, creams, lotions,
ointments, or other similar preparations commonly used in this
practice. (3) &#x201C;Massage Business&#x201D; means the activity or providing,
for any form of consideration or gratuity, facilities for:&#xA0;
massage therapy, administration of fomentation, massage, electric
or magnetic treatment, or alcohol rub;&#xA0; or any other type
system for treating or manipulating the human body. (4)
&#x201C;Off-Premises Massage&#x201D; means activity of providing massage
services, or massage facilities as defined herein at a location
other than premises licensed by a permit from the Board. (5)
&#x201C;Massage Therapist&#x201D; means any person who, for any form of
consideration whatsoever, gives or administers to another person a
&#x201C;massage&#x201D; as defined in this section. (6) &#x201C;Permit&#x201D; means the permit
required to be obtained from the Board for the operation of a
Massage business, an Off-Premises Massage business, or for
performing the activities of a Massage Therapist, with or without
an off-premises endorsement. (7) &#x201C;Health Department&#x201D; means the
County of Los Angeles Department of Health Services. (b)
On-Premises Massage Business &#x2013; Permit Required.&#xA0; (Amended by
Ord. No. 175,167, Eff. 5/20/03.)&#xA0; No person shall engage in,
promote, advertise, conduct, or carry on, in or upon any premises
within the City of Los Angeles, the operation of a massage business
without a permit duly issued by the Board pursuant to this
subsection for each business location.&#xA0; This required permit
shall be in addition to any business tax license required by
ordinance. (1) Application for Permit. Permit applications shall be
made in accordance with Chapter X, Article 3, Division 3 of this
Code. (2) Additional Requirements.&#xA0; In addition to those
requirements specified in Chapter X, Article 3, Division 3 of this
Code, each applicant for a Massage permit shall furnish the
following information to the Board: (i) Each residence and business
address of the applicant for the five years&#xA0; immediately
preceding the date the application, and in the inclusive dates of
each address. (ii) Written proof that the applicant is at least 18
years of age. (iii) Applicant&#x2019;s height, weight, color of eyes and
hair. (iv) Three photographs of applicant, of a size specified by
the Board, taken within the six months immediately preceding the
date of application. (v) Applicant&#x2019;s business, occupation and
employment history for the five years immediately preceding the
date of application. (vi) The permit history of the
applicant:&#xA0; whether the person has ever had a&#xA0; license or
permit issued by any agency or board, City, County or State revoked
or suspended, or has had any professional or vocational license or
permit revoked or suspended, and the reason for the revocation or
suspension. (vii) Any other identification and information as may
be required by the Board. (viii) If the applicant is a corporation,
the name of the corporation shall be set forth exactly as shown in
its Articles of Incorporation or Charter, together with the State
and date of incorporation and names and residence addresses of each
of its current officers and directors, and each stockholder holding
more than five percent of the stock of the corporation.&#xA0; If
the applicant is a partnership, the application shall set forth the
name and residence addresses of each of the partners, including
limited partnership, and it shall furnish a copy of its certificate
of limited partnership as filed with the County Clerk.&#xA0; If one
or more of the partners is a corporation, the provisions of this
subsection pertaining to corporation applicants shall apply.&#xA0;
The applicant corporation or partnership shall designate a
responsible managing officer.&#xA0; This person shall complete and
sign all application forms required for an individual applicant
under this ordinance, but only one application fee shall be
charged.&#xA0; A change application shall be filed to change the
responsible managing officer but no additional inspection shall be
necessary.&#xA0; The corporation&#x2019;s or partnership&#x2019;s responsible
managing officer must at all times meet all of the requirements set
for permittees by this section or the corporation or partnership
permit shall be suspended until a responsible managing officer who
does meet all these requirements is designated.&#xA0; If no person
is named within 90 days, the corporation or partnership permit is
deemed cancelled and a new initial application for permit must be
filed. (ix) The name and address of the Owner and Lessor of the
Real Property upon or in which the business is to be conducted, and
a copy of the deed, lease or rental agreements. (x) Upon filing of
the application for a Massage permit with the Office of Finance,
the Office of Finance shall notify the Department of Health.&#xA0;
This department shall cause an inspection to be made of the
premises sought to be licensed within 20 days to ascertain if the
premises are in compliance with all applicable health laws.&#xA0;
If the premises are in compliance, the department shall issue a
letter to the Office of Finance so stating, which shall be
forwarded to the Board with the application.&#xA0; If the premises
are not in compliance, the department shall issue a letter to the
applicant setting forth the deficiencies and shall reinspect the
premises no more than twice upon written request of the
applicant.&#xA0; If a letter of full compliance is not issued by
the department within 90 days of the date of the filing of the
application, the application shall be deemed withdrawn and a new
application must be filed.&#xA0; The Office of Finance shall not
forward the application to the Board until the Health Department
has issued a letter of compliance. (xi) All convictions for any
crime involving conduct which requires registration under any state
law similar to and including California Penal Code Section 290, or
of conduct which is a violation of the provisions of any state law
similar to and including California Penal Code Sections 266i, 314,
315, 316, 318, 647(a), 647(b), or any crime involving dishonesty,
fraud, deceit, or moral turpitude. (xii) A complete list of the
names and residence addresses of all of the proposed massage
therapists and employees practicing in the massage establishment or
off-premises massage business and the name of the manager or
managing employee proposed to be principally in charge of the
operation of the massage establishment or off-premises massage
business.&#xA0; (xiii) A statement in writing by the applicant that
he or she certifies under penalty of perjury that all information
contained in the application is true and correct, with the
declaration being duly dated and signed in the City. (c) Public
Hearings. (1) In addition to the requirements of Subsection (a) and
(b) above, and subsequent to compliance with the provisions of (b),
if substantial public protest or adverse information concerning the
applicant is received, the Board or upon its direction, an Examiner
shall hold a public hearing to gather input from the public before
a permit for the operation of a massage business is issued.&#xA0;
All relevant information so obtained shall be used by the Board in
determining whether or not to issue a massage business
permit.&#xA0; Public hearings shall be held in accordance with
Chapter X, Article 2, Division 3 of this Code. (2) (Amended by Ord.
No. 173,300, Eff. 6/30/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)&#xA0; Notice of an
applicant&#x2019;s intent to establish a massage business &#xA0; shall be
given in the following manner: (i) By at least one publication in a
newspaper of general circulation in the City, designated for that
purpose by the Office of Finance, not less than 24 days after
applying for the permit. (ii) When a public hearing is scheduled,
written notice shall be mailed not less than 24 days prior to the
date of such hearing to the applicant, to the owner or owners of
the property within and outside the City that is within 300 feet of
the area proposed to be subject of the permit application as shown
upon the records of the Office of Finance, or in the case of
property outside of the City the records of the County Assessor.
(3) Record &#x2013; The hearing procedure shall be recorded or summarized
as directed by the Board.&#xA0; When proceedings are recorded and
not summarized, they shall be transcribed at the request of any
party or interested person upon the prepayment of a fee, as
required by ordinance.&#xA0; One copy of such transcript shall be
furnished the Commission to be placed in the files. (4) Hearings -
conducted by whom &#x2013; The public hearing may be conducted by the
Board or an Examiner at its direction.&#xA0; After the conclusion
of a public hearing conducted by an Examiner, the Examiner shall
submit his report to the Board within such time, which may be fixed
by the Board, setting forth his conclusions and recommendations in
writing and stating briefly his reasons therefore. (d) Massage
Business &#x2013; Operating Requirements.&#xA0; No person shall engage in,
promote, advertise, conduct, carry on, or permit to be engaged in,
promoted, advertised, conducted or carried on, any Massage business
unless each and all of the following requirements are met. (1) Each
person employed or acting as a Massage Therapist shall have a valid
permit issued by the Board.&#xA0; It shall be unlawful for any
owner, operator, responsible managing employee, manager or
permittee in charge of or in control of a Massage Business to
employ or permit a person to act as a Massage Therapist, as defined
in this section, who is not in possession of a valid, unrevoked
Massage Therapist permit issued pursuant to this Code. (2) The
possession of a valid Massage Business permit does not authorize
the possessor to perform work for which a Massage Therapist permit
is required. (3) Massage operations shall be carried on, and the
premises shall be open, only between the hours of 7:00 a.m. and
10:00 p.m. (4) A list of services available and the cost of such
services shall be posted in an open and conspicuous place on the
premises.&#xA0; The services shall be described in readily
understandable language. (5) The Massage Business permit, and a
copy of the permit of each and every Massage Therapist employed in
the establishment, shall be displayed in an open and conspicuous
place on the premises. (6) Every permittee operating a Massage
Business under a permit issued pursuant to this Section shall keep
a record of the date and hour of each treatment, the name and
address of the patron, the name of the employee administering such
treatment, and the type of treatment administered.&#xA0; Such
record shall be maintained on a professionally printed form
provided by the permittee.&#xA0; Such records shall be open to
inspection only by Public Health Investigators.&#xA0; The
information furnished or secured as a result of any such record
shall be confidential.&#xA0; Any unauthorized disclosure or use of
such information by an employee of the business or the City or
County of Los Angeles shall constitute a misdemeanor, and such
employee shall be subject to the penalty provisions of this Code in
addition to any other penalties provided by law.&#xA0; Such records
shall be maintained for a period of one (1) year. (7) The
Department of Health shall, from time to time, and at least once a
year, make an inspection of each Massage Business in the City for
the purposes of determining that the health provisions of the laws
of the State of California and ordinances of the City and County of
Los Angeles and this section are met (8) The Massage business meets
any or all of the following conditions which may, in the discretion
of the Board, be imposed on such Business. (i) A minimum of one (1)
tub or shower, and one (1) toilet and wash basin shall be provided
for the patrons in every Massage Business location;&#xA0; however,
if male and female patrons are to be served simultaneously at said
establishment, separate toilet facilities shall be provided for
male and female patrons.&#xA0; In those establishments where steam
rooms or sauna baths are provided, if male and female patrons are
to be served simultaneously, separate steam rooms or sauna rooms
shall be provided for male and female patrons.&#xA0; Hot and cold
running water under pressure shall be provided to all wash basins,
bathtubs, showers, and similar equipment.&#xA0; Each wash basin
shall be provided with soap or detergent and sanitary towels placed
in permanently installed dispensers.&#xA0; A trash receptacle shall
be provided in each toilet room.&#xA0; In addition to the wash
basin provided for patrons, a minimum of one separate wash basin
shall be provided in each massage establishment.&#xA0; This basin
shall provide soap or detergent and hot and cold running water at
all times and shall be located within or as close as practicable to
the area devoted to the performing of massage services.&#xA0; In
addition, there shall be provided at each wash basin, sanitary
towels placed in permanently installed dispensers. EXCEPTION: If
the wash basin for the patrons is not in the toilet room but is
adjacent thereto, this wash basin will meet the separate wash basin
requirement if it is reasonably close to the area devoted to the
performing of massage. (ii) Minimum ventilation shall be provided
in accordance with the Building code of the City of Los
Angeles.&#xA0; A light level of no less than 25 watts shall be
maintained in public rooms, walkways, and at any point within each
room or enclosure where massage services are being performed, and
at all times such services are being provided. (iii) All walls,
ceilings, floors, pools, showers, bathtubs, wet and dry heat rooms,
steam or vapor rooms, tables and all other physical facilities
shall be in good repair and maintained in a clean and sanitary
condition.&#xA0; Wet and dry heat rooms, steam or vapor rooms or
cabinets, showers, compartments and toilet rooms shall be
thoroughly cleaned at least once each day the business is in
operation.&#xA0; Bathtubs shall be thoroughly cleaned after each
use. (iv) Clean and sanitary towels, sheets and linens shall be
provided for each patron of the establishment or each patron
receiving massage services.&#xA0; No common use of towels or linens
shall be permitted.&#xA0; Towels, sheets and linens shall be
provided in sufficient quantity and shall not be used by more than
one (1) person unless they have been first relaundered.&#xA0; Heavy
white paper may be substituted for sheets provided that such paper
is used one for each person and then discarded into a sanitary
receptacle.&#xA0; Separate closed cabinets or containers shall be
provided for the storage of clean and soiled linen and shall be
plainly marked:&#xA0; &#x201C;clean linen&#x201D; and &#x201C;soiled linen.&#x201D; (v)
Disinfecting agents and sterilizing equipment approved by the
Health Department shall be provided for any instruments used in
performing any massage. (vi) Pads used on massage tables shall be
covered in a workmanlike manner with durable, washable plastic or
other waterproof material acceptable to the Health Department.
(vii) All exterior and interior massage room doors shall remain
unlocked during business hours. (viii) A separate locker shall be
provided for each patron to be served, such locker shall be capable
of being locked and available at no extra charge. (ix) No person
shall enter, be or remain, in any part of a Massage Business
location while in the possession of, consuming, or using any
alcoholic beverages or drugs except pursuant to a prescription for
such drugs.&#xA0; The owner, operator, responsible managing
employee, manager or permittee shall not permit any such person to
enter or remain upon such premises. (x) All employees including
Massage Therapists, shall be clean, and shall be fully clothed in
clean nontransparent outer garments.&#xA0; As used herein, &#x201C;fully
clothed&#x201D; shall mean the wearing of undergarments such as bras and
underwear as well as the wearing of clothing which is comparable to
the clothing commonly worn by nurses and physical therapists while
performing their respective professional duties. (e) Off-Premises
Massage Business &#x2013; Permit Required.&#xA0; No person shall engage
in, promote, advertise, conduct, carry on, or permit to be engaged
in, promoted, advertised, conducted or carried on, any Off-Premises
Massage Business in the City of Los Angeles, without a permit duly
issued by the Board pursuant to this subsection for each business
location.&#xA0; The permit required hereby shall be in addition to
any business tax license required by ordinance. (1) Application for
Permit.&#xA0; Permit Applications shall be made in accordance with
the requirements of Chapter X, Article 3, and Section 103.205(b)(2)
of this Code. (2) Operating Requirements.&#xA0; The operating
requirements are as set forth in Section 103.205(d) of this Code
and the following additional requirements shall apply: (i) The
owner, operator, responsible managing employee, manager or
permittee of an Off-Premises Massage Business shall display the
permit issued therefore and a true and correct copy of the permit
of each and every Massage Therapist employed by the business in an
open and conspicuous manner on the business premises and to every
customer who requests the information contained in the permits.
(ii) A record of treatment shall be maintained by each Massage
Therapist employed by the business. (iii) No person operating an
Off-Premises Massage Business shall employee or allow a person to
act as an Off-Premises Massage Therapist unless such person has a
valid, unrevoked Massage Therapist permit endorsed by the Board of
Police Commissioners for Off-Premises Massage. (iv) Upon any change
of employees, the permittee shall inform the Board within ten (10)
days of such change. (f) Massage Business/Off-Premises Permit
Issuance and Denial. (1) Upon receipt of a written application for
a permit to conduct a Massage Business or Off-Premises Massage
Business, the Board shall conduct an investigation in order to
ascertain whether such permit should be issued as requested.&#xA0;
The Board shall approve, conditionally approve, set for an
Administrative Hearing or &#x2018;File Without Further Action&#x2019; the
application within ninety (90) days of the filing of an
application.&#xA0; The Board shall issue such permit as requested
unless the Board makes any of the following findings: (a) Any
person, including but not limited to, employees who will be
directly engaged or employed in the massage establishment or
Off-Premises Massage Business has been convicted or a violation of
Health and Safety Code Section 11550 or a violation of Penal Code
Section 266i, 315, 316, 318, 647(a) P.C., 647(b), or has been
convicted in any other State of any offense which if committed or
attempted in this State, would have been punished as one or more of
the above mentioned offenses, or that any such person is required
to register under the provisions of Penal Code Section 290. (b) Any
person, including, but not limited to, employees who will be
directly engaged or employed in the massage establishment or
Off-Premises Massage Business who has been convicted of any felony
offense involving the sale of a controlled substance specified in
Health and Safety Code Sections 11054, 11055, 11056, 11057, or
11058 or has been convicted in any other State of any offense
which, if committed or attempted in this State would have been
punishable as one or more of the above mentioned offenses. (c) Any
person including, but not limited to, employees who will be
directly engaged or employed in the massage establishment or
Off-Premises Massage Business, who has committed an act, which, if
done by a licensee or permittee under this Chapter, would be
grounds for suspension or revocation of a license or permit. (d)
Any person including, but not limited to, employees who will be
directly engaged or employed in the massage establishment or
Off-Premises Massage Business, who has committed an act involving
dishonesty, fraud, or deceit with the intent to substantially
benefit himself, herself, or another or substantially to injure
another, or an act of violence, which act or acts are substantially
related to the qualifications, functions, or duties of the massage
establishment or Off-Premises Massage Business. (e) The operations
of the massage establishment or Off- Premise Massage Business
would, if allowed, constitute a public nuisance. (f) The applicant
has knowingly made a false, misleading, or fraudulent statement of
fact to the City in the permit application process. (g) The
application does not contain the information required by this
section. (h) The applicant has not satisfied the requirements of
this Code. (2) Conditions of Permit Issuance.&#xA0; The Board shall
condition the issuance of an operator&#x2019;s permit to insure compliance
with this section and other applicable laws.&#xA0; Such conditions
shall include, but not be limited to, the following: (a) The front
door of the massage establishment and the doors of the interior
treatment rooms in which massages are being performed must remain
unlocked during all hours of operation.&#xA0; No electronic locking
device may be utilized on any entrance door.&#xA0; No warning
devices such as buzzers may be installed.&#xA0; No locks may be
installed on any of the treatment room doors. (b) No massage
therapist/practitioner or employee shall expose his or her
genitals, buttocks, or, in the case of a female, her breast nor, in
the course of administering a massage, make intentional contact
with the genitals or anus of another person. (c) The massage
establishment or Off-Premises Massage Business shall not refuse
service on the basis of a customer&#x2019;s sex, race, color, religion,
ancestry, national origin or other arbitrary factor proscribed by
the Unruh Civil Rights Act, Civil Code Section 51 et seq. (d) The
Chief of Police or his authorized representative, and the Los
Angeles County Health Department shall have the right to enter each
and every part of the massage establishment for the purpose of
making unscheduled inspections to observe and enforce compliance
with applicable regulations, laws, and provisions of this
ordinance.&#xA0; It shall be unlawful for any permittee to fail to
allow such inspection officers access to the premises or hinder
such officer in any manner.
</plain_text><html>
					&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#xA0; MASSAGE THERAPY. (Amended by Ord. No. 171,994, Eff.
5/31/98.) The City of Los Angeles recognizes that the practice of
massage is therapeutic and the therapist must have a basic
knowledge of anatomy, physiology and an understanding of the
relationship between the structure and the function of the tissues
being treated and the total function of the body.&#xA0; The City
also recognizes that the practice of massage without sufficient
training and standards can be dangerous to the public.&#xA0;
Therefore, the purpose and &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;intent&lt;/span&gt; of this &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Ordinance&lt;/span&gt; is to regulate
massage establishments and massage therapy practitioners in &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt;
to protect and promote the public health, safety and welfare by: 1.
Providing appropriate standards for education and training of
massage therapists. 2. Providing a clean, sanitary, healthy and
safe environment in which massage therapy is offered to the public.
3. Recognizing massage therapy as a legitimate business occupation
and promoting the public confidence therein. (a) Definitions.&#xA0;
Unless the context or subject matter clearly indicates that a
different meaning is intended, the following words and phrases
shall have the following meanings when used in this section. (1)
&#x201C;Board&#x201D; means the Board of Police Commissioners. (2) &#x201C;&#xFFFD;&#xFFFD; means any
method of pressure on or friction against, or stroking, kneading,
rubbing, tapping, pounding, or stimulating the external parts of
the body with the hands or other parts of the body,&#xA0; or any
other type system for treating or manipulating the human body with
or without the aid of any mechanical or electrical apparatus or
appliances, or with or without supplementary aids such as rubbing
alcohol, liniments, antiseptics, oils, powder, creams, lotions,
ointments, or other similar preparations commonly used in this
practice. (3) &#x201C;Massage Business&#x201D; means the activity or providing,
for any form of consideration or gratuity, facilities for:&#xA0;
massage therapy, administration of fomentation, massage, electric
or magnetic treatment, or alcohol rub;&#xA0; or any other type
system for treating or manipulating the human body. (4)
&#x201C;Off-Premises Massage&#x201D; means activity of providing massage
services, or massage facilities as defined herein at a location
other than premises licensed by a permit from the Board. (5)
&#x201C;Massage Therapist&#x201D; means any person who, for any form of
consideration whatsoever, gives or administers to another person a
&#x201C;massage&#x201D; as defined in this section. (6) &#x201C;Permit&#x201D; means the permit
required to be obtained from the Board for the operation of a
Massage business, an Off-Premises Massage business, or for
performing the activities of a Massage Therapist, with or without
an off-premises endorsement. (7) &#x201C;Health Department&#x201D; means the
County of Los Angeles Department of Health Services. (b)
On-Premises Massage Business &#x2013; Permit Required.&#xA0; (Amended by
Ord. No. 175,167, Eff. 5/20/03.)&#xA0; No person shall engage in,
promote, advertise, conduct, or carry on, in or upon any premises
within the City of Los Angeles, the operation of a massage business
without a permit duly issued by the Board pursuant to this
subsection for each business location.&#xA0; This required permit
shall be in addition to any business tax license required by
&lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt;. (1) Application for Permit. Permit applications shall be
made in accordance with Chapter X, Article 3, Division 3 of this
Code. (2) Additional Requirements.&#xA0; In addition to those
requirements specified in Chapter X, Article 3, Division 3 of this
Code, each applicant for a Massage permit shall furnish the
following information to the Board: (i) Each residence and business
address of the applicant for the five years&#xA0; immediately
preceding the date the application, and in the inclusive dates of
each address. (ii) Written proof that the applicant is at least 18
years of age. (iii) Applicant&#x2019;s height, weight, color of eyes and
hair. (iv) Three photographs of applicant, of a size specified by
the Board, taken within the six months immediately preceding the
date of application. (v) Applicant&#x2019;s business, occupation and
employment history for the five years immediately preceding the
date of application. (vi) The permit history of the
applicant:&#xA0; whether the person has ever had a&#xA0; license or
permit issued by any agency or board, City, County or State revoked
or suspended, or has had any professional or vocational license or
permit revoked or suspended, and the reason for the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;revocation&lt;/span&gt; or
suspension. (vii) Any other identification and information as may
be required by the Board. (viii) If the applicant is a corporation,
the name of the corporation shall be set forth exactly as shown in
its Articles of Incorporation or Charter, together with the State
and date of incorporation and names and residence addresses of each
of its current officers and directors, and each stockholder holding
more than five percent of the stock of the corporation.&#xA0; If
the applicant is a partnership, the application shall set forth the
name and residence addresses of each of the partners, including
limited partnership, and it shall furnish a copy of its certificate
of limited partnership as filed with the County Clerk.&#xA0; If one
or more of the partners is a corporation, the provisions of this
subsection pertaining to corporation applicants shall apply.&#xA0;
The applicant corporation or partnership shall designate a
responsible managing officer.&#xA0; This person shall complete and
sign all application forms required for an individual applicant
under this &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt;, but only one application fee shall be
charged.&#xA0; A change application shall be filed to change the
responsible managing officer but no additional inspection shall be
necessary.&#xA0; The corporation&#x2019;s or partnership&#x2019;s responsible
managing officer must at all times meet all of the requirements set
for permittees by this section or the corporation or partnership
permit shall be suspended until a responsible managing officer who
does meet all these requirements is designated.&#xA0; If no person
is named within 90 days, the corporation or partnership permit is
deemed cancelled and a new initial application for permit must be
filed. (ix) The name and address of the Owner and Lessor of the
Real Property upon or in which the business is to be conducted, and
a copy of the deed, lease or rental agreements. (x) Upon filing of
the application for a Massage permit with the Office of Finance,
the Office of Finance shall notify the Department of Health.&#xA0;
This department shall cause an inspection to be made of the
premises sought to be licensed within 20 days to ascertain if the
premises are in compliance with all applicable health &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;laws&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0;
If the premises are in compliance, the department shall &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;issue&lt;/span&gt; a
letter to the Office of Finance so stating, which shall be
forwarded to the Board with the application.&#xA0; If the premises
are not in compliance, the department shall &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;issue&lt;/span&gt; a letter to the
applicant setting forth the deficiencies and shall reinspect the
premises no more than twice upon written request of the
applicant.&#xA0; If a letter of full compliance is not issued by
the department within 90 days of the date of the filing of the
application, the application shall be deemed withdrawn and a new
application must be filed.&#xA0; The Office of Finance shall not
forward the application to the Board until the Health Department
has issued a letter of compliance. (xi) All &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;convictions&lt;/span&gt; for any
&lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;crime&lt;/span&gt; involving conduct which requires registration under any state
&lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;law&lt;/span&gt; similar to and including California Penal Code Section 290, or
of conduct which is a violation of the provisions of any state &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;law&lt;/span&gt;
similar to and including California Penal Code Sections 266i, 314,
315, 316, 318, 647(a), 647(b), or any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;crime&lt;/span&gt; involving dishonesty,
&lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;fraud&lt;/span&gt;, deceit, or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;moral turpitude&lt;/span&gt;. (xii) A complete list of the
names and residence addresses of all of the proposed massage
therapists and employees practicing in the massage establishment or
off-premises massage business and the name of the manager or
managing employee proposed to be principally in charge of the
operation of the massage establishment or off-premises massage
business.&#xA0; (xiii) A statement in writing by the applicant that
he or she certifies under &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt; of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;perjury&lt;/span&gt; that all information
contained in the application is true and correct, with the
declaration being duly dated and signed in the City. (c) Public
&lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Hearings&lt;/span&gt;. (1) In addition to the requirements of Subsection (a) and
(b) above, and subsequent to compliance with the provisions of (b),
if substantial public protest or adverse information concerning the
applicant is received, the Board or upon its direction, an Examiner
shall hold a public &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; to gather input from the public before
a permit for the operation of a massage business is issued.&#xA0;
All relevant information so obtained shall be used by the Board in
determining whether or not to &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;issue&lt;/span&gt; a massage business
permit.&#xA0; Public &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearings&lt;/span&gt; shall be held in accordance with
Chapter X, Article 2, Division 3 of this Code. (2) (Amended by Ord.
No. 173,300, Eff. 6/30/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)&#xA0; Notice of an
applicant&#x2019;s &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;intent&lt;/span&gt; to establish a massage business &#xA0; shall be
given in the following manner: (i) By at least one publication in a
newspaper of general circulation in the City, designated for that
purpose by the Office of Finance, not less than 24 days after
applying for the permit. (ii) When a public &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; is scheduled,
written notice shall be mailed not less than 24 days prior to the
date of such &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; to the applicant, to the owner or owners of
the property within and outside the City that is within 300 feet of
the area proposed to be subject of the permit application as shown
upon the records of the Office of Finance, or in the case of
property outside of the City the records of the County Assessor.
(3) Record &#x2013; The &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; procedure shall be recorded or summarized
as directed by the Board.&#xA0; When proceedings are recorded and
not summarized, they shall be transcribed at the request of any
&lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;party&lt;/span&gt; or interested person upon the prepayment of a fee, as
required by &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; One copy of such &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;transcript&lt;/span&gt; shall be
furnished the Commission to be placed in the files. (4) &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Hearings&lt;/span&gt; -
conducted by whom &#x2013; The public &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; may be conducted by the
Board or an Examiner at its direction.&#xA0; After the conclusion
of a public &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; conducted by an Examiner, the Examiner shall
submit his report to the Board within such time, which may be fixed
by the Board, setting forth his conclusions and recommendations in
writing and stating briefly his reasons therefore. (d) Massage
Business &#x2013; Operating Requirements.&#xA0; No person shall engage in,
promote, advertise, conduct, carry on, or permit to be engaged in,
promoted, advertised, conducted or carried on, any Massage business
unless each and all of the following requirements are met. (1) Each
person employed or acting as a Massage Therapist shall have a valid
permit issued by the Board.&#xA0; It shall be unlawful for any
owner, operator, responsible managing employee, manager or
permittee in charge of or in control of a Massage Business to
employ or permit a person to act as a Massage Therapist, as defined
in this section, who is not in &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;possession&lt;/span&gt; of a valid, unrevoked
Massage Therapist permit issued pursuant to this Code. (2) The
&lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;possession&lt;/span&gt; of a valid Massage Business permit does not authorize
the possessor to perform work for which a Massage Therapist permit
is required. (3) Massage operations shall be carried on, and the
premises shall be open, only between the hours of 7:00 a.m. and
10:00 p.m. (4) A list of services available and the cost of such
services shall be posted in an open and conspicuous place on the
premises.&#xA0; The services shall be described in readily
understandable language. (5) The Massage Business permit, and a
copy of the permit of each and every Massage Therapist employed in
the establishment, shall be displayed in an open and conspicuous
place on the premises. (6) Every permittee operating a Massage
Business under a permit issued pursuant to this Section shall keep
a record of the date and hour of each treatment, the name and
address of the patron, the name of the employee administering such
treatment, and the type of treatment administered.&#xA0; Such
record shall be maintained on a professionally printed form
provided by the permittee.&#xA0; Such records shall be open to
inspection only by Public Health Investigators.&#xA0; The
information furnished or secured as a result of any such record
shall be confidential.&#xA0; Any unauthorized disclosure or use of
such information by an employee of the business or the City or
County of Los Angeles shall constitute a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;misdemeanor&lt;/span&gt;, and such
employee shall be subject to the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt; provisions of this Code in
addition to any other penalties provided by &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;law&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; Such records
shall be maintained for a period of one (1) year. (7) The
Department of Health shall, from time to time, and at least once a
year, make an inspection of each Massage Business in the City for
the purposes of determining that the health provisions of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;laws&lt;/span&gt;
of the State of California and &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinances&lt;/span&gt; of the City and County of
Los Angeles and this section are met (8) The Massage business meets
any or all of the following conditions which may, in the discretion
of the Board, be imposed on such Business. (i) A minimum of one (1)
tub or shower, and one (1) toilet and wash basin shall be provided
for the patrons in every Massage Business location;&#xA0; however,
if male and female patrons are to be served simultaneously at said
establishment, separate toilet facilities shall be provided for
male and female patrons.&#xA0; In those establishments where steam
rooms or sauna baths are provided, if male and female patrons are
to be served simultaneously, separate steam rooms or sauna rooms
shall be provided for male and female patrons.&#xA0; Hot and cold
running water under pressure shall be provided to all wash basins,
bathtubs, showers, and similar equipment.&#xA0; Each wash basin
shall be provided with soap or detergent and sanitary towels placed
in permanently installed dispensers.&#xA0; A trash receptacle shall
be provided in each toilet room.&#xA0; In addition to the wash
basin provided for patrons, a minimum of one separate wash basin
shall be provided in each massage establishment.&#xA0; This basin
shall provide soap or detergent and hot and cold running water at
all times and shall be located within or as close as practicable to
the area devoted to the performing of massage services.&#xA0; In
addition, there shall be provided at each wash basin, sanitary
towels placed in permanently installed dispensers. EXCEPTION: If
the wash basin for the patrons is not in the toilet room but is
adjacent thereto, this wash basin will meet the separate wash basin
requirement if it is reasonably close to the area devoted to the
performing of massage. (ii) Minimum ventilation shall be provided
in accordance with the Building code of the City of Los
Angeles.&#xA0; A light level of no less than 25 watts shall be
maintained in public rooms, walkways, and at any point within each
room or enclosure where massage services are being performed, and
at all times such services are being provided. (iii) All walls,
ceilings, floors, pools, showers, bathtubs, wet and dry heat rooms,
steam or vapor rooms, tables and all other physical facilities
shall be in good repair and maintained in a clean and sanitary
condition.&#xA0; Wet and dry heat rooms, steam or vapor rooms or
cabinets, showers, compartments and toilet rooms shall be
thoroughly cleaned at least once each day the business is in
operation.&#xA0; Bathtubs shall be thoroughly cleaned after each
use. (iv) Clean and sanitary towels, sheets and linens shall be
provided for each patron of the establishment or each patron
receiving massage services.&#xA0; No common use of towels or linens
shall be permitted.&#xA0; Towels, sheets and linens shall be
provided in sufficient quantity and shall not be used by more than
one (1) person unless they have been first relaundered.&#xA0; Heavy
white paper may be substituted for sheets provided that such paper
is used one for each person and then discarded into a sanitary
receptacle.&#xA0; Separate closed cabinets or containers shall be
provided for the storage of clean and soiled linen and shall be
plainly marked:&#xA0; &#x201C;clean linen&#x201D; and &#x201C;soiled linen.&#x201D; (v)
Disinfecting agents and sterilizing equipment approved by the
Health Department shall be provided for any instruments used in
performing any massage. (vi) Pads used on massage tables shall be
covered in a workmanlike manner with durable, washable plastic or
other waterproof &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;material&lt;/span&gt; acceptable to the Health Department.
(vii) All exterior and interior massage room doors shall remain
unlocked during business hours. (viii) A separate locker shall be
provided for each patron to be served, such locker shall be capable
of being locked and available at no extra charge. (ix) No person
shall enter, be or remain, in any part of a Massage Business
location while in the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;possession&lt;/span&gt; of, consuming, or using any
alcoholic beverages or drugs except pursuant to a prescription for
such drugs.&#xA0; The owner, operator, responsible managing
employee, manager or permittee shall not permit any such person to
enter or remain upon such premises. (x) All employees including
Massage Therapists, shall be clean, and shall be fully clothed in
clean nontransparent outer garments.&#xA0; As used herein, &#x201C;fully
clothed&#x201D; shall mean the wearing of undergarments such as bras and
underwear as well as the wearing of clothing which is comparable to
the clothing commonly worn by nurses and physical therapists while
performing their respective professional duties. (e) Off-Premises
Massage Business &#x2013; Permit Required.&#xA0; No person shall engage
in, promote, advertise, conduct, carry on, or permit to be engaged
in, promoted, advertised, conducted or carried on, any Off-Premises
Massage Business in the City of Los Angeles, without a permit duly
issued by the Board pursuant to this subsection for each business
location.&#xA0; The permit required hereby shall be in addition to
any business tax license required by &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt;. (1) Application for
Permit.&#xA0; Permit Applications shall be made in accordance with
the requirements of Chapter X, Article 3, and Section 103.205(b)(2)
of this Code. (2) Operating Requirements.&#xA0; The operating
requirements are as set forth in Section 103.205(d) of this Code
and the following additional requirements shall apply: (i) The
owner, operator, responsible managing employee, manager or
permittee of an Off-Premises Massage Business shall display the
permit issued therefore and a true and correct copy of the permit
of each and every Massage Therapist employed by the business in an
open and conspicuous manner on the business premises and to every
customer who requests the information contained in the permits.
(ii) A record of treatment shall be maintained by each Massage
Therapist employed by the business. (iii) No person operating an
Off-Premises Massage Business shall employee or allow a person to
act as an Off-Premises Massage Therapist unless such person has a
valid, unrevoked Massage Therapist permit endorsed by the Board of
Police Commissioners for Off-Premises Massage. (iv) Upon any change
of employees, the permittee shall inform the Board within ten (10)
days of such change. (f) Massage Business/Off-Premises Permit
Issuance and Denial. (1) Upon receipt of a written application for
a permit to conduct a Massage Business or Off-Premises Massage
Business, the Board shall conduct an investigation in &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; to
ascertain whether such permit should be issued as requested.&#xA0;
The Board shall approve, conditionally approve, set for an
Administrative &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Hearing&lt;/span&gt; or &#x2018;File Without Further Action&#x2019; the
application within ninety (90) days of the filing of an
application.&#xA0; The Board shall &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;issue&lt;/span&gt; such permit as requested
unless the Board makes any of the following &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;findings&lt;/span&gt;: (a) Any
person, including but not limited to, employees who will be
directly engaged or employed in the massage establishment or
Off-Premises Massage Business has been convicted or a violation of
Health and Safety Code Section 11550 or a violation of Penal Code
Section 266i, 315, 316, 318, 647(a) P.C., 647(b), or has been
convicted in any other State of any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;offense&lt;/span&gt; which if committed or
attempted in this State, would have been punished as one or more of
the above mentioned &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;offenses&lt;/span&gt;, or that any such person is required
to register under the provisions of Penal Code Section 290. (b) Any
person, including, but not limited to, employees who will be
directly engaged or employed in the massage establishment or
Off-Premises Massage Business who has been convicted of any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;felony&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;offense&lt;/span&gt; involving the sale of a controlled substance specified in
Health and Safety Code Sections 11054, 11055, 11056, 11057, or
11058 or has been convicted in any other State of any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;offense&lt;/span&gt;
which, if committed or attempted in this State would have been
punishable as one or more of the above mentioned &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;offenses&lt;/span&gt;. (c) Any
person including, but not limited to, employees who will be
directly engaged or employed in the massage establishment or
Off-Premises Massage Business, who has committed an act, which, if
done by a licensee or permittee under this Chapter, would be
grounds for suspension or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;revocation&lt;/span&gt; of a license or permit. (d)
Any person including, but not limited to, employees who will be
directly engaged or employed in the massage establishment or
Off-Premises Massage Business, who has committed an act involving
dishonesty, &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;fraud&lt;/span&gt;, or deceit with the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;intent&lt;/span&gt; to substantially
benefit himself, herself, or another or substantially to injure
another, or an act of violence, which act or acts are substantially
related to the qualifications, functions, or duties of the massage
establishment or Off-Premises Massage Business. (e) The operations
of the massage establishment or Off- Premise Massage Business
would, if allowed, constitute a public nuisance. (f) The applicant
has knowingly made a false, misleading, or fraudulent statement of
&lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;fact&lt;/span&gt; to the City in the permit application process. (g) The
application does not contain the information required by this
section. (h) The applicant has not satisfied the requirements of
this Code. (2) Conditions of Permit Issuance.&#xA0; The Board shall
condition the issuance of an operator&#x2019;s permit to insure compliance
with this section and other applicable &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;laws&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; Such conditions
shall include, but not be limited to, the following: (a) The front
door of the massage establishment and the doors of the interior
treatment rooms in which massages are being performed must remain
unlocked during all hours of operation.&#xA0; No electronic locking
device may be utilized on any entrance door.&#xA0; No warning
devices such as buzzers may be installed.&#xA0; No locks may be
installed on any of the treatment room doors. (b) No massage
therapist/practitioner or employee shall expose his or her
genitals, buttocks, or, in the case of a female, her breast nor, in
the course of administering a massage, make intentional contact
with the genitals or anus of another person. (c) The massage
establishment or Off-Premises Massage Business shall not refuse
service on the basis of a customer&#x2019;s sex, race, color, religion,
ancestry, national origin or other arbitrary factor proscribed by
the Unruh Civil Rights Act, Civil Code Section 51 et seq. (d) The
Chief of Police or his authorized representative, and the Los
Angeles County Health Department shall have the right to enter each
and every part of the massage establishment for the purpose of
making unscheduled inspections to observe and enforce compliance
with applicable regulations, &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;laws&lt;/span&gt;, and provisions of this
&lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; It shall be unlawful for any permittee to fail to
allow such inspection officers access to the premises or hinder
such officer in any manner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</html><previous_section id="4074"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.204.1</section_number><catch_line>Tow Unit Operators.</catch_line><url>/103.204.1/</url><token>103.204.1</token></previous_section><text><unit id="441" prefix=""><text>&#xA0; MASSAGE THERAPY. (Amended by Ord. No. 171,994, Eff.
5/31/98.) The City of Los Angeles recognizes that the practice of
massage is therapeutic and the therapist must have a basic
knowledge of anatomy, physiology and an understanding of the
relationship between the structure and the function of the tissues
being treated and the total function of the body.&#xA0; The City
also recognizes that the practice of massage without sufficient
training and standards can be dangerous to the public.&#xA0;
Therefore, the purpose and intent of this Ordinance is to regulate
massage establishments and massage therapy practitioners in order
to protect and promote the public health, safety and welfare by: 1.
Providing appropriate standards for education and training of
massage therapists. 2. Providing a clean, sanitary, healthy and
safe environment in which massage therapy is offered to the public.
3. Recognizing massage therapy as a legitimate business occupation
and promoting the public confidence therein. (a) Definitions.&#xA0;
Unless the context or subject matter clearly indicates that a
different meaning is intended, the following words and phrases
shall have the following meanings when used in this section. (1)
&#x201C;Board&#x201D; means the Board of Police Commissioners. (2) &#x201C;&#xFFFD;&#xFFFD; means any
method of pressure on or friction against, or stroking, kneading,
rubbing, tapping, pounding, or stimulating the external parts of
the body with the hands or other parts of the body,&#xA0; or any
other type system for treating or manipulating the human body with
or without the aid of any mechanical or electrical apparatus or
appliances, or with or without supplementary aids such as rubbing
alcohol, liniments, antiseptics, oils, powder, creams, lotions,
ointments, or other similar preparations commonly used in this
practice. (3) &#x201C;Massage Business&#x201D; means the activity or providing,
for any form of consideration or gratuity, facilities for:&#xA0;
massage therapy, administration of fomentation, massage, electric
or magnetic treatment, or alcohol rub;&#xA0; or any other type
system for treating or manipulating the human body. (4)
&#x201C;Off-Premises Massage&#x201D; means activity of providing massage
services, or massage facilities as defined herein at a location
other than premises licensed by a permit from the Board. (5)
&#x201C;Massage Therapist&#x201D; means any person who, for any form of
consideration whatsoever, gives or administers to another person a
&#x201C;massage&#x201D; as defined in this section. (6) &#x201C;Permit&#x201D; means the permit
required to be obtained from the Board for the operation of a
Massage business, an Off-Premises Massage business, or for
performing the activities of a Massage Therapist, with or without
an off-premises endorsement. (7) &#x201C;Health Department&#x201D; means the
County of Los Angeles Department of Health Services. (b)
On-Premises Massage Business &#x2013; Permit Required.&#xA0; (Amended by
Ord. No. 175,167, Eff. 5/20/03.)&#xA0; No person shall engage in,
promote, advertise, conduct, or carry on, in or upon any premises
within the City of Los Angeles, the operation of a massage business
without a permit duly issued by the Board pursuant to this
subsection for each business location.&#xA0; This required permit
shall be in addition to any business tax license required by
ordinance. (1) Application for Permit. Permit applications shall be
made in accordance with Chapter X, Article 3, Division 3 of this
Code. (2) Additional Requirements.&#xA0; In addition to those
requirements specified in Chapter X, Article 3, Division 3 of this
Code, each applicant for a Massage permit shall furnish the
following information to the Board: (i) Each residence and business
address of the applicant for the five years&#xA0; immediately
preceding the date the application, and in the inclusive dates of
each address. (ii) Written proof that the applicant is at least 18
years of age. (iii) Applicant&#x2019;s height, weight, color of eyes and
hair. (iv) Three photographs of applicant, of a size specified by
the Board, taken within the six months immediately preceding the
date of application. (v) Applicant&#x2019;s business, occupation and
employment history for the five years immediately preceding the
date of application. (vi) The permit history of the
applicant:&#xA0; whether the person has ever had a&#xA0; license or
permit issued by any agency or board, City, County or State revoked
or suspended, or has had any professional or vocational license or
permit revoked or suspended, and the reason for the revocation or
suspension. (vii) Any other identification and information as may
be required by the Board. (viii) If the applicant is a corporation,
the name of the corporation shall be set forth exactly as shown in
its Articles of Incorporation or Charter, together with the State
and date of incorporation and names and residence addresses of each
of its current officers and directors, and each stockholder holding
more than five percent of the stock of the corporation.&#xA0; If
the applicant is a partnership, the application shall set forth the
name and residence addresses of each of the partners, including
limited partnership, and it shall furnish a copy of its certificate
of limited partnership as filed with the County Clerk.&#xA0; If one
or more of the partners is a corporation, the provisions of this
subsection pertaining to corporation applicants shall apply.&#xA0;
The applicant corporation or partnership shall designate a
responsible managing officer.&#xA0; This person shall complete and
sign all application forms required for an individual applicant
under this ordinance, but only one application fee shall be
charged.&#xA0; A change application shall be filed to change the
responsible managing officer but no additional inspection shall be
necessary.&#xA0; The corporation&#x2019;s or partnership&#x2019;s responsible
managing officer must at all times meet all of the requirements set
for permittees by this section or the corporation or partnership
permit shall be suspended until a responsible managing officer who
does meet all these requirements is designated.&#xA0; If no person
is named within 90 days, the corporation or partnership permit is
deemed cancelled and a new initial application for permit must be
filed. (ix) The name and address of the Owner and Lessor of the
Real Property upon or in which the business is to be conducted, and
a copy of the deed, lease or rental agreements. (x) Upon filing of
the application for a Massage permit with the Office of Finance,
the Office of Finance shall notify the Department of Health.&#xA0;
This department shall cause an inspection to be made of the
premises sought to be licensed within 20 days to ascertain if the
premises are in compliance with all applicable health laws.&#xA0;
If the premises are in compliance, the department shall issue a
letter to the Office of Finance so stating, which shall be
forwarded to the Board with the application.&#xA0; If the premises
are not in compliance, the department shall issue a letter to the
applicant setting forth the deficiencies and shall reinspect the
premises no more than twice upon written request of the
applicant.&#xA0; If a letter of full compliance is not issued by
the department within 90 days of the date of the filing of the
application, the application shall be deemed withdrawn and a new
application must be filed.&#xA0; The Office of Finance shall not
forward the application to the Board until the Health Department
has issued a letter of compliance. (xi) All convictions for any
crime involving conduct which requires registration under any state
law similar to and including California Penal Code Section 290, or
of conduct which is a violation of the provisions of any state law
similar to and including California Penal Code Sections 266i, 314,
315, 316, 318, 647(a), 647(b), or any crime involving dishonesty,
fraud, deceit, or moral turpitude. (xii) A complete list of the
names and residence addresses of all of the proposed massage
therapists and employees practicing in the massage establishment or
off-premises massage business and the name of the manager or
managing employee proposed to be principally in charge of the
operation of the massage establishment or off-premises massage
business.&#xA0; (xiii) A statement in writing by the applicant that
he or she certifies under penalty of perjury that all information
contained in the application is true and correct, with the
declaration being duly dated and signed in the City. (c) Public
Hearings. (1) In addition to the requirements of Subsection (a) and
(b) above, and subsequent to compliance with the provisions of (b),
if substantial public protest or adverse information concerning the
applicant is received, the Board or upon its direction, an Examiner
shall hold a public hearing to gather input from the public before
a permit for the operation of a massage business is issued.&#xA0;
All relevant information so obtained shall be used by the Board in
determining whether or not to issue a massage business
permit.&#xA0; Public hearings shall be held in accordance with
Chapter X, Article 2, Division 3 of this Code. (2) (Amended by Ord.
No. 173,300, Eff. 6/30/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)&#xA0; Notice of an
applicant&#x2019;s intent to establish a massage business &#xA0; shall be
given in the following manner: (i) By at least one publication in a
newspaper of general circulation in the City, designated for that
purpose by the Office of Finance, not less than 24 days after
applying for the permit. (ii) When a public hearing is scheduled,
written notice shall be mailed not less than 24 days prior to the
date of such hearing to the applicant, to the owner or owners of
the property within and outside the City that is within 300 feet of
the area proposed to be subject of the permit application as shown
upon the records of the Office of Finance, or in the case of
property outside of the City the records of the County Assessor.
(3) Record &#x2013; The hearing procedure shall be recorded or summarized
as directed by the Board.&#xA0; When proceedings are recorded and
not summarized, they shall be transcribed at the request of any
party or interested person upon the prepayment of a fee, as
required by ordinance.&#xA0; One copy of such transcript shall be
furnished the Commission to be placed in the files. (4) Hearings -
conducted by whom &#x2013; The public hearing may be conducted by the
Board or an Examiner at its direction.&#xA0; After the conclusion
of a public hearing conducted by an Examiner, the Examiner shall
submit his report to the Board within such time, which may be fixed
by the Board, setting forth his conclusions and recommendations in
writing and stating briefly his reasons therefore. (d) Massage
Business &#x2013; Operating Requirements.&#xA0; No person shall engage in,
promote, advertise, conduct, carry on, or permit to be engaged in,
promoted, advertised, conducted or carried on, any Massage business
unless each and all of the following requirements are met. (1) Each
person employed or acting as a Massage Therapist shall have a valid
permit issued by the Board.&#xA0; It shall be unlawful for any
owner, operator, responsible managing employee, manager or
permittee in charge of or in control of a Massage Business to
employ or permit a person to act as a Massage Therapist, as defined
in this section, who is not in possession of a valid, unrevoked
Massage Therapist permit issued pursuant to this Code. (2) The
possession of a valid Massage Business permit does not authorize
the possessor to perform work for which a Massage Therapist permit
is required. (3) Massage operations shall be carried on, and the
premises shall be open, only between the hours of 7:00 a.m. and
10:00 p.m. (4) A list of services available and the cost of such
services shall be posted in an open and conspicuous place on the
premises.&#xA0; The services shall be described in readily
understandable language. (5) The Massage Business permit, and a
copy of the permit of each and every Massage Therapist employed in
the establishment, shall be displayed in an open and conspicuous
place on the premises. (6) Every permittee operating a Massage
Business under a permit issued pursuant to this Section shall keep
a record of the date and hour of each treatment, the name and
address of the patron, the name of the employee administering such
treatment, and the type of treatment administered.&#xA0; Such
record shall be maintained on a professionally printed form
provided by the permittee.&#xA0; Such records shall be open to
inspection only by Public Health Investigators.&#xA0; The
information furnished or secured as a result of any such record
shall be confidential.&#xA0; Any unauthorized disclosure or use of
such information by an employee of the business or the City or
County of Los Angeles shall constitute a misdemeanor, and such
employee shall be subject to the penalty provisions of this Code in
addition to any other penalties provided by law.&#xA0; Such records
shall be maintained for a period of one (1) year. (7) The
Department of Health shall, from time to time, and at least once a
year, make an inspection of each Massage Business in the City for
the purposes of determining that the health provisions of the laws
of the State of California and ordinances of the City and County of
Los Angeles and this section are met (8) The Massage business meets
any or all of the following conditions which may, in the discretion
of the Board, be imposed on such Business. (i) A minimum of one (1)
tub or shower, and one (1) toilet and wash basin shall be provided
for the patrons in every Massage Business location;&#xA0; however,
if male and female patrons are to be served simultaneously at said
establishment, separate toilet facilities shall be provided for
male and female patrons.&#xA0; In those establishments where steam
rooms or sauna baths are provided, if male and female patrons are
to be served simultaneously, separate steam rooms or sauna rooms
shall be provided for male and female patrons.&#xA0; Hot and cold
running water under pressure shall be provided to all wash basins,
bathtubs, showers, and similar equipment.&#xA0; Each wash basin
shall be provided with soap or detergent and sanitary towels placed
in permanently installed dispensers.&#xA0; A trash receptacle shall
be provided in each toilet room.&#xA0; In addition to the wash
basin provided for patrons, a minimum of one separate wash basin
shall be provided in each massage establishment.&#xA0; This basin
shall provide soap or detergent and hot and cold running water at
all times and shall be located within or as close as practicable to
the area devoted to the performing of massage services.&#xA0; In
addition, there shall be provided at each wash basin, sanitary
towels placed in permanently installed dispensers. EXCEPTION: If
the wash basin for the patrons is not in the toilet room but is
adjacent thereto, this wash basin will meet the separate wash basin
requirement if it is reasonably close to the area devoted to the
performing of massage. (ii) Minimum ventilation shall be provided
in accordance with the Building code of the City of Los
Angeles.&#xA0; A light level of no less than 25 watts shall be
maintained in public rooms, walkways, and at any point within each
room or enclosure where massage services are being performed, and
at all times such services are being provided. (iii) All walls,
ceilings, floors, pools, showers, bathtubs, wet and dry heat rooms,
steam or vapor rooms, tables and all other physical facilities
shall be in good repair and maintained in a clean and sanitary
condition.&#xA0; Wet and dry heat rooms, steam or vapor rooms or
cabinets, showers, compartments and toilet rooms shall be
thoroughly cleaned at least once each day the business is in
operation.&#xA0; Bathtubs shall be thoroughly cleaned after each
use. (iv) Clean and sanitary towels, sheets and linens shall be
provided for each patron of the establishment or each patron
receiving massage services.&#xA0; No common use of towels or linens
shall be permitted.&#xA0; Towels, sheets and linens shall be
provided in sufficient quantity and shall not be used by more than
one (1) person unless they have been first relaundered.&#xA0; Heavy
white paper may be substituted for sheets provided that such paper
is used one for each person and then discarded into a sanitary
receptacle.&#xA0; Separate closed cabinets or containers shall be
provided for the storage of clean and soiled linen and shall be
plainly marked:&#xA0; &#x201C;clean linen&#x201D; and &#x201C;soiled linen.&#x201D; (v)
Disinfecting agents and sterilizing equipment approved by the
Health Department shall be provided for any instruments used in
performing any massage. (vi) Pads used on massage tables shall be
covered in a workmanlike manner with durable, washable plastic or
other waterproof material acceptable to the Health Department.
(vii) All exterior and interior massage room doors shall remain
unlocked during business hours. (viii) A separate locker shall be
provided for each patron to be served, such locker shall be capable
of being locked and available at no extra charge. (ix) No person
shall enter, be or remain, in any part of a Massage Business
location while in the possession of, consuming, or using any
alcoholic beverages or drugs except pursuant to a prescription for
such drugs.&#xA0; The owner, operator, responsible managing
employee, manager or permittee shall not permit any such person to
enter or remain upon such premises. (x) All employees including
Massage Therapists, shall be clean, and shall be fully clothed in
clean nontransparent outer garments.&#xA0; As used herein, &#x201C;fully
clothed&#x201D; shall mean the wearing of undergarments such as bras and
underwear as well as the wearing of clothing which is comparable to
the clothing commonly worn by nurses and physical therapists while
performing their respective professional duties. (e) Off-Premises
Massage Business &#x2013; Permit Required.&#xA0; No person shall engage
in, promote, advertise, conduct, carry on, or permit to be engaged
in, promoted, advertised, conducted or carried on, any Off-Premises
Massage Business in the City of Los Angeles, without a permit duly
issued by the Board pursuant to this subsection for each business
location.&#xA0; The permit required hereby shall be in addition to
any business tax license required by ordinance. (1) Application for
Permit.&#xA0; Permit Applications shall be made in accordance with
the requirements of Chapter X, Article 3, and Section 103.205(b)(2)
of this Code. (2) Operating Requirements.&#xA0; The operating
requirements are as set forth in Section 103.205(d) of this Code
and the following additional requirements shall apply: (i) The
owner, operator, responsible managing employee, manager or
permittee of an Off-Premises Massage Business shall display the
permit issued therefore and a true and correct copy of the permit
of each and every Massage Therapist employed by the business in an
open and conspicuous manner on the business premises and to every
customer who requests the information contained in the permits.
(ii) A record of treatment shall be maintained by each Massage
Therapist employed by the business. (iii) No person operating an
Off-Premises Massage Business shall employee or allow a person to
act as an Off-Premises Massage Therapist unless such person has a
valid, unrevoked Massage Therapist permit endorsed by the Board of
Police Commissioners for Off-Premises Massage. (iv) Upon any change
of employees, the permittee shall inform the Board within ten (10)
days of such change. (f) Massage Business/Off-Premises Permit
Issuance and Denial. (1) Upon receipt of a written application for
a permit to conduct a Massage Business or Off-Premises Massage
Business, the Board shall conduct an investigation in order to
ascertain whether such permit should be issued as requested.&#xA0;
The Board shall approve, conditionally approve, set for an
Administrative Hearing or &#x2018;File Without Further Action&#x2019; the
application within ninety (90) days of the filing of an
application.&#xA0; The Board shall issue such permit as requested
unless the Board makes any of the following findings: (a) Any
person, including but not limited to, employees who will be
directly engaged or employed in the massage establishment or
Off-Premises Massage Business has been convicted or a violation of
Health and Safety Code Section 11550 or a violation of Penal Code
Section 266i, 315, 316, 318, 647(a) P.C., 647(b), or has been
convicted in any other State of any offense which if committed or
attempted in this State, would have been punished as one or more of
the above mentioned offenses, or that any such person is required
to register under the provisions of Penal Code Section 290. (b) Any
person, including, but not limited to, employees who will be
directly engaged or employed in the massage establishment or
Off-Premises Massage Business who has been convicted of any felony
offense involving the sale of a controlled substance specified in
Health and Safety Code Sections 11054, 11055, 11056, 11057, or
11058 or has been convicted in any other State of any offense
which, if committed or attempted in this State would have been
punishable as one or more of the above mentioned offenses. (c) Any
person including, but not limited to, employees who will be
directly engaged or employed in the massage establishment or
Off-Premises Massage Business, who has committed an act, which, if
done by a licensee or permittee under this Chapter, would be
grounds for suspension or revocation of a license or permit. (d)
Any person including, but not limited to, employees who will be
directly engaged or employed in the massage establishment or
Off-Premises Massage Business, who has committed an act involving
dishonesty, fraud, or deceit with the intent to substantially
benefit himself, herself, or another or substantially to injure
another, or an act of violence, which act or acts are substantially
related to the qualifications, functions, or duties of the massage
establishment or Off-Premises Massage Business. (e) The operations
of the massage establishment or Off- Premise Massage Business
would, if allowed, constitute a public nuisance. (f) The applicant
has knowingly made a false, misleading, or fraudulent statement of
fact to the City in the permit application process. (g) The
application does not contain the information required by this
section. (h) The applicant has not satisfied the requirements of
this Code. (2) Conditions of Permit Issuance.&#xA0; The Board shall
condition the issuance of an operator&#x2019;s permit to insure compliance
with this section and other applicable laws.&#xA0; Such conditions
shall include, but not be limited to, the following: (a) The front
door of the massage establishment and the doors of the interior
treatment rooms in which massages are being performed must remain
unlocked during all hours of operation.&#xA0; No electronic locking
device may be utilized on any entrance door.&#xA0; No warning
devices such as buzzers may be installed.&#xA0; No locks may be
installed on any of the treatment room doors. (b) No massage
therapist/practitioner or employee shall expose his or her
genitals, buttocks, or, in the case of a female, her breast nor, in
the course of administering a massage, make intentional contact
with the genitals or anus of another person. (c) The massage
establishment or Off-Premises Massage Business shall not refuse
service on the basis of a customer&#x2019;s sex, race, color, religion,
ancestry, national origin or other arbitrary factor proscribed by
the Unruh Civil Rights Act, Civil Code Section 51 et seq. (d) The
Chief of Police or his authorized representative, and the Los
Angeles County Health Department shall have the right to enter each
and every part of the massage establishment for the purpose of
making unscheduled inspections to observe and enforce compliance
with applicable regulations, laws, and provisions of this
ordinance.&#xA0; It shall be unlawful for any permittee to fail to
allow such inspection officers access to the premises or hinder
such officer in any manner.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><unit></unit></prefixes><entire_prefix></entire_prefix><prefix_anchor></prefix_anchor><level>1</level></unit></text></law>
