<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><section_number>103.205.1</section_number><edition_id>1</edition_id><section_id>3536</section_id><structure_id>33</structure_id><catch_line>Massage Therapists.</catch_line><history></history><full_text>&#xA0; MASSAGE THERAPISTS.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,994, Eff. 5/31/98.)

	(a)	Definitions.&#xA0; The words and phrases defined in Section 103.205(a) of this Code, shall have the same meanings when used in this section.&#xA0; In addition thereto, the following words and phrases shall have the following meanings when used in this section.

	(1)	&#x201C;Off-Premises Massage Therapist&#x201D; means a person who, for any compensation of any kind, gives a massage to a person at a location other than a place that has a valid and outstanding Massage Business Permit issued pursuant to Section 103.205(b) of this Code.

	(b)	Massage Therapist &#x2014; Permit Required.&#xA0; No person shall engage in the business of acting or act as a Massage Therapist unless such person holds a valid Massage Therapist permit issued by the Board.&#xA0; No person shall engage in the business of acting, or act as an Off-Premises Massage Therapist unless such person holds a valid permit issued by the Board and endorsed for Off-Premises work.&#xA0; Persons not licensed by the State of California, to practice pursuant to the Medical Practices Act who are employed by a physician, surgeon, chiropractor, osteopath, acupuncturist, nurse, or other medical practitioner are not exempt under this section.

	(1)	EXEMPTIONS.&#xA0; This section shall not apply to the following classes of individuals, and no permit shall be required of such persons, while engaged in the performance of the duties of their respective professions:

	(i)	Physicians, surgeons, chiropractors, osteopaths, acupuncturists, or physical therapists who are duly licensed to practice their respective professions in the State of California.

	(ii)	Nurses who are registered as such under the laws of the State of California.

	(iii)	Barbers and beauticians who are duly licensed under the laws of the State of California.

	(iv)	Athletic trainers employed by or on behalf of a professional athletic team performing or training within this State shall be exempt from the provisions of this act.

	(v)	Hospitals, nursing homes, sanitariums, or other health care facilities duly licensed by the State of California.

	(vi)	An exemption granted is effective to the extent that an exempted person&#x2019;s practice or profession overlaps with the practice of massage.

	(2)	Additional Requirements.&#xA0; In addition to those requirements specified in Chapter X, Article 3, Division 3 of this Code, each applicant for a Massage Therapist permit shall furnish the following information to the Board prior to the issuance of a permit, but subsequent to applicant&#x2019;s having taken and passed the examination provided for in Section 103.205.1(b) (3).

	(i)	Each residence and business address of applicant for the five (5) years immediately preceding the date of the application, and the inclusive dates of each such address.

	(ii)	Written proof that the applicant is at least eighteen (18) years of age.

	(iii)	Applicant&#x2019;s height, weight, color of eyes and hair.

	(iv)	Three (3) photographs of applicant, of a size specified by the Board, taken within the six (6) months immediately preceding the date of application.

	(v)	Applicant&#x2019;s business, occupation and employment history for the five (5) years immediately preceding the date of application.

	(vi)	The permit history of the applicant; whether applicant has ever had any license or permit issued by any agency or Board, City, County or State revoked or suspended, or has had any professional or vocational license or permit revoked or suspended, and the reason therefore.

	(vii)	A certificate from a medical doctor, licensed to practice in the State of California, issued within thirty (30) days, that certifies that applicant has been examined and had no communicable disease on the date of the examination.

	(viii)	Such other identification and information as may be required by the Board.

	(ix)	Beginning on the effective date of this ordinance all applicants applying for a massage therapy permit, shall show proof of completion of a minimum of 150 hours of training at a state approved school of massage.&#xA0; Beginning January 1, 2000, all applicants thereafter shall show proof of completion of 300 hours of training at a state approved school of massage.

	(x)	All criminal convictions excluding traffic misdemeanors or infraction violations, shall be reported.

	(xi)	Each applicant must furnish a diploma or certificate and transcript of graduation from an approved school wherein the method, profession, anatomical and physiological knowledge and practice of a massage therapist are taught.&#xA0; The term &#x201C;approved school&#x201D; shall mean and include any school or institute of learning licensed by the State of California and approved by the State Superintendent of Public Instruction pursuant to Education Code Section 94311D and reviewed by the superintendent within the preceding twelve month period which school has for its purpose teaching of theory, the method, profession, or work of massage therapists and which school requires a resident course of study of not less than 150 hours or 300 hours beginning January 1, 2000.&#xA0; Schools offering a correspondence course not requiring actual attendance shall not be deemed a recognized school.&#xA0; The City of Los Angeles shall have the right to confirm that the applicant has actually attended a class in a State approved school.&#xA0; If requested, the applicant must also supply a course description, an outline of material covered, a certified transcript and a letter to the City from the school administrator verifying completion or alternative documentation of education completed as verified and approved by the City, Board, or its agents and employees, in cases where the school no longer is in business.&#xA0; The Board may consider an applicants study of massage completed outside the State of California if proof of completion of a formalized course of study in massage practice, anatomy, and physiology is provided upon application.&#xA0; Proof of completion shall include, but not be limited to dates of study, the name of the school attended and the address and phone number of the school attended.&#xA0; Any outside course of study submitted for approval shall meet the State of California&#x2019;s Office of Post Secondary Education minimum requirements and the City of Los Angeles&#x2019; permit requirements.&#xA0; The provisions of this subsection may be satisfied by proof satisfactory to the Board that the applicant has graduated from an educational institution licensed or approved by another State and having equivalent standards as provided herein, or by proof that the applicant has passed the examination administered by the National Certification Board for Therapeutic Massage and Bodywork.

	(xii)	Authorization for the City, Board, its agents and employees to seek verification of the information contained in the application and qualification of the applicant for the permit.

	(xiii)	A statement in writing by the applicant that he or she certifies under penalty of perjury that all information contained in the application is true and correct, said declaration being duly dated and signed in the City.

	(3)	Annual Medical Certificate.&#xA0; Each Massage Therapist shall annually at the time of the renewal of his or her permit supply the Board with a new medical certificate required by Section 103.205.1(b) (2) (vii) of this Code.

	(c)	Massage Therapist Permit Issuance and Denial.

	(1)	Upon receipt of written application for a permit, the Board shall conduct an investigation to ascertain whether such permit should be issued as requested.&#xA0; The permit shall be denied if the Board makes any of the following findings:

	(a)	The applicant has been convicted of a violation of Health and Safety Code Section 11550 or a violation of Penal Code Sections 266i, 315, 316, 318, 647(a) or 647(b), or has been convicted in any other state of any offense which if committed or attempted in this state, would have been punished as one or more of the above mentioned offenses, or that any such person is required to register under the provisions of Penal Code Section 290.

	(b)	The applicant has been convicted of a felony offense involving the sale of a controlled substance specified in Health and Safety Code Sections 11054, 11055, 11056, 11057 or 11058 or has been convicted in any other state of any offense which, if committed or attempted in this state would have been punishable as one or more of the above mentioned offenses.

	(c)	The applicant has committed an act, which, if done by a permittee under this section, would be grounds for suspension or revocation of a permit.

	(d)	The applicant has committed an act involving dishonesty, fraud, or deceit with the intent to substantially benefit himself, herself, or another or substantially to injure another, or an act of violence, which act or acts are substantially related to the qualifications functions, or duties of the Massage Therapist.

	(e)	The applicant has knowingly made a false, misleading, or fraudulent statement of fact to the City in the permit application process.

	(f)	The applicant has not satisfied the requirements of this Code.

	(e)	Operative Date &#x2013; &#xA0; All persons operating or employed as masseurs or masseuses in Massage establishments at the time this ordinance becomes effective shall obtain a Massage Therapist Permit within one year of the effective date of this ordinance.

	(a)	Every massage therapist/practitioner licensed pursuant to Section 103.205.1 shall be required for renewal in 2001 and each subsequent renewal thereafter, to complete 6 contact hours of continuing education courses approved by the Board.&#xA0; Such courses shall have been completed within the 12 months preceding the date the renewal is due.</full_text><order_by>205.1</order_by><ancestry><unit id="33" label="article"><name>Police Permit Regulation</name><identifier>3</identifier><url>/10/3/</url></unit><unit id="29" label="chapter"><name>Business Regulations</name><identifier>10</identifier><url>/10/</url></unit></ancestry><structure_contents><unit id="1971"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.00</section_number><catch_line>Scope.</catch_line><url>/103.00/</url><token>103.00</token></unit><unit id="2728"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.01</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/103.01/</url><token>103.01</token></unit><unit id="3947"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.02</section_number><catch_line>Permit Required.</catch_line><url>/103.02/</url><token>103.02</token></unit><unit id="1237"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.02.1</section_number><catch_line>Permit Applications.</catch_line><url>/103.02.1/</url><token>103.02.1</token></unit><unit id="3529"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.03</section_number><catch_line>Public Hearings.</catch_line><url>/103.03/</url><token>103.03</token></unit><unit id="1633"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.04</section_number><catch_line>False Statements.</catch_line><url>/103.04/</url><token>103.04</token></unit><unit id="3757"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.05</section_number><catch_line>Overlapping Business.</catch_line><url>/103.05/</url><token>103.05</token></unit><unit id="3124"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.06</section_number><catch_line>Permits &#x2013; Duration.</catch_line><url>/103.06/</url><token>103.06</token></unit><unit id="2153"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.06.1</section_number><catch_line>Permits &#x2013; Renewal.</catch_line><url>/103.06.1/</url><token>103.06.1</token></unit><unit id="626"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.06.2</section_number><catch_line>Temporary Permits.</catch_line><url>/103.06.2/</url><token>103.06.2</token></unit><unit id="2080"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.07</section_number><catch_line>Permits &#x2013; Annual Fee.</catch_line><url>/103.07/</url><token>103.07</token></unit><unit id="935"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.08</section_number><catch_line>Permits Non-Transferable.</catch_line><url>/103.08/</url><token>103.08</token></unit><unit id="1789"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.09</section_number><catch_line>Permit For Each Location.</catch_line><url>/103.09/</url><token>103.09</token></unit><unit id="1610"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.10</section_number><catch_line>Change Of Location.</catch_line><url>/103.10/</url><token>103.10</token></unit><unit id="2237"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.11</section_number><catch_line>Additional Locations.</catch_line><url>/103.11/</url><token>103.11</token></unit><unit id="4168"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.12</section_number><catch_line>Fees.</catch_line><url>/103.12/</url><token>103.12</token></unit><unit id="2834"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.13</section_number><catch_line>Records.</catch_line><url>/103.13/</url><token>103.13</token></unit><unit id="1926"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.14</section_number><catch_line>Inspection.</catch_line><url>/103.14/</url><token>103.14</token></unit><unit id="3867"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.15</section_number><catch_line>Reports.</catch_line><url>/103.15/</url><token>103.15</token></unit><unit id="1179"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.16</section_number><catch_line>Property.</catch_line><url>/103.16/</url><token>103.16</token></unit><unit id="2714"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.17</section_number><catch_line>Advertising.</catch_line><url>/103.17/</url><token>103.17</token></unit><unit id="4164"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.18</section_number><catch_line>Permittee &#x2013; Responsibility.</catch_line><url>/103.18/</url><token>103.18</token></unit><unit id="1396"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.19</section_number><catch_line>Signs Required.</catch_line><url>/103.19/</url><token>103.19</token></unit><unit id="3238"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.20</section_number><catch_line>Display Of Permit.</catch_line><url>/103.20/</url><token>103.20</token></unit><unit id="663"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.21</section_number><catch_line>Change In Owner Information.</catch_line><url>/103.21/</url><token>103.21</token></unit><unit id="1862"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.22</section_number><catch_line>Identification Cards.</catch_line><url>/103.22/</url><token>103.22</token></unit><unit id="57"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.23</section_number><catch_line>Surrender Of Permits.</catch_line><url>/103.23/</url><token>103.23</token></unit><unit id="1606"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.24</section_number><catch_line>Hours Of Business.</catch_line><url>/103.24/</url><token>103.24</token></unit><unit id="3896"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.25</section_number><catch_line>Doing Business With Minor.</catch_line><url>/103.25/</url><token>103.25</token></unit><unit id="3138"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.26</section_number><catch_line>True Name, Age And Address.</catch_line><url>/103.26/</url><token>103.26</token></unit><unit id="233"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.27</section_number><catch_line>Administration.</catch_line><url>/103.27/</url><token>103.27</token></unit><unit id="2008"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.28</section_number><catch_line>Investigation By Board.</catch_line><url>/103.28/</url><token>103.28</token></unit><unit id="3636"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.29</section_number><catch_line>Timing Of Action On Application.</catch_line><url>/103.29/</url><token>103.29</token></unit><unit id="1985"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.29.01</section_number><catch_line>Executive Director Action On Application.</catch_line><url>/103.29.01/</url><token>103.29.01</token></unit><unit id="3913"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.30</section_number><catch_line>Effect Of Granting Permit.</catch_line><url>/103.30/</url><token>103.30</token></unit><unit id="1563"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.31</section_number><catch_line>Denial Of Application.</catch_line><url>/103.31/</url><token>103.31</token></unit><unit id="608"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.31.1</section_number><catch_line>Final Decisions.</catch_line><url>/103.31.1/</url><token>103.31.1</token></unit><unit id="2525"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.31.2</section_number><catch_line>Effective Date Of Notices.</catch_line><url>/103.31.2/</url><token>103.31.2</token></unit><unit id="3821"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.32</section_number><catch_line>Denial &#x2013;Notice To Applicant.</catch_line><url>/103.32/</url><token>103.32</token></unit><unit id="569"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.33</section_number><catch_line>Hearing On Denial &#x2013; Request By Applicant.</catch_line><url>/103.33/</url><token>103.33</token></unit><unit id="3240"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.34</section_number><catch_line>Suspension Or Revocation Of Permits Issued Under This Article.</catch_line><url>/103.34/</url><token>103.34</token></unit><unit id="3508"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.34.1</section_number><catch_line>Suspension Or Revocation Of Permits Issued Pursuant To Sections 103.101.1, 103.102 And 103.109.</catch_line><url>/103.34.1/</url><token>103.34.1</token></unit><unit id="3371"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.34.2</section_number><catch_line>Judicial Review Of Board Action On Applications And Permits Subject To Sections 103.101.1, 103.102 And 103.109.</catch_line><url>/103.34.2/</url><token>103.34.2</token></unit><unit id="2882"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.35</section_number><catch_line>Disciplinary Action &#x2013; Grounds.</catch_line><url>/103.35/</url><token>103.35</token></unit><unit id="214"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.36</section_number><catch_line>Suspension Or Revocation Without Hearing.</catch_line><url>/103.36/</url><token>103.36</token></unit><unit id="2189"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.37</section_number><catch_line>Suspension Or Revocation &#x2013; Effect On Other Permits.</catch_line><url>/103.37/</url><token>103.37</token></unit><unit id="4000"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.38</section_number><catch_line>New Permit Application After Denial Or Revocation.</catch_line><url>/103.38/</url><token>103.38</token></unit><unit id="755"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.39</section_number><catch_line>Cancelled Or Suspended Permit &#x2013; Jurisdiction Of The Board.</catch_line><url>/103.39/</url><token>103.39</token></unit><unit id="3036"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.40</section_number><catch_line>Pending Revocation Or Suspension Proceedings &#x2013; Effect On Permittee.</catch_line><url>/103.40/</url><token>103.40</token></unit><unit id="2541"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.40.1</section_number><catch_line>Power Of Board To Limit And/Or Condition A Permit.</catch_line><url>/103.40.1/</url><token>103.40.1</token></unit><unit id="3520"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.40.2</section_number><catch_line>Subject Matter Of Limitations And/Or Conditions To A Permit.</catch_line><url>/103.40.2/</url><token>103.40.2</token></unit><unit id="982"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.41</section_number><catch_line>Prior Acts No Bar To Board Action.</catch_line><url>/103.41/</url><token>103.41</token></unit><unit id="911"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.42</section_number><catch_line>Stolen Property &#x2013; Investigation.</catch_line><url>/103.42/</url><token>103.42</token></unit><unit id="2845"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.43</section_number><catch_line>Record Search &#x2013; Charge Authorized.</catch_line><url>/103.43/</url><token>103.43</token></unit><unit id="102"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.44</section_number><catch_line>Instructional Materials &#x2013; Custody &#x2013; Fees For Rental Or Sale.</catch_line><url>/103.44/</url><token>103.44</token></unit><unit id="2184"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101</section_number><catch_line>Picture Arcade.</catch_line><url>/103.101/</url><token>103.101</token></unit><unit id="845"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101.1</section_number><catch_line>Picture Arcade Permits And Regulations.</catch_line><url>/103.101.1/</url><token>103.101.1</token></unit><unit id="3778"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101.2</section_number><catch_line>Compliance By Existing Permittees.</catch_line><url>/103.101.2/</url><token>103.101.2</token></unit><unit id="445"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101.3</section_number><catch_line>Game Arcade.</catch_line><url>/103.101.3/</url><token>103.101.3</token></unit><unit id="3234"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.101.4</section_number><catch_line>Cyber Caf&#xC9;S.</catch_line><url>/103.101.4/</url><token>103.101.4</token></unit><unit id="1486"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.102</section_number><catch_line>Cafe Entertainment And Shows.</catch_line><url>/103.102/</url><token>103.102</token></unit><unit id="3379"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.102.1</section_number><catch_line>Additional Regulations.</catch_line><url>/103.102.1/</url><token>103.102.1</token></unit><unit id="3638"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.102.2</section_number><catch_line>Compliance By Existing Permittees And Effect Of Noncompliance.</catch_line><url>/103.102.2/</url><token>103.102.2</token></unit><unit id="2551"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.103</section_number><catch_line>Card Club &#x2013; Social Card Club &#x2013; Card School.</catch_line><url>/103.103/</url><token>103.103</token></unit><unit id="2151"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.104</section_number><catch_line>Carnivals.</catch_line><url>/103.104/</url><token>103.104</token></unit><unit id="1602"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.105</section_number><catch_line>Dancing Academies.</catch_line><url>/103.105/</url><token>103.105</token></unit><unit id="1052"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.106</section_number><catch_line>Dance Halls, Dancing Clubs, Public Dances.</catch_line><url>/103.106/</url><token>103.106</token></unit><unit id="2839"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.106.1</section_number><catch_line>Hostess Dance Hall.</catch_line><url>/103.106.1/</url><token>103.106.1</token></unit><unit id="3668"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.107</section_number><catch_line>Escort Bureaus.</catch_line><url>/103.107/</url><token>103.107</token></unit><unit id="268"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.107.1</section_number><catch_line>Escort &#x2013; Permit Required.</catch_line><url>/103.107.1/</url><token>103.107.1</token></unit><unit id="1084"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.109</section_number><catch_line>Motion Picture Shows.</catch_line><url>/103.109/</url><token>103.109</token></unit><unit id="94"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.111</section_number><catch_line>Parades And Assemblies.</catch_line><url>/103.111/</url><token>103.111</token></unit><unit id="3445"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.112</section_number><catch_line>Billiard Rooms, Poolrooms, Bowling Alleys.</catch_line><url>/103.112/</url><token>103.112</token></unit><unit id="3049"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.112.1</section_number><catch_line>Family Billiard Rooms.</catch_line><url>/103.112.1/</url><token>103.112.1</token></unit><unit id="277"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.113</section_number><catch_line>Rides.</catch_line><url>/103.113/</url><token>103.113</token></unit><unit id="442"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.115</section_number><catch_line>Skating Rinks.</catch_line><url>/103.115/</url><token>103.115</token></unit><unit id="2194"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.116</section_number><catch_line>Games Of Skill And Science.</catch_line><url>/103.116/</url><token>103.116</token></unit><unit id="384"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.117</section_number><catch_line>Rifle Range &#x2013; Shooting Gallery.</catch_line><url>/103.117/</url><token>103.117</token></unit><unit id="1306"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.118</section_number><catch_line>Teenage Dances.</catch_line><url>/103.118/</url><token>103.118</token></unit><unit id="2754"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.120</section_number><catch_line>Soundproofing Of Places Of Amusement &#x2013; When Required.</catch_line><url>/103.120/</url><token>103.120</token></unit><unit id="2832"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.202</section_number><catch_line>Automobile Parking Lots.</catch_line><url>/103.202/</url><token>103.202</token></unit><unit id="2880"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.204</section_number><catch_line>Towing Operation.</catch_line><url>/103.204/</url><token>103.204</token></unit><unit id="4074"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.204.1</section_number><catch_line>Tow Unit Operators.</catch_line><url>/103.204.1/</url><token>103.204.1</token></unit><unit id="448"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.205</section_number><catch_line>Massage Therapy.</catch_line><url>/103.205/</url><token>103.205</token></unit><unit id="3536"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.205.1</section_number><catch_line>Massage Therapists.</catch_line><url>/103.205.1/</url><token>103.205.1</token></unit><unit id="2047"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.205.2</section_number><catch_line>Baths.</catch_line><url>/103.205.2/</url><token>103.205.2</token></unit><unit id="687"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.206</section_number><catch_line>Alarm Systems.</catch_line><url>/103.206/</url><token>103.206</token></unit><unit id="2780"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.206.1</section_number><catch_line>Alarm Company Operators.</catch_line><url>/103.206.1/</url><token>103.206.1</token></unit><unit id="3551"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.206.2</section_number><catch_line>Commercial Unsecured Buildings.</catch_line><url>/103.206.2/</url><token>103.206.2</token></unit><unit id="2339"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.208</section_number><catch_line>Key Duplicator.</catch_line><url>/103.208/</url><token>103.208</token></unit><unit id="2609"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.211</section_number><catch_line>Handbill Distribution.</catch_line><url>/103.211/</url><token>103.211</token></unit><unit id="1701"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.212</section_number><catch_line>Soliciting &#x2013; Peace Officers&#x2019; And Firefighters&#x2019; Organizations &#x2013; Permits.</catch_line><url>/103.212/</url><token>103.212</token></unit><unit id="3677"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.213</section_number><catch_line>Figure Studios.</catch_line><url>/103.213/</url><token>103.213</token></unit><unit id="966"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.301</section_number><catch_line>Antique Shops.</catch_line><url>/103.301/</url><token>103.301</token></unit><unit id="1483"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.301.1</section_number><catch_line>Antique Show Or Collectors Exchange Show.</catch_line><url>/103.301.1/</url><token>103.301.1</token></unit><unit id="3136"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.304</section_number><catch_line>Junk Collectors.</catch_line><url>/103.304/</url><token>103.304</token></unit><unit id="3016"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.305</section_number><catch_line>Junk Dealers.</catch_line><url>/103.305/</url><token>103.305</token></unit><unit id="3600"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.306</section_number><catch_line>Pawnbroker.</catch_line><url>/103.306/</url><token>103.306</token></unit><unit id="1834"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.307</section_number><catch_line>Rummage Sale.</catch_line><url>/103.307/</url><token>103.307</token></unit><unit id="1830"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.308</section_number><catch_line>Sales &#x2013; Fire And Closing Out.</catch_line><url>/103.308/</url><token>103.308</token></unit><unit id="236"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.309</section_number><catch_line>Secondhand Auto Parts Dealer.</catch_line><url>/103.309/</url><token>103.309</token></unit><unit id="3361"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.310</section_number><catch_line>Secondhand Book Dealers.</catch_line><url>/103.310/</url><token>103.310</token></unit><unit id="3558"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.311</section_number><catch_line>Secondhand Dealers.</catch_line><url>/103.311/</url><token>103.311</token></unit><unit id="3738"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.311.1</section_number><catch_line>Firearms Sales By Secondhand Dealers Prohibited.</catch_line><url>/103.311.1/</url><token>103.311.1</token></unit><unit id="2476"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.314</section_number><catch_line>Sellers Of Firearms.</catch_line><url>/103.314/</url><token>103.314</token></unit><unit id="3698"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.314.1</section_number><catch_line>Sellers Of Firearm Ammunition.</catch_line><url>/103.314.1/</url><token>103.314.1</token></unit></structure_contents><next_section id="2047"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.205.2</section_number><catch_line>Baths.</catch_line><url>/103.205.2/</url><token>103.205.2</token></next_section><metadata></metadata><references></references><url>/103.205.1/</url><token>103.205.1</token><formats><txt>/103.205.1.txt</txt><json>/103.205.1.xml</json></formats><dublin_core><Title>Massage Therapists.</Title><Type>Text</Type><Format>text/html</Format><Identifier>&#xA7; 103.205.1</Identifier><Relation>Los Angeles Municipal Code</Relation></dublin_core><plain_text>                            LOS ANGELES MUNICIPAL CODE

MASSAGE THERAPISTS. (&#xA7; 103.205.1)

&#xA0; MASSAGE THERAPISTS.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,994, Eff. 5/31/98.)	(a)	Definitions.&#xA0; The words and
phrases defined in Section 103.205(a) of this Code, shall have the same meanings
when used in this section.&#xA0; In addition thereto, the following words and
phrases shall have the following meanings when used in this
section.	(1)	&#x201C;Off-Premises Massage Therapist&#x201D; means a person who, for any
compensation of any kind, gives a massage to a person at a location other than a
place that has a valid and outstanding Massage Business Permit issued pursuant
to Section 103.205(b) of this Code.	(b)	Massage Therapist &#x2014; Permit Required.&#xA0;
No person shall engage in the business of acting or act as a Massage Therapist
unless such person holds a valid Massage Therapist permit issued by the Board.&#xA0;
No person shall engage in the business of acting, or act as an Off-Premises
Massage Therapist unless such person holds a valid permit issued by the Board
and endorsed for Off-Premises work.&#xA0; Persons not licensed by the State of
California, to practice pursuant to the Medical Practices Act who are employed
by a physician, surgeon, chiropractor, osteopath, acupuncturist, nurse, or other
medical practitioner are not exempt under this section.	(1)	EXEMPTIONS.&#xA0; This
section shall not apply to the following classes of individuals, and no permit
shall be required of such persons, while engaged in the performance of the
duties of their respective professions:	(i)	Physicians, surgeons, chiropractors,
osteopaths, acupuncturists, or physical therapists who are duly licensed to
practice their respective professions in the State of California.	(ii)	Nurses
who are registered as such under the laws of the State of
California.	(iii)	Barbers and beauticians who are duly licensed under the laws
of the State of California.	(iv)	Athletic trainers employed by or on behalf of a
professional athletic team performing or training within this State shall be
exempt from the provisions of this act.	(v)	Hospitals, nursing homes,
sanitariums, or other health care facilities duly licensed by the State of
California.	(vi)	An exemption granted is effective to the extent that an
exempted person&#x2019;s practice or profession overlaps with the practice of
massage.	(2)	Additional Requirements.&#xA0; In addition to those requirements
specified in Chapter X, Article 3, Division 3 of this Code, each applicant for a
Massage Therapist permit shall furnish the following information to the Board
prior to the issuance of a permit, but subsequent to applicant&#x2019;s having taken
and passed the examination provided for in Section 103.205.1(b) (3).	(i)	Each
residence and business address of applicant for the five (5) years immediately
preceding the date of the application, and the inclusive dates of each such
address.	(ii)	Written proof that the applicant is at least eighteen (18) years
of age.	(iii)	Applicant&#x2019;s height, weight, color of eyes and hair.	(iv)	Three
(3) photographs of applicant, of a size specified by the Board, taken within the
six (6) months immediately preceding the date of application.	(v)	Applicant&#x2019;s
business, occupation and employment history for the five (5) years immediately
preceding the date of application.	(vi)	The permit history of the applicant;
whether applicant has ever had any license or permit issued by any agency or
Board, City, County or State revoked or suspended, or has had any professional
or vocational license or permit revoked or suspended, and the reason
therefore.	(vii)	A certificate from a medical doctor, licensed to practice in
the State of California, issued within thirty (30) days, that certifies that
applicant has been examined and had no communicable disease on the date of the
examination.	(viii)	Such other identification and information as may be required
by the Board.	(ix)	Beginning on the effective date of this ordinance all
applicants applying for a massage therapy permit, shall show proof of completion
of a minimum of 150 hours of training at a state approved school of massage.&#xA0;
Beginning January 1, 2000, all applicants thereafter shall show proof of
completion of 300 hours of training at a state approved school of
massage.	(x)	All criminal convictions excluding traffic misdemeanors or
infraction violations, shall be reported.	(xi)	Each applicant must furnish a
diploma or certificate and transcript of graduation from an approved school
wherein the method, profession, anatomical and physiological knowledge and
practice of a massage therapist are taught.&#xA0; The term &#x201C;approved school&#x201D;
shall mean and include any school or institute of learning licensed by the State
of California and approved by the State Superintendent of Public Instruction
pursuant to Education Code Section 94311D and reviewed by the superintendent
within the preceding twelve month period which school has for its purpose
teaching of theory, the method, profession, or work of massage therapists and
which school requires a resident course of study of not less than 150 hours or
300 hours beginning January 1, 2000.&#xA0; Schools offering a correspondence course
not requiring actual attendance shall not be deemed a recognized school.&#xA0; The
City of Los Angeles shall have the right to confirm that the applicant has
actually attended a class in a State approved school.&#xA0; If requested, the
applicant must also supply a course description, an outline of material covered,
a certified transcript and a letter to the City from the school administrator
verifying completion or alternative documentation of education completed as
verified and approved by the City, Board, or its agents and employees, in cases
where the school no longer is in business.&#xA0; The Board may consider an
applicants study of massage completed outside the State of California if proof
of completion of a formalized course of study in massage practice, anatomy, and
physiology is provided upon application.&#xA0; Proof of completion shall include,
but not be limited to dates of study, the name of the school attended and the
address and phone number of the school attended.&#xA0; Any outside course of study
submitted for approval shall meet the State of California&#x2019;s Office of Post
Secondary Education minimum requirements and the City of Los Angeles&#x2019; permit
requirements.&#xA0; The provisions of this subsection may be satisfied by proof
satisfactory to the Board that the applicant has graduated from an educational
institution licensed or approved by another State and having equivalent
standards as provided herein, or by proof that the applicant has passed the
examination administered by the National Certification Board for Therapeutic
Massage and Bodywork.	(xii)	Authorization for the City, Board, its agents and
employees to seek verification of the information contained in the application
and qualification of the applicant for the permit.	(xiii)	A statement in writing
by the applicant that he or she certifies under penalty of perjury that all
information contained in the application is true and correct, said declaration
being duly dated and signed in the City.	(3)	Annual Medical Certificate.&#xA0; Each
Massage Therapist shall annually at the time of the renewal of his or her permit
supply the Board with a new medical certificate required by Section 103.205.1(b)
(2) (vii) of this Code.	(c)	Massage Therapist Permit Issuance and
Denial.	(1)	Upon receipt of written application for a permit, the Board shall
conduct an investigation to ascertain whether such permit should be issued as
requested.&#xA0; The permit shall be denied if the Board makes any of the following
findings:	(a)	The applicant has been convicted of a violation of Health and
Safety Code Section 11550 or a violation of Penal Code Sections 266i, 315, 316,
318, 647(a) or 647(b), or has been convicted in any other state of any offense
which if committed or attempted in this state, would have been punished as one
or more of the above mentioned offenses, or that any such person is required to
register under the provisions of Penal Code Section 290.	(b)	The applicant has
been convicted of a felony offense involving the sale of a controlled substance
specified in Health and Safety Code Sections 11054, 11055, 11056, 11057 or 11058
or has been convicted in any other state of any offense which, if committed or
attempted in this state would have been punishable as one or more of the above
mentioned offenses.	(c)	The applicant has committed an act, which, if done by a
permittee under this section, would be grounds for suspension or revocation of a
permit.	(d)	The applicant has committed an act involving dishonesty, fraud, or
deceit with the intent to substantially benefit himself, herself, or another or
substantially to injure another, or an act of violence, which act or acts are
substantially related to the qualifications functions, or duties of the Massage
Therapist.	(e)	The applicant has knowingly made a false, misleading, or
fraudulent statement of fact to the City in the permit application
process.	(f)	The applicant has not satisfied the requirements of this
Code.	(e)	Operative Date &#x2013; &#xA0; All persons operating or employed as masseurs or
masseuses in Massage establishments at the time this ordinance becomes effective
shall obtain a Massage Therapist Permit within one year of the effective date of
this ordinance.	(a)	Every massage therapist/practitioner licensed pursuant to
Section 103.205.1 shall be required for renewal in 2001 and each subsequent
renewal thereafter, to complete 6 contact hours of continuing education courses
approved by the Board.&#xA0; Such courses shall have been completed within the 12
months preceding the date the renewal is due.
</plain_text><html>
					&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#xA0; MASSAGE THERAPISTS.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,994, Eff. 5/31/98.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(a)	Definitions.&#xA0; The words and phrases defined in Section 103.205(a) of this Code, shall have the same meanings when used in this section.&#xA0; In addition thereto, the following words and phrases shall have the following meanings when used in this section.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(1)	&#x201C;Off-Premises Massage Therapist&#x201D; means a person who, for any compensation of any kind, gives a massage to a person at a location other than a place that has a valid and outstanding Massage Business Permit issued pursuant to Section 103.205(b) of this Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(b)	Massage Therapist &#x2014; Permit Required.&#xA0; No person shall engage in the business of acting or act as a Massage Therapist unless such person holds a valid Massage Therapist permit issued by the Board.&#xA0; No person shall engage in the business of acting, or act as an Off-Premises Massage Therapist unless such person holds a valid permit issued by the Board and endorsed for Off-Premises work.&#xA0; Persons not licensed by the State of California, to practice pursuant to the Medical Practices Act who are employed by a physician, surgeon, chiropractor, osteopath, acupuncturist, nurse, or other medical practitioner are not exempt under this section.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(1)	EXEMPTIONS.&#xA0; This section shall not apply to the following classes of individuals, and no permit shall be required of such persons, while engaged in the performance of the duties of their respective professions:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(i)	Physicians, surgeons, chiropractors, osteopaths, acupuncturists, or physical therapists who are duly licensed to practice their respective professions in the State of California.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(ii)	Nurses who are registered as such under the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;laws&lt;/span&gt; of the State of California.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(iii)	Barbers and beauticians who are duly licensed under the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;laws&lt;/span&gt; of the State of California.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(iv)	Athletic trainers employed by or on behalf of a professional athletic team performing or training within this State shall be exempt from the provisions of this act.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(v)	Hospitals, nursing homes, sanitariums, or other health care facilities duly licensed by the State of California.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(vi)	An exemption granted is effective to the extent that an exempted person&#x2019;s practice or profession overlaps with the practice of massage.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(2)	Additional Requirements.&#xA0; In addition to those requirements specified in Chapter X, Article 3, Division 3 of this Code, each applicant for a Massage Therapist permit shall furnish the following information to the Board prior to the issuance of a permit, but subsequent to applicant&#x2019;s having taken and passed the examination provided for in Section 103.205.1(b) (3).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(i)	Each residence and business address of applicant for the five (5) years immediately preceding the date of the application, and the inclusive dates of each such address.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(ii)	Written proof that the applicant is at least eighteen (18) years of age.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(iii)	Applicant&#x2019;s height, weight, color of eyes and hair.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(iv)	Three (3) photographs of applicant, of a size specified by the Board, taken within the six (6) months immediately preceding the date of application.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(v)	Applicant&#x2019;s business, occupation and employment history for the five (5) years immediately preceding the date of application.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(vi)	The permit history of the applicant; whether applicant has ever had any license or permit issued by any agency or Board, City, County or State revoked or suspended, or has had any professional or vocational license or permit revoked or suspended, and the reason therefore.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(vii)	A certificate from a medical doctor, licensed to practice in the State of California, issued within thirty (30) days, that certifies that applicant has been examined and had no communicable disease on the date of the examination.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(viii)	Such other identification and information as may be required by the Board.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(ix)	Beginning on the effective date of this &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt; all applicants applying for a massage therapy permit, shall show proof of completion of a minimum of 150 hours of training at a state approved school of massage.&#xA0; Beginning January 1, 2000, all applicants thereafter shall show proof of completion of 300 hours of training at a state approved school of massage.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(x)	All criminal &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;convictions&lt;/span&gt; excluding traffic &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;misdemeanors&lt;/span&gt; or infraction violations, shall be reported.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(xi)	Each applicant must furnish a diploma or certificate and &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;transcript&lt;/span&gt; of graduation from an approved school wherein the method, profession, anatomical and physiological knowledge and practice of a massage therapist are taught.&#xA0; The term &#x201C;approved school&#x201D; shall mean and include any school or institute of learning licensed by the State of California and approved by the State Superintendent of Public Instruction pursuant to Education Code Section 94311D and reviewed by the superintendent within the preceding twelve month period which school has for its purpose teaching of theory, the method, profession, or work of massage therapists and which school requires a resident course of study of not less than 150 hours or 300 hours beginning January 1, 2000.&#xA0; Schools offering a correspondence course not requiring actual attendance shall not be deemed a recognized school.&#xA0; The City of Los Angeles shall have the right to confirm that the applicant has actually attended a class in a State approved school.&#xA0; If requested, the applicant must also supply a course description, an outline of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;material&lt;/span&gt; covered, a certified &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;transcript&lt;/span&gt; and a letter to the City from the school administrator verifying completion or alternative documentation of education completed as verified and approved by the City, Board, or its agents and employees, in cases where the school no longer is in business.&#xA0; The Board may consider an applicants study of massage completed outside the State of California if proof of completion of a formalized course of study in massage practice, anatomy, and physiology is provided upon application.&#xA0; Proof of completion shall include, but not be limited to dates of study, the name of the school attended and the address and phone number of the school attended.&#xA0; Any outside course of study submitted for approval shall meet the State of California&#x2019;s Office of Post Secondary Education minimum requirements and the City of Los Angeles&#x2019; permit requirements.&#xA0; The provisions of this subsection may be satisfied by proof satisfactory to the Board that the applicant has graduated from an educational institution licensed or approved by another State and having equivalent standards as provided herein, or by proof that the applicant has passed the examination administered by the National Certification Board for Therapeutic Massage and Bodywork.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(xii)	Authorization for the City, Board, its agents and employees to seek verification of the information contained in the application and qualification of the applicant for the permit.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(xiii)	A statement in writing by the applicant that he or she certifies under &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt; of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;perjury&lt;/span&gt; that all information contained in the application is true and correct, said declaration being duly dated and signed in the City.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(3)	Annual Medical Certificate.&#xA0; Each Massage Therapist shall annually at the time of the renewal of his or her permit supply the Board with a new medical certificate required by Section 103.205.1(b) (2) (vii) of this Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(c)	Massage Therapist Permit Issuance and Denial.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(1)	Upon receipt of written application for a permit, the Board shall conduct an investigation to ascertain whether such permit should be issued as requested.&#xA0; The permit shall be denied if the Board makes any of the following &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;findings&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(a)	The applicant has been convicted of a violation of Health and Safety Code Section 11550 or a violation of Penal Code Sections 266i, 315, 316, 318, 647(a) or 647(b), or has been convicted in any other state of any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;offense&lt;/span&gt; which if committed or attempted in this state, would have been punished as one or more of the above mentioned &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;offenses&lt;/span&gt;, or that any such person is required to register under the provisions of Penal Code Section 290.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(b)	The applicant has been convicted of a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;felony&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;offense&lt;/span&gt; involving the sale of a controlled substance specified in Health and Safety Code Sections 11054, 11055, 11056, 11057 or 11058 or has been convicted in any other state of any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;offense&lt;/span&gt; which, if committed or attempted in this state would have been punishable as one or more of the above mentioned &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;offenses&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(c)	The applicant has committed an act, which, if done by a permittee under this section, would be grounds for suspension or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;revocation&lt;/span&gt; of a permit.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(d)	The applicant has committed an act involving dishonesty, &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;fraud&lt;/span&gt;, or deceit with the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;intent&lt;/span&gt; to substantially benefit himself, herself, or another or substantially to injure another, or an act of violence, which act or acts are substantially related to the qualifications functions, or duties of the Massage Therapist.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(e)	The applicant has knowingly made a false, misleading, or fraudulent statement of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;fact&lt;/span&gt; to the City in the permit application process.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(f)	The applicant has not satisfied the requirements of this Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(e)	Operative Date &#x2013; &#xA0; All persons operating or employed as masseurs or masseuses in Massage establishments at the time this &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt; becomes effective shall obtain a Massage Therapist Permit within one year of the effective date of this &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(a)	Every massage therapist/practitioner licensed pursuant to Section 103.205.1 shall be required for renewal in 2001 and each subsequent renewal thereafter, to complete 6 contact hours of continuing education courses approved by the Board.&#xA0; Such courses shall have been completed within the 12 months preceding the date the renewal is due.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</html><previous_section id="448"><structure_id>33</structure_id><section_number>103.205</section_number><catch_line>Massage Therapy.</catch_line><url>/103.205/</url><token>103.205</token></previous_section><text><unit id="3510" prefix=""><text>&#xA0; MASSAGE THERAPISTS.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,994, Eff. 5/31/98.)	(a)	Definitions.&#xA0; The words and phrases defined in Section 103.205(a) of this Code, shall have the same meanings when used in this section.&#xA0; In addition thereto, the following words and phrases shall have the following meanings when used in this section.	(1)	&#x201C;Off-Premises Massage Therapist&#x201D; means a person who, for any compensation of any kind, gives a massage to a person at a location other than a place that has a valid and outstanding Massage Business Permit issued pursuant to Section 103.205(b) of this Code.	(b)	Massage Therapist &#x2014; Permit Required.&#xA0; No person shall engage in the business of acting or act as a Massage Therapist unless such person holds a valid Massage Therapist permit issued by the Board.&#xA0; No person shall engage in the business of acting, or act as an Off-Premises Massage Therapist unless such person holds a valid permit issued by the Board and endorsed for Off-Premises work.&#xA0; Persons not licensed by the State of California, to practice pursuant to the Medical Practices Act who are employed by a physician, surgeon, chiropractor, osteopath, acupuncturist, nurse, or other medical practitioner are not exempt under this section.	(1)	EXEMPTIONS.&#xA0; This section shall not apply to the following classes of individuals, and no permit shall be required of such persons, while engaged in the performance of the duties of their respective professions:	(i)	Physicians, surgeons, chiropractors, osteopaths, acupuncturists, or physical therapists who are duly licensed to practice their respective professions in the State of California.	(ii)	Nurses who are registered as such under the laws of the State of California.	(iii)	Barbers and beauticians who are duly licensed under the laws of the State of California.	(iv)	Athletic trainers employed by or on behalf of a professional athletic team performing or training within this State shall be exempt from the provisions of this act.	(v)	Hospitals, nursing homes, sanitariums, or other health care facilities duly licensed by the State of California.	(vi)	An exemption granted is effective to the extent that an exempted person&#x2019;s practice or profession overlaps with the practice of massage.	(2)	Additional Requirements.&#xA0; In addition to those requirements specified in Chapter X, Article 3, Division 3 of this Code, each applicant for a Massage Therapist permit shall furnish the following information to the Board prior to the issuance of a permit, but subsequent to applicant&#x2019;s having taken and passed the examination provided for in Section 103.205.1(b) (3).	(i)	Each residence and business address of applicant for the five (5) years immediately preceding the date of the application, and the inclusive dates of each such address.	(ii)	Written proof that the applicant is at least eighteen (18) years of age.	(iii)	Applicant&#x2019;s height, weight, color of eyes and hair.	(iv)	Three (3) photographs of applicant, of a size specified by the Board, taken within the six (6) months immediately preceding the date of application.	(v)	Applicant&#x2019;s business, occupation and employment history for the five (5) years immediately preceding the date of application.	(vi)	The permit history of the applicant; whether applicant has ever had any license or permit issued by any agency or Board, City, County or State revoked or suspended, or has had any professional or vocational license or permit revoked or suspended, and the reason therefore.	(vii)	A certificate from a medical doctor, licensed to practice in the State of California, issued within thirty (30) days, that certifies that applicant has been examined and had no communicable disease on the date of the examination.	(viii)	Such other identification and information as may be required by the Board.	(ix)	Beginning on the effective date of this ordinance all applicants applying for a massage therapy permit, shall show proof of completion of a minimum of 150 hours of training at a state approved school of massage.&#xA0; Beginning January 1, 2000, all applicants thereafter shall show proof of completion of 300 hours of training at a state approved school of massage.	(x)	All criminal convictions excluding traffic misdemeanors or infraction violations, shall be reported.	(xi)	Each applicant must furnish a diploma or certificate and transcript of graduation from an approved school wherein the method, profession, anatomical and physiological knowledge and practice of a massage therapist are taught.&#xA0; The term &#x201C;approved school&#x201D; shall mean and include any school or institute of learning licensed by the State of California and approved by the State Superintendent of Public Instruction pursuant to Education Code Section 94311D and reviewed by the superintendent within the preceding twelve month period which school has for its purpose teaching of theory, the method, profession, or work of massage therapists and which school requires a resident course of study of not less than 150 hours or 300 hours beginning January 1, 2000.&#xA0; Schools offering a correspondence course not requiring actual attendance shall not be deemed a recognized school.&#xA0; The City of Los Angeles shall have the right to confirm that the applicant has actually attended a class in a State approved school.&#xA0; If requested, the applicant must also supply a course description, an outline of material covered, a certified transcript and a letter to the City from the school administrator verifying completion or alternative documentation of education completed as verified and approved by the City, Board, or its agents and employees, in cases where the school no longer is in business.&#xA0; The Board may consider an applicants study of massage completed outside the State of California if proof of completion of a formalized course of study in massage practice, anatomy, and physiology is provided upon application.&#xA0; Proof of completion shall include, but not be limited to dates of study, the name of the school attended and the address and phone number of the school attended.&#xA0; Any outside course of study submitted for approval shall meet the State of California&#x2019;s Office of Post Secondary Education minimum requirements and the City of Los Angeles&#x2019; permit requirements.&#xA0; The provisions of this subsection may be satisfied by proof satisfactory to the Board that the applicant has graduated from an educational institution licensed or approved by another State and having equivalent standards as provided herein, or by proof that the applicant has passed the examination administered by the National Certification Board for Therapeutic Massage and Bodywork.	(xii)	Authorization for the City, Board, its agents and employees to seek verification of the information contained in the application and qualification of the applicant for the permit.	(xiii)	A statement in writing by the applicant that he or she certifies under penalty of perjury that all information contained in the application is true and correct, said declaration being duly dated and signed in the City.	(3)	Annual Medical Certificate.&#xA0; Each Massage Therapist shall annually at the time of the renewal of his or her permit supply the Board with a new medical certificate required by Section 103.205.1(b) (2) (vii) of this Code.	(c)	Massage Therapist Permit Issuance and Denial.	(1)	Upon receipt of written application for a permit, the Board shall conduct an investigation to ascertain whether such permit should be issued as requested.&#xA0; The permit shall be denied if the Board makes any of the following findings:	(a)	The applicant has been convicted of a violation of Health and Safety Code Section 11550 or a violation of Penal Code Sections 266i, 315, 316, 318, 647(a) or 647(b), or has been convicted in any other state of any offense which if committed or attempted in this state, would have been punished as one or more of the above mentioned offenses, or that any such person is required to register under the provisions of Penal Code Section 290.	(b)	The applicant has been convicted of a felony offense involving the sale of a controlled substance specified in Health and Safety Code Sections 11054, 11055, 11056, 11057 or 11058 or has been convicted in any other state of any offense which, if committed or attempted in this state would have been punishable as one or more of the above mentioned offenses.	(c)	The applicant has committed an act, which, if done by a permittee under this section, would be grounds for suspension or revocation of a permit.	(d)	The applicant has committed an act involving dishonesty, fraud, or deceit with the intent to substantially benefit himself, herself, or another or substantially to injure another, or an act of violence, which act or acts are substantially related to the qualifications functions, or duties of the Massage Therapist.	(e)	The applicant has knowingly made a false, misleading, or fraudulent statement of fact to the City in the permit application process.	(f)	The applicant has not satisfied the requirements of this Code.	(e)	Operative Date &#x2013; &#xA0; All persons operating or employed as masseurs or masseuses in Massage establishments at the time this ordinance becomes effective shall obtain a Massage Therapist Permit within one year of the effective date of this ordinance.	(a)	Every massage therapist/practitioner licensed pursuant to Section 103.205.1 shall be required for renewal in 2001 and each subsequent renewal thereafter, to complete 6 contact hours of continuing education courses approved by the Board.&#xA0; Such courses shall have been completed within the 12 months preceding the date the renewal is due.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><unit></unit></prefixes><entire_prefix></entire_prefix><prefix_anchor></prefix_anchor><level>1</level></unit></text></law>
