<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><section_number>12.27.1</section_number><edition_id>1</edition_id><section_id>799</section_id><structure_id>20</structure_id><catch_line>Administrative Nuisance Abatement Proceedings.</catch_line><history></history><full_text>&#xA0; ADMINISTRATIVE NUISANCE ABATEMENT PROCEEDINGS.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 180,409, Eff. 1/18/09.)

	A.	Purpose.&#xA0; It is the intent of this section to consolidate a number of existing code provisions relating to the administrative abatement of public nuisances, and revocations, rescissions, discontinuances or modifications of discretionary zoning approvals.&#xA0; In addition, this section also sets forth procedures allowing the Director to modify or remove conditions imposed as a result of nuisance abatement proceedings; to enforce conditions imposed as part of any discretionary zoning approval; and to require that the cost of a proceeding instituted pursuant to this section be paid by those responsible for the maintenance and operation of the subject use.

	These provisions allow the City&#x2019;s zoning authorities to protect the public peace, health and safety from any land use which becomes a nuisance; adversely affects the health, peace or safety of persons residing or working in the surrounding area; or violates any land use related condition imposed pursuant to this chapter or other provision of law, while protecting the constitutional rights of the parties involved.

	B.	Authority.&#xA0; Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code to the contrary, the Director may require the modification, discontinuance or revocation of any land use or discretionary zoning approval if it is found that the land use or discretionary zoning approval as operated or maintained:

	1.	Jeopardizes or adversely affects the public health, peace, or safety of persons residing or working on the premises or in the surrounding area; or

	2.	Constitutes a public nuisance; or

	3.	Has resulted in repeated nuisance activities, including, but not limited to, disturbances of the peace, illegal drug activity, public drunkenness, drinking in public, harassment of passersby, gambling, prostitution, sale of stolen goods, public urination, theft, assaults, batteries, acts of vandalism, loitering, excessive littering, illegal parking, excessive loud noises (especially in the late night or early morning hours), traffic violations, curfew violations, lewd conduct, or police detentions and arrests; or

	4.	Adversely impacts nearby uses; or

	5.	Violates any provision of this chapter; or any other city, state, or federal regulation, ordinance, or statute; or

	6.	Violates any condition imposed by a prior discretionary land use approval including approvals granted pursuant to Sections 12.24, 12.27, 12.28, 12.32 or 14.00 of this Code; or an approval initiated by application of a property owner or owner&#x2019;s representative related to the use of land including, but not limited to, parcel map, tentative tract map, coastal development permit, development agreement, density transfer plan, exception from a specific plan, and project permit pursuant to a moratorium or an interim control ordinance.

	C.	Procedures:&#xA0; Notice, Hearings and Appeals.&#xA0; The Director shall give notice to the record owner and lessee(s) of the real property affected to appear at a public hearing at a time and place fixed by the Director and show cause why the land use or discretionary zoning approval should not be modified, discontinued, or revoked.

	1.	Notice.&#xA0; A written notice shall be mailed not less than 24 calendar days prior to the date of hearing to the owner and lessee(s) of the property involved, and to the owners of all property within and outside of the City that is within 500 feet of the exterior boundaries of the property involved, using for the purpose of notification the last known name and address of the owners, as shown in the City Clerk&#x2019;s records or in the records of the County Assessor.&#xA0; If all property within the 500-foot radius is under the same ownership as the property involved in the proceeding, then the owners of all property which adjoins that ownership shall be included in this notification.&#xA0; Written notice shall also be mailed to residential, commercial and industrial occupants of the property involved, and all property within 500 feet of the exterior boundaries of the property involved.&#xA0; This requirement can be met by mailing the notice to &#x201C;occupant&#x201D;.&#xA0; If this notice provision will not result in notice being given to at least 20 different owners of at least 20 different lots other than the subject property, then the 500-foot radius for notification shall be increased in increments of 50 feet until the required number of persons and lots are encompassed within the expanded area.&#xA0; Notification shall then be given to all property owners and occupants within the expanded area.

	Notwithstanding the above 24-calendar day notification period and the 500-foot notification radius, only 15 calendar days and a 500-foot radius shall be required for any hearing conducted on the same site for a land use or discretionary zoning approval for which a previous final decision pursuant to this section has been made by the City.

	2.	Hearing and Decision.&#xA0; The matter may be set for public hearing before the Director.&#xA0; After the conclusion of a public hearing, the Director may require the modification, discontinuance or revocation of the land use or discretionary zoning approval, as the case may be.&#xA0; As part of the action, the Director may impose conditions of operation as he or she deems appropriate, including those necessary to protect the best interests of the surrounding property or neighborhood; to eliminate, lessen, or prevent any detrimental effect on the surrounding property or neighborhood; or to assure compliance with other applicable provisions of law or conditions of an earlier discretionary approval.&#xA0; Conditions imposed may include the establishment of amortization schedules, the closure or removal of buildings or structures, and affect the establishment, maintenance, or operation of the subject use, and related land uses, buildings, or structures.

	Whenever the Director initiates an action pursuant to this section he or she shall impose a condition requiring payment of the fee set forth in Section 19.01 P. of this Code (fee condition) to cover the City&#x2019;s costs in processing the matter.&#xA0; A fee is not required if the Director finds that the operation of the land use does not create a nuisance or that the property owner, business operator or person in control, is in substantial compliance with the conditions of operation.&#xA0; The fee condition shall further provide that if the decision is not appealed, then the fee shall be paid in full to the City with confirmation of the payment being provided to the Director within 30 days of the decision date.&#xA0; If an appeal is filed and the decision of the Director is upheld on appeal, then the fee shall be paid in full with confirmation made to the Director within 30 days of the effective date of the decision.&#xA0; If the Council reverses in total the decision of the Director, then no payment of fees other than the appeal fee specified in Section 19.01 P. shall be required.

	Any determination shall be supported by written findings, including a finding that the Director&#x2019;s determination does not impair the constitutional rights of any person.&#xA0; The written determination shall also state that failure to comply with any or all conditions imposed may result in the issuance of an order to discontinue or revoke the land use or discretionary zoning approval.&#xA0; The Director may require the discontinuance or revocation of a land use or discretionary zoning approval only upon finding that:

	(a)	prior governmental efforts to cause the owner or operator to eliminate the problems associated with the land use or discretionary zoning approval have failed (examples include formal action, such as citations, orders or hearings by the Police Department, Department of Building and Safety, the Director, a Zoning Administrator, the City Planning Commission, or any other governmental agency); and

	(b)	the owner or operator has failed to demonstrate, to the satisfaction of the Director, the willingness or ability to eliminate the problems associated with the land use or discretionary zoning approval.

	If the Director discontinues or revokes any land use or discretionary zoning approval pursuant to this section, the full cost of the abatement, including the cost of inspection, shall become the personal obligation of the business operator, property owner, or person in control.&#xA0; If confirmed by the Council, a lien may be placed against the property in accordance with the procedures described in Administrative Code Sec. 7.35.3.

	3.	Compliance Review.&#xA0; Upon any finding of nuisance or non-compliance with existing conditions imposed on the land use or discretionary zoning approval, the Director&#x2019;s determination shall impose a condition requiring the business operator or property owner to file a Plan Approval application for Review of Compliance with Conditions within two years of the effective date.&#xA0; At the discretion of the Director, the due date for the Plan Approval application can be set for 90 days, 180 days, one year, 18 months or two years from the effective date of the Director&#x2019;s determination or the Council action on appeal.

	4.	Appeals.&#xA0; An appeal from the decision of the Director may be taken to the Council in the same manner as prescribed in Section 12.24 I.

	An appeal fee shall be charged pursuant to Section 19.01 P.&#xA0; The Council&#x2019;s decision on appeal shall be processed in the manner prescribed in Section 12.24 I.6.&#xA0;

	Further, if it is determined by the Council that the decision of the Director impairs the constitutional rights of any person, then it shall modify the action accordingly, or refer the matter back to the Director for further action.

	5.	Violations.&#xA0; It shall be unlawful to violate or fail to comply with any requirement or condition imposed by the Director or the Council pursuant to this section.&#xA0; Violation or failure to comply shall constitute a violation of this chapter and shall be subject to the same penalties as any other violation of this chapter. In the event of a violation of an order to discontinue or revoke a land use or discretionary zoning approval pursuant to this section, the Department of Building and Safety shall order the owner to vacate and secure the property, premises, buildings or portion of any property, premises or building pursuant to Section 91.9003 of this Code.&#xA0; The Department of Building and Safety shall institute enforcement as provided in Section 91.9003.3 of this Code.&#xA0; The Director shall cause the determination or revocation to be recorded.

	D.	Residential Uses.&#xA0; This subsection shall apply to all single-family and multi-family residential uses, including residential hotels as defined in Section 47.73 T. of this Code.&#xA0; This subsection shall not apply to hotels or motels that are not residential hotels. Nothing in this section or Section 91.9001 et seq. of this Code is intended to supersede or abrogate the rights of tenants provided by State statute or by the Los Angeles Housing Code and Rent Stabilization Ordinance, or by any other provision of this Code.

	1.	The Director, as the initial decision maker, or the Council on appeal, shall ask the City Attorney to initiate the process of having the residential use placed in receivership pursuant to California Civil Code Section 3479 and Code of Civil Procedure Section 564(b)(9), upon finding that:

	(a)	prior governmental efforts to cause the owner or operator to eliminate the problems associated with the land use or discretionary zoning approval have failed (examples include formal action, such as citations, orders or hearings by the Police Department, Department of Building and Safety, the Director, a Zoning Administrator, the City Planning Commission, or any other governmental agency); and

	(b)	that the owner or operator has failed to demonstrate, to the satisfaction of the Director, the willingness or ability to eliminate the problems associated with the land use or discretionary zoning approval.

	2.	If the residential use is not placed in receivership and the Director, as the initial decision maker, or the Council on appeal, discontinues or revokes the land use or discretionary zoning approval, resulting in the displacement of tenants then the following provisions shall apply:

	(a)	The Housing Department shall identify each tenant who was displaced and is eligible for relocation assistance, and shall issue an order requiring the owner to pay relocation benefits in the amounts specified in Section 151.09 G. of this Code.

	(b)	If the owner fails to pay relocation benefits to an eligible tenant as required by this subsection, the Housing Department may advance relocation benefits to the tenant in the amount set forth in Section 151.09 G. of this Code.

	(c)	If the owner fails to comply with an order of the Housing Department to pay relocation benefits, the owner shall be liable to the City for any relocation payments advanced, and the Housing Department may obtain a lien upon the property pursuant to Los Angeles Administrative Code Section 7.35.3 to recover the amount advanced and associated costs.

	(d)	Relocation benefits shall not be payable to any tenant who has caused or substantially contributed to the condition giving rise to an order to vacate issued pursuant to Section 91.9003.1 of this Code.&#xA0; The Director shall determine whether a tenant has caused or substantially contributed to the condition giving rise to the order to vacate.

	(e)	The Housing Department shall inform each eligible tenant of his/her right to re-rental of the same unit, or comparable unit, if the owner, or subsequent owner, re-establishes the residential use.&#xA0; The Housing Department shall inform the eligible tenant that he/she must advise the owner in writing of his/her interest in re-renting and must provide the owner with an address to which the owner can direct an offer.

	(f)	When the residential use is re-established, the accommodations shall be offered, and rented or leased at the lawful rent in effect at the time the residential use was discontinued or revoked, plus annual adjustments available under Section 151.06 of this Code.

	(g)	The Director&#x2019;s determination or the Council&#x2019;s action shall include the provisions of this subsection and shall be recorded by the Director as a covenant with the Office of the County Recorder.

	E.	Modification of Administrative Decisions.&#xA0; Any administrative nuisance abatement decision made pursuant to this chapter, any conditions imposed by that decision, or any decisions on a discretionary zoning approval pursuant to this section may be modified pursuant to the provisions of this subsection.&#xA0; Upon application by the business operator, property owner or lessee(s), the Director may modify or eliminate the conditions of a prior decision.&#xA0; An application shall be made on official forms provided by the Department of Planning and shall be accompanied by a filing fee as specified in Section 19.01 P.

	An application may be considered if a time period of at least one year has passed from the date the conditions were originally imposed; or if there have been substantial changes in the nature and operation of the land use or discretionary zoning approval; or if there has been a change in circumstances such that the continued enforcement of the previously imposed conditions is no longer reasonable or necessary.&#xA0; All applications shall include a radius map, a list of property owners and occupants within 500 feet, and plot plan drawn to scale.

	An application shall be set for public hearing.&#xA0; The Director may grant or deny the requested application, or modify the prior decision, including imposing new or different substitute conditions as the Director deems appropriate.&#xA0; No modification shall be approved pursuant to this subsection unless the Director finds each of the following:

	1.	That the requirements for consideration of the application under this subsection have been met; and

	2.	That due consideration has been given to the effects of the modification on surrounding properties.

	An appeal from the decision of the Director may be taken to the Council in the same manner as prescribed in Subsection C. of this section.

	When the Director orders the discontinuance or revocation of a land use or discretionary zoning approval and the applicant files for re-instatement of the land use pursuant to this subsection, the Director may re-instate the land use if all findings of this subsection are met.&#xA0; The applicant will not be issued a new certificate of occupancy.

	Subsequent applications for reconsideration may be filed in accordance with this subsection.&#xA0; If the application is denied with prejudice, a subsequent application for reconsideration shall not be filed within one year from the reconsideration decision date, and then only if a property owner, business operator or lessee(s) shows that the circumstances involving the land use or discretionary zoning approval have substantially and materially changed since the last reconsideration.

	F.	Continuation of Prior Decisions.&#xA0; Prior administrative nuisance abatement decisions regarding land uses and discontinuances, revocations, rescissions or modifications of discretionary zoning approvals made by the Zoning Administrator, City Planning Commission or the Council shall remain in full force and effect.&#xA0; Further, it shall continue to be unlawful to violate or fail to comply with any prior requirement or condition imposed by the Zoning Administrator, the former Board of Zoning Appeals, the City Planning Commission, or the Council.&#xA0; Violation or failure to comply shall constitute a violation of this chapter and shall be subject to the same penalties as any other violation of this chapter.&#xA0; In the event of a violation of an order of discontinuance or revocation, the Department of Building and Safety shall order the business operator, property owner or lessee(s) to vacate and secure the property, premises, buildings or portion thereof pursuant to Section 91.9003 of this Code.&#xA0; The Department of Building and Safety shall institute enforcement as provided in LAMC Sec. 91.9003.4 of this Code.</full_text><order_by>27.1</order_by><ancestry><unit id="20" label="article"><name>Specific Planning &#x2013; Zoning
Comprehensive Zoning Plan</name><identifier>2</identifier><url>/1/2/</url></unit><unit id="7" label="chapter"><name>General Provisions and Zoning</name><identifier>1</identifier><url>/1/</url></unit></ancestry><structure_contents><unit id="3095"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.00</section_number><catch_line>Title.</catch_line><url>/12.00/</url><token>12.00</token></unit><unit id="1517"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.01</section_number><catch_line>Continuation Of Existing Regulations.</catch_line><url>/12.01/</url><token>12.01</token></unit><unit id="1627"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.02</section_number><catch_line>Purpose.</catch_line><url>/12.02/</url><token>12.02</token></unit><unit id="2312"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.03</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/12.03/</url><token>12.03</token></unit><unit id="3734"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.04</section_number><catch_line>Zones - Districts - Symbols.</catch_line><url>/12.04/</url><token>12.04</token></unit><unit id="1459"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.04.01</section_number><catch_line>Violations Of Specific Plans.</catch_line><url>/12.04.01/</url><token>12.04.01</token></unit><unit id="1812"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.04.05</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;Os&#x201D; Open Space Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.04.05/</url><token>12.04.05</token></unit><unit id="4037"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.04.09</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;Pf&#x201D; Public Facilities Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.04.09/</url><token>12.04.09</token></unit><unit id="3058"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.05</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;A1&#x201D; Agriculture Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.05/</url><token>12.05</token></unit><unit id="1807"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.06</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;A2&#x201D; Agricultural Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.06/</url><token>12.06</token></unit><unit id="2434"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.07</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;Ra&#x201D; Suburban Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.07/</url><token>12.07</token></unit><unit id="833"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.07.01</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;Re&#x201D; Residential Estate Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.07.01/</url><token>12.07.01</token></unit><unit id="3662"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.07.1</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;Rs&#x201D; Suburban Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.07.1/</url><token>12.07.1</token></unit><unit id="1550"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.08</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;R1&#x201D; One-Family Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.08/</url><token>12.08</token></unit><unit id="1455"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.08.1</section_number><catch_line>Ru Residential Urban Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.08.1/</url><token>12.08.1</token></unit><unit id="1635"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.08.3</section_number><catch_line>Rz Residential Zero Side Yard Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.08.3/</url><token>12.08.3</token></unit><unit id="504"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.08.5</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;Rw1&#x201D; Residential Waterways Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.08.5/</url><token>12.08.5</token></unit><unit id="2976"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.09</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;R2&#x201D; Two-Family Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.09/</url><token>12.09</token></unit><unit id="3015"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.09.1</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;Rd&#x201D; Restricted Density Multiple Dwelling Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.09.1/</url><token>12.09.1</token></unit><unit id="3789"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.09.3</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;Rmp&#x201D; Mobilehome Park Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.09.3/</url><token>12.09.3</token></unit><unit id="3264"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.09.5</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;Rw2&#x201D; Residential Waterways Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.09.5/</url><token>12.09.5</token></unit><unit id="1735"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.10</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;R3&#x201D; Multiple Dwelling Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.10/</url><token>12.10</token></unit><unit id="2343"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.10.5</section_number><catch_line>Ras3 Residential/Accessory Services Zone Purpose Statement.</catch_line><url>/12.10.5/</url><token>12.10.5</token></unit><unit id="621"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.11</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;R4&#x201D; Multiple Dwelling Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.11/</url><token>12.11</token></unit><unit id="1231"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.11.5</section_number><catch_line>Ras4 Residential/Accessory Services Zone Purpose Statement.</catch_line><url>/12.11.5/</url><token>12.11.5</token></unit><unit id="1666"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.12</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;R5&#x201D; Multiple Dwelling Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.12/</url><token>12.12</token></unit><unit id="601"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.12.1</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;P&#x201D; Automobile Parking Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.12.1/</url><token>12.12.1</token></unit><unit id="286"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.12.1.5</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;Pb&#x201D; Parking Building Zone.*</catch_line><url>/12.12.1.5/</url><token>12.12.1.5</token></unit><unit id="2454"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.12.2</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;Cr&#x201D; Limited Commercial Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.12.2/</url><token>12.12.2</token></unit><unit id="3444"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.13</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;C1&#x201D; Limited Commercial Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.13/</url><token>12.13</token></unit><unit id="2973"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.13.5</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;C1.5&#x201D; Limited Commercial Zone</catch_line><url>/12.13.5/</url><token>12.13.5</token></unit><unit id="156"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.14</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;C2&#x201D; Commercial Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.14/</url><token>12.14</token></unit><unit id="1739"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.16</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;C4&#x201D;Commercial Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.16/</url><token>12.16</token></unit><unit id="24"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.16.1</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;Cw&#x201D; Central City West Specific Plan Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.16.1/</url><token>12.16.1</token></unit><unit id="1075"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.16.2</section_number><catch_line>Adp Alameda District Specific Plan Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.16.2/</url><token>12.16.2</token></unit><unit id="265"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.16.3</section_number><catch_line>Lased Los Angeles Sports And Entertainment District Specific Plan Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.16.3/</url><token>12.16.3</token></unit><unit id="1579"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.17</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;C5&#x201D; Commercial Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.17/</url><token>12.17</token></unit><unit id="2695"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.17.1</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;Cm&#x201D; Commercial Manufacturing Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.17.1/</url><token>12.17.1</token></unit><unit id="2925"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.17.2</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;Cm(Gm)&#x201D;Commercial Manufacturing (Glencoe/Maxella) Specific Plan Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.17.2/</url><token>12.17.2</token></unit><unit id="1704"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.17.5</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;Mr1&#x201D; Restricted Industrial Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.17.5/</url><token>12.17.5</token></unit><unit id="383"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.17.5.5</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;Ccs&#x201D; Century City South Specific Plan Studio Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.17.5.5/</url><token>12.17.5.5</token></unit><unit id="1032"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.17.6</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;M1&#x201D; Limited Industrial Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.17.6/</url><token>12.17.6</token></unit><unit id="65"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.18</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;Mr2&#x201D; Restricted Light Industrial Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.18/</url><token>12.18</token></unit><unit id="2426"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.18.1</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;Wc&#x201D; Warner Center Specific Plan Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.18.1/</url><token>12.18.1</token></unit><unit id="1290"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.19</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;M2&#x201D; Light Industrial Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.19/</url><token>12.19</token></unit><unit id="1435"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.19.1</section_number><catch_line>Lax Los Angeles International Airport Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.19.1/</url><token>12.19.1</token></unit><unit id="3523"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.20</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;M3&#x201D; Heavy Industrial Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.20/</url><token>12.20</token></unit><unit id="3019"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.20.1</section_number><catch_line>Sl Ocean &#x2013; Submerged Land Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.20.1/</url><token>12.20.1</token></unit><unit id="3360"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.20.2</section_number><catch_line>Coastal Development Permits (Prior To Certification Of The Local Coastal Program.)</catch_line><url>/12.20.2/</url><token>12.20.2</token></unit><unit id="2874"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.20.2.1</section_number><catch_line>Coastal Development Permit Procedures After Certification Of The Local Coastal Program.</catch_line><url>/12.20.2.1/</url><token>12.20.2.1</token></unit><unit id="2479"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.20.3</section_number><catch_line>&#x201C;Hp&#x201D; Historic Preservation Overlay Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.20.3/</url><token>12.20.3</token></unit><unit id="3236"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.21.1</section_number><catch_line>Height Of Building Or Structures.</catch_line><url>/12.21.1/</url><token>12.21.1</token></unit><unit id="488"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.21.2</section_number><catch_line>Height Of Buildings Or Structures In Century City.</catch_line><url>/12.21.2/</url><token>12.21.2</token></unit><unit id="2253"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.21.3</section_number><catch_line>Height Of Buildings Or Structures In Community Redevelopment Plan Areas.</catch_line><url>/12.21.3/</url><token>12.21.3</token></unit><unit id="3709"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.21.4</section_number><catch_line>Height Of Buildings Or Structures In Enterprise Zones.</catch_line><url>/12.21.4/</url><token>12.21.4</token></unit><unit id="605"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.21.5</section_number><catch_line>Height Of Buildings Or Structures In Centers Study Areas.</catch_line><url>/12.21.5/</url><token>12.21.5</token></unit><unit id="1399"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.22</section_number><catch_line>Exceptions.</catch_line><url>/12.22/</url><token>12.22</token></unit><unit id="2993"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.22.1</section_number><catch_line>Safer Sex.</catch_line><url>/12.22.1/</url><token>12.22.1</token></unit><unit id="3237"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.23</section_number><catch_line>Nonconforming Building And Uses.</catch_line><url>/12.23/</url><token>12.23</token></unit><unit id="1191"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.24</section_number><catch_line>Conditional Use Permits And Other Similar Quasi-Judicial Approvals.</catch_line><url>/12.24/</url><token>12.24</token></unit><unit id="546"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.24.1</section_number><catch_line>Land Use Determination By City Planning Commission.</catch_line><url>/12.24.1/</url><token>12.24.1</token></unit><unit id="1889"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.25</section_number><catch_line>Time Limitations.</catch_line><url>/12.25/</url><token>12.25</token></unit><unit id="2902"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.26</section_number><catch_line>Department Of Building And Safety.</catch_line><url>/12.26/</url><token>12.26</token></unit><unit id="2923"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.27</section_number><catch_line>Variances.</catch_line><url>/12.27/</url><token>12.27</token></unit><unit id="799"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.27.1</section_number><catch_line>Administrative Nuisance Abatement Proceedings.</catch_line><url>/12.27.1/</url><token>12.27.1</token></unit><unit id="4040"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.28</section_number><catch_line>Adjustments And Slight Modifications.</catch_line><url>/12.28/</url><token>12.28</token></unit><unit id="2103"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.29</section_number><catch_line>Violation Of Conditions &#x2013; Penalty.</catch_line><url>/12.29/</url><token>12.29</token></unit><unit id="339"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.30</section_number><catch_line>Boundaries Of Zones.</catch_line><url>/12.30/</url><token>12.30</token></unit><unit id="1073"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.31</section_number><catch_line>Interpretation &#x2013; Purpose &#x2013; Conflict.</catch_line><url>/12.31/</url><token>12.31</token></unit><unit id="3171"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.32</section_number><catch_line>Land Use Legislative Actions.</catch_line><url>/12.32/</url><token>12.32</token></unit><unit id="511"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.33</section_number><catch_line>Dedication Of Land Or Payment For Park And Recreational Facilities As A Requirement For A Zone Change For A Multiple Residential Use In Any Multiple Residential Or Commercial Zone.</catch_line><url>/12.33/</url><token>12.33</token></unit><unit id="1730"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.34</section_number><catch_line>Application Of Provisions.</catch_line><url>/12.34/</url><token>12.34</token></unit><unit id="3843"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.35</section_number><catch_line>Zoning Of Annexed Or Unzoned Areas.</catch_line><url>/12.35/</url><token>12.35</token></unit><unit id="1352"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.36</section_number><catch_line>Projects Requiring Multiple Approvals.(Charter &#xA7; 564).</catch_line><url>/12.36/</url><token>12.36</token></unit><unit id="1765"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.37</section_number><catch_line>Highway And Collector Street Dedication And Improvement.</catch_line><url>/12.37/</url><token>12.37</token></unit><unit id="2301"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.38</section_number><catch_line>Dedication Of Streets By Long Term Leases.</catch_line><url>/12.38/</url><token>12.38</token></unit><unit id="2657"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.39</section_number><catch_line>Low And Moderate Housing.</catch_line><url>/12.39/</url><token>12.39</token></unit><unit id="1295"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.40</section_number><catch_line>Landscape - General Requirements.</catch_line><url>/12.40/</url><token>12.40</token></unit><unit id="2364"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.41</section_number><catch_line>Landscape - Water Management.</catch_line><url>/12.41/</url><token>12.41</token></unit><unit id="2169"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.42</section_number><catch_line>Landscape.</catch_line><url>/12.42/</url><token>12.42</token></unit><unit id="4030"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.43</section_number><catch_line>Source Reduction Of Waste.</catch_line><url>/12.43/</url><token>12.43</token></unit><unit id="1485"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.50</section_number><catch_line>Airport Approach Zoning Regulations.</catch_line><url>/12.50/</url><token>12.50</token></unit><unit id="1328"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.70</section_number><catch_line>Adult Entertainment Zoning.</catch_line><url>/12.70/</url><token>12.70</token></unit><unit id="481"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.80</section_number><catch_line>Homeless Shelters - Emergencies - Government Owned And Leased Property.</catch_line><url>/12.80/</url><token>12.80</token></unit><unit id="737"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.81</section_number><catch_line>Homeless Shelters - Emergencies - Charitable
Organizations.</catch_line><url>/12.81/</url><token>12.81</token></unit></structure_contents><next_section id="4040"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.28</section_number><catch_line>Adjustments And Slight Modifications.</catch_line><url>/12.28/</url><token>12.28</token></next_section><metadata></metadata><references></references><url>/12.27.1/</url><token>12.27.1</token><formats><txt>/12.27.1.txt</txt><json>/12.27.1.xml</json></formats><dublin_core><Title>Administrative Nuisance Abatement Proceedings.</Title><Type>Text</Type><Format>text/html</Format><Identifier>&#xA7; 12.27.1</Identifier><Relation>Los Angeles Municipal Code</Relation></dublin_core><plain_text>                            LOS ANGELES MUNICIPAL CODE

ADMINISTRATIVE NUISANCE ABATEMENT PROCEEDINGS. (&#xA7; 12.27.1)

&#xA0; ADMINISTRATIVE NUISANCE ABATEMENT PROCEEDINGS.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 180,409, Eff. 1/18/09.)	A.	Purpose.&#xA0; It is the intent of
this section to consolidate a number of existing code provisions relating to the
administrative abatement of public nuisances, and revocations, rescissions,
discontinuances or modifications of discretionary zoning approvals.&#xA0; In
addition, this section also sets forth procedures allowing the Director to
modify or remove conditions imposed as a result of nuisance abatement
proceedings; to enforce conditions imposed as part of any discretionary zoning
approval; and to require that the cost of a proceeding instituted pursuant to
this section be paid by those responsible for the maintenance and operation of
the subject use.	These provisions allow the City&#x2019;s zoning authorities to
protect the public peace, health and safety from any land use which becomes a
nuisance; adversely affects the health, peace or safety of persons residing or
working in the surrounding area; or violates any land use related condition
imposed pursuant to this chapter or other provision of law, while protecting the
constitutional rights of the parties involved.	B.	Authority.&#xA0; Notwithstanding
any other provision of this Code to the contrary, the Director may require the
modification, discontinuance or revocation of any land use or discretionary
zoning approval if it is found that the land use or discretionary zoning
approval as operated or maintained:	1.	Jeopardizes or adversely affects the
public health, peace, or safety of persons residing or working on the premises
or in the surrounding area; or	2.	Constitutes a public nuisance; or	3.	Has
resulted in repeated nuisance activities, including, but not limited to,
disturbances of the peace, illegal drug activity, public drunkenness, drinking
in public, harassment of passersby, gambling, prostitution, sale of stolen
goods, public urination, theft, assaults, batteries, acts of vandalism,
loitering, excessive littering, illegal parking, excessive loud noises
(especially in the late night or early morning hours), traffic violations,
curfew violations, lewd conduct, or police detentions and arrests;
or	4.	Adversely impacts nearby uses; or	5.	Violates any provision of this
chapter; or any other city, state, or federal regulation, ordinance, or statute;
or	6.	Violates any condition imposed by a prior discretionary land use approval
including approvals granted pursuant to Sections 12.24, 12.27, 12.28, 12.32 or
14.00 of this Code; or an approval initiated by application of a property owner
or owner&#x2019;s representative related to the use of land including, but not
limited to, parcel map, tentative tract map, coastal development permit,
development agreement, density transfer plan, exception from a specific plan,
and project permit pursuant to a moratorium or an interim control
ordinance.	C.	Procedures:&#xA0; Notice, Hearings and Appeals.&#xA0; The Director shall
give notice to the record owner and lessee(s) of the real property affected to
appear at a public hearing at a time and place fixed by the Director and show
cause why the land use or discretionary zoning approval should not be modified,
discontinued, or revoked.	1.	Notice.&#xA0; A written notice shall be mailed not less
than 24 calendar days prior to the date of hearing to the owner and lessee(s) of
the property involved, and to the owners of all property within and outside of
the City that is within 500 feet of the exterior boundaries of the property
involved, using for the purpose of notification the last known name and address
of the owners, as shown in the City Clerk&#x2019;s records or in the records of the
County Assessor.&#xA0; If all property within the 500-foot radius is under the same
ownership as the property involved in the proceeding, then the owners of all
property which adjoins that ownership shall be included in this notification.&#xA0;
Written notice shall also be mailed to residential, commercial and industrial
occupants of the property involved, and all property within 500 feet of the
exterior boundaries of the property involved.&#xA0; This requirement can be met by
mailing the notice to &#x201C;occupant&#x201D;.&#xA0; If this notice provision will not result
in notice being given to at least 20 different owners of at least 20 different
lots other than the subject property, then the 500-foot radius for notification
shall be increased in increments of 50 feet until the required number of persons
and lots are encompassed within the expanded area.&#xA0; Notification shall then be
given to all property owners and occupants within the expanded
area.	Notwithstanding the above 24-calendar day notification period and the
500-foot notification radius, only 15 calendar days and a 500-foot radius shall
be required for any hearing conducted on the same site for a land use or
discretionary zoning approval for which a previous final decision pursuant to
this section has been made by the City.	2.	Hearing and Decision.&#xA0; The matter
may be set for public hearing before the Director.&#xA0; After the conclusion of a
public hearing, the Director may require the modification, discontinuance or
revocation of the land use or discretionary zoning approval, as the case may
be.&#xA0; As part of the action, the Director may impose conditions of operation as
he or she deems appropriate, including those necessary to protect the best
interests of the surrounding property or neighborhood; to eliminate, lessen, or
prevent any detrimental effect on the surrounding property or neighborhood; or
to assure compliance with other applicable provisions of law or conditions of an
earlier discretionary approval.&#xA0; Conditions imposed may include the
establishment of amortization schedules, the closure or removal of buildings or
structures, and affect the establishment, maintenance, or operation of the
subject use, and related land uses, buildings, or structures.	Whenever the
Director initiates an action pursuant to this section he or she shall impose a
condition requiring payment of the fee set forth in Section 19.01 P. of this
Code (fee condition) to cover the City&#x2019;s costs in processing the matter.&#xA0; A
fee is not required if the Director finds that the operation of the land use
does not create a nuisance or that the property owner, business operator or
person in control, is in substantial compliance with the conditions of
operation.&#xA0; The fee condition shall further provide that if the decision is not
appealed, then the fee shall be paid in full to the City with confirmation of
the payment being provided to the Director within 30 days of the decision
date.&#xA0; If an appeal is filed and the decision of the Director is upheld on
appeal, then the fee shall be paid in full with confirmation made to the
Director within 30 days of the effective date of the decision.&#xA0; If the Council
reverses in total the decision of the Director, then no payment of fees other
than the appeal fee specified in Section 19.01 P. shall be required.	Any
determination shall be supported by written findings, including a finding that
the Director&#x2019;s determination does not impair the constitutional rights of any
person.&#xA0; The written determination shall also state that failure to comply with
any or all conditions imposed may result in the issuance of an order to
discontinue or revoke the land use or discretionary zoning approval.&#xA0; The
Director may require the discontinuance or revocation of a land use or
discretionary zoning approval only upon finding that:	(a)	prior governmental
efforts to cause the owner or operator to eliminate the problems associated with
the land use or discretionary zoning approval have failed (examples include
formal action, such as citations, orders or hearings by the Police Department,
Department of Building and Safety, the Director, a Zoning Administrator, the
City Planning Commission, or any other governmental agency); and	(b)	the owner
or operator has failed to demonstrate, to the satisfaction of the Director, the
willingness or ability to eliminate the problems associated with the land use or
discretionary zoning approval.	If the Director discontinues or revokes any land
use or discretionary zoning approval pursuant to this section, the full cost of
the abatement, including the cost of inspection, shall become the personal
obligation of the business operator, property owner, or person in control.&#xA0; If
confirmed by the Council, a lien may be placed against the property in
accordance with the procedures described in Administrative Code Sec.
7.35.3.	3.	Compliance Review.&#xA0; Upon any finding of nuisance or non-compliance
with existing conditions imposed on the land use or discretionary zoning
approval, the Director&#x2019;s determination shall impose a condition requiring the
business operator or property owner to file a Plan Approval application for
Review of Compliance with Conditions within two years of the effective date.&#xA0;
At the discretion of the Director, the due date for the Plan Approval
application can be set for 90 days, 180 days, one year, 18 months or two years
from the effective date of the Director&#x2019;s determination or the Council action
on appeal.	4.	Appeals.&#xA0; An appeal from the decision of the Director may be
taken to the Council in the same manner as prescribed in Section 12.24 I.	An
appeal fee shall be charged pursuant to Section 19.01 P.&#xA0; The Council&#x2019;s
decision on appeal shall be processed in the manner prescribed in Section 12.24
I.6.&#xA0;	Further, if it is determined by the Council that the decision of the
Director impairs the constitutional rights of any person, then it shall modify
the action accordingly, or refer the matter back to the Director for further
action.	5.	Violations.&#xA0; It shall be unlawful to violate or fail to comply with
any requirement or condition imposed by the Director or the Council pursuant to
this section.&#xA0; Violation or failure to comply shall constitute a violation of
this chapter and shall be subject to the same penalties as any other violation
of this chapter. In the event of a violation of an order to discontinue or
revoke a land use or discretionary zoning approval pursuant to this section, the
Department of Building and Safety shall order the owner to vacate and secure the
property, premises, buildings or portion of any property, premises or building
pursuant to Section 91.9003 of this Code.&#xA0; The Department of Building and
Safety shall institute enforcement as provided in Section 91.9003.3 of this
Code.&#xA0; The Director shall cause the determination or revocation to be
recorded.	D.	Residential Uses.&#xA0; This subsection shall apply to all
single-family and multi-family residential uses, including residential hotels as
defined in Section 47.73 T. of this Code.&#xA0; This subsection shall not apply to
hotels or motels that are not residential hotels. Nothing in this section or
Section 91.9001 et seq. of this Code is intended to supersede or abrogate the
rights of tenants provided by State statute or by the Los Angeles Housing Code
and Rent Stabilization Ordinance, or by any other provision of this Code.	1.	The
Director, as the initial decision maker, or the Council on appeal, shall ask the
City Attorney to initiate the process of having the residential use placed in
receivership pursuant to California Civil Code Section 3479 and Code of Civil
Procedure Section 564(b)(9), upon finding that:	(a)	prior governmental efforts
to cause the owner or operator to eliminate the problems associated with the
land use or discretionary zoning approval have failed (examples include formal
action, such as citations, orders or hearings by the Police Department,
Department of Building and Safety, the Director, a Zoning Administrator, the
City Planning Commission, or any other governmental agency); and	(b)	that the
owner or operator has failed to demonstrate, to the satisfaction of the
Director, the willingness or ability to eliminate the problems associated with
the land use or discretionary zoning approval.	2.	If the residential use is not
placed in receivership and the Director, as the initial decision maker, or the
Council on appeal, discontinues or revokes the land use or discretionary zoning
approval, resulting in the displacement of tenants then the following provisions
shall apply:	(a)	The Housing Department shall identify each tenant who was
displaced and is eligible for relocation assistance, and shall issue an order
requiring the owner to pay relocation benefits in the amounts specified in
Section 151.09 G. of this Code.	(b)	If the owner fails to pay relocation
benefits to an eligible tenant as required by this subsection, the Housing
Department may advance relocation benefits to the tenant in the amount set forth
in Section 151.09 G. of this Code.	(c)	If the owner fails to comply with an
order of the Housing Department to pay relocation benefits, the owner shall be
liable to the City for any relocation payments advanced, and the Housing
Department may obtain a lien upon the property pursuant to Los Angeles
Administrative Code Section 7.35.3 to recover the amount advanced and associated
costs.	(d)	Relocation benefits shall not be payable to any tenant who has caused
or substantially contributed to the condition giving rise to an order to vacate
issued pursuant to Section 91.9003.1 of this Code.&#xA0; The Director shall
determine whether a tenant has caused or substantially contributed to the
condition giving rise to the order to vacate.	(e)	The Housing Department shall
inform each eligible tenant of his/her right to re-rental of the same unit, or
comparable unit, if the owner, or subsequent owner, re-establishes the
residential use.&#xA0; The Housing Department shall inform the eligible tenant that
he/she must advise the owner in writing of his/her interest in re-renting and
must provide the owner with an address to which the owner can direct an
offer.	(f)	When the residential use is re-established, the accommodations shall
be offered, and rented or leased at the lawful rent in effect at the time the
residential use was discontinued or revoked, plus annual adjustments available
under Section 151.06 of this Code.	(g)	The Director&#x2019;s determination or the
Council&#x2019;s action shall include the provisions of this subsection and shall be
recorded by the Director as a covenant with the Office of the County
Recorder.	E.	Modification of Administrative Decisions.&#xA0; Any administrative
nuisance abatement decision made pursuant to this chapter, any conditions
imposed by that decision, or any decisions on a discretionary zoning approval
pursuant to this section may be modified pursuant to the provisions of this
subsection.&#xA0; Upon application by the business operator, property owner or
lessee(s), the Director may modify or eliminate the conditions of a prior
decision.&#xA0; An application shall be made on official forms provided by the
Department of Planning and shall be accompanied by a filing fee as specified in
Section 19.01 P.	An application may be considered if a time period of at least
one year has passed from the date the conditions were originally imposed; or if
there have been substantial changes in the nature and operation of the land use
or discretionary zoning approval; or if there has been a change in circumstances
such that the continued enforcement of the previously imposed conditions is no
longer reasonable or necessary.&#xA0; All applications shall include a radius map, a
list of property owners and occupants within 500 feet, and plot plan drawn to
scale.	An application shall be set for public hearing.&#xA0; The Director may grant
or deny the requested application, or modify the prior decision, including
imposing new or different substitute conditions as the Director deems
appropriate.&#xA0; No modification shall be approved pursuant to this subsection
unless the Director finds each of the following:	1.	That the requirements for
consideration of the application under this subsection have been met;
and	2.	That due consideration has been given to the effects of the modification
on surrounding properties.	An appeal from the decision of the Director may be
taken to the Council in the same manner as prescribed in Subsection C. of this
section.	When the Director orders the discontinuance or revocation of a land use
or discretionary zoning approval and the applicant files for re-instatement of
the land use pursuant to this subsection, the Director may re-instate the land
use if all findings of this subsection are met.&#xA0; The applicant will not be
issued a new certificate of occupancy.	Subsequent applications for
reconsideration may be filed in accordance with this subsection.&#xA0; If the
application is denied with prejudice, a subsequent application for
reconsideration shall not be filed within one year from the reconsideration
decision date, and then only if a property owner, business operator or lessee(s)
shows that the circumstances involving the land use or discretionary zoning
approval have substantially and materially changed since the last
reconsideration.	F.	Continuation of Prior Decisions.&#xA0; Prior administrative
nuisance abatement decisions regarding land uses and discontinuances,
revocations, rescissions or modifications of discretionary zoning approvals made
by the Zoning Administrator, City Planning Commission or the Council shall
remain in full force and effect.&#xA0; Further, it shall continue to be unlawful to
violate or fail to comply with any prior requirement or condition imposed by the
Zoning Administrator, the former Board of Zoning Appeals, the City Planning
Commission, or the Council.&#xA0; Violation or failure to comply shall constitute a
violation of this chapter and shall be subject to the same penalties as any
other violation of this chapter.&#xA0; In the event of a violation of an order of
discontinuance or revocation, the Department of Building and Safety shall order
the business operator, property owner or lessee(s) to vacate and secure the
property, premises, buildings or portion thereof pursuant to Section 91.9003 of
this Code.&#xA0; The Department of Building and Safety shall institute enforcement
as provided in LAMC Sec. 91.9003.4 of this Code.
</plain_text><html>
					&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#xA0; ADMINISTRATIVE NUISANCE ABATEMENT PROCEEDINGS.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 180,409, Eff. 1/18/09.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	A.	Purpose.&#xA0; It is the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;intent&lt;/span&gt; of this section to consolidate a number of existing code provisions relating to the administrative abatement of public nuisances, and &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;revocations&lt;/span&gt;, rescissions, discontinuances or modifications of discretionary zoning approvals.&#xA0; In addition, this section also sets forth procedures allowing the Director to modify or remove conditions imposed as a result of nuisance abatement proceedings; to enforce conditions imposed as part of any discretionary zoning approval; and to require that the cost of a proceeding instituted pursuant to this section be paid by those responsible for the maintenance and operation of the subject use.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	These provisions allow the City&#x2019;s zoning authorities to protect the public peace, health and safety from any land use which becomes a nuisance; adversely affects the health, peace or safety of persons residing or working in the surrounding area; or violates any land use related condition imposed pursuant to this chapter or other provision of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;law&lt;/span&gt;, while protecting the constitutional rights of the parties involved.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	B.	Authority.&#xA0; Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code to the contrary, the Director may require the modification, discontinuance or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;revocation&lt;/span&gt; of any land use or discretionary zoning approval if it is found that the land use or discretionary zoning approval as operated or maintained:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	Jeopardizes or adversely affects the public health, peace, or safety of persons residing or working on the premises or in the surrounding area; or&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	Constitutes a public nuisance; or&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	Has resulted in repeated nuisance activities, including, but not limited to, disturbances of the peace, illegal drug activity, public drunkenness, drinking in public, harassment of passersby, gambling, prostitution, sale of stolen goods, public urination, theft, &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;assaults&lt;/span&gt;, batteries, acts of vandalism, loitering, excessive littering, illegal parking, excessive loud noises (especially in the late night or early morning hours), traffic violations, curfew violations, lewd conduct, or police detentions and &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;arrests&lt;/span&gt;; or&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	4.	Adversely impacts nearby uses; or&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	5.	Violates any provision of this chapter; or any other city, state, or federal regulation, &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt;, or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;statute&lt;/span&gt;; or&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	6.	Violates any condition imposed by a prior discretionary land use approval including approvals granted pursuant to Sections 12.24, 12.27, 12.28, 12.32 or 14.00 of this Code; or an approval initiated by application of a property owner or owner&#x2019;s representative related to the use of land including, but not limited to, parcel map, tentative tract map, coastal development permit, development agreement, density transfer plan, exception from a specific plan, and project permit pursuant to a moratorium or an interim control &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	C.	Procedures:&#xA0; Notice, &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Hearings&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Appeals&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; The Director shall give notice to the record owner and lessee(s) of the real property affected to appear at a public &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; at a time and place fixed by the Director and show cause why the land use or discretionary zoning approval should not be modified, discontinued, or revoked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	Notice.&#xA0; A written notice shall be mailed not less than 24 calendar days prior to the date of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; to the owner and lessee(s) of the property involved, and to the owners of all property within and outside of the City that is within 500 feet of the exterior boundaries of the property involved, using for the purpose of notification the last known name and address of the owners, as shown in the City Clerk&#x2019;s records or in the records of the County Assessor.&#xA0; If all property within the 500-foot radius is under the same ownership as the property involved in the proceeding, then the owners of all property which adjoins that ownership shall be included in this notification.&#xA0; Written notice shall also be mailed to residential, commercial and industrial occupants of the property involved, and all property within 500 feet of the exterior boundaries of the property involved.&#xA0; This requirement can be met by mailing the notice to &#x201C;occupant&#x201D;.&#xA0; If this notice provision will not result in notice being given to at least 20 different owners of at least 20 different lots other than the subject property, then the 500-foot radius for notification shall be increased in increments of 50 feet until the required number of persons and lots are encompassed within the expanded area.&#xA0; Notification shall then be given to all property owners and occupants within the expanded area.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	Notwithstanding the above 24-calendar day notification period and the 500-foot notification radius, only 15 calendar days and a 500-foot radius shall be required for any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; conducted on the same site for a land use or discretionary zoning approval for which a previous final decision pursuant to this section has been made by the City.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	&lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Hearing&lt;/span&gt; and Decision.&#xA0; The matter may be set for public &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; before the Director.&#xA0; After the conclusion of a public &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt;, the Director may require the modification, discontinuance or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;revocation&lt;/span&gt; of the land use or discretionary zoning approval, as the case may be.&#xA0; As part of the action, the Director may impose conditions of operation as he or she deems appropriate, including those necessary to protect the best interests of the surrounding property or neighborhood; to eliminate, lessen, or prevent any detrimental effect on the surrounding property or neighborhood; or to assure compliance with other applicable provisions of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;law&lt;/span&gt; or conditions of an earlier discretionary approval.&#xA0; Conditions imposed may include the establishment of amortization &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;schedules&lt;/span&gt;, the closure or removal of buildings or structures, and affect the establishment, maintenance, or operation of the subject use, and related land uses, buildings, or structures.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	Whenever the Director initiates an action pursuant to this section he or she shall impose a condition requiring payment of the fee set forth in Section 19.01 P. of this Code (fee condition) to cover the City&#x2019;s costs in processing the matter.&#xA0; A fee is not required if the Director finds that the operation of the land use does not create a nuisance or that the property owner, business operator or person in control, is in substantial compliance with the conditions of operation.&#xA0; The fee condition shall further provide that if the decision is not appealed, then the fee shall be paid in full to the City with confirmation of the payment being provided to the Director within 30 days of the decision date.&#xA0; If an &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; is filed and the decision of the Director is upheld on &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt;, then the fee shall be paid in full with confirmation made to the Director within 30 days of the effective date of the decision.&#xA0; If the Council &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;reverses&lt;/span&gt; in total the decision of the Director, then no payment of fees other than the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; fee specified in Section 19.01 P. shall be required.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	Any determination shall be supported by written &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;findings&lt;/span&gt;, including a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;finding&lt;/span&gt; that the Director&#x2019;s determination does not impair the constitutional rights of any person.&#xA0; The written determination shall also state that failure to comply with any or all conditions imposed may result in the issuance of an &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; to discontinue or revoke the land use or discretionary zoning approval.&#xA0; The Director may require the discontinuance or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;revocation&lt;/span&gt; of a land use or discretionary zoning approval only upon &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;finding&lt;/span&gt; that:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(a)	prior governmental efforts to cause the owner or operator to eliminate the problems associated with the land use or discretionary zoning approval have failed (examples include formal action, such as &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;citations&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;orders&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearings&lt;/span&gt; by the Police Department, Department of Building and Safety, the Director, a Zoning Administrator, the City Planning Commission, or any other governmental agency); and&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(b)	the owner or operator has failed to demonstrate, to the satisfaction of the Director, the willingness or ability to eliminate the problems associated with the land use or discretionary zoning approval.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	If the Director discontinues or revokes any land use or discretionary zoning approval pursuant to this section, the full cost of the abatement, including the cost of inspection, shall become the personal obligation of the business operator, property owner, or person in control.&#xA0; If confirmed by the Council, a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt; may be placed against the property in accordance with the procedures described in Administrative Code Sec. 7.35.3.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	Compliance Review.&#xA0; Upon any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;finding&lt;/span&gt; of nuisance or non-compliance with existing conditions imposed on the land use or discretionary zoning approval, the Director&#x2019;s determination shall impose a condition requiring the business operator or property owner to file a Plan Approval application for Review of Compliance with Conditions within two years of the effective date.&#xA0; At the discretion of the Director, the due date for the Plan Approval application can be set for 90 days, 180 days, one year, 18 months or two years from the effective date of the Director&#x2019;s determination or the Council action on &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	4.	&lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Appeals&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; An &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; from the decision of the Director may be taken to the Council in the same manner as prescribed in Section 12.24 I.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	An &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; fee shall be charged pursuant to Section 19.01 P.&#xA0; The Council&#x2019;s decision on &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; shall be processed in the manner prescribed in Section 12.24 I.6.&#xA0;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	Further, if it is determined by the Council that the decision of the Director impairs the constitutional rights of any person, then it shall modify the action accordingly, or refer the matter back to the Director for further action.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	5.	Violations.&#xA0; It shall be unlawful to violate or fail to comply with any requirement or condition imposed by the Director or the Council pursuant to this section.&#xA0; Violation or failure to comply shall constitute a violation of this chapter and shall be subject to the same penalties as any other violation of this chapter. In the event of a violation of an &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; to discontinue or revoke a land use or discretionary zoning approval pursuant to this section, the Department of Building and Safety shall &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; the owner to vacate and secure the property, premises, buildings or portion of any property, premises or building pursuant to Section 91.9003 of this Code.&#xA0; The Department of Building and Safety shall institute enforcement as provided in Section 91.9003.3 of this Code.&#xA0; The Director shall cause the determination or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;revocation&lt;/span&gt; to be recorded.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	D.	Residential Uses.&#xA0; This subsection shall apply to all single-family and multi-family residential uses, including residential hotels as defined in Section 47.73 T. of this Code.&#xA0; This subsection shall not apply to hotels or motels that are not residential hotels. Nothing in this section or Section 91.9001 et seq. of this Code is intended to supersede or abrogate the rights of tenants provided by State &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;statute&lt;/span&gt; or by the Los Angeles Housing Code and Rent Stabilization &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Ordinance&lt;/span&gt;, or by any other provision of this Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	The Director, as the initial decision maker, or the Council on &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt;, shall ask the City Attorney to initiate the process of having the residential use placed in receivership pursuant to California Civil Code Section 3479 and Code of Civil Procedure Section 564(b)(9), upon &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;finding&lt;/span&gt; that:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(a)	prior governmental efforts to cause the owner or operator to eliminate the problems associated with the land use or discretionary zoning approval have failed (examples include formal action, such as &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;citations&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;orders&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearings&lt;/span&gt; by the Police Department, Department of Building and Safety, the Director, a Zoning Administrator, the City Planning Commission, or any other governmental agency); and&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(b)	that the owner or operator has failed to demonstrate, to the satisfaction of the Director, the willingness or ability to eliminate the problems associated with the land use or discretionary zoning approval.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	If the residential use is not placed in receivership and the Director, as the initial decision maker, or the Council on &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt;, discontinues or revokes the land use or discretionary zoning approval, resulting in the displacement of tenants then the following provisions shall apply:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(a)	The Housing Department shall identify each tenant who was displaced and is eligible for relocation assistance, and shall &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;issue&lt;/span&gt; an &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; requiring the owner to pay relocation benefits in the amounts specified in Section 151.09 G. of this Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(b)	If the owner fails to pay relocation benefits to an eligible tenant as required by this subsection, the Housing Department may advance relocation benefits to the tenant in the amount set forth in Section 151.09 G. of this Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(c)	If the owner fails to comply with an &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; of the Housing Department to pay relocation benefits, the owner shall be liable to the City for any relocation payments advanced, and the Housing Department may obtain a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt; upon the property pursuant to Los Angeles Administrative Code Section 7.35.3 to recover the amount advanced and associated costs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(d)	Relocation benefits shall not be payable to any tenant who has caused or substantially contributed to the condition giving rise to an &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; to vacate issued pursuant to Section 91.9003.1 of this Code.&#xA0; The Director shall determine whether a tenant has caused or substantially contributed to the condition giving rise to the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; to vacate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(e)	The Housing Department shall inform each eligible tenant of his/her right to re-rental of the same unit, or comparable unit, if the owner, or subsequent owner, re-establishes the residential use.&#xA0; The Housing Department shall inform the eligible tenant that he/she must advise the owner in writing of his/her interest in re-renting and must provide the owner with an address to which the owner can direct an offer.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(f)	When the residential use is re-established, the accommodations shall be offered, and rented or leased at the lawful rent in effect at the time the residential use was discontinued or revoked, plus annual adjustments available under Section 151.06 of this Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(g)	The Director&#x2019;s determination or the Council&#x2019;s action shall include the provisions of this subsection and shall be recorded by the Director as a covenant with the Office of the County Recorder.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	E.	Modification of Administrative Decisions.&#xA0; Any administrative nuisance abatement decision made pursuant to this chapter, any conditions imposed by that decision, or any decisions on a discretionary zoning approval pursuant to this section may be modified pursuant to the provisions of this subsection.&#xA0; Upon application by the business operator, property owner or lessee(s), the Director may modify or eliminate the conditions of a prior decision.&#xA0; An application shall be made on official forms provided by the Department of Planning and shall be accompanied by a filing fee as specified in Section 19.01 P.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	An application may be considered if a time period of at least one year has passed from the date the conditions were originally imposed; or if there have been substantial changes in the nature and operation of the land use or discretionary zoning approval; or if there has been a change in circumstances such that the continued enforcement of the previously imposed conditions is no longer reasonable or necessary.&#xA0; All applications shall include a radius map, a list of property owners and occupants within 500 feet, and plot plan drawn to scale.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	An application shall be set for public &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; The Director may grant or deny the requested application, or modify the prior decision, including imposing new or different substitute conditions as the Director deems appropriate.&#xA0; No modification shall be approved pursuant to this subsection unless the Director finds each of the following:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	That the requirements for consideration of the application under this subsection have been met; and&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	That due consideration has been given to the effects of the modification on surrounding properties.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	An &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; from the decision of the Director may be taken to the Council in the same manner as prescribed in Subsection C. of this section.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	When the Director &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;orders&lt;/span&gt; the discontinuance or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;revocation&lt;/span&gt; of a land use or discretionary zoning approval and the applicant files for re-instatement of the land use pursuant to this subsection, the Director may re-instate the land use if all &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;findings&lt;/span&gt; of this subsection are met.&#xA0; The applicant will not be issued a new certificate of occupancy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	Subsequent applications for reconsideration may be filed in accordance with this subsection.&#xA0; If the application is denied with prejudice, a subsequent application for reconsideration shall not be filed within one year from the reconsideration decision date, and then only if a property owner, business operator or lessee(s) shows that the circumstances involving the land use or discretionary zoning approval have substantially and materially changed since the last reconsideration.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	F.	Continuation of Prior Decisions.&#xA0; Prior administrative nuisance abatement decisions regarding land uses and discontinuances, &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;revocations&lt;/span&gt;, rescissions or modifications of discretionary zoning approvals made by the Zoning Administrator, City Planning Commission or the Council shall remain in full force and effect.&#xA0; Further, it shall continue to be unlawful to violate or fail to comply with any prior requirement or condition imposed by the Zoning Administrator, the former Board of Zoning &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Appeals&lt;/span&gt;, the City Planning Commission, or the Council.&#xA0; Violation or failure to comply shall constitute a violation of this chapter and shall be subject to the same penalties as any other violation of this chapter.&#xA0; In the event of a violation of an &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; of discontinuance or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;revocation&lt;/span&gt;, the Department of Building and Safety shall &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; the business operator, property owner or lessee(s) to vacate and secure the property, premises, buildings or portion thereof pursuant to Section 91.9003 of this Code.&#xA0; The Department of Building and Safety shall institute enforcement as provided in LAMC Sec. 91.9003.4 of this Code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</html><previous_section id="2923"><structure_id>20</structure_id><section_number>12.27</section_number><catch_line>Variances.</catch_line><url>/12.27/</url><token>12.27</token></previous_section><text><unit id="788" prefix=""><text>&#xA0; ADMINISTRATIVE NUISANCE ABATEMENT PROCEEDINGS.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 180,409, Eff. 1/18/09.)	A.	Purpose.&#xA0; It is the intent of this section to consolidate a number of existing code provisions relating to the administrative abatement of public nuisances, and revocations, rescissions, discontinuances or modifications of discretionary zoning approvals.&#xA0; In addition, this section also sets forth procedures allowing the Director to modify or remove conditions imposed as a result of nuisance abatement proceedings; to enforce conditions imposed as part of any discretionary zoning approval; and to require that the cost of a proceeding instituted pursuant to this section be paid by those responsible for the maintenance and operation of the subject use.	These provisions allow the City&#x2019;s zoning authorities to protect the public peace, health and safety from any land use which becomes a nuisance; adversely affects the health, peace or safety of persons residing or working in the surrounding area; or violates any land use related condition imposed pursuant to this chapter or other provision of law, while protecting the constitutional rights of the parties involved.	B.	Authority.&#xA0; Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code to the contrary, the Director may require the modification, discontinuance or revocation of any land use or discretionary zoning approval if it is found that the land use or discretionary zoning approval as operated or maintained:	1.	Jeopardizes or adversely affects the public health, peace, or safety of persons residing or working on the premises or in the surrounding area; or	2.	Constitutes a public nuisance; or	3.	Has resulted in repeated nuisance activities, including, but not limited to, disturbances of the peace, illegal drug activity, public drunkenness, drinking in public, harassment of passersby, gambling, prostitution, sale of stolen goods, public urination, theft, assaults, batteries, acts of vandalism, loitering, excessive littering, illegal parking, excessive loud noises (especially in the late night or early morning hours), traffic violations, curfew violations, lewd conduct, or police detentions and arrests; or	4.	Adversely impacts nearby uses; or	5.	Violates any provision of this chapter; or any other city, state, or federal regulation, ordinance, or statute; or	6.	Violates any condition imposed by a prior discretionary land use approval including approvals granted pursuant to Sections 12.24, 12.27, 12.28, 12.32 or 14.00 of this Code; or an approval initiated by application of a property owner or owner&#x2019;s representative related to the use of land including, but not limited to, parcel map, tentative tract map, coastal development permit, development agreement, density transfer plan, exception from a specific plan, and project permit pursuant to a moratorium or an interim control ordinance.	C.	Procedures:&#xA0; Notice, Hearings and Appeals.&#xA0; The Director shall give notice to the record owner and lessee(s) of the real property affected to appear at a public hearing at a time and place fixed by the Director and show cause why the land use or discretionary zoning approval should not be modified, discontinued, or revoked.	1.	Notice.&#xA0; A written notice shall be mailed not less than 24 calendar days prior to the date of hearing to the owner and lessee(s) of the property involved, and to the owners of all property within and outside of the City that is within 500 feet of the exterior boundaries of the property involved, using for the purpose of notification the last known name and address of the owners, as shown in the City Clerk&#x2019;s records or in the records of the County Assessor.&#xA0; If all property within the 500-foot radius is under the same ownership as the property involved in the proceeding, then the owners of all property which adjoins that ownership shall be included in this notification.&#xA0; Written notice shall also be mailed to residential, commercial and industrial occupants of the property involved, and all property within 500 feet of the exterior boundaries of the property involved.&#xA0; This requirement can be met by mailing the notice to &#x201C;occupant&#x201D;.&#xA0; If this notice provision will not result in notice being given to at least 20 different owners of at least 20 different lots other than the subject property, then the 500-foot radius for notification shall be increased in increments of 50 feet until the required number of persons and lots are encompassed within the expanded area.&#xA0; Notification shall then be given to all property owners and occupants within the expanded area.	Notwithstanding the above 24-calendar day notification period and the 500-foot notification radius, only 15 calendar days and a 500-foot radius shall be required for any hearing conducted on the same site for a land use or discretionary zoning approval for which a previous final decision pursuant to this section has been made by the City.	2.	Hearing and Decision.&#xA0; The matter may be set for public hearing before the Director.&#xA0; After the conclusion of a public hearing, the Director may require the modification, discontinuance or revocation of the land use or discretionary zoning approval, as the case may be.&#xA0; As part of the action, the Director may impose conditions of operation as he or she deems appropriate, including those necessary to protect the best interests of the surrounding property or neighborhood; to eliminate, lessen, or prevent any detrimental effect on the surrounding property or neighborhood; or to assure compliance with other applicable provisions of law or conditions of an earlier discretionary approval.&#xA0; Conditions imposed may include the establishment of amortization schedules, the closure or removal of buildings or structures, and affect the establishment, maintenance, or operation of the subject use, and related land uses, buildings, or structures.	Whenever the Director initiates an action pursuant to this section he or she shall impose a condition requiring payment of the fee set forth in Section 19.01 P. of this Code (fee condition) to cover the City&#x2019;s costs in processing the matter.&#xA0; A fee is not required if the Director finds that the operation of the land use does not create a nuisance or that the property owner, business operator or person in control, is in substantial compliance with the conditions of operation.&#xA0; The fee condition shall further provide that if the decision is not appealed, then the fee shall be paid in full to the City with confirmation of the payment being provided to the Director within 30 days of the decision date.&#xA0; If an appeal is filed and the decision of the Director is upheld on appeal, then the fee shall be paid in full with confirmation made to the Director within 30 days of the effective date of the decision.&#xA0; If the Council reverses in total the decision of the Director, then no payment of fees other than the appeal fee specified in Section 19.01 P. shall be required.	Any determination shall be supported by written findings, including a finding that the Director&#x2019;s determination does not impair the constitutional rights of any person.&#xA0; The written determination shall also state that failure to comply with any or all conditions imposed may result in the issuance of an order to discontinue or revoke the land use or discretionary zoning approval.&#xA0; The Director may require the discontinuance or revocation of a land use or discretionary zoning approval only upon finding that:	(a)	prior governmental efforts to cause the owner or operator to eliminate the problems associated with the land use or discretionary zoning approval have failed (examples include formal action, such as citations, orders or hearings by the Police Department, Department of Building and Safety, the Director, a Zoning Administrator, the City Planning Commission, or any other governmental agency); and	(b)	the owner or operator has failed to demonstrate, to the satisfaction of the Director, the willingness or ability to eliminate the problems associated with the land use or discretionary zoning approval.	If the Director discontinues or revokes any land use or discretionary zoning approval pursuant to this section, the full cost of the abatement, including the cost of inspection, shall become the personal obligation of the business operator, property owner, or person in control.&#xA0; If confirmed by the Council, a lien may be placed against the property in accordance with the procedures described in Administrative Code Sec. 7.35.3.	3.	Compliance Review.&#xA0; Upon any finding of nuisance or non-compliance with existing conditions imposed on the land use or discretionary zoning approval, the Director&#x2019;s determination shall impose a condition requiring the business operator or property owner to file a Plan Approval application for Review of Compliance with Conditions within two years of the effective date.&#xA0; At the discretion of the Director, the due date for the Plan Approval application can be set for 90 days, 180 days, one year, 18 months or two years from the effective date of the Director&#x2019;s determination or the Council action on appeal.	4.	Appeals.&#xA0; An appeal from the decision of the Director may be taken to the Council in the same manner as prescribed in Section 12.24 I.	An appeal fee shall be charged pursuant to Section 19.01 P.&#xA0; The Council&#x2019;s decision on appeal shall be processed in the manner prescribed in Section 12.24 I.6.&#xA0;	Further, if it is determined by the Council that the decision of the Director impairs the constitutional rights of any person, then it shall modify the action accordingly, or refer the matter back to the Director for further action.	5.	Violations.&#xA0; It shall be unlawful to violate or fail to comply with any requirement or condition imposed by the Director or the Council pursuant to this section.&#xA0; Violation or failure to comply shall constitute a violation of this chapter and shall be subject to the same penalties as any other violation of this chapter. In the event of a violation of an order to discontinue or revoke a land use or discretionary zoning approval pursuant to this section, the Department of Building and Safety shall order the owner to vacate and secure the property, premises, buildings or portion of any property, premises or building pursuant to Section 91.9003 of this Code.&#xA0; The Department of Building and Safety shall institute enforcement as provided in Section 91.9003.3 of this Code.&#xA0; The Director shall cause the determination or revocation to be recorded.	D.	Residential Uses.&#xA0; This subsection shall apply to all single-family and multi-family residential uses, including residential hotels as defined in Section 47.73 T. of this Code.&#xA0; This subsection shall not apply to hotels or motels that are not residential hotels. Nothing in this section or Section 91.9001 et seq. of this Code is intended to supersede or abrogate the rights of tenants provided by State statute or by the Los Angeles Housing Code and Rent Stabilization Ordinance, or by any other provision of this Code.	1.	The Director, as the initial decision maker, or the Council on appeal, shall ask the City Attorney to initiate the process of having the residential use placed in receivership pursuant to California Civil Code Section 3479 and Code of Civil Procedure Section 564(b)(9), upon finding that:	(a)	prior governmental efforts to cause the owner or operator to eliminate the problems associated with the land use or discretionary zoning approval have failed (examples include formal action, such as citations, orders or hearings by the Police Department, Department of Building and Safety, the Director, a Zoning Administrator, the City Planning Commission, or any other governmental agency); and	(b)	that the owner or operator has failed to demonstrate, to the satisfaction of the Director, the willingness or ability to eliminate the problems associated with the land use or discretionary zoning approval.	2.	If the residential use is not placed in receivership and the Director, as the initial decision maker, or the Council on appeal, discontinues or revokes the land use or discretionary zoning approval, resulting in the displacement of tenants then the following provisions shall apply:	(a)	The Housing Department shall identify each tenant who was displaced and is eligible for relocation assistance, and shall issue an order requiring the owner to pay relocation benefits in the amounts specified in Section 151.09 G. of this Code.	(b)	If the owner fails to pay relocation benefits to an eligible tenant as required by this subsection, the Housing Department may advance relocation benefits to the tenant in the amount set forth in Section 151.09 G. of this Code.	(c)	If the owner fails to comply with an order of the Housing Department to pay relocation benefits, the owner shall be liable to the City for any relocation payments advanced, and the Housing Department may obtain a lien upon the property pursuant to Los Angeles Administrative Code Section 7.35.3 to recover the amount advanced and associated costs.	(d)	Relocation benefits shall not be payable to any tenant who has caused or substantially contributed to the condition giving rise to an order to vacate issued pursuant to Section 91.9003.1 of this Code.&#xA0; The Director shall determine whether a tenant has caused or substantially contributed to the condition giving rise to the order to vacate.	(e)	The Housing Department shall inform each eligible tenant of his/her right to re-rental of the same unit, or comparable unit, if the owner, or subsequent owner, re-establishes the residential use.&#xA0; The Housing Department shall inform the eligible tenant that he/she must advise the owner in writing of his/her interest in re-renting and must provide the owner with an address to which the owner can direct an offer.	(f)	When the residential use is re-established, the accommodations shall be offered, and rented or leased at the lawful rent in effect at the time the residential use was discontinued or revoked, plus annual adjustments available under Section 151.06 of this Code.	(g)	The Director&#x2019;s determination or the Council&#x2019;s action shall include the provisions of this subsection and shall be recorded by the Director as a covenant with the Office of the County Recorder.	E.	Modification of Administrative Decisions.&#xA0; Any administrative nuisance abatement decision made pursuant to this chapter, any conditions imposed by that decision, or any decisions on a discretionary zoning approval pursuant to this section may be modified pursuant to the provisions of this subsection.&#xA0; Upon application by the business operator, property owner or lessee(s), the Director may modify or eliminate the conditions of a prior decision.&#xA0; An application shall be made on official forms provided by the Department of Planning and shall be accompanied by a filing fee as specified in Section 19.01 P.	An application may be considered if a time period of at least one year has passed from the date the conditions were originally imposed; or if there have been substantial changes in the nature and operation of the land use or discretionary zoning approval; or if there has been a change in circumstances such that the continued enforcement of the previously imposed conditions is no longer reasonable or necessary.&#xA0; All applications shall include a radius map, a list of property owners and occupants within 500 feet, and plot plan drawn to scale.	An application shall be set for public hearing.&#xA0; The Director may grant or deny the requested application, or modify the prior decision, including imposing new or different substitute conditions as the Director deems appropriate.&#xA0; No modification shall be approved pursuant to this subsection unless the Director finds each of the following:	1.	That the requirements for consideration of the application under this subsection have been met; and	2.	That due consideration has been given to the effects of the modification on surrounding properties.	An appeal from the decision of the Director may be taken to the Council in the same manner as prescribed in Subsection C. of this section.	When the Director orders the discontinuance or revocation of a land use or discretionary zoning approval and the applicant files for re-instatement of the land use pursuant to this subsection, the Director may re-instate the land use if all findings of this subsection are met.&#xA0; The applicant will not be issued a new certificate of occupancy.	Subsequent applications for reconsideration may be filed in accordance with this subsection.&#xA0; If the application is denied with prejudice, a subsequent application for reconsideration shall not be filed within one year from the reconsideration decision date, and then only if a property owner, business operator or lessee(s) shows that the circumstances involving the land use or discretionary zoning approval have substantially and materially changed since the last reconsideration.	F.	Continuation of Prior Decisions.&#xA0; Prior administrative nuisance abatement decisions regarding land uses and discontinuances, revocations, rescissions or modifications of discretionary zoning approvals made by the Zoning Administrator, City Planning Commission or the Council shall remain in full force and effect.&#xA0; Further, it shall continue to be unlawful to violate or fail to comply with any prior requirement or condition imposed by the Zoning Administrator, the former Board of Zoning Appeals, the City Planning Commission, or the Council.&#xA0; Violation or failure to comply shall constitute a violation of this chapter and shall be subject to the same penalties as any other violation of this chapter.&#xA0; In the event of a violation of an order of discontinuance or revocation, the Department of Building and Safety shall order the business operator, property owner or lessee(s) to vacate and secure the property, premises, buildings or portion thereof pursuant to Section 91.9003 of this Code.&#xA0; The Department of Building and Safety shall institute enforcement as provided in LAMC Sec. 91.9003.4 of this Code.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><unit></unit></prefixes><entire_prefix></entire_prefix><prefix_anchor></prefix_anchor><level>1</level></unit></text></law>
