<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><section_number>162.07</section_number><edition_id>1</edition_id><section_id>3780</section_id><structure_id>112</structure_id><catch_line>Escrow Account.</catch_line><history></history><full_text>&#xA0; ESCROW ACCOUNT.
	(Added by Ord. No. 173,810, Eff. 4/16/01.)

	A.	Establishment of Account.

	1.	Within five working days after the decision accepting a building into REAP has become final, the Department shall establish as part of the REAP Trust Fund an account for the building into which tenants may deposit rent payments.&#xA0; The Department shall mail notification to all tenants of the existence of the account, including an explanation of how payments may be deposited into the account.&#xA0; The Department shall provide a receipt to each tenant making a deposit.&#xA0; The Department shall provide, at least once a month, a periodic report to the landlord concerning the activity in the account.&#xA0; The records of the account shall be reasonably available to the landlord or any interested party, or their representatives, in accordance with the regulations, including the provision for payment of reasonable fees, as the Commission may promulgate.

	2.	Interest at a rate established by the Rent Adjustment Commission pursuant to the provisions of Paragraph a. of Subdivision 1. of Subsection B. of Section 151.06.02 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code shall accrue to the funds held in each account established by the Department pursuant to the provisions of Subdivision 1. of this Section, and shall be disbursed upon termination of the account in accordance with Subsection D. of Section 162.08.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 177,119, Eff. 12/26/05.)

	B.	Withdrawals from 

	1.	The Department shall deduct a non-refundable administrative fee of $50.00 for each individual rent payment made into the account.&#xA0; Only one such fee shall be deducted for each residential unit for each month.

	2.	A landlord, any tenant, any Enforcement Agency, any interested party, and any creditor may apply to the General Manager for a release of funds from the escrow account, in accordance with the regulations the RAC shall enact.&#xA0; Withdrawals may be for the following reasons, in addition to other reasons adopted by regulation:

	a.	When necessary to prevent a significant diminution of an essential service to the building, including utilities;

	b.	When necessary for the correction of deficiencies, including but not limited to those that caused the acceptance into REAP;

	c.	When, to the extent legally permissible, requested by a tenant who has performed or wishes to repair conditions that affect the tenant&#x2019;s health and safety, that result in a deprivation of housing services, as defined in Section 151.02, or that result in a habitability violation, as defined in Section 153.02. Those repairs are not limited to the repair of violations that caused the acceptance into REAP;

	d.	When requested by a tenant who wishes to or has relocated from the unit or building.&#xA0; These withdrawals are not limited to the amount of relocation assistance permitted by the RSO;

	e.	When requested by a tenant who has sustained expenses due to uninhabitable conditions; or

	f.	When ordered by a court.

	3.	Upon receipt of an application for release of funds, the General Manager shall hold a hearing following the procedures set forth in Division 8 of Article 1 of Chapter XVI of this Code.&#xA0; The General Manager shall order the release of funds from the escrow account where it has been demonstrated to the satisfaction of the General Manager that the conditions set forth in paragraph 2 above, or other conditions enacted by regulation, have been met.&#xA0; When necessary to address an imminent threat to the health or safety of the occupants, or to prevent the termination of utilities, the General Manager may release funds without a hearing or on shortened notice.&#xA0; The RAC shall promulgate regulations governing expedited releases.&#xA0; Any aggrieved party may appeal the General Manager&#x2019;s decision to the Appeals Board following the procedures set forth in Division 10 of Article 1 of Chapter XVI of this Code.&#xA0; An application fee required pursuant to the provisions of Section 161.1002.2 may be waived by the Department in accordance with the standards and procedures set forth in the provisions of Section 151.14 C.&#xA0; (Last Sentence Added by Ord. No. 177,634, Eff. 7/22/06.)

	4.	If a building is in more than one escrow program of the Department (including REAP, UMP, URP or HEP), disbursement of funds in excess of the $50.00 administrative fee to make repairs, to address the health and safety of the occupants, or to preserve essential services, shall be given priority over expenditures for other purposes.

	5.	The pendency of an unlawful detainer action or an unlawful detainer judgement shall not prevent the disbursement of funds to a tenant. The General Manager shall take into account the facts and circumstances of the unlawful detainer action.

	6.	The General Manager shall deny the application where it determines that the application is intended, in whole or in part, to circumvent the provisions of this article.&#xA0; A debt incurred subsequent to notice to a creditor that the building was under consideration for or had been selected for participation in REAP, shall be presumed, subject to rebuttal, to be for the purpose of circumventing the provisions of this article.</full_text><order_by>07</order_by><ancestry><unit id="112" label="article"><name>Rent Escrow Account Program</name><identifier>2</identifier><url>/16/2/</url></unit><unit id="27" label="chapter"><name>Housing Regulations</name><identifier>16</identifier><url>/16/</url></unit></ancestry><structure_contents><unit id="2966"><structure_id>112</structure_id><section_number>162.00</section_number><catch_line>Title.</catch_line><url>/162.00/</url><token>162.00</token></unit><unit id="1224"><structure_id>112</structure_id><section_number>162.01</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/162.01/</url><token>162.01</token></unit><unit id="900"><structure_id>112</structure_id><section_number>162.02</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/162.02/</url><token>162.02</token></unit><unit id="3964"><structure_id>112</structure_id><section_number>162.03</section_number><catch_line>Referral To Reap.</catch_line><url>/162.03/</url><token>162.03</token></unit><unit id="3207"><structure_id>112</structure_id><section_number>162.04</section_number><catch_line>Acceptance.</catch_line><url>/162.04/</url><token>162.04</token></unit><unit id="3469"><structure_id>112</structure_id><section_number>162.05</section_number><catch_line>Rent Reduction Schedule.</catch_line><url>/162.05/</url><token>162.05</token></unit><unit id="789"><structure_id>112</structure_id><section_number>162.06</section_number><catch_line>Appeals.</catch_line><url>/162.06/</url><token>162.06</token></unit><unit id="3780"><structure_id>112</structure_id><section_number>162.07</section_number><catch_line>Escrow Account.</catch_line><url>/162.07/</url><token>162.07</token></unit><unit id="756"><structure_id>112</structure_id><section_number>162.08</section_number><catch_line>Termination Of Reap.</catch_line><url>/162.08/</url><token>162.08</token></unit><unit id="2474"><structure_id>112</structure_id><section_number>162.09</section_number><catch_line>Tenant Protections.</catch_line><url>/162.09/</url><token>162.09</token></unit><unit id="3965"><structure_id>112</structure_id><section_number>162.10</section_number><catch_line>Contact With Tenants.</catch_line><url>/162.10/</url><token>162.10</token></unit><unit id="1477"><structure_id>112</structure_id><section_number>162.11</section_number><catch_line>Recording Of Reap Order And Termination Of Reap.</catch_line><url>/162.11/</url><token>162.11</token></unit><unit id="1975"><structure_id>112</structure_id><section_number>162.12</section_number><catch_line>Collection Of Reap Fees.</catch_line><url>/162.12/</url><token>162.12</token></unit></structure_contents><next_section id="756"><structure_id>112</structure_id><section_number>162.08</section_number><catch_line>Termination Of Reap.</catch_line><url>/162.08/</url><token>162.08</token></next_section><metadata></metadata><references></references><url>/162.07/</url><token>162.07</token><formats><txt>/162.07.txt</txt><json>/162.07.xml</json></formats><dublin_core><Title>Escrow Account.</Title><Type>Text</Type><Format>text/html</Format><Identifier>&#xA7; 162.07</Identifier><Relation>Los Angeles Municipal Code</Relation></dublin_core><plain_text>                            LOS ANGELES MUNICIPAL CODE

ESCROW ACCOUNT. (&#xA7; 162.07)

&#xA0; ESCROW ACCOUNT.
	(Added by Ord. No. 173,810, Eff. 4/16/01.)	A.	Establishment of
Account.	1.	Within five working days after the decision accepting a building
into REAP has become final, the Department shall establish as part of the REAP
Trust Fund an account for the building into which tenants may deposit rent
payments.&#xA0; The Department shall mail notification to all tenants of the
existence of the account, including an explanation of how payments may be
deposited into the account.&#xA0; The Department shall provide a receipt to each
tenant making a deposit.&#xA0; The Department shall provide, at least once a month,
a periodic report to the landlord concerning the activity in the account.&#xA0; The
records of the account shall be reasonably available to the landlord or any
interested party, or their representatives, in accordance with the regulations,
including the provision for payment of reasonable fees, as the Commission may
promulgate.	2.	Interest at a rate established by the Rent Adjustment Commission
pursuant to the provisions of Paragraph a. of Subdivision 1. of Subsection B. of
Section 151.06.02 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code shall accrue to the funds
held in each account established by the Department pursuant to the provisions of
Subdivision 1. of this Section, and shall be disbursed upon termination of the
account in accordance with Subsection D. of Section 162.08.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No.
177,119, Eff. 12/26/05.)	B.	Withdrawals from 	1.	The Department shall deduct a
non-refundable administrative fee of $50.00 for each individual rent payment
made into the account.&#xA0; Only one such fee shall be deducted for each
residential unit for each month.	2.	A landlord, any tenant, any Enforcement
Agency, any interested party, and any creditor may apply to the General Manager
for a release of funds from the escrow account, in accordance with the
regulations the RAC shall enact.&#xA0; Withdrawals may be for the following reasons,
in addition to other reasons adopted by regulation:	a.	When necessary to prevent
a significant diminution of an essential service to the building, including
utilities;	b.	When necessary for the correction of deficiencies, including but
not limited to those that caused the acceptance into REAP;	c.	When, to the
extent legally permissible, requested by a tenant who has performed or wishes to
repair conditions that affect the tenant&#x2019;s health and safety, that result in a
deprivation of housing services, as defined in Section 151.02, or that result in
a habitability violation, as defined in Section 153.02. Those repairs are not
limited to the repair of violations that caused the acceptance into
REAP;	d.	When requested by a tenant who wishes to or has relocated from the unit
or building.&#xA0; These withdrawals are not limited to the amount of relocation
assistance permitted by the RSO;	e.	When requested by a tenant who has sustained
expenses due to uninhabitable conditions; or	f.	When ordered by a court.	3.	Upon
receipt of an application for release of funds, the General Manager shall hold a
hearing following the procedures set forth in Division 8 of Article 1 of Chapter
XVI of this Code.&#xA0; The General Manager shall order the release of funds from
the escrow account where it has been demonstrated to the satisfaction of the
General Manager that the conditions set forth in paragraph 2 above, or other
conditions enacted by regulation, have been met.&#xA0; When necessary to address an
imminent threat to the health or safety of the occupants, or to prevent the
termination of utilities, the General Manager may release funds without a
hearing or on shortened notice.&#xA0; The RAC shall promulgate regulations governing
expedited releases.&#xA0; Any aggrieved party may appeal the General Manager&#x2019;s
decision to the Appeals Board following the procedures set forth in Division 10
of Article 1 of Chapter XVI of this Code.&#xA0; An application fee required pursuant
to the provisions of Section 161.1002.2 may be waived by the Department in
accordance with the standards and procedures set forth in the provisions of
Section 151.14 C.&#xA0; (Last Sentence Added by Ord. No. 177,634, Eff.
7/22/06.)	4.	If a building is in more than one escrow program of the Department
(including REAP, UMP, URP or HEP), disbursement of funds in excess of the $50.00
administrative fee to make repairs, to address the health and safety of the
occupants, or to preserve essential services, shall be given priority over
expenditures for other purposes.	5.	The pendency of an unlawful detainer action
or an unlawful detainer judgement shall not prevent the disbursement of funds to
a tenant. The General Manager shall take into account the facts and
circumstances of the unlawful detainer action.	6.	The General Manager shall deny
the application where it determines that the application is intended, in whole
or in part, to circumvent the provisions of this article.&#xA0; A debt incurred
subsequent to notice to a creditor that the building was under consideration for
or had been selected for participation in REAP, shall be presumed, subject to
rebuttal, to be for the purpose of circumventing the provisions of this article.
</plain_text><html>
					&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#xA0; ESCROW ACCOUNT.
	(Added by Ord. No. 173,810, Eff. 4/16/01.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	A.	Establishment of Account.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	Within five working days after the decision accepting a building into REAP has become final, the Department shall establish as part of the REAP Trust Fund an account for the building into which tenants may deposit rent payments.&#xA0; The Department shall mail notification to all tenants of the existence of the account, including an explanation of how payments may be deposited into the account.&#xA0; The Department shall provide a receipt to each tenant making a deposit.&#xA0; The Department shall provide, at least once a month, a periodic report to the landlord concerning the activity in the account.&#xA0; The records of the account shall be reasonably available to the landlord or any interested party, or their representatives, in accordance with the regulations, including the provision for payment of reasonable fees, as the Commission may promulgate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	Interest at a rate established by the Rent Adjustment Commission pursuant to the provisions of Paragraph a. of Subdivision 1. of Subsection B. of Section 151.06.02 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code shall accrue to the funds held in each account established by the Department pursuant to the provisions of Subdivision 1. of this Section, and shall be disbursed upon termination of the account in accordance with Subsection D. of Section 162.08.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 177,119, Eff. 12/26/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	B.	Withdrawals from &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	The Department shall deduct a non-refundable administrative fee of $50.00 for each individual rent payment made into the account.&#xA0; Only one such fee shall be deducted for each residential unit for each month.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	A landlord, any tenant, any Enforcement Agency, any interested party, and any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;creditor&lt;/span&gt; may apply to the General Manager for a release of funds from the escrow account, in accordance with the regulations the RAC shall enact.&#xA0; Withdrawals may be for the following reasons, in addition to other reasons adopted by regulation:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	a.	When necessary to prevent a significant diminution of an essential service to the building, including utilities;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	b.	When necessary for the correction of deficiencies, including but not limited to those that caused the acceptance into REAP;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	c.	When, to the extent legally permissible, requested by a tenant who has performed or wishes to repair conditions that affect the tenant&#x2019;s health and safety, that result in a deprivation of housing services, as defined in Section 151.02, or that result in a habitability violation, as defined in Section 153.02. Those repairs are not limited to the repair of violations that caused the acceptance into REAP;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	d.	When requested by a tenant who wishes to or has relocated from the unit or building.&#xA0; These withdrawals are not limited to the amount of relocation assistance permitted by the RSO;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	e.	When requested by a tenant who has sustained expenses due to uninhabitable conditions; or&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	f.	When ordered by a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;court&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	Upon receipt of an application for release of funds, the General Manager shall hold a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; following the procedures set forth in Division 8 of Article 1 of Chapter XVI of this Code.&#xA0; The General Manager shall &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; the release of funds from the escrow account where it has been demonstrated to the satisfaction of the General Manager that the conditions set forth in paragraph 2 above, or other conditions enacted by regulation, have been met.&#xA0; When necessary to address an imminent threat to the health or safety of the occupants, or to prevent the termination of utilities, the General Manager may release funds without a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; or on shortened notice.&#xA0; The RAC shall promulgate regulations governing expedited releases.&#xA0; Any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;aggrieved party&lt;/span&gt; may &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; the General Manager&#x2019;s decision to the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Appeals&lt;/span&gt; Board following the procedures set forth in Division 10 of Article 1 of Chapter XVI of this Code.&#xA0; An application fee required pursuant to the provisions of Section 161.1002.2 may be waived by the Department in accordance with the standards and procedures set forth in the provisions of Section 151.14 C.&#xA0; (Last Sentence Added by Ord. No. 177,634, Eff. 7/22/06.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	4.	If a building is in more than one escrow program of the Department (including REAP, UMP, URP or HEP), disbursement of funds in excess of the $50.00 administrative fee to make repairs, to address the health and safety of the occupants, or to preserve essential services, shall be given priority over expenditures for other purposes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	5.	The pendency of an &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;unlawful detainer action&lt;/span&gt; or an unlawful detainer judgement shall not prevent the disbursement of funds to a tenant. The General Manager shall take into account the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;facts&lt;/span&gt; and circumstances of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;unlawful detainer action&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	6.	The General Manager shall deny the application where it determines that the application is intended, in whole or in part, to circumvent the provisions of this article.&#xA0; A debt incurred subsequent to notice to a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;creditor&lt;/span&gt; that the building was under consideration for or had been selected for participation in REAP, shall be presumed, subject to &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;rebuttal&lt;/span&gt;, to be for the purpose of circumventing the provisions of this article.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</html><previous_section id="789"><structure_id>112</structure_id><section_number>162.06</section_number><catch_line>Appeals.</catch_line><url>/162.06/</url><token>162.06</token></previous_section><text><unit id="3754" prefix=""><text>&#xA0; ESCROW ACCOUNT.
	(Added by Ord. No. 173,810, Eff. 4/16/01.)	A.	Establishment of Account.	1.	Within five working days after the decision accepting a building into REAP has become final, the Department shall establish as part of the REAP Trust Fund an account for the building into which tenants may deposit rent payments.&#xA0; The Department shall mail notification to all tenants of the existence of the account, including an explanation of how payments may be deposited into the account.&#xA0; The Department shall provide a receipt to each tenant making a deposit.&#xA0; The Department shall provide, at least once a month, a periodic report to the landlord concerning the activity in the account.&#xA0; The records of the account shall be reasonably available to the landlord or any interested party, or their representatives, in accordance with the regulations, including the provision for payment of reasonable fees, as the Commission may promulgate.	2.	Interest at a rate established by the Rent Adjustment Commission pursuant to the provisions of Paragraph a. of Subdivision 1. of Subsection B. of Section 151.06.02 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code shall accrue to the funds held in each account established by the Department pursuant to the provisions of Subdivision 1. of this Section, and shall be disbursed upon termination of the account in accordance with Subsection D. of Section 162.08.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 177,119, Eff. 12/26/05.)	B.	Withdrawals from 	1.	The Department shall deduct a non-refundable administrative fee of $50.00 for each individual rent payment made into the account.&#xA0; Only one such fee shall be deducted for each residential unit for each month.	2.	A landlord, any tenant, any Enforcement Agency, any interested party, and any creditor may apply to the General Manager for a release of funds from the escrow account, in accordance with the regulations the RAC shall enact.&#xA0; Withdrawals may be for the following reasons, in addition to other reasons adopted by regulation:	a.	When necessary to prevent a significant diminution of an essential service to the building, including utilities;	b.	When necessary for the correction of deficiencies, including but not limited to those that caused the acceptance into REAP;	c.	When, to the extent legally permissible, requested by a tenant who has performed or wishes to repair conditions that affect the tenant&#x2019;s health and safety, that result in a deprivation of housing services, as defined in Section 151.02, or that result in a habitability violation, as defined in Section 153.02. Those repairs are not limited to the repair of violations that caused the acceptance into REAP;	d.	When requested by a tenant who wishes to or has relocated from the unit or building.&#xA0; These withdrawals are not limited to the amount of relocation assistance permitted by the RSO;	e.	When requested by a tenant who has sustained expenses due to uninhabitable conditions; or	f.	When ordered by a court.	3.	Upon receipt of an application for release of funds, the General Manager shall hold a hearing following the procedures set forth in Division 8 of Article 1 of Chapter XVI of this Code.&#xA0; The General Manager shall order the release of funds from the escrow account where it has been demonstrated to the satisfaction of the General Manager that the conditions set forth in paragraph 2 above, or other conditions enacted by regulation, have been met.&#xA0; When necessary to address an imminent threat to the health or safety of the occupants, or to prevent the termination of utilities, the General Manager may release funds without a hearing or on shortened notice.&#xA0; The RAC shall promulgate regulations governing expedited releases.&#xA0; Any aggrieved party may appeal the General Manager&#x2019;s decision to the Appeals Board following the procedures set forth in Division 10 of Article 1 of Chapter XVI of this Code.&#xA0; An application fee required pursuant to the provisions of Section 161.1002.2 may be waived by the Department in accordance with the standards and procedures set forth in the provisions of Section 151.14 C.&#xA0; (Last Sentence Added by Ord. No. 177,634, Eff. 7/22/06.)	4.	If a building is in more than one escrow program of the Department (including REAP, UMP, URP or HEP), disbursement of funds in excess of the $50.00 administrative fee to make repairs, to address the health and safety of the occupants, or to preserve essential services, shall be given priority over expenditures for other purposes.	5.	The pendency of an unlawful detainer action or an unlawful detainer judgement shall not prevent the disbursement of funds to a tenant. The General Manager shall take into account the facts and circumstances of the unlawful detainer action.	6.	The General Manager shall deny the application where it determines that the application is intended, in whole or in part, to circumvent the provisions of this article.&#xA0; A debt incurred subsequent to notice to a creditor that the building was under consideration for or had been selected for participation in REAP, shall be presumed, subject to rebuttal, to be for the purpose of circumventing the provisions of this article.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><unit></unit></prefixes><entire_prefix></entire_prefix><prefix_anchor></prefix_anchor><level>1</level></unit></text></law>
