<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><section_number>21.26</section_number><edition_id>1</edition_id><section_id>2959</section_id><structure_id>19</structure_id><catch_line>Empowerment Zone &#x2013; City Business Tax Reductions, Limitations, And Exemptions.</catch_line><history></history><full_text>&#xA0; EMPOWERMENT ZONE &#x2013; CITY BUSINESS TAX REDUCTIONS, LIMITATIONS, AND EXEMPTIONS.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 172,358, Eff. 1/31/99.)

	(a)	Minimum Business Tax.&#xA0; After payment of a minimum business tax of $25.00, the amount of business tax relief to a person engaged in business at a location in the business tax economic incentive area described in Subsection (j) but not excluded from such tax relief by Subsection (h) shall be an exemption from the next $500.00 in business tax liability.

	(b)	Time Period of Business Tax Relief.&#xA0; The business tax relief described in Subsection (a) of this section shall be for the tax period beginning on or after January 1, 1995 and ending on or before the termination of the City&#x2019;s Empowerment Zone as established by the City Council by ordinance.&#xA0; The time period for business tax relief for census tracts that are added to the City&#x2019;s business tax economic incentive area will commence on the effective date of the Ordinance adding the census tracts and cover the entire calendar year.

	A person will only be entitled to the additional business tax relief provided for in Subsections (c), (d), (e), and (f) for up to a maximum period of five years.

	(c)	Additional Business Tax Relief for Existing Businesses Within the Business Tax Economic Incentive Area.&#xA0; Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, for the tax years beginning on January 1, 1999 the annual business taxes paid starting in 1999 by any person for a business located within the business tax economic incentive area described in Subsection (j) on or after January 1, 1998, shall not exceed the business taxes paid by such person for the year ended December 31, 1998.&#xA0; Such additional relief shall be for a period of up to five years, as set forth in Subsection (b) above.

	(d)	Business Tax Relief for Existing Businesses Within the City Relocating into the Business Tax Economic Incentive Area.&#xA0; Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, the annual business taxes paid during any taxable year by any person for a business (1) located within the City of Los Angeles but outside the business tax economic incentive area on or before December 31, 1998 and (2) which relocates its business activity within the business tax economic incentive area on or after January 1, 1999, shall not exceed the annual business taxes paid by such person during the tax year during which the business relocated into the business tax economic incentive area, subject to the relief provided in Subsection (a) above.&#xA0; Such additional relief shall be for a period of up to five years as set forth in Subsection (b) above.

	(e)	Business Tax Relief for Existing Businesses Outside the City Relocating Into the Business Tax Economic Incentive Area.&#xA0; Any person whose business was located outside the City of Los Angeles as of December 31, 1997 and which locates its business activity within the business tax economic incentive area on or after January 1, 1998, shall pay no business taxes other than the $25 minimum tax specified in Subsection (a) above for up to a five-year period as set forth in Subsection (b) above.

	(f)	Business Tax Relief for Newly Established Businesses Within the Business Tax Economic Incentive Area.&#xA0; Any person who starts a &#x201C;newly established business&#x201D; as defined in Section 21.00 (c) of this Code within the business tax economic incentive area on or after January 1, 1998 shall pay no business taxes other than the $25 minimum business tax specified in Subsection (a) above for up to a five-year period as set forth in Subsection (b) above.

	(g)	Change of Ownership of Existing Businesses.&#xA0; New proprietors of pre-existing businesses located within the business tax economic incentive area shall not be eligible to receive the incentives set forth in Subsection (e) and (f) above.

	(h)	Excluded Businesses.&#xA0; The business tax relief described in Subsections (a) through (f) of this section is available to all business tax classifications located within the business tax economic incentive area except that no business tax exemption, waiver, decrease or freeze shall be available to any person whose primary activity at a location is the sale of alcoholic beverages for off-premises consumption or the sale of guns and ammunition, or which is an&#xA0; &#x201C;adult entertainment business&#x201D; as defined in the Los Angeles Municipal Code Section 12.70B.

	(i)	Conditions to Receive Tax Exemption.&#xA0; The Director of Finance shall determine that one of the following conditions applies to each person seeking business tax relief under Subsections (e) and (f) above unless application of said conditions is waived by the Mayor&#x2019;s Office.

	(1)	The business pays all of its work force at a rate at least equal to the living wage as identified in the City&#x2019;s Living Wage Ordinance in Los Angeles Administrative Code Section 10.37.

	(2)	The business provides goods or services that are urgently needed in the business tax economic incentive area.

	(3)	The business can show proof of a significant investment in its workforce (For example: job training, childcare, retirement or investment programs; health or life insurance programs).

	(4)	A newly established business in the business tax economic incentive area hires at least 50% of its workforce locally from the business tax economic incentive area, or the buffer zone.

	The Mayor&#x2019;s Office shall provide annual reports to the Community and Economic Development Committee of the Council of waivers granted and the justification for those waivers.

	(j)	Description of Business Tax Economic Incentive Area.&#xA0; The business tax economic incentive area shall lie within the boundaries of the federal Empowerment Zone except that the business license tax economic incentive area shall extend beyond the boundaries of the Empowerment Zone to include both sides of a street in which there is business activity where only one side of that street is included in the Empowerment Zone.

	(1)	The business tax economic incentive area consists of the area included within the following United States Census Tract numbers, as extended by this subsection where applicable:

1041.020, 1047.010, 2045.000, 2051.000, 2060.000, 2062.000, 2063.000, 2073.000, 2260.000, 2270.000, 2281.000, 2282.000, 2286.000, 2287.000, 2288.000, 2289.000, 2291.000, 2371.000, 2372.000, 2383,000, 2392.000. 2393.000, 2397.000, 2400.000, 2402.000, 2405.000, 2408.000, 2409.000, 2420.000, 2421.000, 2422.000, 2423.000, 2426.000, 2427.000, 2430.000, 2431.000

	(2)	The map set forth below illustrates the location of the United States Census Tracts listed in Paragraph (1) of this subsection that comprise the business tax economic incentive area.&#xA0; The boundaries of said business tax economic incentive area are extended as set forth in this subsection where applicable.

LOCATION OF UNITED STATES CENSUS TRACTS THAT COMPRISE BUSINESS TAX ECONOMIC INCENTIVE AREA
(NOT ALL TRACTS PICTURED ARE LOCATED IN BUSINESS TAX ECONOMIC INCENTIVE AREA &#x2013; SEE L.A.M.C. SEC. 21.26(j)(1))

[Editor&#x2019;s Note:&#xA0; The map referred to in this section is on file in the official City documents located in the Office of the City Clerk in Council File No. CF-97-0401-S1.]

	(3)	The business tax economic incentive area is described in the table set forth below.&#xA0; The boundaries of said area are extended as set forth in this subsection where applicable.

BUSINESS TAX ECONOMIC INCENTIVE AREA FOR THE CITY OF LOS ANGELES

	The table describes both part A and part B in a continuous loop.&#xA0; The loop starts southward by describing part A&#x2019;s western half and going down to the Slauson and South Central Avenue intersection where part B begins.&#xA0; At the intersection the loop travels in a westwardly direction around part B.&#xA0; Eventually the loop travels back North to describe part A&#x2019;s eastern half.

SECTION ONE
FIRST HALF OF PART A
INTERSECTION OF N. BROADWAY AND THE LOS ANGELES RIVER


  
    
      
        BEGINNING POINT
      
      
        DIRECTION
      
      
        ENDING LIMIT
      
    
    
      
        N. Broadway
      
      
        Southwest to
      
      
        College Street
      
    
    
      
        College Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        N. Alameda
      
    
    
      
        N. Alameda
      
      
        South to
      
      
        Temple Street
      
    
    
      
        Temple Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        San Pedro
      
    
    
      
        San Pedro
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 1st
      
    
    
      
        E. 1st
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Los Angeles Street
      
    
    
      
        Los Angeles Street
      
      
        South to
      
      
        2nd Street
      
    
    
      
        2nd Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        S. Hill
      
    
    
      
        S. Hill
      
      
        South to
      
      
        9th Street
      
    
    
      
        9th Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Maple Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Maple Ave.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 21st Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 21st Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Central Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Central Ave.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        42nd Street
      
    
    
      
        42nd Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Avalon
      
    
    
      
        Avalon
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 48th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 48th Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        McKinley Ave.
      
    
    
      
        McKinley Ave.
      
      
        North to&#xA0;
        &amp; back up
      
      
        E. 48th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 48th Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Central Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Central Ave.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        Slauson Ave.
      
    
  



BEGINNING OF PART B OF SECTION ONE
INTERSECTION OF CENTRAL AVE. &amp; SLAUSON AVE.


  
    
      
        BEGINNING POINT
      
      
        DIRECTION
      
      
        ENDING LIMIT
      
    
    
      
        Slauson Ave.
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Van Ness Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Van Ness Ave.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        62nd Street
      
    
    
      
        62nd Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        S. Broadway Ave.
      
    
    
      
        S. Broadway
      
      
        South to
      
      
        Florence Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Florence Ave.
      
      
        East to
      
      
        S. Central Ave.
      
    
    
      
        S. Central Ave.
      
      
        North to X-section
      
      
        Slauson Ave.
      
    
  



SECOND HALF OF PART A SECTION ONE
INTERSECTION OF S. CENTRAL &amp; SLAUSON


  
    
      
        BEGINNING POINT
      
      
        DIRECTION
      
      
        ENDING LIMIT
      
    
    
      
        Slauson Ave.
      
      
        East to
      
      
        S. Alameda
      
    
    
      
        S. Alameda
      
      
        North to
      
      
        E. 25th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 25th Street
      
      
        East to &amp; following
      
      
        Southern City Limits With Vernon
      
    
    
      
        Southern City Limits with Vernon
      
      
        Follow to
      
      
        Spence Street
      
    
    
      
        Spence Street
      
      
        North to
      
      
        E. 8th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 8th Street
      
      
        Northwest to
      
      
        Soto Street
      
    
    
      
        Soto Street
      
      
        North to
      
      
        Santa Monica FWY.
      
    
    
      
        Santa Monica FWY.
      
      
        West to
      
      
        S. Boyle Ave.
      
    
    
      
        S. Boyle Ave.
      
      
        North to
      
      
        Golden State FWY.
      
    
    
      
        Golden State FWY.
      
      
        North to
      
      
        E. 4th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 4th Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        N. State Street
      
    
    
      
        N. State Street
      
      
        North to
      
      
        E. 1st Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 1st Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Los Angeles River
      
    
    
      
        Los Angeles River
      
      
        North to
      
      
        N. Broadway
      
    
  



END OF SECTION ONE (PARTS A&amp;B)


SECTION TWO
INTERSECTION OF S. CENTRAL AVE. &amp; E. MANCHESTER


  
    
      
        BEGINNING POINT
      
      
        DIRECTION
      
      
        ENDING LIMIT
      
    
    
      
        E. Manchester
      
      
        West to
      
      
        San Pedro Street
      
    
    
      
        San Pedro Street
      
      
        North to
      
      
        E. 79th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 79th Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        S. Vermont Ave.
      
    
    
      
        S. Vermont Ave.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        Manchester Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Manchester Ave.
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Figueroa
      
    
    
      
        Figueroa
      
      
        South to
      
      
        104th Street
      
    
    
      
        104th Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Wall Street
      
    
    
      
        Wall Street
      
      
        North to
      
      
        93rd Street
      
    
    
      
        93rd Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        E. City Limits with Walnut Park
      
    
    
      
        E. City Limits with Walnut Park
      
      
        North to
      
      
        Intersection of Manchester &amp; S. Central Avenues
      
    
  



END OF SECTION TWO


SECTION THREE
INTERSECTION OF 104TH &amp; SAN PEDRO STREET


  
    
      
        BEGINNING POINT
      
      
        DIRECTION
      
      
        ENDING LIMIT
      
    
    
      
        San Pedro St.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        Imperial Hwy
      
    
    
      
        Imperial Hwy
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Wadsworth &amp; E. 114th
      
    
    
      
        114th St.
      
      
        East to
      
      
        S. Central Ave
      
    
    
      
        S. Central Ave
      
      
        South to
      
      
        Imperial Hwy
      
    
    
      
        Imperial Hwy.
      
      
        East to
      
      
        E. City/County Limits at Mona Blvd.
      
    
    
      
        E. City/County Limits at Mona Blvd.
      
      
        North to
      
      
        92nd Street
      
    
    
      
        92nd Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Maine St.
      
    
    
      
        Maine St.
      
      
        North
      
      
        E. 91st Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 91st Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Compton
      
    
    
      
        Compton
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 92nd Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 92nd Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Success Street
      
    
    
      
        Success Street
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 103rd Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 103rd Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        S. Central Ave
      
    
    
      
        S. Central Ave
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 104th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 104th Street
      
      
        West to X-section
      
      
        San Pedro
      
    
  


END OF SECTION THREE


SECTION FOUR
INTERSECTION OF THE VAN NUYS BLVD. &amp; THE FOOTHILL FWY.


  
    
      
        BEGINNING POINT
      
      
        DIRECTION
      
      
        ENDING LIMIT
      
    
    
      
        Van Nuys Blvd.
      
      
        Southwest to
      
      
        San Fernando Rd.
      
    
    
      
        San Fernando Rd.
      
      
        Southeast to
      
      
        Pierce Street
      
    
    
      
        Pierce Street
      
      
        Northeast to
      
      
        Glenoaks Blvd.
      
    
    
      
        Glenoaks Blvd.
      
      
        Southeast to
      
      
        Osborne Street
      
    
    
      
        Osborne Street
      
      
        North to
      
      
        West side of the Hansen Dam
      
    
    
      
        West side of the Hansen Dam
      
      
        Follow East to the
      
      
        Rancho Tujunga Rancho Ex Mission DE San Fernando line
      
    
    
      
        Rancho Tujunga Rancho Ex Mission DE San Fernando line
      
      
        North to
      
      
        Foothill FWY.
      
    
    
      
        Foothill FWY.	
      
      
        West to X-section
      
      
        Van Nuys Blvd.
      
    
  


END OF SECTION FOUR

	(k)	Administration.&#xA0; The business tax economic incentive program shall be administered by the Director of Finance who shall notify all known persons engaged in business at a location in the business tax economic incentive area of the program.

	(l)	Business Tax Forms.&#xA0; It shall be the responsibility of each person engaged in business to compare its activity to the tax relief provided by this section and complete its business tax forms accordingly.

	(m)	Annual Report to the Mayor and Council by Director of the Office of Administrative and Research Services.&#xA0; The Director of the Office of Administrative and Research Services shall report annually on the measurable costs and benefits of the Business Tax Economic Incentive program.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 173,304, Eff. 6/30/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)</full_text><order_by>26</order_by><ancestry><unit id="19" label="article"><name>Business Taxes</name><identifier>1</identifier><url>/2/1/</url></unit><unit id="1" label="chapter"><name>Licenses, Permits, Business Regulations</name><identifier>2</identifier><url>/2/</url></unit></ancestry><structure_contents><unit id="3386"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.00</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/21.00/</url><token>21.00</token></unit><unit id="3139"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.01</section_number><catch_line>Unlawful Business Not Authorized.</catch_line><url>/21.01/</url><token>21.01</token></unit><unit id="986"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.02</section_number><catch_line>Constitutional Exemptions.</catch_line><url>/21.02/</url><token>21.02</token></unit><unit id="1313"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.03</section_number><catch_line>Imposition Of Tax.</catch_line><url>/21.03/</url><token>21.03</token></unit><unit id="2833"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.03.1</section_number><catch_line>Automatic Tax Rate Reduction.</catch_line><url>/21.03.1/</url><token>21.03.1</token></unit><unit id="2639"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.04</section_number><catch_line>Due Dates.</catch_line><url>/21.04/</url><token>21.04</token></unit><unit id="287"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.05</section_number><catch_line>Delinquent Dates &#x2013;Interest &#x2013; Penalties.</catch_line><url>/21.05/</url><token>21.05</token></unit><unit id="1321"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.06</section_number><catch_line>Separate Registration Certificate Required For Each Location And Each Business Tax Classification.</catch_line><url>/21.06/</url><token>21.06</token></unit><unit id="135"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.06.1</section_number><catch_line>Single Primary Tax Classification Election.</catch_line><url>/21.06.1/</url><token>21.06.1</token></unit><unit id="3840"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.07</section_number><catch_line>Refunds Of Overpayments.</catch_line><url>/21.07/</url><token>21.07</token></unit><unit id="2938"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.08</section_number><catch_line>Business Tax Registration Certificate &#x2014; Form.</catch_line><url>/21.08/</url><token>21.08</token></unit><unit id="2372"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.09</section_number><catch_line>Business Tax Registration Certificates &#x2014; Posting And Keeping.</catch_line><url>/21.09/</url><token>21.09</token></unit><unit id="2408"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.10</section_number><catch_line>Business Tax Registration Certificates &#x2014; Charge For Duplication.</catch_line><url>/21.10/</url><token>21.10</token></unit><unit id="1153"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.11</section_number><catch_line>Business Tax Registration Certificate &#x2014;Transfer.</catch_line><url>/21.11/</url><token>21.11</token></unit><unit id="3208"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.12</section_number><catch_line>Business Tax Registration Certificates &#x2014;Suspension.</catch_line><url>/21.12/</url><token>21.12</token></unit><unit id="3457"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.13</section_number><catch_line>Newly Established Businesses &#x2013; Computation Of Business Tax.</catch_line><url>/21.13/</url><token>21.13</token></unit><unit id="859"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.14</section_number><catch_line>Written Statements &#x2013; When Required &#x2013;Computation Of The Tax.</catch_line><url>/21.14/</url><token>21.14</token></unit><unit id="4177"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.15</section_number><catch_line>Director Of Finance &#x2013; Duty To Enforce &#x2013;Rules And Regulations.</catch_line><url>/21.15/</url><token>21.15</token></unit><unit id="4100"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.16</section_number><catch_line>Assessment &#x2014; Administrative Remedy.</catch_line><url>/21.16/</url><token>21.16</token></unit><unit id="2921"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.17</section_number><catch_line>Confidential Character Of Information Obtained&#x2013; Disclosure Unlawful.</catch_line><url>/21.17/</url><token>21.17</token></unit><unit id="1223"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.18</section_number><catch_line>Delinquent Taxes &#x2013; Installment Payment.</catch_line><url>/21.18/</url><token>21.18</token></unit><unit id="1532"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.19</section_number><catch_line>Delinquent Taxes &#x2013; Suit For Recovery.</catch_line><url>/21.19/</url><token>21.19</token></unit><unit id="3349"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.20</section_number><catch_line>Delinquent Taxes &#x2013; Debt Not Discharged By Penal Conviction.</catch_line><url>/21.20/</url><token>21.20</token></unit><unit id="2132"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.21</section_number><catch_line>Delinquent Taxes &#x2013; Uncollectible.</catch_line><url>/21.21/</url><token>21.21</token></unit><unit id="4086"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.22</section_number><catch_line>Religious, Charity, Etc.; Procedure For Issuance Of Tax Exempt Registration Certificates.</catch_line><url>/21.22/</url><token>21.22</token></unit><unit id="3446"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.23</section_number><catch_line>Effect Of Repeals And Amendments.</catch_line><url>/21.23/</url><token>21.23</token></unit><unit id="3020"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.24</section_number><catch_line>Exemption For Persons Having Equal Or Greater Payroll Expense Tax Liability.</catch_line><url>/21.24/</url><token>21.24</token></unit><unit id="2672"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.25</section_number><catch_line>Relief For Earthquake Interruption.</catch_line><url>/21.25/</url><token>21.25</token></unit><unit id="2959"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.26</section_number><catch_line>Empowerment Zone - City Business Tax Reductions, Limitations, And Exemptions.</catch_line><url>/21.26/</url><token>21.26</token></unit><unit id="3092"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.27</section_number><catch_line>Entertainment And Multimedia Business Tax Limitations.</catch_line><url>/21.27/</url><token>21.27</token></unit><unit id="992"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.28</section_number><catch_line>Fiscal Year Reporting.</catch_line><url>/21.28/</url><token>21.28</token></unit><unit id="3672"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.29</section_number><catch_line>Small Business Exemption.</catch_line><url>/21.29/</url><token>21.29</token></unit><unit id="1797"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.30</section_number><catch_line>New Business Exemption.</catch_line><url>/21.30/</url><token>21.30</token></unit><unit id="2622"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.31</section_number><catch_line>Settlement Bureau.</catch_line><url>/21.31/</url><token>21.31</token></unit><unit id="3785"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.32</section_number><catch_line>Rewards For Information.</catch_line><url>/21.32/</url><token>21.32</token></unit><unit id="2451"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.33</section_number><catch_line>Tax Rates.</catch_line><url>/21.33/</url><token>21.33</token></unit><unit id="3764"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.41</section_number><catch_line>Gross Receipts Fund Class 1.</catch_line><url>/21.41/</url><token>21.41</token></unit><unit id="1839"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.42</section_number><catch_line>Gross Receipts Fund Class 2.</catch_line><url>/21.42/</url><token>21.42</token></unit><unit id="1484"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.43</section_number><catch_line>Gross Receipts Fund Class 3.</catch_line><url>/21.43/</url><token>21.43</token></unit><unit id="3800"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.44</section_number><catch_line>Gross Receipts Fund Class 4.</catch_line><url>/21.44/</url><token>21.44</token></unit><unit id="3973"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.45</section_number><catch_line>Gross Receipts Fund Class 5.</catch_line><url>/21.45/</url><token>21.45</token></unit><unit id="3401"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.46</section_number><catch_line>Gross Receipts Fund Class 6.</catch_line><url>/21.46/</url><token>21.46</token></unit><unit id="786"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.47</section_number><catch_line>Gross Receipts Fund Class 7.</catch_line><url>/21.47/</url><token>21.47</token></unit><unit id="3868"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.48</section_number><catch_line>Gross Receipts Fund Class 8.</catch_line><url>/21.48/</url><token>21.48</token></unit><unit id="22"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.49</section_number><catch_line>Gross Receipts Fund Class 9.</catch_line><url>/21.49/</url><token>21.49</token></unit><unit id="2094"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.50</section_number><catch_line>Taxation Of Medical Marijuana Collectives.</catch_line><url>/21.50/</url><token>21.50</token></unit><unit id="963"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.53</section_number><catch_line>Amusement Park.</catch_line><url>/21.53/</url><token>21.53</token></unit><unit id="121"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.55</section_number><catch_line>Auctioneer.</catch_line><url>/21.55/</url><token>21.55</token></unit><unit id="3750"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.56</section_number><catch_line>Auto Park</catch_line><url>/21.56/</url><token>21.56</token></unit><unit id="2828"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.59</section_number><catch_line>Baseball, Football, Etc.</catch_line><url>/21.59/</url><token>21.59</token></unit><unit id="4153"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.62</section_number><catch_line>Billiards, Etc.</catch_line><url>/21.62/</url><token>21.62</token></unit><unit id="3553"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.63</section_number><catch_line>Amusement Machines.</catch_line><url>/21.63/</url><token>21.63</token></unit><unit id="886"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.64</section_number><catch_line>Coin-Operated Phonographs And Music Machines.</catch_line><url>/21.64/</url><token>21.64</token></unit><unit id="106"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.65</section_number><catch_line>Vending Machines.</catch_line><url>/21.65/</url><token>21.65</token></unit><unit id="4010"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.65.1</section_number><catch_line>Coin-Operated Scales And Service Machines.</catch_line><url>/21.65.1/</url><token>21.65.1</token></unit><unit id="4093"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.70</section_number><catch_line>Bowling Alley, Skee-Ball Shuffleboard, Etc.</catch_line><url>/21.70/</url><token>21.70</token></unit><unit id="2800"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.74</section_number><catch_line>Circuses.</catch_line><url>/21.74/</url><token>21.74</token></unit><unit id="460"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.75</section_number><catch_line>Side Shows, Carnivals, Concessions.</catch_line><url>/21.75/</url><token>21.75</token></unit><unit id="1734"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.78</section_number><catch_line>Collection Agencies.</catch_line><url>/21.78/</url><token>21.78</token></unit><unit id="240"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.79</section_number><catch_line>Commission Brokers.</catch_line><url>/21.79/</url><token>21.79</token></unit><unit id="3209"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.80</section_number><catch_line>Independent Telemarketing Agency.</catch_line><url>/21.80/</url><token>21.80</token></unit><unit id="3925"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.83</section_number><catch_line>Dance Hall.</catch_line><url>/21.83/</url><token>21.83</token></unit><unit id="3285"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.85</section_number><catch_line>Public Dance.</catch_line><url>/21.85/</url><token>21.85</token></unit><unit id="577"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.94</section_number><catch_line>Rides.</catch_line><url>/21.94/</url><token>21.94</token></unit><unit id="453"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.98</section_number><catch_line>Office Commercial Buildings, Etc., Rentals.</catch_line><url>/21.98/</url><token>21.98</token></unit><unit id="2915"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.98.1</section_number><catch_line>Swap Meet Operator.</catch_line><url>/21.98.1/</url><token>21.98.1</token></unit><unit id="1721"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.98.2</section_number><catch_line>Antique Show And Collectors&#x2019; Exchange Show Promoter.</catch_line><url>/21.98.2/</url><token>21.98.2</token></unit><unit id="2654"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.99</section_number><catch_line>Renting Accommodations.</catch_line><url>/21.99/</url><token>21.99</token></unit><unit id="4094"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.102</section_number><catch_line>Laundry, Cleaning And Dyeing Agent, Collector, Linen Supply, Shoe Repair.</catch_line><url>/21.102/</url><token>21.102</token></unit><unit id="3665"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.108</section_number><catch_line>Money Lenders.</catch_line><url>/21.108/</url><token>21.108</token></unit><unit id="3823"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.109</section_number><catch_line>Motion Picture, Television And Radio Producers.</catch_line><url>/21.109/</url><token>21.109</token></unit><unit id="715"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.124</section_number><catch_line>Oil Wells.</catch_line><url>/21.124/</url><token>21.124</token></unit><unit id="2325"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.141</section_number><catch_line>Warehouse &#x2013; Storage Of Goods.</catch_line><url>/21.141/</url><token>21.141</token></unit><unit id="1832"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.142</section_number><catch_line>Stevedores.</catch_line><url>/21.142/</url><token>21.142</token></unit><unit id="3610"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.143</section_number><catch_line>Tugboat And Barge Operators.</catch_line><url>/21.143/</url><token>21.143</token></unit><unit id="1927"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.147</section_number><catch_line>Theatre.</catch_line><url>/21.147/</url><token>21.147</token></unit><unit id="2812"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.166</section_number><catch_line>Merchandise Wholesale Selling.</catch_line><url>/21.166/</url><token>21.166</token></unit><unit id="968"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.167</section_number><catch_line>Merchandise &#x2013; Retail Selling.</catch_line><url>/21.167/</url><token>21.167</token></unit><unit id="4173"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.167.1</section_number><catch_line>Sales Of Firearms And Ammunition.</catch_line><url>/21.167.1/</url><token>21.167.1</token></unit><unit id="2302"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.168.1</section_number><catch_line>Out Of State Sales.</catch_line><url>/21.168.1/</url><token>21.168.1</token></unit><unit id="1061"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.168.2</section_number><catch_line>Sale For Convenience.</catch_line><url>/21.168.2/</url><token>21.168.2</token></unit><unit id="1130"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.168.3</section_number><catch_line>Certain Solicitors Deemed Employees.</catch_line><url>/21.168.3/</url><token>21.168.3</token></unit><unit id="3420"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.168.4</section_number><catch_line>Exemption &#x2013; Temporary Exhibitors At Tradeshows.</catch_line><url>/21.168.4/</url><token>21.168.4</token></unit><unit id="2858"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.168.5</section_number><catch_line>Certified Producers Deemed Employees.</catch_line><url>/21.168.5/</url><token>21.168.5</token></unit><unit id="2995"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.169</section_number><catch_line>Christmas Trees.</catch_line><url>/21.169/</url><token>21.169</token></unit><unit id="1790"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.170</section_number><catch_line>Christmas Tree Lot Clean-Up Deposits.</catch_line><url>/21.170/</url><token>21.170</token></unit><unit id="90"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.171</section_number><catch_line>Retailers Of New Passenger Motor Vehicles.</catch_line><url>/21.171/</url><token>21.171</token></unit><unit id="438"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.187</section_number><catch_line>Common Carrier Bus.</catch_line><url>/21.187/</url><token>21.187</token></unit><unit id="1180"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.188</section_number><catch_line>Contractors.</catch_line><url>/21.188/</url><token>21.188</token></unit><unit id="606"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.189.1</section_number><catch_line>Miscellaneous Services.</catch_line><url>/21.189.1/</url><token>21.189.1</token></unit><unit id="3010"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.189.2</section_number><catch_line>Radio And Television Broadcaster.</catch_line><url>/21.189.2/</url><token>21.189.2</token></unit><unit id="882"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.189.3</section_number><catch_line>Child Care Providers.</catch_line><url>/21.189.3/</url><token>21.189.3</token></unit><unit id="1269"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.189.4</section_number><catch_line>Multimedia Businesses.</catch_line><url>/21.189.4/</url><token>21.189.4</token></unit><unit id="1082"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.190</section_number><catch_line>Professions And Occupations.</catch_line><url>/21.190/</url><token>21.190</token></unit><unit id="3470"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.190.1</section_number><catch_line>Exemption.</catch_line><url>/21.190.1/</url><token>21.190.1</token></unit><unit id="2849"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.191</section_number><catch_line>Health Maintenance Organizations.</catch_line><url>/21.191/</url><token>21.191</token></unit><unit id="691"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.192</section_number><catch_line>Personal Property Rental.</catch_line><url>/21.192/</url><token>21.192</token></unit><unit id="128"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.192.1</section_number><catch_line>Rental &#x2013; Out Of State Property.</catch_line><url>/21.192.1/</url><token>21.192.1</token></unit><unit id="2572"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.193</section_number><catch_line>Sale Of Real Property.</catch_line><url>/21.193/</url><token>21.193</token></unit><unit id="686"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.194</section_number><catch_line>Transporting Persons For Hire.</catch_line><url>/21.194/</url><token>21.194</token></unit><unit id="3292"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.195</section_number><catch_line>Trucking &#x2013; Hauling</catch_line><url>/21.195/</url><token>21.195</token></unit><unit id="1629"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.196</section_number><catch_line>Miscellaneous Trucking.</catch_line><url>/21.196/</url><token>21.196</token></unit><unit id="3790"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.197</section_number><catch_line>Telephone Companies.</catch_line><url>/21.197/</url><token>21.197</token></unit><unit id="1096"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.199</section_number><catch_line>Sales Tax.</catch_line><url>/21.199/</url><token>21.199</token></unit></structure_contents><next_section id="3092"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.27</section_number><catch_line>Entertainment And Multimedia Business Tax Limitations.</catch_line><url>/21.27/</url><token>21.27</token></next_section><metadata></metadata><references></references><url>/21.26/</url><token>21.26</token><formats><txt>/21.26.txt</txt><json>/21.26.xml</json></formats><dublin_core><Title>Empowerment Zone &#x2013; City Business Tax Reductions, Limitations, And Exemptions.</Title><Type>Text</Type><Format>text/html</Format><Identifier>&#xA7; 21.26</Identifier><Relation>Los Angeles Municipal Code</Relation></dublin_core><plain_text>                            LOS ANGELES MUNICIPAL CODE

EMPOWERMENT ZONE &#x2013; CITY BUSINESS TAX REDUCTIONS, LIMITATIONS, AND EXEMPTIONS.
(&#xA7; 21.26)

&#xA0; EMPOWERMENT ZONE &#x2013; CITY BUSINESS TAX REDUCTIONS, LIMITATIONS, AND
EXEMPTIONS.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 172,358, Eff. 1/31/99.)	(a)	Minimum Business Tax.&#xA0; After
payment of a minimum business tax of $25.00, the amount of business tax relief
to a person engaged in business at a location in the business tax economic
incentive area described in Subsection (j) but not excluded from such tax relief
by Subsection (h) shall be an exemption from the next $500.00 in business tax
liability.	(b)	Time Period of Business Tax Relief.&#xA0; The business tax relief
described in Subsection (a) of this section shall be for the tax period
beginning on or after January 1, 1995 and ending on or before the termination of
the City&#x2019;s Empowerment Zone as established by the City Council by ordinance.&#xA0;
The time period for business tax relief for census tracts that are added to the
City&#x2019;s business tax economic incentive area will commence on the effective
date of the Ordinance adding the census tracts and cover the entire calendar
year.	A person will only be entitled to the additional business tax relief
provided for in Subsections (c), (d), (e), and (f) for up to a maximum period of
five years.	(c)	Additional Business Tax Relief for Existing Businesses Within
the Business Tax Economic Incentive Area.&#xA0; Notwithstanding any other provision
of this Code, for the tax years beginning on January 1, 1999 the annual business
taxes paid starting in 1999 by any person for a business located within the
business tax economic incentive area described in Subsection (j) on or after
January 1, 1998, shall not exceed the business taxes paid by such person for the
year ended December 31, 1998.&#xA0; Such additional relief shall be for a period of
up to five years, as set forth in Subsection (b) above.	(d)	Business Tax Relief
for Existing Businesses Within the City Relocating into the Business Tax
Economic Incentive Area.&#xA0; Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, the
annual business taxes paid during any taxable year by any person for a business
(1) located within the City of Los Angeles but outside the business tax economic
incentive area on or before December 31, 1998 and (2) which relocates its
business activity within the business tax economic incentive area on or after
January 1, 1999, shall not exceed the annual business taxes paid by such person
during the tax year during which the business relocated into the business tax
economic incentive area, subject to the relief provided in Subsection (a)
above.&#xA0; Such additional relief shall be for a period of up to five years as set
forth in Subsection (b) above.	(e)	Business Tax Relief for Existing Businesses
Outside the City Relocating Into the Business Tax Economic Incentive Area.&#xA0; Any
person whose business was located outside the City of Los Angeles as of December
31, 1997 and which locates its business activity within the business tax
economic incentive area on or after January 1, 1998, shall pay no business taxes
other than the $25 minimum tax specified in Subsection (a) above for up to a
five-year period as set forth in Subsection (b) above.	(f)	Business Tax Relief
for Newly Established Businesses Within the Business Tax Economic Incentive
Area.&#xA0; Any person who starts a &#x201C;newly established business&#x201D; as defined in
Section 21.00 (c) of this Code within the business tax economic incentive area
on or after January 1, 1998 shall pay no business taxes other than the $25
minimum business tax specified in Subsection (a) above for up to a five-year
period as set forth in Subsection (b) above.	(g)	Change of Ownership of Existing
Businesses.&#xA0; New proprietors of pre-existing businesses located within the
business tax economic incentive area shall not be eligible to receive the
incentives set forth in Subsection (e) and (f) above.	(h)	Excluded Businesses.&#xA0;
The business tax relief described in Subsections (a) through (f) of this section
is available to all business tax classifications located within the business tax
economic incentive area except that no business tax exemption, waiver, decrease
or freeze shall be available to any person whose primary activity at a location
is the sale of alcoholic beverages for off-premises consumption or the sale of
guns and ammunition, or which is an&#xA0; &#x201C;adult entertainment business&#x201D; as
defined in the Los Angeles Municipal Code Section 12.70B.	(i)	Conditions to
Receive Tax Exemption.&#xA0; The Director of Finance shall determine that one of the
following conditions applies to each person seeking business tax relief under
Subsections (e) and (f) above unless application of said conditions is waived by
the Mayor&#x2019;s Office.	(1)	The business pays all of its work force at a rate at
least equal to the living wage as identified in the City&#x2019;s Living Wage
Ordinance in Los Angeles Administrative Code Section 10.37.	(2)	The business
provides goods or services that are urgently needed in the business tax economic
incentive area.	(3)	The business can show proof of a significant investment in
its workforce (For example: job training, childcare, retirement or investment
programs; health or life insurance programs).	(4)	A newly established business
in the business tax economic incentive area hires at least 50% of its workforce
locally from the business tax economic incentive area, or the buffer zone.	The
Mayor&#x2019;s Office shall provide annual reports to the Community and Economic
Development Committee of the Council of waivers granted and the justification
for those waivers.	(j)	Description of Business Tax Economic Incentive Area.&#xA0;
The business tax economic incentive area shall lie within the boundaries of the
federal Empowerment Zone except that the business license tax economic incentive
area shall extend beyond the boundaries of the Empowerment Zone to include both
sides of a street in which there is business activity where only one side of
that street is included in the Empowerment Zone.	(1)	The business tax economic
incentive area consists of the area included within the following United States
Census Tract numbers, as extended by this subsection where applicable:1041.020,
1047.010, 2045.000, 2051.000, 2060.000, 2062.000, 2063.000, 2073.000, 2260.000,
2270.000, 2281.000, 2282.000, 2286.000, 2287.000, 2288.000, 2289.000, 2291.000,
2371.000, 2372.000, 2383,000, 2392.000. 2393.000, 2397.000, 2400.000, 2402.000,
2405.000, 2408.000, 2409.000, 2420.000, 2421.000, 2422.000, 2423.000, 2426.000,
2427.000, 2430.000, 2431.000	(2)	The map set forth below illustrates the
location of the United States Census Tracts listed in Paragraph (1) of this
subsection that comprise the business tax economic incentive area.&#xA0; The
boundaries of said business tax economic incentive area are extended as set
forth in this subsection where applicable.LOCATION OF UNITED STATES CENSUS
TRACTS THAT COMPRISE BUSINESS TAX ECONOMIC INCENTIVE AREA
(NOT ALL TRACTS PICTURED ARE LOCATED IN BUSINESS TAX ECONOMIC INCENTIVE AREA &#x2013;
SEE L.A.M.C. SEC. 21.26(j)(1))[Editor&#x2019;s Note:&#xA0; The map referred to in this
section is on file in the official City documents located in the Office of the
City Clerk in Council File No. CF-97-0401-S1.]	(3)	The business tax economic
incentive area is described in the table set forth below.&#xA0; The boundaries of
said area are extended as set forth in this subsection where applicable.BUSINESS
TAX ECONOMIC INCENTIVE AREA FOR THE CITY OF LOS ANGELES	The table describes both
part A and part B in a continuous loop.&#xA0; The loop starts southward by
describing part A&#x2019;s western half and going down to the Slauson and South
Central Avenue intersection where part B begins.&#xA0; At the intersection the loop
travels in a westwardly direction around part B.&#xA0; Eventually the loop travels
back North to describe part A&#x2019;s eastern half.SECTION ONE
FIRST HALF OF PART A
INTERSECTION OF N. BROADWAY AND THE LOS ANGELES RIVER
  
    
      
        BEGINNING POINT
      
      
        DIRECTION
      
      
        ENDING LIMIT
      
    
    
      
        N. Broadway
      
      
        Southwest to
      
      
        College Street
      
    
    
      
        College Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        N. Alameda
      
    
    
      
        N. Alameda
      
      
        South to
      
      
        Temple Street
      
    
    
      
        Temple Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        San Pedro
      
    
    
      
        San Pedro
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 1st
      
    
    
      
        E. 1st
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Los Angeles Street
      
    
    
      
        Los Angeles Street
      
      
        South to
      
      
        2nd Street
      
    
    
      
        2nd Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        S. Hill
      
    
    
      
        S. Hill
      
      
        South to
      
      
        9th Street
      
    
    
      
        9th Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Maple Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Maple Ave.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 21st Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 21st Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Central Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Central Ave.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        42nd Street
      
    
    
      
        42nd Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Avalon
      
    
    
      
        Avalon
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 48th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 48th Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        McKinley Ave.
      
    
    
      
        McKinley Ave.
      
      
        North to&#xA0;
        &amp; back up
      
      
        E. 48th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 48th Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Central Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Central Ave.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        Slauson Ave.
      
    
  BEGINNING OF PART B OF SECTION ONE
INTERSECTION OF CENTRAL AVE. &amp; SLAUSON AVE.
  
    
      
        BEGINNING POINT
      
      
        DIRECTION
      
      
        ENDING LIMIT
      
    
    
      
        Slauson Ave.
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Van Ness Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Van Ness Ave.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        62nd Street
      
    
    
      
        62nd Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        S. Broadway Ave.
      
    
    
      
        S. Broadway
      
      
        South to
      
      
        Florence Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Florence Ave.
      
      
        East to
      
      
        S. Central Ave.
      
    
    
      
        S. Central Ave.
      
      
        North to X-section
      
      
        Slauson Ave.
      
    
  SECOND HALF OF PART A SECTION ONE
INTERSECTION OF S. CENTRAL &amp; SLAUSON
  
    
      
        BEGINNING POINT
      
      
        DIRECTION
      
      
        ENDING LIMIT
      
    
    
      
        Slauson Ave.
      
      
        East to
      
      
        S. Alameda
      
    
    
      
        S. Alameda
      
      
        North to
      
      
        E. 25th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 25th Street
      
      
        East to &amp; following
      
      
        Southern City Limits With Vernon
      
    
    
      
        Southern City Limits with Vernon
      
      
        Follow to
      
      
        Spence Street
      
    
    
      
        Spence Street
      
      
        North to
      
      
        E. 8th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 8th Street
      
      
        Northwest to
      
      
        Soto Street
      
    
    
      
        Soto Street
      
      
        North to
      
      
        Santa Monica FWY.
      
    
    
      
        Santa Monica FWY.
      
      
        West to
      
      
        S. Boyle Ave.
      
    
    
      
        S. Boyle Ave.
      
      
        North to
      
      
        Golden State FWY.
      
    
    
      
        Golden State FWY.
      
      
        North to
      
      
        E. 4th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 4th Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        N. State Street
      
    
    
      
        N. State Street
      
      
        North to
      
      
        E. 1st Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 1st Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Los Angeles River
      
    
    
      
        Los Angeles River
      
      
        North to
      
      
        N. Broadway
      
    
  END OF SECTION ONE (PARTS A&amp;B)
SECTION TWO
INTERSECTION OF S. CENTRAL AVE. &amp; E. MANCHESTER
  
    
      
        BEGINNING POINT
      
      
        DIRECTION
      
      
        ENDING LIMIT
      
    
    
      
        E. Manchester
      
      
        West to
      
      
        San Pedro Street
      
    
    
      
        San Pedro Street
      
      
        North to
      
      
        E. 79th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 79th Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        S. Vermont Ave.
      
    
    
      
        S. Vermont Ave.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        Manchester Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Manchester Ave.
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Figueroa
      
    
    
      
        Figueroa
      
      
        South to
      
      
        104th Street
      
    
    
      
        104th Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Wall Street
      
    
    
      
        Wall Street
      
      
        North to
      
      
        93rd Street
      
    
    
      
        93rd Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        E. City Limits with Walnut Park
      
    
    
      
        E. City Limits with Walnut Park
      
      
        North to
      
      
        Intersection of Manchester &amp; S. Central Avenues
      
    
  END OF SECTION TWO
SECTION THREE
INTERSECTION OF 104TH &amp; SAN PEDRO STREET
  
    
      
        BEGINNING POINT
      
      
        DIRECTION
      
      
        ENDING LIMIT
      
    
    
      
        San Pedro St.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        Imperial Hwy
      
    
    
      
        Imperial Hwy
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Wadsworth &amp; E. 114th
      
    
    
      
        114th St.
      
      
        East to
      
      
        S. Central Ave
      
    
    
      
        S. Central Ave
      
      
        South to
      
      
        Imperial Hwy
      
    
    
      
        Imperial Hwy.
      
      
        East to
      
      
        E. City/County Limits at Mona Blvd.
      
    
    
      
        E. City/County Limits at Mona Blvd.
      
      
        North to
      
      
        92nd Street
      
    
    
      
        92nd Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Maine St.
      
    
    
      
        Maine St.
      
      
        North
      
      
        E. 91st Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 91st Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Compton
      
    
    
      
        Compton
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 92nd Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 92nd Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Success Street
      
    
    
      
        Success Street
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 103rd Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 103rd Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        S. Central Ave
      
    
    
      
        S. Central Ave
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 104th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 104th Street
      
      
        West to X-section
      
      
        San Pedro
      
    
  
END OF SECTION THREE
SECTION FOUR
INTERSECTION OF THE VAN NUYS BLVD. &amp; THE FOOTHILL FWY.
  
    
      
        BEGINNING POINT
      
      
        DIRECTION
      
      
        ENDING LIMIT
      
    
    
      
        Van Nuys Blvd.
      
      
        Southwest to
      
      
        San Fernando Rd.
      
    
    
      
        San Fernando Rd.
      
      
        Southeast to
      
      
        Pierce Street
      
    
    
      
        Pierce Street
      
      
        Northeast to
      
      
        Glenoaks Blvd.
      
    
    
      
        Glenoaks Blvd.
      
      
        Southeast to
      
      
        Osborne Street
      
    
    
      
        Osborne Street
      
      
        North to
      
      
        West side of the Hansen Dam
      
    
    
      
        West side of the Hansen Dam
      
      
        Follow East to the
      
      
        Rancho Tujunga Rancho Ex Mission DE San Fernando line
      
    
    
      
        Rancho Tujunga Rancho Ex Mission DE San Fernando line
      
      
        North to
      
      
        Foothill FWY.
      
    
    
      
        Foothill FWY.	
      
      
        West to X-section
      
      
        Van Nuys Blvd.
      
    
  
END OF SECTION FOUR	(k)	Administration.&#xA0; The business tax economic incentive
program shall be administered by the Director of Finance who shall notify all
known persons engaged in business at a location in the business tax economic
incentive area of the program.	(l)	Business Tax Forms.&#xA0; It shall be the
responsibility of each person engaged in business to compare its activity to the
tax relief provided by this section and complete its business tax forms
accordingly.	(m)	Annual Report to the Mayor and Council by Director of the
Office of Administrative and Research Services.&#xA0; The Director of the Office of
Administrative and Research Services shall report annually on the measurable
costs and benefits of the Business Tax Economic Incentive program.&#xA0; (Amended by
Ord. No. 173,304, Eff. 6/30/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)
</plain_text><html>
					&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#xA0; EMPOWERMENT ZONE &#x2013; CITY BUSINESS TAX REDUCTIONS, LIMITATIONS, AND EXEMPTIONS.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 172,358, Eff. 1/31/99.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(a)	Minimum Business Tax.&#xA0; After payment of a minimum business tax of $25.00, the amount of business tax relief to a person engaged in business at a location in the business tax economic incentive area described in Subsection (j) but not excluded from such tax relief by Subsection (h) shall be an exemption from the next $500.00 in business tax liability.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(b)	Time Period of Business Tax Relief.&#xA0; The business tax relief described in Subsection (a) of this section shall be for the tax period beginning on or after January 1, 1995 and ending on or before the termination of the City&#x2019;s Empowerment Zone as established by the City Council by &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; The time period for business tax relief for census tracts that are added to the City&#x2019;s business tax economic incentive area will commence on the effective date of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Ordinance&lt;/span&gt; adding the census tracts and cover the entire calendar year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	A person will only be entitled to the additional business tax relief provided for in Subsections (c), (d), (e), and (f) for up to a maximum period of five years.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(c)	Additional Business Tax Relief for Existing Businesses Within the Business Tax Economic Incentive Area.&#xA0; Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, for the tax years beginning on January 1, 1999 the annual business taxes paid starting in 1999 by any person for a business located within the business tax economic incentive area described in Subsection (j) on or after January 1, 1998, shall not exceed the business taxes paid by such person for the year ended December 31, 1998.&#xA0; Such additional relief shall be for a period of up to five years, as set forth in Subsection (b) above.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(d)	Business Tax Relief for Existing Businesses Within the City Relocating into the Business Tax Economic Incentive Area.&#xA0; Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, the annual business taxes paid during any taxable year by any person for a business (1) located within the City of Los Angeles but outside the business tax economic incentive area on or before December 31, 1998 and (2) which relocates its business activity within the business tax economic incentive area on or after January 1, 1999, shall not exceed the annual business taxes paid by such person during the tax year during which the business relocated into the business tax economic incentive area, subject to the relief provided in Subsection (a) above.&#xA0; Such additional relief shall be for a period of up to five years as set forth in Subsection (b) above.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(e)	Business Tax Relief for Existing Businesses Outside the City Relocating Into the Business Tax Economic Incentive Area.&#xA0; Any person whose business was located outside the City of Los Angeles as of December 31, 1997 and which locates its business activity within the business tax economic incentive area on or after January 1, 1998, shall pay no business taxes other than the $25 minimum tax specified in Subsection (a) above for up to a five-year period as set forth in Subsection (b) above.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(f)	Business Tax Relief for Newly Established Businesses Within the Business Tax Economic Incentive Area.&#xA0; Any person who starts a &#x201C;newly established business&#x201D; as defined in Section 21.00 (c) of this Code within the business tax economic incentive area on or after January 1, 1998 shall pay no business taxes other than the $25 minimum business tax specified in Subsection (a) above for up to a five-year period as set forth in Subsection (b) above.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(g)	Change of Ownership of Existing Businesses.&#xA0; New proprietors of pre-existing businesses located within the business tax economic incentive area shall not be eligible to receive the incentives set forth in Subsection (e) and (f) above.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(h)	Excluded Businesses.&#xA0; The business tax relief described in Subsections (a) through (f) of this section is available to all business tax classifications located within the business tax economic incentive area except that no business tax exemption, &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;waiver&lt;/span&gt;, decrease or freeze shall be available to any person whose primary activity at a location is the sale of alcoholic beverages for off-premises consumption or the sale of guns and ammunition, or which is an&#xA0; &#x201C;adult entertainment business&#x201D; as defined in the Los Angeles Municipal Code Section 12.70B.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(i)	Conditions to Receive Tax Exemption.&#xA0; The Director of Finance shall determine that one of the following conditions applies to each person seeking business tax relief under Subsections (e) and (f) above unless application of said conditions is waived by the Mayor&#x2019;s Office.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(1)	The business pays all of its work force at a rate at least equal to the living wage as identified in the City&#x2019;s Living Wage &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Ordinance&lt;/span&gt; in Los Angeles Administrative Code Section 10.37.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(2)	The business provides goods or services that are urgently needed in the business tax economic incentive area.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(3)	The business can show proof of a significant investment in its workforce (For example: job training, childcare, retirement or investment programs; health or life insurance programs).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(4)	A newly established business in the business tax economic incentive area hires at least 50% of its workforce locally from the business tax economic incentive area, or the buffer zone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	The Mayor&#x2019;s Office shall provide annual reports to the Community and Economic Development Committee of the Council of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;waivers&lt;/span&gt; granted and the justification for those &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;waivers&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(j)	Description of Business Tax Economic Incentive Area.&#xA0; The business tax economic incentive area shall lie within the boundaries of the federal Empowerment Zone except that the business license tax economic incentive area shall extend beyond the boundaries of the Empowerment Zone to include both sides of a street in which there is business activity where only one side of that street is included in the Empowerment Zone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(1)	The business tax economic incentive area consists of the area included within the following United States Census Tract numbers, as extended by this subsection where applicable:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1041.020, 1047.010, 2045.000, 2051.000, 2060.000, 2062.000, 2063.000, 2073.000, 2260.000, 2270.000, 2281.000, 2282.000, 2286.000, 2287.000, 2288.000, 2289.000, 2291.000, 2371.000, 2372.000, 2383,000, 2392.000. 2393.000, 2397.000, 2400.000, 2402.000, 2405.000, 2408.000, 2409.000, 2420.000, 2421.000, 2422.000, 2423.000, 2426.000, 2427.000, 2430.000, 2431.000&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(2)	The map set forth below illustrates the location of the United States Census Tracts listed in Paragraph (1) of this subsection that comprise the business tax economic incentive area.&#xA0; The boundaries of said business tax economic incentive area are extended as set forth in this subsection where applicable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;LOCATION OF UNITED STATES CENSUS TRACTS THAT COMPRISE BUSINESS TAX ECONOMIC INCENTIVE AREA
(NOT ALL TRACTS PICTURED ARE LOCATED IN BUSINESS TAX ECONOMIC INCENTIVE AREA &#x2013; SEE L.A.M.C. SEC. 21.26(j)(1))&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[Editor&#x2019;s Note:&#xA0; The map referred to in this section is on file in the official City documents located in the Office of the City Clerk in Council File No. CF-97-0401-S1.]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(3)	The business tax economic incentive area is described in the table set forth below.&#xA0; The boundaries of said area are extended as set forth in this subsection where applicable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;BUSINESS TAX ECONOMIC INCENTIVE AREA FOR THE CITY OF LOS ANGELES&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	The table describes both part A and part B in a continuous loop.&#xA0; The loop starts southward by describing part A&#x2019;s western half and going down to the Slauson and South Central Avenue intersection where part B begins.&#xA0; At the intersection the loop travels in a westwardly direction around part B.&#xA0; Eventually the loop travels back North to describe part A&#x2019;s eastern half.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SECTION ONE
FIRST HALF OF PART A
INTERSECTION OF N. BROADWAY AND THE LOS ANGELES RIVER&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  
    
      
        BEGINNING POINT
      
      
        DIRECTION
      
      
        ENDING LIMIT
      
    
    
      
        N. Broadway
      
      
        Southwest to
      
      
        College Street
      
    
    
      
        College Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        N. Alameda
      
    
    
      
        N. Alameda
      
      
        South to
      
      
        Temple Street
      
    
    
      
        Temple Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        San Pedro
      
    
    
      
        San Pedro
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 1st
      
    
    
      
        E. 1st
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Los Angeles Street
      
    
    
      
        Los Angeles Street
      
      
        South to
      
      
        2nd Street
      
    
    
      
        2nd Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        S. Hill
      
    
    
      
        S. Hill
      
      
        South to
      
      
        9th Street
      
    
    
      
        9th Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Maple Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Maple Ave.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 21st Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 21st Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Central Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Central Ave.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        42nd Street
      
    
    
      
        42nd Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Avalon
      
    
    
      
        Avalon
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 48th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 48th Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        McKinley Ave.
      
    
    
      
        McKinley Ave.
      
      
        North to&#xA0;
        </html><previous_section id="2672"><structure_id>19</structure_id><section_number>21.25</section_number><catch_line>Relief For Earthquake Interruption.</catch_line><url>/21.25/</url><token>21.25</token></previous_section><text><unit id="2934" prefix=""><text>&#xA0; EMPOWERMENT ZONE &#x2013; CITY BUSINESS TAX REDUCTIONS, LIMITATIONS, AND EXEMPTIONS.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 172,358, Eff. 1/31/99.)	(a)	Minimum Business Tax.&#xA0; After payment of a minimum business tax of $25.00, the amount of business tax relief to a person engaged in business at a location in the business tax economic incentive area described in Subsection (j) but not excluded from such tax relief by Subsection (h) shall be an exemption from the next $500.00 in business tax liability.	(b)	Time Period of Business Tax Relief.&#xA0; The business tax relief described in Subsection (a) of this section shall be for the tax period beginning on or after January 1, 1995 and ending on or before the termination of the City&#x2019;s Empowerment Zone as established by the City Council by ordinance.&#xA0; The time period for business tax relief for census tracts that are added to the City&#x2019;s business tax economic incentive area will commence on the effective date of the Ordinance adding the census tracts and cover the entire calendar year.	A person will only be entitled to the additional business tax relief provided for in Subsections (c), (d), (e), and (f) for up to a maximum period of five years.	(c)	Additional Business Tax Relief for Existing Businesses Within the Business Tax Economic Incentive Area.&#xA0; Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, for the tax years beginning on January 1, 1999 the annual business taxes paid starting in 1999 by any person for a business located within the business tax economic incentive area described in Subsection (j) on or after January 1, 1998, shall not exceed the business taxes paid by such person for the year ended December 31, 1998.&#xA0; Such additional relief shall be for a period of up to five years, as set forth in Subsection (b) above.	(d)	Business Tax Relief for Existing Businesses Within the City Relocating into the Business Tax Economic Incentive Area.&#xA0; Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, the annual business taxes paid during any taxable year by any person for a business (1) located within the City of Los Angeles but outside the business tax economic incentive area on or before December 31, 1998 and (2) which relocates its business activity within the business tax economic incentive area on or after January 1, 1999, shall not exceed the annual business taxes paid by such person during the tax year during which the business relocated into the business tax economic incentive area, subject to the relief provided in Subsection (a) above.&#xA0; Such additional relief shall be for a period of up to five years as set forth in Subsection (b) above.	(e)	Business Tax Relief for Existing Businesses Outside the City Relocating Into the Business Tax Economic Incentive Area.&#xA0; Any person whose business was located outside the City of Los Angeles as of December 31, 1997 and which locates its business activity within the business tax economic incentive area on or after January 1, 1998, shall pay no business taxes other than the $25 minimum tax specified in Subsection (a) above for up to a five-year period as set forth in Subsection (b) above.	(f)	Business Tax Relief for Newly Established Businesses Within the Business Tax Economic Incentive Area.&#xA0; Any person who starts a &#x201C;newly established business&#x201D; as defined in Section 21.00 (c) of this Code within the business tax economic incentive area on or after January 1, 1998 shall pay no business taxes other than the $25 minimum business tax specified in Subsection (a) above for up to a five-year period as set forth in Subsection (b) above.	(g)	Change of Ownership of Existing Businesses.&#xA0; New proprietors of pre-existing businesses located within the business tax economic incentive area shall not be eligible to receive the incentives set forth in Subsection (e) and (f) above.	(h)	Excluded Businesses.&#xA0; The business tax relief described in Subsections (a) through (f) of this section is available to all business tax classifications located within the business tax economic incentive area except that no business tax exemption, waiver, decrease or freeze shall be available to any person whose primary activity at a location is the sale of alcoholic beverages for off-premises consumption or the sale of guns and ammunition, or which is an&#xA0; &#x201C;adult entertainment business&#x201D; as defined in the Los Angeles Municipal Code Section 12.70B.	(i)	Conditions to Receive Tax Exemption.&#xA0; The Director of Finance shall determine that one of the following conditions applies to each person seeking business tax relief under Subsections (e) and (f) above unless application of said conditions is waived by the Mayor&#x2019;s Office.	(1)	The business pays all of its work force at a rate at least equal to the living wage as identified in the City&#x2019;s Living Wage Ordinance in Los Angeles Administrative Code Section 10.37.	(2)	The business provides goods or services that are urgently needed in the business tax economic incentive area.	(3)	The business can show proof of a significant investment in its workforce (For example: job training, childcare, retirement or investment programs; health or life insurance programs).	(4)	A newly established business in the business tax economic incentive area hires at least 50% of its workforce locally from the business tax economic incentive area, or the buffer zone.	The Mayor&#x2019;s Office shall provide annual reports to the Community and Economic Development Committee of the Council of waivers granted and the justification for those waivers.	(j)	Description of Business Tax Economic Incentive Area.&#xA0; The business tax economic incentive area shall lie within the boundaries of the federal Empowerment Zone except that the business license tax economic incentive area shall extend beyond the boundaries of the Empowerment Zone to include both sides of a street in which there is business activity where only one side of that street is included in the Empowerment Zone.	(1)	The business tax economic incentive area consists of the area included within the following United States Census Tract numbers, as extended by this subsection where applicable:1041.020, 1047.010, 2045.000, 2051.000, 2060.000, 2062.000, 2063.000, 2073.000, 2260.000, 2270.000, 2281.000, 2282.000, 2286.000, 2287.000, 2288.000, 2289.000, 2291.000, 2371.000, 2372.000, 2383,000, 2392.000. 2393.000, 2397.000, 2400.000, 2402.000, 2405.000, 2408.000, 2409.000, 2420.000, 2421.000, 2422.000, 2423.000, 2426.000, 2427.000, 2430.000, 2431.000	(2)	The map set forth below illustrates the location of the United States Census Tracts listed in Paragraph (1) of this subsection that comprise the business tax economic incentive area.&#xA0; The boundaries of said business tax economic incentive area are extended as set forth in this subsection where applicable.LOCATION OF UNITED STATES CENSUS TRACTS THAT COMPRISE BUSINESS TAX ECONOMIC INCENTIVE AREA
(NOT ALL TRACTS PICTURED ARE LOCATED IN BUSINESS TAX ECONOMIC INCENTIVE AREA &#x2013; SEE L.A.M.C. SEC. 21.26(j)(1))[Editor&#x2019;s Note:&#xA0; The map referred to in this section is on file in the official City documents located in the Office of the City Clerk in Council File No. CF-97-0401-S1.]	(3)	The business tax economic incentive area is described in the table set forth below.&#xA0; The boundaries of said area are extended as set forth in this subsection where applicable.BUSINESS TAX ECONOMIC INCENTIVE AREA FOR THE CITY OF LOS ANGELES	The table describes both part A and part B in a continuous loop.&#xA0; The loop starts southward by describing part A&#x2019;s western half and going down to the Slauson and South Central Avenue intersection where part B begins.&#xA0; At the intersection the loop travels in a westwardly direction around part B.&#xA0; Eventually the loop travels back North to describe part A&#x2019;s eastern half.SECTION ONE
FIRST HALF OF PART A
INTERSECTION OF N. BROADWAY AND THE LOS ANGELES RIVER
  
    
      
        BEGINNING POINT
      
      
        DIRECTION
      
      
        ENDING LIMIT
      
    
    
      
        N. Broadway
      
      
        Southwest to
      
      
        College Street
      
    
    
      
        College Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        N. Alameda
      
    
    
      
        N. Alameda
      
      
        South to
      
      
        Temple Street
      
    
    
      
        Temple Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        San Pedro
      
    
    
      
        San Pedro
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 1st
      
    
    
      
        E. 1st
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Los Angeles Street
      
    
    
      
        Los Angeles Street
      
      
        South to
      
      
        2nd Street
      
    
    
      
        2nd Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        S. Hill
      
    
    
      
        S. Hill
      
      
        South to
      
      
        9th Street
      
    
    
      
        9th Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Maple Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Maple Ave.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 21st Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 21st Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Central Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Central Ave.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        42nd Street
      
    
    
      
        42nd Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Avalon
      
    
    
      
        Avalon
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 48th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 48th Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        McKinley Ave.
      
    
    
      
        McKinley Ave.
      
      
        North to&#xA0;
        &amp; back up
      
      
        E. 48th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 48th Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Central Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Central Ave.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        Slauson Ave.
      
    
  BEGINNING OF PART B OF SECTION ONE
INTERSECTION OF CENTRAL AVE. &amp; SLAUSON AVE.
  
    
      
        BEGINNING POINT
      
      
        DIRECTION
      
      
        ENDING LIMIT
      
    
    
      
        Slauson Ave.
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Van Ness Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Van Ness Ave.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        62nd Street
      
    
    
      
        62nd Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        S. Broadway Ave.
      
    
    
      
        S. Broadway
      
      
        South to
      
      
        Florence Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Florence Ave.
      
      
        East to
      
      
        S. Central Ave.
      
    
    
      
        S. Central Ave.
      
      
        North to X-section
      
      
        Slauson Ave.
      
    
  SECOND HALF OF PART A SECTION ONE
INTERSECTION OF S. CENTRAL &amp; SLAUSON
  
    
      
        BEGINNING POINT
      
      
        DIRECTION
      
      
        ENDING LIMIT
      
    
    
      
        Slauson Ave.
      
      
        East to
      
      
        S. Alameda
      
    
    
      
        S. Alameda
      
      
        North to
      
      
        E. 25th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 25th Street
      
      
        East to &amp; following
      
      
        Southern City Limits With Vernon
      
    
    
      
        Southern City Limits with Vernon
      
      
        Follow to
      
      
        Spence Street
      
    
    
      
        Spence Street
      
      
        North to
      
      
        E. 8th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 8th Street
      
      
        Northwest to
      
      
        Soto Street
      
    
    
      
        Soto Street
      
      
        North to
      
      
        Santa Monica FWY.
      
    
    
      
        Santa Monica FWY.
      
      
        West to
      
      
        S. Boyle Ave.
      
    
    
      
        S. Boyle Ave.
      
      
        North to
      
      
        Golden State FWY.
      
    
    
      
        Golden State FWY.
      
      
        North to
      
      
        E. 4th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 4th Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        N. State Street
      
    
    
      
        N. State Street
      
      
        North to
      
      
        E. 1st Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 1st Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Los Angeles River
      
    
    
      
        Los Angeles River
      
      
        North to
      
      
        N. Broadway
      
    
  END OF SECTION ONE (PARTS A&amp;B)
SECTION TWO
INTERSECTION OF S. CENTRAL AVE. &amp; E. MANCHESTER
  
    
      
        BEGINNING POINT
      
      
        DIRECTION
      
      
        ENDING LIMIT
      
    
    
      
        E. Manchester
      
      
        West to
      
      
        San Pedro Street
      
    
    
      
        San Pedro Street
      
      
        North to
      
      
        E. 79th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 79th Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        S. Vermont Ave.
      
    
    
      
        S. Vermont Ave.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        Manchester Ave.
      
    
    
      
        Manchester Ave.
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Figueroa
      
    
    
      
        Figueroa
      
      
        South to
      
      
        104th Street
      
    
    
      
        104th Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Wall Street
      
    
    
      
        Wall Street
      
      
        North to
      
      
        93rd Street
      
    
    
      
        93rd Street
      
      
        East to
      
      
        E. City Limits with Walnut Park
      
    
    
      
        E. City Limits with Walnut Park
      
      
        North to
      
      
        Intersection of Manchester &amp; S. Central Avenues
      
    
  END OF SECTION TWO
SECTION THREE
INTERSECTION OF 104TH &amp; SAN PEDRO STREET
  
    
      
        BEGINNING POINT
      
      
        DIRECTION
      
      
        ENDING LIMIT
      
    
    
      
        San Pedro St.
      
      
        South to
      
      
        Imperial Hwy
      
    
    
      
        Imperial Hwy
      
      
        East to
      
      
        Wadsworth &amp; E. 114th
      
    
    
      
        114th St.
      
      
        East to
      
      
        S. Central Ave
      
    
    
      
        S. Central Ave
      
      
        South to
      
      
        Imperial Hwy
      
    
    
      
        Imperial Hwy.
      
      
        East to
      
      
        E. City/County Limits at Mona Blvd.
      
    
    
      
        E. City/County Limits at Mona Blvd.
      
      
        North to
      
      
        92nd Street
      
    
    
      
        92nd Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Maine St.
      
    
    
      
        Maine St.
      
      
        North
      
      
        E. 91st Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 91st Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Compton
      
    
    
      
        Compton
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 92nd Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 92nd Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        Success Street
      
    
    
      
        Success Street
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 103rd Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 103rd Street
      
      
        West to
      
      
        S. Central Ave
      
    
    
      
        S. Central Ave
      
      
        South to
      
      
        E. 104th Street
      
    
    
      
        E. 104th Street
      
      
        West to X-section
      
      
        San Pedro
      
    
  
END OF SECTION THREE
SECTION FOUR
INTERSECTION OF THE VAN NUYS BLVD. &amp; THE FOOTHILL FWY.
  
    
      
        BEGINNING POINT
      
      
        DIRECTION
      
      
        ENDING LIMIT
      
    
    
      
        Van Nuys Blvd.
      
      
        Southwest to
      
      
        San Fernando Rd.
      
    
    
      
        San Fernando Rd.
      
      
        Southeast to
      
      
        Pierce Street
      
    
    
      
        Pierce Street
      
      
        Northeast to
      
      
        Glenoaks Blvd.
      
    
    
      
        Glenoaks Blvd.
      
      
        Southeast to
      
      
        Osborne Street
      
    
    
      
        Osborne Street
      
      
        North to
      
      
        West side of the Hansen Dam
      
    
    
      
        West side of the Hansen Dam
      
      
        Follow East to the
      
      
        Rancho Tujunga Rancho Ex Mission DE San Fernando line
      
    
    
      
        Rancho Tujunga Rancho Ex Mission DE San Fernando line
      
      
        North to
      
      
        Foothill FWY.
      
    
    
      
        Foothill FWY.	
      
      
        West to X-section
      
      
        Van Nuys Blvd.
      
    
  
END OF SECTION FOUR	(k)	Administration.&#xA0; The business tax economic incentive program shall be administered by the Director of Finance who shall notify all known persons engaged in business at a location in the business tax economic incentive area of the program.	(l)	Business Tax Forms.&#xA0; It shall be the responsibility of each person engaged in business to compare its activity to the tax relief provided by this section and complete its business tax forms accordingly.	(m)	Annual Report to the Mayor and Council by Director of the Office of Administrative and Research Services.&#xA0; The Director of the Office of Administrative and Research Services shall report annually on the measurable costs and benefits of the Business Tax Economic Incentive program.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 173,304, Eff. 6/30/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)</text><type>section</type><prefixes><unit></unit></prefixes><entire_prefix></entire_prefix><prefix_anchor></prefix_anchor><level>1</level></unit></text></law>
