<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><section_number>41.70.1</section_number><edition_id>1</edition_id><section_id>3589</section_id><structure_id>66</structure_id><catch_line>Nuisance Vehicles &#x2013; Controlled Substances.</catch_line><history></history><full_text>&#xA0; NUISANCE VEHICLES &#x2013; CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES.
	(Added by Ord. No. 175,573, Eff. 11/24/03.)

	A.	Definitions.

	&#x201C;Controlled substance&#x201D; means a drug, substance or immediate precursor that is listed in any schedule in California Health and Safety Code Sections 11054, 11055, 11056, 11057 or 11058.

	&#x201C;Driver&#x201D; means any person who drives or is in physical control of a vehicle.

	&#x201C;Vehicle&#x201D; means any transportation device which requires the driver to have in his or her immediate possession a valid driver&#x2019;s license for the appropriate class of vehicle being driven.

	B.	Abatement of Nuisance Vehicle by Seizure and Forfeiture.

	1.	Any vehicle used to illegally acquire or attempt to illegally acquire any controlled substance is declared a nuisance and the vehicle shall be enjoined and abated as provided in this section.&#xA0;

	2.	Any person or his or her servant, agent, or employee who owns, leases, conducts or maintains any vehicle used for any of the purposes or acts set forth in this section is responsible for creating a public nuisance.

	C.	Title to Vest in the City.&#xA0; All right, title and interest in any vehicle described in Subsection B. shall vest in the City upon commission of the act giving rise to the nuisance under this section.

	D.	Seizure of Vehicle.

	1.	A peace officer may seize a vehicle subject to forfeiture under this section upon the issuance of an order by a court having jurisdiction of the vehicle.&#xA0; Seizure without court order may be made in any of the following circumstances:

	(a)	The seizure is incident to an arrest or search under a search warrant;

	(b)	There is probable cause to believe the vehicle was used in violation of this section.

	2.	A peace officer seizing a vehicle under this section shall complete a receipt in accordance with Penal Code Section 1412 and deliver it to the person from whose possession the vehicle was seized.

	3.	An immediate investigation shall be made by the public agency making the seizure as to any potential claimant to a seized vehicle whose right, title, interest, or lien is of record in the Department of Motor Vehicles of this or any other state or appropriate federal agency. The public agency shall send a notice of seizure within two business days of the vehicle&#x2019;s seizure, to all potential claimants whose right, title, interest or lien did not arise subsequent to the date and time of seizure of the vehicle, if that person or entity was not previously given a notice of seizure.

	4.	The public agency seizing the vehicle shall provide any potential claimants discovered as a result of the investigation set out in D.3. with the opportunity for a post-seizure hearing to determine the validity of the seizure. The post-seizure hearing shall be conducted within two business days of the request for the hearing.&#xA0; The public agency may authorize its own officer or employee to conduct the hearing if the hearing officer is not the same person who directed the seizure of the vehicle. Failure of the potential claimant to request or attend a scheduled hearing within the appropriate time frame shall satisfy the post-seizure requirement.

	(a)	The notice of seizure shall include the following:

	(i)	the name, address and telephone number of the agency providing the notice;

	(ii)	the authority and reason for the seizure;

	(iii)	a statement that in order to receive their post-seizure hearing, the potential claimant shall request the hearing in person, in writing, or by telephone within ten calendar days of the date of the notice; and

	(iv)	the time in which a claim of interest in the vehicle seized or subject to forfeiture is required to be filed.

	5.	A vehicle seized pursuant to this section, where appropriate may be held as evidence in any proceeding brought by the City Attorney or District Attorney.

	E.	Forfeiture and Notice of Intended Forfeiture of Vehicle.

	1.	The City Attorney may, pursuant to this section, order the forfeiture of vehicles seized under this section.

	2.	If the City Attorney determines that the factual circumstances warrant&#xA0; forfeiture of the vehicle described in Subsection B., the City Attorney shall serve a notice of intended forfeiture upon any person who has an interest in the seized vehicle.&#xA0; The notice shall be served as soon as practicable, but in any event within 30 calendar days of the seizure of the vehicle subject to forfeiture.

	3.	The notice of intended forfeiture shall be served as follows:

	(a)	By personal delivery or certified mail, return receipt requested, upon any person who has an interest in the seized vehicle as determined pursuant to Subsection D.3.

	(b)	In the event that the person entitled to service refuses to accept certified return receipt mail or cannot be personally served, service may be made by substituted service.&#xA0; Substituted service may be accomplished by any one of the following methods:&#xA0;

	(i)	By leaving a copy during usual business hours at the recipient&#x2019;s business with the person who is apparently in charge, and by thereafter mailing by first class mail a copy to the recipient where the copy was left;&#xA0;

	(ii)	By leaving a copy at the recipient&#x2019;s dwelling or usual place of abode, in the presence of a competent member of the household and thereafter mailing by first class mail a copy to the recipient at the address where the copy was left.

	(c)	If the person entitled to service lives out of state and will not accept certified return receipt mail, then service may be made by first class mail.

	(d)	If the person entitled to notice cannot be located, or service cannot be effected as set forth in this subsection, service may be made by publication in a Los Angeles newspaper of general circulation.&#xA0; Service shall be deemed sufficient when it is accomplished pursuant to Government Code Section 6063.

	F.	Claim Opposing Forfeiture and Court Proceedings.

	1.	A person claiming an interest in the vehicle seized pursuant to Subsection B. must within ten calendar days from the date of the notice of intended forfeiture or within 30 calendar days from the date of first publication of the notice of intended forfeiture, file with the Superior Court of the county in which the vehicle was seized, a Claim Opposing Forfeiture, verified in accordance with Section 446 of the Code of Civil&#xA0; Procedure, stating his, her or its interest in the vehicle.&#xA0; An endorsed copy of the claim shall be served upon the City Attorney within ten calendar days of the filing of the claim.&#xA0;

	2.	If a verified claim is filed in accordance with this section, the forfeiture proceeding shall be set for hearing within 30 calendar days from the date the claim is filed with the court. The City Attorney shall file a petition for forfeiture with the court within ten calendar days of service of the claim upon the City Attorney. A copy of the petition shall be served upon the claimant.

	3.	The hearing shall be before the Superior Court of Los Angeles County.&#xA0; The provisions of the Code of Civil Procedure shall apply to proceedings under this section unless otherwise inconsistent with the provisions or procedures set forth in this section. &#xA0; However, in proceedings under this section, there shall be no joinder of actions, coordination of actions, except for forfeiture proceedings, or cross-complaints, and the issues shall be limited strictly to the questions related to this section. Trial shall be by court or jury.

	4.	With respect to vehicles described in Subsection B. for which forfeiture is sought and as to which forfeiture is contested, the City Attorney shall have the burden of proving by a preponderance of the evidence that the vehicle was used as set forth in&#xA0; Subsection B.&#xA0;

	5.	Upon proof that the vehicle was used for any of the purposes set forth in Subsection B., the court shall declare the vehicle a nuisance and order that the vehicle be forfeited, sold, and the proceeds distributed as set forth in Subsection G.&#xA0; The court may make a different distribution of the proceeds, if the court finds that the claimant did not know that the vehicle was used for a purpose that constitutes a violation of this section

	6.	If no claims are timely filed, the City Attorney shall prepare a written declaration of forfeiture of the vehicle to the City.&#xA0; A written declaration of forfeiture signed by the City Attorney under this section shall be deemed to provide good and sufficient title to the forfeited vehicle.&#xA0; The proceeds from the disposal of the vehicle declared forfeited by the City Attorney shall be distributed in accordance with Subsection G.&#xA0; The City Attorney ordering forfeiture pursuant to this section shall provide a copy of the declaration of forfeiture to any person who received notice of the forfeiture proceedings.

	G.	Disposal of Vehicle and Distribution of Proceeds.

	1.	In all cases where vehicles seized pursuant to this section are forfeited to the City, the vehicles shall be sold, or if cash is paid as settlement in lieu of forfeiture of the vehicle, the proceeds of sale or settlement shall be distributed and appropriated as follows:&#xA0;
&#xA0;
	(a)	To pay costs associated with the towing, storage and release of any vehicle seized under this section.

	(b) 	To pay costs associated with the sale of the vehicle.

	(c)	To the lien holder of the vehicle, if any, up to the amount of his, her or its interest in the vehicle.

	2.	The remaining funds shall be distributed as follows:

	(a)	To the City Attorney for all expenditures other than personnel costs, made or incurred by the Office in connection with the enforcement of this section, including but not limited to, costs for equipment, investigation, supplies, litigation, insurance and liability resulting from enforcement of this section and costs of publication of the notices set forth in Subsection E.

	(b)	To local law enforcement for all expenditures other than personnel costs, made or incurred by the Department in connection with enforcement of this section, including but not limited to, costs for equipment, investigation and supplies related to enforcement of this section.

	(c)	To the general fund.
	
	3.	For budgeting purposes, funds attributable to this ordinance shall not be considered anticipated revenue into the general fund.

	H.	Stolen Vehicles.&#xA0; A vehicle that has been reported stolen, prior to a seizure under this section shall not be subject to forfeiture unless the identity of the registered owner cannot be reasonably ascertained or the registered owner fails to redeem the vehicle within 60 days of the seizure.&#xA0; The registered owner of the vehicle may claim the vehicle upon payment of tow, storage and release charges, provided the vehicle is not subject to any holds for traffic or parking violations and the vehicle registration is current.&#xA0;

	I.	Recovery of Monetary Loss.&#xA0; Nothing in this section shall preclude an owner of a vehicle who suffers a monetary loss from the forfeiture of a vehicle under this section from recovering the amount of the actual monetary loss from the person who committed the act giving rise to forfeiture under this section.</full_text><order_by>70.1</order_by><ancestry><unit id="66" label="article"><name>Disorderly Conduct
Places And Publications</name><identifier>1</identifier><url>/4/1/</url></unit><unit id="11" label="chapter"><name>Public Welfare</name><identifier>4</identifier><url>/4/</url></unit></ancestry><structure_contents><unit id="2975"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.03</section_number><catch_line>Lookouts For Illegal Acts.</catch_line><url>/41.03/</url><token>41.03</token></unit><unit id="4179"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.14</section_number><catch_line>Injury To Public Property.</catch_line><url>/41.14/</url><token>41.14</token></unit><unit id="2377"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.16</section_number><catch_line>Snuff &#x2013; Throwing Of.</catch_line><url>/41.16/</url><token>41.16</token></unit><unit id="507"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.17</section_number><catch_line>Library Books &#x2013; Retention After Notice.</catch_line><url>/41.17/</url><token>41.17</token></unit><unit id="4062"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.18</section_number><catch_line>Sidewalks, Pedestrian Subways &#x2013; Loitering.</catch_line><url>/41.18/</url><token>41.18</token></unit><unit id="2873"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.19</section_number><catch_line>Public Assemblages &#x2013; Obstructing Entrance.</catch_line><url>/41.19/</url><token>41.19</token></unit><unit id="2652"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.20</section_number><catch_line>Closure Of Streets.</catch_line><url>/41.20/</url><token>41.20</token></unit><unit id="1364"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.20.1</section_number><catch_line>Special Event Application Process And Definitions.</catch_line><url>/41.20.1/</url><token>41.20.1</token></unit><unit id="617"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.21</section_number><catch_line>Cutting Into Gasoline Lines Prohibited.</catch_line><url>/41.21/</url><token>41.21</token></unit><unit id="1698"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.22</section_number><catch_line>Loitering &#x2013; River Bed.</catch_line><url>/41.22/</url><token>41.22</token></unit><unit id="4027"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.23</section_number><catch_line>Trespass On Housing Authority Property.</catch_line><url>/41.23/</url><token>41.23</token></unit><unit id="252"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.24</section_number><catch_line>Trespass On Private Property.</catch_line><url>/41.24/</url><token>41.24</token></unit><unit id="878"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.27</section_number><catch_line>Intoxication.</catch_line><url>/41.27/</url><token>41.27</token></unit><unit id="953"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.29</section_number><catch_line>Hand Organs On Streets.</catch_line><url>/41.29/</url><token>41.29</token></unit><unit id="2290"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.30</section_number><catch_line>Spite Fences.</catch_line><url>/41.30/</url><token>41.30</token></unit><unit id="1611"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.31</section_number><catch_line>Trees &#x2013; Injury To.</catch_line><url>/41.31/</url><token>41.31</token></unit><unit id="2884"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.32</section_number><catch_line>Theatres &#x2013; Sound Amplifiers.</catch_line><url>/41.32/</url><token>41.32</token></unit><unit id="3573"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.33</section_number><catch_line>Landlords &#x2013; Disturbing Tenants.</catch_line><url>/41.33/</url><token>41.33</token></unit><unit id="206"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.34</section_number><catch_line>Pesticides &#x2013; Notice To Tenants.</catch_line><url>/41.34/</url><token>41.34</token></unit><unit id="3302"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.38</section_number><catch_line>Use Of Certain Signs On Vehicles Prohibited.</catch_line><url>/41.38/</url><token>41.38</token></unit><unit id="1767"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.39</section_number><catch_line>Stowaways &#x2013; Entry A Misdemeanor.</catch_line><url>/41.39/</url><token>41.39</token></unit><unit id="1857"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.40</section_number><catch_line>Noise Due To Construction, Excavation Work &#x2013; When Prohibited.</catch_line><url>/41.40/</url><token>41.40</token></unit><unit id="818"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.41</section_number><catch_line>Evading Payment Of Admission Fee.</catch_line><url>/41.41/</url><token>41.41</token></unit><unit id="2748"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.42</section_number><catch_line>Music Reproducing Devices &#x2013; Hours Of Operation.</catch_line><url>/41.42/</url><token>41.42</token></unit><unit id="2050"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.43</section_number><catch_line>Selling Goods Near Private Parks.</catch_line><url>/41.43/</url><token>41.43</token></unit><unit id="1693"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.43.1</section_number><catch_line>Door To Door Selling Or Soliciting.</catch_line><url>/41.43.1/</url><token>41.43.1</token></unit><unit id="3565"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.44</section_number><catch_line>Miniature Golf Courses And Driving Fairways.</catch_line><url>/41.44/</url><token>41.44</token></unit><unit id="1897"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.45</section_number><catch_line>Unauthorized Removal, Use Or Possession Of Shopping Carts.</catch_line><url>/41.45/</url><token>41.45</token></unit><unit id="3090"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.46</section_number><catch_line>Sidewalks &#x2013; Cleaning Of.</catch_line><url>/41.46/</url><token>41.46</token></unit><unit id="3367"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.47</section_number><catch_line>Water Closets &#x2013; Use Of.</catch_line><url>/41.47/</url><token>41.47</token></unit><unit id="3199"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.47.1</section_number><catch_line>Restroom Facilities.</catch_line><url>/41.47.1/</url><token>41.47.1</token></unit><unit id="3793"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.47.2</section_number><catch_line>Urinating Or Defecating In Public.</catch_line><url>/41.47.2/</url><token>41.47.2</token></unit><unit id="3936"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.48</section_number><catch_line>Restaurants &#x2013; Minimum Light Intensity.</catch_line><url>/41.48/</url><token>41.48</token></unit><unit id="4033"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.49</section_number><catch_line>Hotel Registers And Room Rentals.</catch_line><url>/41.49/</url><token>41.49</token></unit><unit id="3882"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.50</section_number><catch_line>Smoking Prohibited In Designated Areas.</catch_line><url>/41.50/</url><token>41.50</token></unit><unit id="2857"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.50.5</section_number><catch_line>Signage Regulations For Places Subject To Regulation Pursuant To Labor Code Section 6404.5.</catch_line><url>/41.50.5/</url><token>41.50.5</token></unit><unit id="1140"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.51</section_number><catch_line>Smoking In Elevators Prohibited.</catch_line><url>/41.51/</url><token>41.51</token></unit><unit id="2159"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.52</section_number><catch_line>Smoking In Buses.</catch_line><url>/41.52/</url><token>41.52</token></unit><unit id="3194"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.53</section_number><catch_line>Public Bath Houses.</catch_line><url>/41.53/</url><token>41.53</token></unit><unit id="2202"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.54</section_number><catch_line>Fishing Within One Mile Of Public Sewer Outlet.</catch_line><url>/41.54/</url><token>41.54</token></unit><unit id="350"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.55</section_number><catch_line>Oil &#x2013; Discharge In Ocean And Beaches.</catch_line><url>/41.55/</url><token>41.55</token></unit><unit id="523"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.56</section_number><catch_line>Unlawful Activities At Sporting Events, Theatricals And Exhibitions.</catch_line><url>/41.56/</url><token>41.56</token></unit><unit id="1291"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.57</section_number><catch_line>Loud And Raucous Noise Prohibited.</catch_line><url>/41.57/</url><token>41.57</token></unit><unit id="1957"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.58</section_number><catch_line>Loud Party Second Response Fee.</catch_line><url>/41.58/</url><token>41.58</token></unit><unit id="2269"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.59</section_number><catch_line>Prohibition Against Certain Forms Of Aggressive Solicitation.</catch_line><url>/41.59/</url><token>41.59</token></unit><unit id="1569"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.60</section_number><catch_line>Hospitals; Patient Transport.</catch_line><url>/41.60/</url><token>41.60</token></unit><unit id="3658"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.70</section_number><catch_line>Nuisance Vehicles &#x2013; Prostitution.</catch_line><url>/41.70/</url><token>41.70</token></unit><unit id="3589"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.70.1</section_number><catch_line>Nuisance Vehicles &#x2013; Controlled Substances.</catch_line><url>/41.70.1/</url><token>41.70.1</token></unit><unit id="1691"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.70.2</section_number><catch_line>Nuisance Vehicles &#x2013; Speed Contests And Exhibitions Of Speed.</catch_line><url>/41.70.2/</url><token>41.70.2</token></unit><unit id="3984"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.70.3</section_number><catch_line>Nuisance Vehicles &#x2013; Illegal Dumping.</catch_line><url>/41.70.3/</url><token>41.70.3</token></unit><unit id="4031"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.71</section_number><catch_line>Gang-Related Nuisance Vehicle Forfeiture.</catch_line><url>/41.71/</url><token>41.71</token></unit><unit id="4113"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.72</section_number><catch_line>Counterfeit Goods Nuisance Abatement Law.</catch_line><url>/41.72/</url><token>41.72</token></unit></structure_contents><next_section id="1691"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.70.2</section_number><catch_line>Nuisance Vehicles &#x2013; Speed Contests And Exhibitions Of Speed.</catch_line><url>/41.70.2/</url><token>41.70.2</token></next_section><metadata></metadata><references></references><url>/41.70.1/</url><token>41.70.1</token><formats><txt>/41.70.1.txt</txt><json>/41.70.1.xml</json></formats><dublin_core><Title>Nuisance Vehicles &#x2013; Controlled Substances.</Title><Type>Text</Type><Format>text/html</Format><Identifier>&#xA7; 41.70.1</Identifier><Relation>Los Angeles Municipal Code</Relation></dublin_core><plain_text>                            LOS ANGELES MUNICIPAL CODE

NUISANCE VEHICLES &#x2013; CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES. (&#xA7; 41.70.1)

&#xA0; NUISANCE VEHICLES &#x2013; CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES.
	(Added by Ord. No. 175,573, Eff. 11/24/03.)	A.	Definitions.	&#x201C;Controlled
substance&#x201D; means a drug, substance or immediate precursor that is listed in
any schedule in California Health and Safety Code Sections 11054, 11055, 11056,
11057 or 11058.	&#x201C;Driver&#x201D; means any person who drives or is in physical
control of a vehicle.	&#x201C;Vehicle&#x201D; means any transportation device which
requires the driver to have in his or her immediate possession a valid
driver&#x2019;s license for the appropriate class of vehicle being
driven.	B.	Abatement of Nuisance Vehicle by Seizure and Forfeiture.	1.	Any
vehicle used to illegally acquire or attempt to illegally acquire any controlled
substance is declared a nuisance and the vehicle shall be enjoined and abated as
provided in this section.&#xA0;	2.	Any person or his or her servant, agent, or
employee who owns, leases, conducts or maintains any vehicle used for any of the
purposes or acts set forth in this section is responsible for creating a public
nuisance.	C.	Title to Vest in the City.&#xA0; All right, title and interest in any
vehicle described in Subsection B. shall vest in the City upon commission of the
act giving rise to the nuisance under this section.	D.	Seizure of Vehicle.	1.	A
peace officer may seize a vehicle subject to forfeiture under this section upon
the issuance of an order by a court having jurisdiction of the vehicle.&#xA0;
Seizure without court order may be made in any of the following
circumstances:	(a)	The seizure is incident to an arrest or search under a search
warrant;	(b)	There is probable cause to believe the vehicle was used in
violation of this section.	2.	A peace officer seizing a vehicle under this
section shall complete a receipt in accordance with Penal Code Section 1412 and
deliver it to the person from whose possession the vehicle was seized.	3.	An
immediate investigation shall be made by the public agency making the seizure as
to any potential claimant to a seized vehicle whose right, title, interest, or
lien is of record in the Department of Motor Vehicles of this or any other state
or appropriate federal agency. The public agency shall send a notice of seizure
within two business days of the vehicle&#x2019;s seizure, to all potential claimants
whose right, title, interest or lien did not arise subsequent to the date and
time of seizure of the vehicle, if that person or entity was not previously
given a notice of seizure.	4.	The public agency seizing the vehicle shall
provide any potential claimants discovered as a result of the investigation set
out in D.3. with the opportunity for a post-seizure hearing to determine the
validity of the seizure. The post-seizure hearing shall be conducted within two
business days of the request for the hearing.&#xA0; The public agency may authorize
its own officer or employee to conduct the hearing if the hearing officer is not
the same person who directed the seizure of the vehicle. Failure of the
potential claimant to request or attend a scheduled hearing within the
appropriate time frame shall satisfy the post-seizure requirement.	(a)	The
notice of seizure shall include the following:	(i)	the name, address and
telephone number of the agency providing the notice;	(ii)	the authority and
reason for the seizure;	(iii)	a statement that in order to receive their
post-seizure hearing, the potential claimant shall request the hearing in
person, in writing, or by telephone within ten calendar days of the date of the
notice; and	(iv)	the time in which a claim of interest in the vehicle seized or
subject to forfeiture is required to be filed.	5.	A vehicle seized pursuant to
this section, where appropriate may be held as evidence in any proceeding
brought by the City Attorney or District Attorney.	E.	Forfeiture and Notice of
Intended Forfeiture of Vehicle.	1.	The City Attorney may, pursuant to this
section, order the forfeiture of vehicles seized under this section.	2.	If the
City Attorney determines that the factual circumstances warrant&#xA0; forfeiture of
the vehicle described in Subsection B., the City Attorney shall serve a notice
of intended forfeiture upon any person who has an interest in the seized
vehicle.&#xA0; The notice shall be served as soon as practicable, but in any event
within 30 calendar days of the seizure of the vehicle subject to
forfeiture.	3.	The notice of intended forfeiture shall be served as
follows:	(a)	By personal delivery or certified mail, return receipt requested,
upon any person who has an interest in the seized vehicle as determined pursuant
to Subsection D.3.	(b)	In the event that the person entitled to service refuses
to accept certified return receipt mail or cannot be personally served, service
may be made by substituted service.&#xA0; Substituted service may be accomplished by
any one of the following methods:&#xA0;	(i)	By leaving a copy during usual business
hours at the recipient&#x2019;s business with the person who is apparently in charge,
and by thereafter mailing by first class mail a copy to the recipient where the
copy was left;&#xA0;	(ii)	By leaving a copy at the recipient&#x2019;s dwelling or usual
place of abode, in the presence of a competent member of the household and
thereafter mailing by first class mail a copy to the recipient at the address
where the copy was left.	(c)	If the person entitled to service lives out of
state and will not accept certified return receipt mail, then service may be
made by first class mail.	(d)	If the person entitled to notice cannot be
located, or service cannot be effected as set forth in this subsection, service
may be made by publication in a Los Angeles newspaper of general circulation.&#xA0;
Service shall be deemed sufficient when it is accomplished pursuant to
Government Code Section 6063.	F.	Claim Opposing Forfeiture and Court
Proceedings.	1.	A person claiming an interest in the vehicle seized pursuant to
Subsection B. must within ten calendar days from the date of the notice of
intended forfeiture or within 30 calendar days from the date of first
publication of the notice of intended forfeiture, file with the Superior Court
of the county in which the vehicle was seized, a Claim Opposing Forfeiture,
verified in accordance with Section 446 of the Code of Civil&#xA0; Procedure,
stating his, her or its interest in the vehicle.&#xA0; An endorsed copy of the claim
shall be served upon the City Attorney within ten calendar days of the filing of
the claim.&#xA0;	2.	If a verified claim is filed in accordance with this section,
the forfeiture proceeding shall be set for hearing within 30 calendar days from
the date the claim is filed with the court. The City Attorney shall file a
petition for forfeiture with the court within ten calendar days of service of
the claim upon the City Attorney. A copy of the petition shall be served upon
the claimant.	3.	The hearing shall be before the Superior Court of Los Angeles
County.&#xA0; The provisions of the Code of Civil Procedure shall apply to
proceedings under this section unless otherwise inconsistent with the provisions
or procedures set forth in this section. &#xA0; However, in proceedings under this
section, there shall be no joinder of actions, coordination of actions, except
for forfeiture proceedings, or cross-complaints, and the issues shall be limited
strictly to the questions related to this section. Trial shall be by court or
jury.	4.	With respect to vehicles described in Subsection B. for which
forfeiture is sought and as to which forfeiture is contested, the City Attorney
shall have the burden of proving by a preponderance of the evidence that the
vehicle was used as set forth in&#xA0; Subsection B.&#xA0;	5.	Upon proof that the
vehicle was used for any of the purposes set forth in Subsection B., the court
shall declare the vehicle a nuisance and order that the vehicle be forfeited,
sold, and the proceeds distributed as set forth in Subsection G.&#xA0; The court may
make a different distribution of the proceeds, if the court finds that the
claimant did not know that the vehicle was used for a purpose that constitutes a
violation of this section	6.	If no claims are timely filed, the City Attorney
shall prepare a written declaration of forfeiture of the vehicle to the City.&#xA0;
A written declaration of forfeiture signed by the City Attorney under this
section shall be deemed to provide good and sufficient title to the forfeited
vehicle.&#xA0; The proceeds from the disposal of the vehicle declared forfeited by
the City Attorney shall be distributed in accordance with Subsection G.&#xA0; The
City Attorney ordering forfeiture pursuant to this section shall provide a copy
of the declaration of forfeiture to any person who received notice of the
forfeiture proceedings.	G.	Disposal of Vehicle and Distribution of
Proceeds.	1.	In all cases where vehicles seized pursuant to this section are
forfeited to the City, the vehicles shall be sold, or if cash is paid as
settlement in lieu of forfeiture of the vehicle, the proceeds of sale or
settlement shall be distributed and appropriated as follows:&#xA0;
&#xA0;
	(a)	To pay costs associated with the towing, storage and release of any vehicle
seized under this section.	(b) 	To pay costs associated with the sale of the
vehicle.	(c)	To the lien holder of the vehicle, if any, up to the amount of his,
her or its interest in the vehicle.	2.	The remaining funds shall be distributed
as follows:	(a)	To the City Attorney for all expenditures other than personnel
costs, made or incurred by the Office in connection with the enforcement of this
section, including but not limited to, costs for equipment, investigation,
supplies, litigation, insurance and liability resulting from enforcement of this
section and costs of publication of the notices set forth in Subsection
E.	(b)	To local law enforcement for all expenditures other than personnel costs,
made or incurred by the Department in connection with enforcement of this
section, including but not limited to, costs for equipment, investigation and
supplies related to enforcement of this section.	(c)	To the general fund.
	
	3.	For budgeting purposes, funds attributable to this ordinance shall not be
considered anticipated revenue into the general fund.	H.	Stolen Vehicles.&#xA0; A
vehicle that has been reported stolen, prior to a seizure under this section
shall not be subject to forfeiture unless the identity of the registered owner
cannot be reasonably ascertained or the registered owner fails to redeem the
vehicle within 60 days of the seizure.&#xA0; The registered owner of the vehicle may
claim the vehicle upon payment of tow, storage and release charges, provided the
vehicle is not subject to any holds for traffic or parking violations and the
vehicle registration is current.&#xA0;	I.	Recovery of Monetary Loss.&#xA0; Nothing in
this section shall preclude an owner of a vehicle who suffers a monetary loss
from the forfeiture of a vehicle under this section from recovering the amount
of the actual monetary loss from the person who committed the act giving rise to
forfeiture under this section.
</plain_text><html>
					&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#xA0; NUISANCE VEHICLES &#x2013; CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES.
	(Added by Ord. No. 175,573, Eff. 11/24/03.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	A.	Definitions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	&#x201C;Controlled substance&#x201D; means a drug, substance or immediate precursor that is listed in any schedule in California Health and Safety Code Sections 11054, 11055, 11056, 11057 or 11058.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	&#x201C;Driver&#x201D; means any person who drives or is in physical control of a vehicle.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	&#x201C;Vehicle&#x201D; means any transportation device which requires the driver to have in his or her immediate &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;possession&lt;/span&gt; a valid driver&#x2019;s license for the appropriate class of vehicle being driven.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	B.	Abatement of Nuisance Vehicle by Seizure and Forfeiture.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	Any vehicle used to illegally acquire or attempt to illegally acquire any controlled substance is declared a nuisance and the vehicle shall be enjoined and abated as provided in this section.&#xA0;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	Any person or his or her servant, agent, or employee who owns, leases, conducts or maintains any vehicle used for any of the purposes or acts set forth in this section is responsible for creating a public nuisance.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	C.	Title to Vest in the City.&#xA0; All right, title and interest in any vehicle described in Subsection B. shall vest in the City upon commission of the act giving rise to the nuisance under this section.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	D.	Seizure of Vehicle.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	A &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;peace officer&lt;/span&gt; may seize a vehicle subject to forfeiture under this section upon the issuance of an order by a court having &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;jurisdiction&lt;/span&gt; of the vehicle.&#xA0; Seizure without &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;court order&lt;/span&gt; may be made in any of the following circumstances:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(a)	The seizure is incident to an &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;arrest&lt;/span&gt; or search under a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;search warrant&lt;/span&gt;;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(b)	There is &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;probable cause&lt;/span&gt; to believe the vehicle was used in violation of this section.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	A &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;peace officer&lt;/span&gt; seizing a vehicle under this section shall complete a receipt in accordance with Penal Code Section 1412 and deliver it to the person from whose &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;possession&lt;/span&gt; the vehicle was seized.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	An immediate investigation shall be made by the public agency making the seizure as to any potential claimant to a seized vehicle whose right, title, interest, or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt; is of record in the Department of Motor Vehicles of this or any other state or appropriate federal agency. The public agency shall send a notice of seizure within two business days of the vehicle&#x2019;s seizure, to all potential claimants whose right, title, interest or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt; did not arise subsequent to the date and time of seizure of the vehicle, if that person or entity was not previously given a notice of seizure.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	4.	The public agency seizing the vehicle shall provide any potential claimants discovered as a result of the investigation set out in D.3. with the opportunity for a post-seizure &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; to determine the validity of the seizure. The post-seizure &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; shall be conducted within two business days of the request for the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; The public agency may authorize its own officer or employee to conduct the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; if the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; officer is not the same person who directed the seizure of the vehicle. Failure of the potential claimant to request or attend a scheduled &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; within the appropriate time frame shall satisfy the post-seizure requirement.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(a)	The notice of seizure shall include the following:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(i)	the name, address and telephone number of the agency providing the notice;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(ii)	the authority and reason for the seizure;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(iii)	a statement that in order to receive their post-seizure &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt;, the potential claimant shall request the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; in person, in writing, or by telephone within ten calendar days of the date of the notice; and&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(iv)	the time in which a claim of interest in the vehicle seized or subject to forfeiture is required to be filed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	5.	A vehicle seized pursuant to this section, where appropriate may be held as evidence in any proceeding brought by the City Attorney or District Attorney.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	E.	Forfeiture and Notice of Intended Forfeiture of Vehicle.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	The City Attorney may, pursuant to this section, order the forfeiture of vehicles seized under this section.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	If the City Attorney determines that the factual circumstances warrant&#xA0; forfeiture of the vehicle described in Subsection B., the City Attorney shall serve a notice of intended forfeiture upon any person who has an interest in the seized vehicle.&#xA0; The notice shall be served as soon as practicable, but in any event within 30 calendar days of the seizure of the vehicle subject to forfeiture.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	The notice of intended forfeiture shall be served as follows:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(a)	By personal delivery or certified mail, return receipt requested, upon any person who has an interest in the seized vehicle as determined pursuant to Subsection D.3.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(b)	In the event that the person entitled to service refuses to accept certified return receipt mail or cannot be personally served, service may be made by substituted service.&#xA0; Substituted service may be accomplished by any one of the following methods:&#xA0;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(i)	By leaving a copy during usual business hours at the recipient&#x2019;s business with the person who is apparently in charge, and by thereafter mailing by first class mail a copy to the recipient where the copy was left;&#xA0;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(ii)	By leaving a copy at the recipient&#x2019;s dwelling or usual place of abode, in the presence of a competent member of the household and thereafter mailing by first class mail a copy to the recipient at the address where the copy was left.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(c)	If the person entitled to service lives out of state and will not accept certified return receipt mail, then service may be made by first class mail.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(d)	If the person entitled to notice cannot be located, or service cannot be effected as set forth in this subsection, service may be made by publication in a Los Angeles newspaper of general circulation.&#xA0; Service shall be deemed sufficient when it is accomplished pursuant to Government Code Section 6063.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	F.	Claim Opposing Forfeiture and Court Proceedings.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	A person claiming an interest in the vehicle seized pursuant to Subsection B. must within ten calendar days from the date of the notice of intended forfeiture or within 30 calendar days from the date of first publication of the notice of intended forfeiture, file with the Superior Court of the county in which the vehicle was seized, a Claim Opposing Forfeiture, verified in accordance with Section 446 of the Code of Civil&#xA0; Procedure, stating his, her or its interest in the vehicle.&#xA0; An endorsed copy of the claim shall be served upon the City Attorney within ten calendar days of the filing of the claim.&#xA0;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	If a verified claim is filed in accordance with this section, the forfeiture proceeding shall be set for &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; within 30 calendar days from the date the claim is filed with the court. The City Attorney shall file a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;petition&lt;/span&gt; for forfeiture with the court within ten calendar days of service of the claim upon the City Attorney. A copy of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;petition&lt;/span&gt; shall be served upon the claimant.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	The &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; shall be before the Superior Court of Los Angeles County.&#xA0; The provisions of the Code of Civil Procedure shall apply to proceedings under this section unless otherwise inconsistent with the provisions or procedures set forth in this section. &#xA0; However, in proceedings under this section, there shall be no joinder of actions, coordination of actions, except for forfeiture proceedings, or cross-complaints, and the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;issues&lt;/span&gt; shall be limited strictly to the questions related to this section. &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Trial&lt;/span&gt; shall be by court or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;jury&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	4.	With respect to vehicles described in Subsection B. for which forfeiture is sought and as to which forfeiture is contested, the City Attorney shall have the burden of proving by a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;preponderance of the evidence&lt;/span&gt; that the vehicle was used as set forth in&#xA0; Subsection B.&#xA0;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	5.	Upon proof that the vehicle was used for any of the purposes set forth in Subsection B., the court shall declare the vehicle a nuisance and order that the vehicle be forfeited, sold, and the proceeds distributed as set forth in Subsection G.&#xA0; The court may make a different distribution of the proceeds, if the court finds that the claimant did not know that the vehicle was used for a purpose that constitutes a violation of this section&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	6.	If no claims are timely filed, the City Attorney shall prepare a written declaration of forfeiture of the vehicle to the City.&#xA0; A written declaration of forfeiture signed by the City Attorney under this section shall be deemed to provide good and sufficient title to the forfeited vehicle.&#xA0; The proceeds from the disposal of the vehicle declared forfeited by the City Attorney shall be distributed in accordance with Subsection G.&#xA0; The City Attorney ordering forfeiture pursuant to this section shall provide a copy of the declaration of forfeiture to any person who received notice of the forfeiture proceedings.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	G.	Disposal of Vehicle and Distribution of Proceeds.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	In all cases where vehicles seized pursuant to this section are forfeited to the City, the vehicles shall be sold, or if cash is paid as &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;settlement&lt;/span&gt; in lieu of forfeiture of the vehicle, the proceeds of sale or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;settlement&lt;/span&gt; shall be distributed and appropriated as follows:&#xA0;
&#xA0;
	(a)	To pay costs associated with the towing, storage and release of any vehicle seized under this section.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(b) 	To pay costs associated with the sale of the vehicle.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(c)	To the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt; holder of the vehicle, if any, up to the amount of his, her or its interest in the vehicle.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	The remaining funds shall be distributed as follows:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(a)	To the City Attorney for all expenditures other than personnel costs, made or incurred by the Office in connection with the enforcement of this section, including but not limited to, costs for equipment, investigation, supplies, &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;litigation&lt;/span&gt;, insurance and liability resulting from enforcement of this section and costs of publication of the notices set forth in Subsection E.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(b)	To local &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;law&lt;/span&gt; enforcement for all expenditures other than personnel costs, made or incurred by the Department in connection with enforcement of this section, including but not limited to, costs for equipment, investigation and supplies related to enforcement of this section.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(c)	To the general fund.
	
	3.	For budgeting purposes, funds attributable to this &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt; shall not be considered anticipated revenue into the general fund.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	H.	Stolen Vehicles.&#xA0; A vehicle that has been reported stolen, prior to a seizure under this section shall not be subject to forfeiture unless the identity of the registered owner cannot be reasonably ascertained or the registered owner fails to redeem the vehicle within 60 days of the seizure.&#xA0; The registered owner of the vehicle may claim the vehicle upon payment of tow, storage and release charges, provided the vehicle is not subject to any holds for traffic or parking violations and the vehicle registration is current.&#xA0;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	I.	Recovery of Monetary Loss.&#xA0; Nothing in this section shall preclude an owner of a vehicle who suffers a monetary loss from the forfeiture of a vehicle under this section from recovering the amount of the actual monetary loss from the person who committed the act giving rise to forfeiture under this section.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</html><previous_section id="3658"><structure_id>66</structure_id><section_number>41.70</section_number><catch_line>Nuisance Vehicles &#x2013; Prostitution.</catch_line><url>/41.70/</url><token>41.70</token></previous_section><text><unit id="3563" prefix=""><text>&#xA0; NUISANCE VEHICLES &#x2013; CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES.
	(Added by Ord. No. 175,573, Eff. 11/24/03.)	A.	Definitions.	&#x201C;Controlled substance&#x201D; means a drug, substance or immediate precursor that is listed in any schedule in California Health and Safety Code Sections 11054, 11055, 11056, 11057 or 11058.	&#x201C;Driver&#x201D; means any person who drives or is in physical control of a vehicle.	&#x201C;Vehicle&#x201D; means any transportation device which requires the driver to have in his or her immediate possession a valid driver&#x2019;s license for the appropriate class of vehicle being driven.	B.	Abatement of Nuisance Vehicle by Seizure and Forfeiture.	1.	Any vehicle used to illegally acquire or attempt to illegally acquire any controlled substance is declared a nuisance and the vehicle shall be enjoined and abated as provided in this section.&#xA0;	2.	Any person or his or her servant, agent, or employee who owns, leases, conducts or maintains any vehicle used for any of the purposes or acts set forth in this section is responsible for creating a public nuisance.	C.	Title to Vest in the City.&#xA0; All right, title and interest in any vehicle described in Subsection B. shall vest in the City upon commission of the act giving rise to the nuisance under this section.	D.	Seizure of Vehicle.	1.	A peace officer may seize a vehicle subject to forfeiture under this section upon the issuance of an order by a court having jurisdiction of the vehicle.&#xA0; Seizure without court order may be made in any of the following circumstances:	(a)	The seizure is incident to an arrest or search under a search warrant;	(b)	There is probable cause to believe the vehicle was used in violation of this section.	2.	A peace officer seizing a vehicle under this section shall complete a receipt in accordance with Penal Code Section 1412 and deliver it to the person from whose possession the vehicle was seized.	3.	An immediate investigation shall be made by the public agency making the seizure as to any potential claimant to a seized vehicle whose right, title, interest, or lien is of record in the Department of Motor Vehicles of this or any other state or appropriate federal agency. The public agency shall send a notice of seizure within two business days of the vehicle&#x2019;s seizure, to all potential claimants whose right, title, interest or lien did not arise subsequent to the date and time of seizure of the vehicle, if that person or entity was not previously given a notice of seizure.	4.	The public agency seizing the vehicle shall provide any potential claimants discovered as a result of the investigation set out in D.3. with the opportunity for a post-seizure hearing to determine the validity of the seizure. The post-seizure hearing shall be conducted within two business days of the request for the hearing.&#xA0; The public agency may authorize its own officer or employee to conduct the hearing if the hearing officer is not the same person who directed the seizure of the vehicle. Failure of the potential claimant to request or attend a scheduled hearing within the appropriate time frame shall satisfy the post-seizure requirement.	(a)	The notice of seizure shall include the following:	(i)	the name, address and telephone number of the agency providing the notice;	(ii)	the authority and reason for the seizure;	(iii)	a statement that in order to receive their post-seizure hearing, the potential claimant shall request the hearing in person, in writing, or by telephone within ten calendar days of the date of the notice; and	(iv)	the time in which a claim of interest in the vehicle seized or subject to forfeiture is required to be filed.	5.	A vehicle seized pursuant to this section, where appropriate may be held as evidence in any proceeding brought by the City Attorney or District Attorney.	E.	Forfeiture and Notice of Intended Forfeiture of Vehicle.	1.	The City Attorney may, pursuant to this section, order the forfeiture of vehicles seized under this section.	2.	If the City Attorney determines that the factual circumstances warrant&#xA0; forfeiture of the vehicle described in Subsection B., the City Attorney shall serve a notice of intended forfeiture upon any person who has an interest in the seized vehicle.&#xA0; The notice shall be served as soon as practicable, but in any event within 30 calendar days of the seizure of the vehicle subject to forfeiture.	3.	The notice of intended forfeiture shall be served as follows:	(a)	By personal delivery or certified mail, return receipt requested, upon any person who has an interest in the seized vehicle as determined pursuant to Subsection D.3.	(b)	In the event that the person entitled to service refuses to accept certified return receipt mail or cannot be personally served, service may be made by substituted service.&#xA0; Substituted service may be accomplished by any one of the following methods:&#xA0;	(i)	By leaving a copy during usual business hours at the recipient&#x2019;s business with the person who is apparently in charge, and by thereafter mailing by first class mail a copy to the recipient where the copy was left;&#xA0;	(ii)	By leaving a copy at the recipient&#x2019;s dwelling or usual place of abode, in the presence of a competent member of the household and thereafter mailing by first class mail a copy to the recipient at the address where the copy was left.	(c)	If the person entitled to service lives out of state and will not accept certified return receipt mail, then service may be made by first class mail.	(d)	If the person entitled to notice cannot be located, or service cannot be effected as set forth in this subsection, service may be made by publication in a Los Angeles newspaper of general circulation.&#xA0; Service shall be deemed sufficient when it is accomplished pursuant to Government Code Section 6063.	F.	Claim Opposing Forfeiture and Court Proceedings.	1.	A person claiming an interest in the vehicle seized pursuant to Subsection B. must within ten calendar days from the date of the notice of intended forfeiture or within 30 calendar days from the date of first publication of the notice of intended forfeiture, file with the Superior Court of the county in which the vehicle was seized, a Claim Opposing Forfeiture, verified in accordance with Section 446 of the Code of Civil&#xA0; Procedure, stating his, her or its interest in the vehicle.&#xA0; An endorsed copy of the claim shall be served upon the City Attorney within ten calendar days of the filing of the claim.&#xA0;	2.	If a verified claim is filed in accordance with this section, the forfeiture proceeding shall be set for hearing within 30 calendar days from the date the claim is filed with the court. The City Attorney shall file a petition for forfeiture with the court within ten calendar days of service of the claim upon the City Attorney. A copy of the petition shall be served upon the claimant.	3.	The hearing shall be before the Superior Court of Los Angeles County.&#xA0; The provisions of the Code of Civil Procedure shall apply to proceedings under this section unless otherwise inconsistent with the provisions or procedures set forth in this section. &#xA0; However, in proceedings under this section, there shall be no joinder of actions, coordination of actions, except for forfeiture proceedings, or cross-complaints, and the issues shall be limited strictly to the questions related to this section. Trial shall be by court or jury.	4.	With respect to vehicles described in Subsection B. for which forfeiture is sought and as to which forfeiture is contested, the City Attorney shall have the burden of proving by a preponderance of the evidence that the vehicle was used as set forth in&#xA0; Subsection B.&#xA0;	5.	Upon proof that the vehicle was used for any of the purposes set forth in Subsection B., the court shall declare the vehicle a nuisance and order that the vehicle be forfeited, sold, and the proceeds distributed as set forth in Subsection G.&#xA0; The court may make a different distribution of the proceeds, if the court finds that the claimant did not know that the vehicle was used for a purpose that constitutes a violation of this section	6.	If no claims are timely filed, the City Attorney shall prepare a written declaration of forfeiture of the vehicle to the City.&#xA0; A written declaration of forfeiture signed by the City Attorney under this section shall be deemed to provide good and sufficient title to the forfeited vehicle.&#xA0; The proceeds from the disposal of the vehicle declared forfeited by the City Attorney shall be distributed in accordance with Subsection G.&#xA0; The City Attorney ordering forfeiture pursuant to this section shall provide a copy of the declaration of forfeiture to any person who received notice of the forfeiture proceedings.	G.	Disposal of Vehicle and Distribution of Proceeds.	1.	In all cases where vehicles seized pursuant to this section are forfeited to the City, the vehicles shall be sold, or if cash is paid as settlement in lieu of forfeiture of the vehicle, the proceeds of sale or settlement shall be distributed and appropriated as follows:&#xA0;
&#xA0;
	(a)	To pay costs associated with the towing, storage and release of any vehicle seized under this section.	(b) 	To pay costs associated with the sale of the vehicle.	(c)	To the lien holder of the vehicle, if any, up to the amount of his, her or its interest in the vehicle.	2.	The remaining funds shall be distributed as follows:	(a)	To the City Attorney for all expenditures other than personnel costs, made or incurred by the Office in connection with the enforcement of this section, including but not limited to, costs for equipment, investigation, supplies, litigation, insurance and liability resulting from enforcement of this section and costs of publication of the notices set forth in Subsection E.	(b)	To local law enforcement for all expenditures other than personnel costs, made or incurred by the Department in connection with enforcement of this section, including but not limited to, costs for equipment, investigation and supplies related to enforcement of this section.	(c)	To the general fund.
	
	3.	For budgeting purposes, funds attributable to this ordinance shall not be considered anticipated revenue into the general fund.	H.	Stolen Vehicles.&#xA0; A vehicle that has been reported stolen, prior to a seizure under this section shall not be subject to forfeiture unless the identity of the registered owner cannot be reasonably ascertained or the registered owner fails to redeem the vehicle within 60 days of the seizure.&#xA0; The registered owner of the vehicle may claim the vehicle upon payment of tow, storage and release charges, provided the vehicle is not subject to any holds for traffic or parking violations and the vehicle registration is current.&#xA0;	I.	Recovery of Monetary Loss.&#xA0; Nothing in this section shall preclude an owner of a vehicle who suffers a monetary loss from the forfeiture of a vehicle under this section from recovering the amount of the actual monetary loss from the person who committed the act giving rise to forfeiture under this section.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><unit></unit></prefixes><entire_prefix></entire_prefix><prefix_anchor></prefix_anchor><level>1</level></unit></text></law>
