<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><section_number>42.00</section_number><edition_id>1</edition_id><section_id>2783</section_id><structure_id>21</structure_id><catch_line>Regulation Of Soliciting And Sales In Streets.</catch_line><history></history><full_text>&#xA0; REGULATION OF SOLICITING AND SALES IN STREETS.

	(a)	(Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)&#xA0; In this section, unless the context or subject matter otherwise requires:

	&#x201C;News racks&#x201D; shall mean any self-service or coin-operated box, container, storage unit or other dispenser installed, used, or maintained for the display and sale of newspapers, news periodicals or other news publications.

	&#x201C;Newsstand&#x201D; shall mean any stand, shelter, case, cabinet, box or other structure installed, used, or maintained for the display, sale or storage of newspapers, news periodicals or other news publications which is attended by the owner or his employee while making sales therefrom.
	&#x201C;Street&#x201D; shall mean all that area dedicated to public use for public street purposes and shall include, but not be limited to roadways, parkways, alleys and sidewalks.

	&#x201C;Roadway&#x201D; shall mean that portion of a street improved, designed, or ordinarily used for vehicular travel.

	&#x201C;Parkway&#x201D; shall mean that area between the edge of the roadway and the adjacent property line excluding that area occupied by the sidewalks. Parkway shall also include any area within a roadway which is not open to vehicular travel.

	&#x201C;Sidewalk&#x201D; shall mean any surface provided for the exclusive use of pedestrians.

	(b)	Street Sale of Goods Prohibited.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 169,319, Eff. 2/18/94.)&#xA0; No person, except as otherwise permitted by this section, shall on any sidewalk or street offer for sale, solicit the sale of, announce by any means the availability of, or have in his or her possession, control or custody, whether upon his or her person or upon some other animate or inanimate object, any goods, wares or merchandise which the public may purchase at any time.&#xA0; This subsection shall not apply to the sale of poppies, badges and labels as defined by Military and Veterans Code Section 1800 on a parkway or sidewalk by persons bearing a valid information card issued pursuant to Article 4 of this chapter authorizing such person to do so.

	(c)	Street-Soliciting Employment of Services Prohibited.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(1)	No person, except as otherwise permitted by this section, shall on any street offer for sale, solicit the employment of, or announce by any means the availability of, any goods, wares, merchandise, services or facilities, or solicit patrons for or advertise any show, exhibition, entertainment, tour, excursion, sight-seeing trip, or real estate viewing or inspection trip.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 169,319, Eff. 2/18/94.)

	(2)	No person who is visible or audible to any person on any street shall, in a loud, boisterous, raucous, offensive or insulting manner, offer for sale, solicit the purchase of, announce the availability of, or solicit the employment of any goods, wares, merchandise, services or facilities, or solicit patronage for or advertise any show, exhibition, entertainment tour, excursion sight-seeing trip, real estate, or oil well viewing or inspection trip.

	(3)	Nothing in Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be so construed as to apply to a sight-seeing tour operating under and by virtue of a permit from and regulations of the Public Utilities Commission of the State of California and for which tour a fixed charge is made to the person carried.

	(d)	Street-Sidewalk &#x2013; Advertising on.&#xA0; No person shall except as otherwise provided in Subsection (j) of this section have, bear, wear or carry upon any street, any advertising banner, flag, board, sign, transparency, wearing apparel or other device advertising, publicity announcing or calling attention to any goods, wares, merchandise, or commodities, or to any place of business, occupation, show, exhibition, event or entertainment. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to the wearing of apparel without remuneration for doing so or business identification on wearing apparel. (Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(e)	Streets News Venders.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(1)	No person shall sell or offer for sale any newspaper, magazine, periodical, news publication or other printed matter while upon the roadway of any street within the City of Los Angeles provided, however, that persons engaged in selling or offering for sale or disposing of newspapers, news periodicals or other news publications may sell, offer for sale, solicit the purchase of and advertise the same upon any portion of the sidewalk or parkway, subject to Subsections (f), (g), (h) and (j) of this section where applicable.

	(2)	No person, under the age of 10 years, shall sell or offer for sale any newspaper, magazine, periodical, news publication or other printed matter while upon any portion of a street. This subsection shall not prohibit persons, except as otherwise prohibited by law, from soliciting the sale of or delivery of newspapers, magazines, periodicals, news publications and other printed matter to residences or places of business fronting upon a street.

	(f)	Streets &#x2013; News Racks.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 176,339, Eff. 1/19/05.)

	(1)	Definitions:&#xA0; The following words, terms and phrases, when used in the following subsections shall have the meaning ascribed to them in this subsection, except where the context clearly indicates a different meaning:

	(A)	&#x201C;Equivalent newsrack&#x201D; means any newsrack that is of the same size and dimensions of the specified newsrack.

	(B)	If &#x201C;demand warrants&#x201D; or &#x201C;warranted demand&#x201D; means the measured stack height needed to meet the newspaper publisher&#x2019;s or distributor&#x2019;s peak daily distribution at the requested newsrack location, as proven to the Board by the newspaper publisher or distributor, exceeds (14) inches.

	(C)	&#x201C;Individual newsrack&#x201D; means and includes a newsrack designed with a single enclosed compartment to accommodate at any one time the display, sale, or free distribution of like copies of a single newspaper or other publication, or which has more than one (1) compartment and complies with the dimensions of an individual newsrack as provided in Subsection (7)(B).

	(D)	&#x201C;Newsrack&#x201D; or &#x201C;News Rack&#x201D; means any unstaffed, self-service, free, or coin-operated box, container, storage unit or other dispenser located in or upon, or projecting onto, or over, any part of the public right-of-way, and which is installed, used or maintained for the display, sale, or free distribution of newspapers and other publications.

	(E)	&#x201C;Modular newsrack&#x201D; means a newsrack which is designed with separate enclosed compartments to accommodate at any one time the display, sale or free distribution of multiple distinct and separate newspapers or other publications, and which exceeds the dimensions of an individual newsrack as provided in Subsection (7)(B).

	(F)	&#x201C;Modular newsrack provider&#x201D; means the person or other legal entity that is authorized under Subsection (4)(A)(7) to place and maintain modular newsracks upon the public right-of-way.

	(G)	&#x201C;Publisher&#x201D; means the person or other legal entity selling, displaying, or distributing free newspapers or other publications in a newsrack.

	(H)	&#x201C;News-Stand/Kiosk&#x201D; means any stand, shelter, or other structure installed, used, or maintained for the display, sale or storage of newspapers, news periodicals or other news publications.

	(I)	&#x201C;Public right-of-way&#x201D; means any public street, sidewalk, parkway, alley or other location owned or otherwise controlled by the City for the benefit of the general public.

	(J)	&#x201C;Block face&#x201D; means the sidewalk on one side of a street, between one intersection and the immediately adjacent intersection.&#xA0;

	(2)	Purpose and Criteria:&#xA0; The purpose of the following Subsections is to promote the public health, safety, and general welfare of the citizens and visitors to the City through the regulation of placement, type, appearance, and maintenance of newsracks on public rights-of-way so as to:

	(A)	Provide for pedestrian and driver safety and convenience.

	(B)	Restrict unreasonable interference with the flow of pedestrian or vehicular traffic, including, but not limited to, ingress into and egress from any residence or place of business, or from the street to the sidewalk, or from the sidewalk to the street by persons exiting or entering parked or standing vehicles.

	(C)	Provide for the safety of the general public and property during emergency conditions.

	(D)	Provide reasonable access for the use and maintenance of poles, posts, traffic signs and/or signals, hydrants, mailboxes, and access to locations used for public transportation purposes.

	(E)	Allow for the placement and maintenance of modular newsracks in the modular newsrack areas, as determined by the City Council, to be placed in locations throughout the city which afford easy, convenient service to pedestrians, but do not obstruct or interfere with access to abutting properties, and which do not impede or endanger pedestrian, bicycle, or vehicular traffic.

	(F)	Relocate and/or replace or remove newsracks which result in visual blight and/or are not installed according to this code on the public rights-of-way or which block or interfere with the aesthetics of store window displays, adjacent businesses, landscaping, street furniture, public or private, and other improvements as well as to allow the removal of abandoned newsracks.

	(G)	Maintain and protect the values of surrounding properties, and ensure that the aesthetics and historical attributes of adjacent businesses are not compromised by the unregulated placement of newsracks in the public right-of-way.

	(H)	Reduce unnecessary exposure of the public to personal injury or property damage.

	(I)	Maintain and preserve freedom of the press to distribute periodicals and newspapers.

	(J)	Reduce visual blight and improve the aesthetic appearance of the City&#x2019;s streets and sidewalks for the merchants, citizens and visitors to the City by coordinating the uniform color of all newsracks with the color of the City&#x2019;s extensive multi-million dollar street furniture program; and in Specific Plan Areas, Streetscape Plan Areas or other Special Planning Districts, which have a standard streetscape color, to allow for a uniform newsrack color from a limited palate of colors in order to coordinate the color of newsracks with their streetscape.

	(3)	Compliance Phase In:

	(A)	The provisions of this subdivision shall apply to all newsracks, whether installed and maintained prior to or after the effective date of this ordinance which in whole or in part rests upon, in, or over any dedicated sidewalk, right-of-way or parkway.&#xA0; Those newsracks installed prior to the effective date of this revised ordinance shall be brought into compliance with the all provisions of this code, except uniform color, as this revised ordinance is implemented by Street Services, area by area, within the City.&#xA0; In no event shall compliance be later than 12 months after the effective date hereof, except that, if the City&#x2019;s implementation schedule takes longer than 12 months, then compliance by the publishers shall follow the City&#x2019;s implementation schedule.&#xA0; If a publisher chooses not to come into compliance with the uniform color requirement of this ordinance at the time it obtains a valid permit and legally places its newsracks as required by the City&#x2019;s implementation schedule, then compliance with the uniform color requirement must be accomplished no later than 24 months after the effective date of this ordinance.&#xA0; However, Publishers experiencing financial hardship, solely due to compliance with LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f) as it applies to uniform color, may request the Board to approve one 12-month extension allowing them a total of 36 months to come into full compliance with the uniform color requirement of the Newsrack Ordinance, if evidence of financial hardship is proven to the satisfaction of the Board.&#xA0; Any newsrack not brought into compliance within the aforementioned time period shall be deemed to be in violation of LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f).

	(4)	Permit Required:&#xA0; No person shall install or maintain any newsrack upon any public right-of-way without first applying for and receiving a permit from the City&#x2019;s Board of Public Works, herein after referred to as &#x201C;Board&#x201D;.&#xA0; A permit will not be issued unless the application is completed in full, the requested installation meets all the appropriate placement criteria as set forth below, and the application is accompanied by the appropriate permit fee for the type of newsrack, single, pedestal, or modular, for each individual newsrack installation requested.&#xA0; Any permit granted pursuant to the provisions of this code shall only be valid as to the specific location specified in the permit application.&#xA0; Where application is made for the installation of two or more single newsracks, a separate permit shall be required for each individual newsrack.&#xA0; Upon this revised ordinance taking legal effect in the City of Los Angeles, any owner of a newsrack currently existing on any City right-of-way must apply for a permit pursuant to this ordinance within the time specified by the Board of Public Works in its Rules and Regulations for the implementation of this ordinance.&#xA0; Any newsrack which is not the subject of a valid permit application as required by the City&#x2019;s implementation Rules and Regulations will be deemed to be in violation of 42.00 (f) of this code and subject to removal from the right-of-way as set forth herein.

	(A)	Permit Application.&#xA0; Permit applications shall be in writing and on forms as provided by the Board.&#xA0; The permit application shall include the following information:

	(1)	The name, address, and telephone number of the applicant who is the owner and/or principal responsible for the newsrack.

	(2)	The name, address, and telephone number of a responsible person whom the City may notify or contact at any time concerning the applicant&#x2019;s newsrack(s).

	(3)	The specified number of newsracks and the detailed proposed location for each one, shown on a drawing of the location, or GIS/Address based program provided by applicant which is compatible with the City&#x2019;s GIS program and which indicates all existing buildings, existing newsracks at the location and general vicinity, and all other possible obstructions within 20 feet of the proposed location of the newsrack.

	(4)	Names of newspaper(s) or periodical(s) to be placed in each newsrack.&#xA0; One or more newspapers or periodicals may be dispensed from a single newsrack if the newsrack is manufactured for this purpose.

	(5)	Type or brand of newsrack, including an illustration and description of the newsrack and mount, if other than a single pedestal, size of base plate and whether the newsrack will have a coin-box attachment, or equivalent.

	(6)	A sworn statement under penalty of perjury, executed by an officer, director, or authorized agent of the applicant, agreeing that the applicant shall not sell, assign, or transfer by any method, the permit for the newsrack location to any other publisher, distributor, entity or individual.

	(7)	The Board, with Council approval, may designate areas of the City where only modular newsracks may be installed and maintained by a City vendor such as the City Hall Historical District, (the east block face on Spring Street between Temple Street and 1st Street, the south block face of Temple Street between Spring Street and Main Street, the west block face of Main Street between Temple Street and 1st Street, and the north block face of 1st Street between Spring Street and Main Street).&#xA0; No application for an individual newsrack permit may be submitted in a modular newsrack area. Upon the effective date of this ordinance, the total number of compartments in modular newsracks in any designated modular newsrack area, shall be substantially equivalent to the highest total number of individual newsracks known to have been legally maintained on the public right-of-way in the modular newsrack areas at any one time during the year preceding the introduction of this amended ordinance but in no event more than the total number of newsracks allowed by subparagraph (F)(4) below.

	(8)	Such other information as, from time to time, may be required by the Board.

	(B)	Expiration &#x2013; Renewal.&#xA0; Unless earlier revoked, newsrack permits issued pursuant to the provisions of this code shall expire on the 30th day of August following the date upon which each such permit is granted.&#xA0; Such permits may thereafter be renewed annually upon the payment of the fee hereinafter prescribed.&#xA0; Applications for renewal shall be made at least 30 days prior to the expiration of any permit issued, and must be accompanied by a permit renewal fee as set forth in Subsection (4)(C), below.&#xA0; Application for permit renewal and payment must be either presented in person to the Bureau of Street Services, via the Internet (if available), or mailed via certified mail, postmarked no later than 30 days prior to the date of permit expiration.&#xA0; Failure to renew an existing newsrack permit before its expiration will require the payment of a late renewal penalty as set forth in Subsection (4)(C), below, or the loss of the placement of the said rack at the subject location.

	(C)	Fees.&#xA0; The Board shall establish all fees, in accordance with the level of enforcement deemed appropriate by the Council, and shall only be used to defray the total expenses of operation of the newsrack program including: permitting, inspection, administration, and enforcement, required by this Ordinance as set forth in the preceding and following sections of this code.&#xA0; The Initial Permit Fee, the Renewal Permit Fee, the Site Inspection Fee, the Site Re-Inspection Fee, Late Renewal Penalty Fee, Impound Fees, and the Bar Code Decal Replacement Fee shall be determined and adopted from time to time by the Board.

	(D)	Insurance.

	(1)	Requirement-Content.&#xA0; As a condition of the City granting any person or persons one or more permits to maintain a newsrack or newsracks in the public right-of-way, any such permittee shall be required to maintain a policy of general liability insurance, naming the City of Los Angeles, the Board of Public Works and its employees, agents etc. as &#x201C;Additional Insureds&#x201D; for the specific purpose of indemnifying and holding harmless the City of Los Angeles, its officers, boards, employees, etc. from and against any and all losses, costs, damages, expenses, or liability, whatsoever, which may result from or arise out of the granting of a permit, and/or the installation and/or the maintenance of any newsrack or newsracks for which the permittee shall be responsible for paying any and all losses or damages that may be sustained by any person or persons as a result of, or which may be caused by or arise out of the installation and/or maintenance of the permitted newsrack or newsracks.&#xA0; The policy of insurance shall be maintained in its original amount by the permittee at permittee&#x2019;s expense at all times during the period for which the permittee holds a valid permit or permits.&#xA0; Should said policy be called upon to satisfy any liability for damages covered by said policy, the policy must be of such a nature that the original amount of coverage is restored after any payment of damages by the policy.&#xA0; In the event that two or more permits are issued to one permittee, the permittee shall only be required to maintain a single policy of insurance covering all such permits held by the permittee in the amount set forth below for the number of newsracks maintained by the permittee.

	(2)	Required Limits of Liability Insurance.&#xA0; The Board shall be responsible, from time to time, for adopting the limits of liability insurance required to be maintained by newsrack permittees under this code.&#xA0; The Board shall receive a recommendation from the City&#x2019;s Risk Manager prior to setting the limits of liability insurance based on the number of racks that each permittee maintains in the City&#x2019;s right-of-way.

	(E)	Every person who installs, uses or maintains any newsrack which in whole or in part rests upon, in, or over any dedicated sidewalk or parkway shall have his or her name, address and telephone number affixed thereto at a place where such information may be easily seen, in addition to a bar code decal issued by the Board for that specific newsrack.

	(5)	Prohibited Where Vehicles Permitted:&#xA0; No person shall install or maintain any newsrack which projects onto, into or over any part of the roadway of any public street, or which rests, wholly or in part, upon, along or over any portion of such roadway.

	(6)	Unlawful Obstructions:&#xA0; No person shall install, use or maintain any newsrack:

	(A)	Within 5 feet of any marked crosswalk;

	(B)	Within 5 feet of the curb return of any unmarked crosswalk;

	(C)	Within 5 feet of any fire hydrant, fire call box or other emergency facility;

	(D)	Within 5 feet ahead and 45 feet to the rear of any sign marking a designated bus stop.&#xA0; No newsrack shall be installed within the marked bus zone;

	(E)	Within 5 feet of any bus bench.

	(F)	Within 10 feet of any transit shelter.&#xA0;

	(G)	In front of an entrance to a business, including the curb area directly across from such entrance where the distance between the entry door and the newsrack is less than 10 feet;

	(H)	In any location used, marked or posted for public utility purpose, public transportation purpose or government use;

	(I)	Where placement unreasonably interferes with the use of poles, posts, traffic signs or signals, mail boxes or other objects legally permitted, but in no event shall the newsrack be closer than one foot from such objects;

	(J)	Where placement interferes with the reasonable use or utility for display purposes of any display window of any building abutting the sidewalk or parkway, but in no event within 4 feet of such window;

	(K)	Within 5 feet of any area improved with lawn, flowers shrubs, trees or street tree well;

	(L)	Within 5 feet of any driveway or driveway apron;

	(M)	Within 4 feet of any outdoor dining areas or patio dining areas;

	(N)	Within 20 feet of both sides of buildings officially designated Los Angeles Historical or Cultural Monuments.&#xA0; If there is a block in which all buildings have been so officially designated, then the Board, in consultation with the Cultural Heritage Commission, shall determine siting on such block face for up to four (4) newsracks.&#xA0; An owner of a building which has been designated as a Historical or Cultural Monument may petition the Board of Public Works to allow newsracks on the sidewalks in front of their building if the placement of such newsracks will not interfere with Historic or Cultural nature of the building.&#xA0; The Board shall listen to evidence from all interested parties and make its determination based on the totality of the evidence.

	(O)	Within 20 feet of both sides of visual public art work created, funded or managed through the City&#x2019;s Municipal Art Program including, but not limited to, murals, sculptures and fountains.

	(P)	Where placement impedes the flow of pedestrian traffic by reducing the clear space to less than 6 feet or, impedes access to or the use of abutting property, including, but not limited to, residences and places of business.

	(Q)	Notwithstanding any other paragraph of this subdivision, no person shall install, use or maintain any newsrack where placement endangers the safety of persons or property.

	(R)	No newsrack shall be installed within 4 feet from any permanently installed structure in the public Right-of-Way, which is not otherwise specifically identified in this subdivision.

	(S)	Within one foot of any utility cover, vent screen or other object that is flush mounted with the sidewalk, except that if the owner or person in control of the below grade sidewalk installation needs additional space for emergency or non-routine maintenance of the installation, any newsrack(s) which interferes with such maintenance may be requested to be temporarily removed to accommodate the required maintenance and then be reinstalled.

	(T)	Within 4 feet to the front and 10 feet to the rear of any parking meter and where there are no parking meters on the curb, 10 feet from the front of any marked parallel parking place.

	(7)	Size, Appearance, Placement, Installation and Construction of Newsracks:

	(A)	 Every newsrack shall be maintained in a neat and clean condition and be in good repair at all times.

	(B)	All newsracks shall be permanently mounted, except as provided in Subsection (7)(C), in accordance with specifications established by the Board as provided in Subsection (9) and adopted from time to time as revisions become necessary, including but not limited to: style, construction, coating, material and fabrication.&#xA0; Specifications for a newsrack shall be:

	(1)	Street tube pedestal, at least four inches by three inches in height;

	(2)	Overall height shall not be less than 46 inches and shall not exceed 52 inches; the overall width shall not be less than 20 inches and shall not exceed 30 inches; and the overall depth shall not be less than 12 inches and shall not exceed 20 inches.

	(3)	All newsracks shall be primarily constructed of metal and shall be &#x201C;Ivy Green&#x201D; in color (Tiger RAL 607 SM, Glossy, Code 28-50081), except as provided in &#xA7; 42.00 (f)(17) &#x201C;Specific Plan/Street Scape Plan Areas&#x201D;.

	(C)	Special Purpose Sidewalks; No Permanent Attachments.&#xA0; Each individual newsrack which is permitted to be placed on a special purpose sidewalk, such as terrazzo, brick, glass prism implanted, or where basements are located under the sidewalk, shall be on legs and shall be mobile and not affixed to the sidewalk in any way.

	(D)	Pedestals.&#xA0; No pedestals shall be maintained on a public right-of-way unless there is attached thereto a newsrack case as provided herein.

	(E)	Removal of Newsracks; Repair of Sidewalks.&#xA0; Upon the removal of any newsrack, the person so removing shall be responsible for the repair of any resulting condition, including filling in of any holes left in the sidewalk and/or the removal of any bolts or other devices used to affix the newsrack to the sidewalk such that there are no obstructions sticking above the grade of the sidewalk.&#xA0; Such work is to be done to the satisfaction of the Department of Public Works.

	(F)	Newsrack Location.

	(1)	Newsracks shall only be situated near a curb with the back of said newsrack situated not less than 18 inches nor more than 24 inches from the edge of the curb.&#xA0; If it is physically impossible to situate a newsrack near a curb, then the Board may authorize the placement of up to four (4) newsracks adjacent to the wall of a building on that block.&#xA0; If the newsrack is placed adjacent to the wall of a building, the back of said newsrack shall be situated parallel to and not more than 6 inches from such wall.&#xA0; No newsrack shall be installed, used or maintained on any sidewalk or parkway opposite a newsstand or other newsrack.

	(2)	Except as otherwise provided by this code, no newsrack placed on the public right-of-way shall be chained, bolted or otherwise attached to any property or to any permanently fixed object.

	(3)	Not more than four newsracks shall be placed immediately adjacent to each other.&#xA0; Any such group of up to four newsracks shall be separated by a space of not less than 48 inches from any other individual newsrack or group of newsracks.

	(4)	Not more than 16 newsracks shall be placed within 200 ft. of the same block face.&#xA0; However, the Board may establish a number greater or less than 16 in any specific block face by conducting an engineering study.&#xA0; In cases where a block face is longer than 200 ft., for every additional 50 ft. of block face greater than 200 ft., an additional four (4) newsracks may be installed.

	(5)	Not more than one permit for installation of a newsrack shall be issued for each publication on one side of a block or within 200 ft. of the same block face, whichever is less. One publication includes: differing geographic editions of the same publication (Orange County edition; Valley edition, etc.); and daily and Sunday editions of the same publication.&#xA0; In cases where a block face is longer than 200 ft., and there is space to legally install additional newsracks, then a permit for one publication to install a second newsrack on the same block face may be issued by the Board.

	(6)	Newsracks shall not be permitted on the public right-of-way adjacent to any property that is zoned exclusively for single-family residential use (R-1).

	(G)	Priorities Related to Placement of Newsracks.

	(1)	In determining in what order newsrack permittees may select their location on a particular block face during implementation of this revised newsrack ordinance, and in particular where there are more requests for newsrack spaces on any one block face than there are legal spaces available, the Board of Public Works shall, pursuant to its authority under paragraph (9) below, develop a content neutral criteria for determining the placement of newsracks applicable to each block face.

	(2)	Once this revised newsrack ordinance has been fully implemented citywide, all subsequent newsrack permits shall be issued on a first come first served basis.

	(8)	Unlawful Use:&#xA0; No newsrack shall be used for advertising signs or publicity purposes. External lettering is restricted to the following:

	(A)	If the newsrack is situated next to the curb, the side parallel to the curb, next to the lanes of traffic, may have external lettering replicating the publication masthead style and color, for the permitted publication in the subject newsrack, in a total area not to exceed 144 square inches.

	If an individual newsrack is used to distribute more than one publication, each publication distributed in that newsrack shall be entitled to have external lettering replicating the publication masthead style and color for the permitted publications in the subject newsrack.&#xA0; However, the total area for all such publication mastheads on that newsrack shall not exceed 144 square inches.

	(B)	The side of the newsrack facing pedestrian traffic, except in Specific Plan/Streetscape Plan Areas, as identified in Section (17), may have a &#x201C;Rack Card&#x201D;, with a total area not to exceed 238 square inches, which exclusively advertises the newspaper or periodical being dispensed, and shall not include any third party advertising.&#xA0; This &#x201C;Rack Card&#x201D; shall be located in the area immediately below the hood on the front access side of the newsrack.

	(C)	Other than as permitted in this section, no other lettering or advertising of any kind shall be permitted anywhere else on the newsrack, including the mount.

	(9)	Authority of the Board of Public Works to Promulgate Rules and Regulations for the Permitting, Installation and Maintenance of the Newsracks in the Public Right-of-Way:&#xA0; Consistent with the intent and requirements of LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f), et seq., the Board may adopt rules and regulations to administer the installation, placement, maintenance, size and material used for construction of newsracks.&#xA0; The Board may adopt any other rule and/or regulation for the protection of public safety, welfare, or property relative to permitting, installation, and maintenance of newsracks.&#xA0; Prior to adoption of any rules and/or regulations, the Board shall hold a public hearing.&#xA0; Once any rules and/or regulations are adopted, they shall be kept posted in the Board office and a copy thereof shall be furnished to any applicant for a newsrack permit.

	(10)	Noncompliance With LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f), et seq.; Tagging of Newsracks:&#xA0; Except as provided in Subsection (12) hereof, whenever any newsrack is found to be in violation of any Subsection of LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f), the Board shall cause a notice tag to be attached to said newsrack specifying the date and nature of the violation, and shall E-mail or fax to the permittee a copy of the violation.&#xA0; Permittee shall within ten (10) calendar days from the date on which the tag was attached, either cause the violation to be corrected or request a hearing pursuant to Subsection (13) hereof.&#xA0; If a hearing is requested, staff will not remove the non compliant newsrack until a final determination by the Board. However, if a newsrack installed within the City right-of-way has no visible evidence that it has been properly permitted (no City issued bar code decal, no visible contact information for the owner or no other evidence that would indicate that a valid permit for the newsrack had been issued) staff may confiscate the offending newsrack and follow the procedures in subparagraph (11)(B) below.&#xA0; There is hereby created a presumption that any newsrack within the City&#x2019;s right-of-way that does not have a city bar code decal, or visible identification and contact information for the owner of the newsrack, has been installed without a valid permit.

	(A)	A newsrack may be tagged for any violation of any requirement of LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f) including, but not limited to, the following:

	(1)	Where its installation, use or maintenance unreasonably interferes with or impedes the flow of vehicular or pedestrian traffic;

	(2)	Where its installation, use or maintenance interferes with the use of poles, posts, traffic signs or signals, hydrants, mailboxes or other objects legally permitted;

	(3)	Where its installation, use or maintenance unreasonably obstructs, interferes with or impedes access to or the use of abutting property, including, but not limited to, residences, places of business, or legally parked or stopped vehicles;

	(4)	When such newsrack does not have a name, address and telephone number affixed in a place where such information may be easily seen and the designee of such newsrack cannot be otherwise identified;

	(5)	When a newsrack is found in the public right-of-way which does not have a visible, city issued, bar code decal present indicating the correct permit number of the newsrack or the newsrack has no valid permit at all; and

	(6)	When a newsrack is found in the public right-of-way which is not maintained in a neat and clean condition and in good repair, in accordance with the following Maintenance Specifications:

	(a)	The newsrack permittee shall maintain all newsracks and the sidewalk surface immediately under and adjacent (within 2 feet) to the newsracks in a safe, clean, attractive and sanitary condition and in good order and repair, as determined by the Department of Public Works, Bureau of Street Services (BOSS).&#xA0; The permittee shall make routine inspection and maintenance calls on each newsrack once a week.&#xA0; Such inspection and maintenance calls may be incorporated with delivery of newspapers or other publications.&#xA0; The permittee shall make more frequent calls if conditions warrant.&#xA0; At each maintenance call, the permittee shall clean, wash and remove all graffiti, stickers, posters, litter, dust, dirt and weeds at each newsrack.&#xA0; The newsrack shall be maintained in a continual good and working condition.

	(b)	Maintenance &#x2013; Permittee shall respond to a request to secure a site or to perform maintenance within 24 hours of notification, but in no event more than 72 hours.&#xA0; The permittee shall use cleaning methods and procedures that have been demonstrated and approved and are environmentally safe, utilizing acceptable industry practices.

	(c)	Repair and Replacement &#x2013; The Permittee shall commence necessary repairs within one week when any damage or vandalism is found by BOSS.&#xA0; If the newsrack damage or vandalism is of an emergency or hazardous nature, the permittee will repair, replace, remove or secure the site within 24 hours of notification.&#xA0; If the newsrack is totally destroyed because of an accident, the Permittee will remove the newsrack and appurtenant structures within 24 hours, including repair of any damage to the public right-of- way, returning the site to its former condition prior to the newsrack installation.

	(d)	Graffiti Removal &#x2013; Permittee will upon notification by BOSS, or upon inspection, remove graffiti within 24 hours from any newsrack.&#xA0;

	(11)	Impounding of Newsracks:

	(A)	Notwithstanding the Department&#x2019;s right to tag newsracks in violation of any Subsection on LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f), the Department may cause any newsrack to be impounded:

	(1)	When the newsrack poses an immediate danger to persons or vehicles;

	(2)	Where its installation, use or maintenance endangers the safety of persons or property;

	(3)	When pursuant to Subsection (10), a tag has been attached to a newsrack and a written notice, such as fax, letter or E-mail has been sent to the owner, operator, or responsible person for the newsrack and the designee has neither caused the violation specified on said tag to be corrected nor requested a hearing pursuant to Subsection (14), hereof within the time permitted;

	(4)	When a hearing and appeal, if filed, have resulted in a final determination that the violation(s) specified on the tag attached to such newsrack has in fact occurred, and the designee has failed to correct such violation(s) within ten (10) calendar days from the date of said determination;

	(5)	When a request for a hearing or appeal has been withdrawn, such request shall be deemed withdrawn, either by actual withdrawal or by the failure of the designee to fully comply with Subsection (14) of this code;

	(6)	When such newsrack has been abandoned; and

	(7)	When such newsrack has been installed on the City&#x2019;s right-of-way without first applying for and receiving a permit as required by this code.

	Pursuant to this Subsection, a newsrack shall be deemed abandoned when it does not contain the newspaper or other publication specified therefor for more than four (4) consecutive days for a daily publication, eight (8) consecutive days for a weekly publication, sixteen (16) consecutive days for a biweekly publication, or thirty-four (34) days for a monthly publication.&#xA0; A newsstand shall be deemed abandoned if it is not open for a period of more than seven (7) consecutive days.

	(B)	Standard impound procedures:&#xA0; Within forty-eight (48) hours after removal of any newsrack, the Board shall notify the owner in writing, fax or E-mail of the removal and the reason for removal where ownership information is posted on the newsrack either through the City bar code decal or the required owner contact information.&#xA0; If ownership information is not readily available because there is no City bar code decal, or ownership identification information posted on the newsrack, or no newspaper or periodical in the newsrack with contact information, the City shall make every reasonable effort to comply with the notification procedure of this subsection.&#xA0; When notification is possible, the notice shall also inform the owner of the right to request, either in writing or in person, within five (5) business days of the date of the postmark of such written notice, a hearing by the Board or its designee pursuant to Subsection (14), to determine whether such removal was proper.

	(12)	Return of Impounded Newsracks:

	(A)	Any newsrack, together with its contents, which has been impounded pursuant to Subdivision (11) hereof, shall be returned to the permittee:

	(1)	Upon receipt of an impound fee as determined herein; or

	(2)	Upon a determination after hearing by the Board or its designee, pursuant to Subsection (14) hereof, that the newsrack should not have been impounded and should be returned to the permittee;

	(B)	In the event a hearing has not been requested pursuant to Subsection (14) within the time permitted following the impoundment of any newsrack, an impound fee as set forth herein shall be imposed upon the permittee and shall be paid before the impounded newsrack is returned.

	(C)	The fees herein shall be determined and adopted by the Board in order to collect sufficient money to defer the complete cost of the City&#x2019;s newsrack permitting and enforcement program as set forth in this code.&#xA0; The fees shall be adjusted from time to time by the Board to reflect any change in the cost of permitting and enforcement.&#xA0; At no time shall the fees adopted by the Board recover more than the actual cost of the program.

	(13)	Sale or Disposal After Impoundment:&#xA0; The Department may sell or otherwise dispose of any newsrack, together with its contents, and retain the proceeds, pursuant to California Government Code Section 50050 et seq., from any such sale or other disposition, and any monies contained in said newsrack at the time of its impoundment, provided that either:

	(A)	No hearing has been requested pursuant to Subsection (14) within the time permitted;

	(B)	A hearing and an appeal, if filed, have resulted in a final determination that said newsrack was properly impounded, and fees assessed pursuant to Subsection (12) have not been received within thirty (30) days from the date of the final determination.

	(14)	Hearings:

	(A)	Request for Hearing &#x2013; Any newsrack permittee may file a written request with the Department for a hearing, in person or by certified mail, for the purpose of demonstrating that a newsrack should not have been impounded, or that a violation as specified on the tag attached to a newsrack pursuant to Subsection (10) hereof has not in fact occurred.

	(B)	Notice of Hearing &#x2013; Within two (2) working days from the date on which the request for hearing is received, the Department shall set a hearing date and shall notify the designee by certified mail of the date, time and place of said hearing.&#xA0; Said hearing shall occur within ten (10) working days of the date of mailing the notice unless the person requesting the hearing wishes to have the hearing at a later date, and both parties agree on the date.

	(C)	Conduct of Hearing &#x2013; At the time set for such hearing, or at the date to which such hearing is continued, the Board or its designee shall receive all evidence relevant to the occurrence or non-occurrence of the specified violation(s), the compliance or noncompliance with any of the provisions of this Subsection, and any other relevant information.&#xA0; Such hearing need not be conducted according to technical rules relating to evidence and witnesses.&#xA0; Oral evidence shall be taken only on oath or affirmation.

	(D)	Decision after Hearing &#x2013; Within ten (10) working days after the conclusion of the hearing, the Board or its designee shall find and determine, from the facts adduced at said hearing, whether the newsrack should have been tagged and/or impounded, and whether said newsrack shall be returned except upon receipt of fees as specified in Subsection (12). The decision of the Board or its designee shall be in writing and shall contain findings of fact, a determination of the issues presented, and the amount of the fee, if any, to be imposed.

	(E)	Notice of Decision &#x2013; The Department shall send to the designee, by certified mail, a copy of its decision and order.

	(15)	No Criminal Sanctions:&#xA0; Notwithstanding any provision of Subsection 11.00 (m) of this Code, no person shall be subject to the imposition of criminal liability for any violation of LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f).

	(16)	No Newsrack Areas &#x2013; Regional Historic or Cultural Significance:

	(A)	No newsrack shall be installed in an area deemed by the City Cultural Heritage Commission and the City Council to be of municipal or regional historic significance or regional cultural significance, including any of the following locations:

	(1)	On the Hollywood Walk of Fame (both sides of Hollywood Boulevard between La Brea Avenue and Gower Street, and both sides of Vine Street between Yucca Street and Sunset Boulevard);

	(2)	On the sidewalks immediately contiguous to the restored City Hall (the east block face on Spring Street between Temple Street and 1st Street, the south block face of Temple Street between Spring Street and Main Street, the west block face of Main Street between Temple Street and 1st Street, and the north block face of 1st Street between Spring Street and Main Street);

	(3)	El Pueblo de Los Angeles (Olvera Street, the east block face of Main Street between Cesar Chavez Avenue and Aliso Street, the south block of Cesar Chavez between Main Street and Alameda Street, the west block face of Alameda Street between Cesar Chavez Avenue and Aliso Street, and the north block face of Aliso Street between Main Street and Alameda Street);

	(4)	On the sidewalks immediately contiguous to Disney Hall (the east block face of Hope Street between 1st Street and Upper 2nd Street; the west south block face of 1st Street between Hope Avenue and Grand Avenue; the west block face of Grand Avenue between 1st Street and Upper 2nd Street; and the north block face of Upper 2nd Street between Hope Avenue and Grand Avenue); or

	(5)	On the sidewalks on the block faces immediately to the west and east of the Music Center and Dorothy Chandler Pavilion (the west block face of Grand Avenue between 1st Street and Temple Street; and the east block face of Hope Street between 1st Street and Temple Street).

	(6)	On the Venice Boardwalk (both sides of Ocean Front Walk between Navy Street on the north and Venice Pier/Washington Boulevard on the south).

	(7)	On the sidewalks of the Westwood Village Broxton Avenue Promenade (both sides of Broxton Avenue between Le Conte Avenue and Kinross Avenue).

	(B)	In the event an area of the City which is deemed by the City Cultural Heritage Commission and the City Council to be of municipal regional historic significance, such an area may apply to the Board for designation as an area where no newsracks shall be installed, subject to the approval of the City Council.

	(17)	Specific Plan/Streetscape Plan Areas:&#xA0; Specific Plan Areas, Streetscape Plan Areas, or other Special Planning Districts approved by the Planning Department, which include a standard streetscape color, may request a uniform newsrack color other than Ivy Green, from the Board, with Council input, and if granted, the color shall be one of the following three colors: black (RAL 9017 &#x201C;Grotto Black&#x201D;), blue (Benjamin Moore No. 805 &#x201C;Westwood Blue&#x201D;) or gray (Marine Silver 38/90010).

	(18)	Severability:&#xA0; If any section or subsection of this ordinance is deemed to be void or unenforceable, such shall be severed from the whole and the remaining portions of the ordinance shall remain in full force and effect.

	(g)	Streets &#x2013; Newsstands.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(1)	No person shall install, use or maintain any newsstand which projects onto, into or over any part of the roadway of any public street, or which rests, wholly or in part, upon, along or over any portion of the roadway of any street.

	(2)	No person shall install, use or maintain any newsstand which in whole or in part rests upon, in or over any sidewalk or parkway when such installation, use or maintenance endangers the safety of persons or property, or when such site or location is used for public utility purposes, public transportation purposes or other governmental use, or when such newsstand unreasonably interferes with or impedes the flow of pedestrian or vehicular traffic, the ingress into or the egress from any residence or place of business, or the use of poles, posts, traffic signs or signals, hydrants, mailboxes, or other objects permitted at or near said locations.

	(3)	Any newsstand which in whole or in part rests upon, in or over any sidewalk or parkway, shall comply with the following standards:

	(A)	No newsstand shall exceed five feet in height, seventy-five inches in width and three feet in depth, except that if erected parallel and adjacent to the wall of a building, it shall not extend over that area of the sidewalk or parkway by more than twenty inches, shall not exceed a length of fifty feet, or a height of eight feet.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(B)	Except for a newsstand erected adjacent to the wall of a building, no newsstand shall be placed less than twelve inches nor more than eighteen inches from the edge of the curb.

	(C)	No newsstand shall be placed or maintained on the sidewalk or parkway opposite another newsstand.

	(D)	No seat, chair, rack, case, canopy, awning, overhang, or other object shall be attached to the exterior of any newsstand, nor shall any such object when attached to any part of a newsstand be permitted to extend beyond its exterior wall.

	(E)	No newsstand shall be so placed that the clear space for the passage of pedestrians upon the sidewalk and parkway is reduced to less than six feet.

	(F)	Newsstands shall be soundly constructed of wood, metal or other suitable permanent material, painted in a manner and color as prescribed by the Board of Public Works, and maintained at all times, in a clean, neat and attractive condition and in good repair and, as to the Central Traffic District, as defined in Section 80.00 of this Code, such newsstands shall be of design and construction approved by the Department of Cultural Affairs.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(G)	No newsstand shall be used for advertising signs or publicity purposes other than that dealing with the display, sale or purchase of newspapers or new periodicals.

	(H)	No newsstand shall be placed within three feet of any area improved with lawn, flowers, shrubs or trees or within three feet of any display window of any building abutting the street or in such manner as to impede or interfere with the reasonable use of such window for display purposes.

	(I)	No newsstand shall be utilized for the sale, or offer for sale, nor for the display for sale, of any article or item other than newspapers, magazines, periodicals and other similar newsprint publications.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(J)	Newsstands, in the Central Traffic District, as defined by Section 80.00 of this Code, shall be open and utilized for business at least six hours a day, five days a week and the holder of the permit shall be present at the newsstand and operating it himself or herself seventy-five percent (75%) of the time it is open, or thirty (30) hours a week, whichever is less. Waivers of such requirement may be granted by the Board of Public Works for good cause.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(4)	Every person placing or maintaining a newsstand on the streets of the City of Los Angeles shall have affixed thereto in a place readily visible to the public a telephone number or postal box number where the owner may be reached.

	(5)	(Amended by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)&#xA0; No person shall install, use or maintain any newsstand which in whole or in part rests upon, in, or over any dedicated sidewalk or parkway in the Central Traffic District, as defined by Section 80.00 of this Code, without first applying for and obtaining a permit from the Department. The issuance of such permit shall be subject to the provisions of this subdivision.

	(A)	Forms for Permit &#x2013; The Department shall prescribe and make available permit application forms. The applicant shall submit to the Department a completed form, on which the following information shall have been entered:

	(i)	The name, address and telephone number of the applicant;

	(ii)	The name, address and telephone number of the person whom the applicant designates to be notified concerning the applicant&#x2019;s newsstand;

	(iii)	The requested location for the newsstand.

	(B)	Issuance of Permit &#x2013; Upon proper application, the Department may, upon the payment of the fee provided below, issue a newsstand permit to the applicant in accordance with the provisions of this Subdivision (5). Such permit shall not be assignable nor shall more than one permit be issued to any one person. No more than two newsstands shall be allowed on any one block. As used herein &#x201C;block&#x201D; shall mean one side of a street between two consecutive intersecting streets.

	(C)	The Board shall enact regulations for the selection of permittees taking into consideration the length of time a newsstand has been operated by the applicant at a particular location, whether there has existed a business license for such newsstand, the number of violations an applicant has incurred in the operation of his or her newsstand and such other factors the Board deems appropriate.

	(D)	Validity of Permit &#x2013; Permits shall be valid from the issuance date until the May 31st following such date, and may be renewed annually thereafter. Such permits shall be issued initially for a period not to exceed one year and renewals thereof shall be for a maximum of one year periods thereafter.

	(E)	Permit Fee &#x2013; There shall be a permit fee for new, and renewal, permits in the amount of twenty-five (25) dollars for each newsstand. Whenever any permit is issued after May 31st, the amount of such fee shall be prorated on a quarterly basis. The permit fee may be increased by the Board if so justified by an increase in the cost of regulation.

	(F)	Permit Decals &#x2013; The Department shall issue to each permittee a permit decal for the newsstand covered by the permit. Permittees shall cause the decal to be affixed to the front face of the newsstand so as to be visible from the sidewalk.

	(6)	Prior to the issuance of a permit by the Department, the applicant shall furnish to the Department a certificate, in a form satisfactory to the Department and City Attorney, that the applicant has then in force public liability and property damage insurance, naming the City as an additional insured, in an amount and type as determined by the Board, subject to reasonable availability. The evidence of insurances filed shall include a statement by the insurance carrier that thirty (30) days notice will be given to the City Attorney before any cancellation of coverage. The City shall be named as an additional insured on any such insurance policy. Such insurance shall be maintained throughout the permit period.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(7)	Any newsstand installed, used or maintained in violation of this subsection shall be removed subject to the provisions of Subdivisions (7) through (12) of Subsection (f) of this section. In addition any violation of this subsection shall subject the applicant and/or violator to the imposition of criminal liability.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(8)	Upon the cessation and abandonment of operations of any newsstand the person holding the permit, or if no one is presently holding a permit the last one to hold a permit for the newsstand, shall be responsible for the removal of such newsstand. If the newsstand is not so removed the City shall so remove it pursuant to Subsection (f) hereof and assess the most recent holder of the permit for the costs incurred.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(9)	Violation of any provision of this subsection may result, after due notice and hearing, in the revocation of the permit by the Board.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(h)	Freeway On-Ramps and Off-Ramps &#x2013; Sales Prohibited.&#xA0; Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, no person on any street, or other public property of whatever nature or description, shall, within fifty feet of the roadway of any freeway on-ramp or off-ramp, distribute, deliver, sell, offer for sale or solicit the sale of any newspapers, magazines, periodicals, circulars, handbills or other printed matter or any goods, wares or merchandise regardless of type, nature, kind or description.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(i)	The provisions of this section shall not apply to the installation and maintenance of any bench installed and maintained in accordance with Article 8 of Chapter VI of this code, nor to the operation and maintenance of searchlights, generators and floodlights in accordance with the restrictions and requirements of Division T of Chapter VIII of this Code. Nor shall the provisions of this section prohibit the putting of business notices, signs or emblems upon ordinary business or carrier vehicles. Nor shall the provisions of this section apply to temporary selling activities and advertising related thereto conducted pursuant to a permit granted under Subsection (j) hereof. (Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(j)	Permit for Temporary Selling Activities Board of Public Works.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(1)	The Board of Public Works may issue upon written application, made upon a form prescribed by the Board, a permit authorizing temporary selling activities and advertising relative thereto, on sidewalks, parkways and roadways, provided that as to roadways such permit&#x2019;s issuance will, in addition to this section&#x2019;s requirements, be governed by the provisions of Section 41.20 of this Code, in connection with a community civic event sponsored and conducted by a nonprofit organization formed for charitable, educational, civic, veteran, philanthropic or other benevolent purposes, under the following conditions:&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 150,706, Eff. 5/13/78.)

	(A)	&#x201C;Community civic center&#x201D; means the sponsoring and conducting by a nonprofit organization of a civic, artistic, cultural, charitable, educational, veteran or benevolent activity of community interest. The Board shall require reasonable proof of the nonprofit status of the sponsoring organization and a sufficient showing of community interest, which showing shall consist of furnishing the Board with names and addresses of at least 100 persons who will support the activity, at least 50% of which either reside or work in the location specified in the application for permit where the activity is to take place.

	(B)	Each permit shall be valid for a period of three consecutive days only, two of which days shall be a Saturday or Sunday. &#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 158,731, Eff. 2/25/84.)

	(C)	Each application for a permit must be accompanied by a fee and must be presented to the Board not less than 40 nor more than 180 days before the commencing date of the proposed permit activities; provided that the Board may waive these time requirements if it determines such waiver to be in the public interest. The fee herein shall be determined and adopted in the same manner as provided in Section 12.37-I, 1 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code for establishing fees.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 165,675, Eff. 5/11/90.)

	(D)	No person or sponsoring organization shall fail to keep the permit, at all times, at the place where the selling activities are being conducted, nor fail, upon demand therefor, to exhibit such permit to any public officer.

	(E)	No selling or advertising activities shall be conducted in the roadway or within two feet of the curb of any sidewalk unless authorized by the Board of Public works.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 150,706, Eff. 5/13/78.)

	(F)	(Amended by Ord. No. 173,283, Eff. 6/26/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)&#xA0; Nor may such selling activities take place without an Information Card, written Notice of Intention, or professional fund-raiser&#x2019;s license if the activity is such that one would be required under Article 4, Chapter 4 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.

	(G)	The application for such permit shall contain:

	1.	The name of the applicant, the sponsoring organization, the event chairman and the addresses and telephone numbers of each.

	2.	The location and outside perimeter of the selling area, indicated upon a map of the area.

	3.	The date and times at which the selling activities are to take place.

	4.	A description of the selling activity which will be conducted.

	5.	A list of all persons who will be engaging in temporary selling activities at any time during the dates and times for which a temporary selling permit is granted. However this list may be furnished after the application has been submitted, so long as it is not furnished later than one week before the event is to take place.

	6.	An agreement to comply with the terms of the permit.

	(2)	Sponsoring organizations may be granted a temporary selling permit if the organization meets the following requirements:

	(A)	That the title of any real property in the City of Los Angeles owned by such organization is vested in the name of such organization, if it be a corporation, or else in the name or names of a responsible trustee or trustees under a declaration of trust or other written instrument setting forth the rights of said organization therein; and recorded in the records of the County Recorder of Los Angeles County.

	(B)	That the declared&#xA0; purposes for which such organization is organized are charitable, educational, civic, community service, veteran, benevolent or other philanthropic purposes, and not for the pecuniary profit of the members of the organization thereof or any of them.

	(C)	That for three months prior to its application for a temporary selling permit said organization has faithfully complied with the following provisions with reference to its accounts, namely: All funds received by it, and all disbursements made by it, have been entered upon the books of its treasurer or other financial officer, receipts have been given or tendered for all money or other property donated to it, whenever required by law or ordinance; all expenditures other than petty cash to a reasonable amount have been made by checks signed by at least two officers of such organization; that the bank book of such organization has been balanced and reconciled with the books of account at reasonable intervals.

	(D)	That no monies of said organization are on loan directly or indirectly to any&#xA0; officer, director, trustee, employee or member thereof, and that the organization has not invested any monies constituting part of its permanent endowment funds except in securities legal as investments for savings banks within the State of California, and has not diverted funds donated to it from an source to purposes other than those for which they were donated.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 156,941, Eff. 8/20/82.)

	(E)	That the work for which such organization has been formed has been faithfully performed.

	(F)	That the bylaws and other written rules and regulations of such organization define the powers and duties of the officers of such organization, and that a copy of the Articles of Incorporation, if it be a corporation, and a copy of the bylaws and other written rules and regulations of such organization have been filed with the Department of Public works.

	(G)	That within one year prior to its application such organization has not violated any law or ordinance applicable to it.

	(3)	The Board shall cause such application to be investigated and shall grant the permit if it determines: that the proposed activities will not disrupt to an unreasonable extent the movement of vehicular or pedestrian traffic or create a hazard to the public; that the proposed activities are not of a size or nature that require the diversion of so great a number of police personnel to regulate such activities that it prevents reasonable police protection for the City or for the councilmanic district where the temporary selling activity is to take place; that the concentration of persons, equipment and materials is not so great in the selling area that it would prevent proper fire, police and ambulance protection; that the applicant agrees to be responsible for cleanup necessitated by the proposed activities and the Board may, in its discretion, require a cleanup deposit to guarantee that cleanup takes place.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 160,175, Eff. 8/24/85.)

	(4)	The Board shall further condition the granting of such permit upon the permit applicant filing with the Board a policy of public liability insurance in which the City has been named as insured or co-insured with the permittee. The policy of insurance shall insure the City and its officers and employees against all claims arising out of or in connection with the issuance of the permit or the operation of the permittee, his agents or representatives pursuant to the permit. The policy of insurance shall provide coverage no less than $100,000 per occurrence of bodily injury and $25,000 per occurrence of property damage.

	(5)	The Board shall adopt uniform rules and regulations so as to carry out the purposes of this subsection and shall condition the granting of permits upon compliance therewith and also with such other conditions as the Board may deem necessary to impose for the proper protection of persons and property.

	(k)	The provisions of this section shall not prohibit sales that are otherwise permitted under the terms of Section 80.73 of this Code.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 150,561, Eff. 3/19/78.)

	(l)	Permit for Flower Vending Booths.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 159,008, Eff. 7/1/84.)

	(1)	The provisions of this section shall not apply to the sale of flowers from a flower vending booth operated pursuant to a permit granted by the Board of Public Works.

	(2)	The Board may issue a revocable permit for the installation and operation of a flower vending booth on a sidewalk pursuant to the one year pilot flower vending booth demonstration program authorized by the City Council in the downtown area.

	(3)	The issuance of any such permit does not preclude the requirements of any other permits or approval for any such installation.

	(m)	Establishment and Regulation of Special Sidewalk Vending Districts.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 169,319, Eff. 2/18/94.)

	(1)	The Board of Public Works, hereinafter referred to as &#x201C;Board,&#x201D; is authorized to form special sidewalk vending districts for the purpose of permitting vending of goods, wares and merchandise and announcing the availability thereof within such districts, and to promulgate rules and regulations with respect to the formation of such districts.&#xA0; The term &#x201C;district&#x201D; whenever used in this subdivision shall mean &#x201C;special sidewalk vending district.&#x201D;&#xA0; No more than eight districts shall be approved by the Board during the first two years following the effective date of this ordinance.&#xA0; Each district shall have a&#xA0; designated police liaison appointed by the Chief of Police.&#xA0; Before any proposed vending districts are established, the City Council shall adopt a humane and comprehensive enforcement policy regarding sidewalk vending both inside and outside the proposed districts.

	(2)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; A petition may be filed with the Sidewalk Vending Administrator of the Community Development Department, hereinafter referred to as &#x201C;Sidewalk Vending Administrator,&#x201D; by any person or persons, hereinafter referred to as &#x201C;applicant,&#x201D; interested in the formation of a special sidewalk vending district.&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall coordinate with the Board regarding the filing and processing of said application.&#xA0; The petition shall be subject to the following conditions and requirements:

	(A)	The applicant shall pay to the Sidewalk Vending Administrator a non refundable application fee to establish a district.&#xA0; However, such fee shall not be paid until after the City Council has approved the formation of the district pursuant to Subdivision (6) of this subsection.&#xA0; No license application in respect to said district shall be approved until the fee has been paid.&#xA0; Said fee shall be determined and adopted in the same manner as provided in Section 12.37-I,1 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code for establishing fees.

	(B)	The petition shall contain the name or names of the applicant(s) and names and signatures together with residence or business addresses within the district of persons endorsing the formation of the district.&#xA0; The endorsing list must consist of the owners or those in possession, such as tenants or lessees, of at least 20 percent of the businesses and 20 percent of the residents in each block or portion thereof to be included in the district.

	(C)	The petition shall set forth:

	1.	The proposed boundaries of the district, which shall only be in commercially zoned areas of the City;

	2.	The location and number of vending sites sought to be approved;

	3.	Any rules or regulations deemed necessary or desirable by the petitioners to organize vending activity within the district; and

	4.	The purpose for establishing the district.

	(D)	The petition shall be accompanied by a list provided by the Sidewalk Vending Administrator of the names and addresses of all property owners, businesses and residents within the district and within a 500-foot radius of the boundaries of the district, together with a cash deposit sufficient to cover the costs of preparing such a list and of mailing and publishing notifications as provided below.

	(E)	The district shall not be limited to any particular size and the proposed density of vending sites may vary from area-to-area within the district.

	(3)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; Upon receipt of said petition, the Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall notify the Council member or Council members in whose district or districts the special sidewalk vending district is proposed to be located, at which time the Council member or Council members shall appoint a Community Advisory Committee.&#xA0; The Community Advisory Committee must contain a Street Use Inspector, a Police Officer and the Sidewalk Vending Administrator.&#xA0; The committee shall have balanced representation of proponents of the district, fixed businesses, and residents within or adjacent to the proposed districts, as well as a representative of the Council office or offices.&#xA0; The committee will make recommendations on boundaries of the district, density and location of vendors, goods sold, design of carts and hours of operation.&#xA0; There shall be a limit of 90 days between filing this petition and a final decision by the Board.

	(4)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; After reviewing the petition for compliance with the provisions of this Code, the Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall transmit said petition to the Board which shall set the matter for public hearing in coordination with the Sidewalk Vending Administrator within 30 days after receipt thereof.&#xA0; Notice of the time, place and purpose of the public hearing shall be given by the Sidewalk Vending Administrator to each applicant by mailing a written notice of the hearing not less than 30 days prior to the date of such hearing.&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall at the same time mail such notice to all property owners, businesses and residents within the proposed district and within a 500-foot radius of the boundaries of the district.&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall further cause there to be published a notice of such public hearing in a newspaper of general circulation in the area wherein the sidewalk vending district is proposed to be established.&#xA0; The notice shall be published in both English and in any other language spoken as their primary language by a substantial number of the persons residing in the proposed district.&#xA0; The notice shall be published as provided for in Section 6064 of the Government Code of the State of California, and shall state the purpose of the proposed district, the boundaries thereof and the date, time and place of the public hearing.

	(5)	Any interested person may appear at such hearing and comment with respect to the proposed vending district.&#xA0; Comments may also be submitted in writing prior to the date of such hearing.&#xA0; The Board shall also consider recommendations of merchant associations, chambers of commerce, the Los Angeles Police Department and various other affected City departments.
	(6)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall refer the matter to the Council member or Council members in whose district or districts the special vending district is proposed to be located for review and recommendation, together with a summary of comments made at the hearing.&#xA0; Based upon the foregoing comments, recommendations of the Community Advisory Committee and Council member recommendations, the Board may make a finding that the public welfare would be served by the establishment of such a district.&#xA0; In so doing, the Board may for good cause alter the proposed district boundaries and the number, location and density of proposed vending sites.&#xA0; The Board shall transmit to the City Council its finding and the reasons therefor together with its recommendation that the district be established in the manner proposed in the petition or as modified by the Board.&#xA0; The City Council may approve, modify or disapprove the recommendation of the Board.&#xA0; The district shall be established upon approval, or approval as modified, of the Board&#x2019;s recommendation.&#xA0; For good cause, after due consideration of all comments and recommendations presented, the Board may make a finding that the public welfare would not be served by the establishment of the district.&#xA0; The Board&#x2019;s finding may be based on factors such as incompatibility of vending pushcarts with area architectural style, conflict with the area&#x2019;s specific plan, the presence of pushcarts as an impediment to the use of on-street parking locations in areas where an unusually heavy demand for such parking exists, or the presence of zoning restrictions prohibiting such vending activities on private property in the area.&#xA0; The Board shall transmit to the City Council its finding and the reasons therefor together with its recommendation that the district not be established.&#xA0; The City Council may approve or disapprove the recommendation of the Board.&#xA0; If disapproved, such disapproval shall establish the district and the Board shall be so informed, provided, however, that either the City Council, or the Board with approval of the Council, may modify district boundaries and number, location and density of proposed vending sites, as set forth in the petition.

	(7)	Upon petition of an interested party, a special district may be disestablished, or areas withdrawn therefrom, for good cause.&#xA0; Each such petition shall contain the signatures of at least 20 percent of the owners or persons in possession, such as tenants or lessees, of businesses in each block or portion thereof of the district or part thereof proposed to be withdrawn, and at least 20 percent of the residents of each such block or portion thereof.&#xA0; Each such petition shall comply with the requirements of Section 42.00(m)(2)(D).&#xA0; The Board shall hold a hearing into the matter preceded by notice as provided for in Subdivision (4) above.&#xA0; In the event the Board makes a finding that the public welfare would be served by disestablishment of the district or by withdrawal of an area, the Board shall transmit to the City Council its finding and the reasons therefor, together with its recommendation that district be disestablished or an area be withdrawn therefrom.&#xA0; The City Council may approve or disapprove the Board&#x2019;s recommendation.&#xA0; Approval disestablishes the district or withdraws the subject area therefrom.

	(8)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall review all rules and regulations proposed by petitioners, the Community Advisory Committee of the particular vending district, and any other interested parties provided that the Community Advisory Committee has had an opportunity to review them and transmit all such rules and regulations to the Board, together with his or her recommendations regarding adoption.&#xA0; The Board shall adopt all such rules and regulations for the district unless good cause exists for non-adoption.&#xA0; In addition, the Board, for good cause, may adopt such other rules and regulations for the district as would promote the public health, welfare and safety.&#xA0; Rules and regulations, when adopted, shall be binding upon all affected persons within the district.

	(9)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; No permit shall be issued, however, until a contract has been executed between the City, through the Community Development Department,&#xA0; and any organization selected to manage the special sidewalk vending district, referred to hereinafter as &#x201C;management organization&#x201D;, as provided for in Los Angeles Administrative Code Section 22.361.

	(10)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; The Community Development Department, through the Sidewalk Vending Administrator, shall determine the allocation of vending permits within the district, whether by lottery or otherwise, in a manner consistent with public health, safety and welfare.&#xA0; However, the Sidewalk Vending Administrator may by contract delegate that function to any organization selected to manage the district subject to the supervision of the Sidewalk Vending Administrator and approval by the Community Development Department as to method of allocation to assure that vending permits are allocated in a fair and impartial manner.

	(11)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; The Community Development Department, through the Sidewalk Vending Administrator, shall issue all sidewalk vending permits and collect all fees and charges in connection therewith.&#xA0; Any person desiring to be issued a permit for sidewalk vending within a district may make application to the Sidewalk Vending Administrator on forms provided.&#xA0; The application shall set forth the following information:

	(A)	The name, address and telephone number of the applicant;

	(B)	The exact location at which the vending is proposed to be conducted;

	(C)	A complete list of what is proposed to be sold;

	(D)	The hours per day and days per week during which sidewalk vending will be conducted; and

	(E)	Any other information required by the Community Development Department.

	(12)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; No permit or renewal permit shall be issued unless the applicant has complied with all of the following requirements:

	(A)	If any food or drink item is proposed to be sold, the applicant has obtained approval from the County Department of Health Services to engage in the vending of the item in the manner proposed;

	(B)	(Amended by Ord. No. 173,298, Eff. 6/30/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)&#xA0; All other necessary City, County and State licenses and permits have been obtained, including a Business Tax Registration Certificate from the Office of Finance.

	(C)	(Amended by Ord. No. 173,363, Eff. 7 /29/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)&#xA0; The applicant has filed with the Community Development Department a policy of public liability and property damage insurance, in a form satisfactory to it and to the City Attorney, in which the City is named as a co-insured with the applicant.&#xA0; The policy of insurance shall so insure the City and its officers and employees against all claims arising out of or in connection with the issuance of the permit or the operation of the permittee.&#xA0; The policy of insurance shall be in an amount and type as determined by the Community Development Department in consultation with the Director of the Office of Administrative and Research Services, subject to reasonable availability.&#xA0; The Community Development Department, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Administrative and Research Services, may waive the requirement of insurance if none is reasonably available.&#xA0; In lieu of individual policies of insurance, the Community Development Department may cause to be secured a general or blanket policy of insurance covering all applicants and thereafter determine the pro rata cost to each applicant, which shall be collected before approval of the application.&#xA0; Any policy of insurance shall contain a statement by the insurance carrier that thirty (30) days&#x2019; notice will be given to the City Attorney before any cancellation of coverage.&#xA0; Insurance shall be maintained throughout the permit period.&#xA0; The Community Development Department may for good cause increase the amount of required insurance.

	(D)	The applicant shows proof of ownership, lease or rental of a pushcart constructed for the purpose of vending goods, wares or merchandise according to the requirements and specifications of the Community Development Department.

	(E)	Approval in writing has been obtained from the owner, tenant or person in lawful possession or control of the property abutting upon the street immediately adjacent to the location where the vending is proposed to be conducted.&#xA0; Such approval may be secured by the management organization.

	(F)	The applicant has provided the City with two passport size photos of the applicant.

	(G)	The applicant has presented adequate identification of himself or herself.&#xA0; Adequate identification shall include, but not be limited to, a California driver&#x2019;s license or a California Department of Motor Vehicles identification card.

	(H)	The applicant is old enough under State law to engage in the vending activity.

	(I)	The applicant has submitted to fingerprinting, in connection with which applicant shall pay a fingerprint process fee.&#xA0; Such fee shall be determined and adopted in the same manner as is provided in Section 12.37-I,1 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code for establishing fees.

	(13)	No permit shall be issued to any applicant who has been convicted of any crime relating to fraudulent business practices, the receipt or sale of stolen property or the illegal sale of any controlled substance under the provisions of the California Controlled Substances Act within five (5) years prior to the date of application for permit.

	(14)	The applicant may designate up to two co-applicants who are authorized by the applicant to vend at the location for which the applicant&#x2019;s permit is issued in his or her temporary absence due to circumstances such as illness, injury or vacation.&#xA0; However, there must be provided the name, address and phone number of each co-applicant and two passport size photos of each co-applicant must be submitted.&#xA0; Each co-applicant must present adequate identification of himself or herself in the same manner as required for the applicant, and must be old enough under State law to engage in vending activity.&#xA0; Each co-applicant shall submit to fingerprinting and shall be subject to provisions of Subdivision 12 with respect to approval as a co-applicant and the provisions of Subdivision (22) with respect to operating requirements.&#xA0; Those approved shall be designated co-permittees and shall pay an application fee for the issuance of a co-permit.&#xA0; Such fee shall be determined and adopted in the same manner as is provided in Section 12.37-I,1 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code for establishing fees.

	(15)	A permit shall be issued only to a natural person and only for the days or hours of the day indicated on the application as days and hours of operation.&#xA0; Such permit shall not be transferable to any other person and shall be valid only for the location for which it is issued.

	(16)	Only one permit shall be issued to each permittee.

	(17)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; A non-refundable annual permit fee shall be paid before issuance of any permit provided, however, that the applicant may elect to pay said fee in semi-annual installments.&#xA0; Such election shall be stated in writing and installments shall be paid as directed by the Sidewalk Vending Administrator.&#xA0; If such election is made, a payment of one-half the annual permit fee shall be required before issuance of a permit.&#xA0; Permits shall be valid for one year from the date of issuance.&#xA0; If any installment fee is not paid on or before the date provided by the Sidewalk Vending Administrator for payment, a letter shall be sent to the permittee advising that such fee is due within 30 days of the date of such letter or the permit shall terminate.&#xA0; If the fee is not paid within the 30-day period, the permit shall terminate and the former permittee shall cease from vending.&#xA0; The permit may be reinstated upon payment of the fee.&#xA0; At the time of making any payment as provided for above, the applicant or permittee shall pay a supplemental fee which is a pro-rated amount determined by the Community Development Department as sufficient to cover the cost to the City of entering into a contract for management of the district.&#xA0; Supplemental fees collected shall be placed in a special fund established for such purpose.&#xA0; In addition fees will be charged for the following:

	Replacement of existing permit in the event of loss, name change or change of company;

	Replacement of existing permit decal; and

	Replacement of any vending identification badge.

	Fees herein shall be determined and adopted in the same manner as provided in Section 12.37-I,1 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code for establishing fees.

	(18)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; In the event an application for permit is denied, the applicant shall be so notified within 60 days, which notification shall also state the reason for denial and that the applicant has 45 days from the date of notice within which to request reconsideration of the denial.

	(19)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; Any permit issued shall be subject to the right of the Community Development Department to rescind issuance thereof in response to a request for reconsideration of its action in issuing the permit.

	(20)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; Either the applicant or any other person affected by the issuance of a vending permit may request reconsideration by the Community Development Department of its decision to grant or deny an application for permit.&#xA0; Such request must be in writing and must be received by the Sidewalk Vending Administrator within the 45 days from the date of issuance of the permit or notification of denial.&#xA0; Upon receipt of such request the Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall set a hearing date no less than 30 days from the date of the receipt of the request.&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall notify the requestor and, if the requestor is not the applicant, the applicant, of the hearing date.&#xA0; The Community Development Department shall rescind issuance of the permit if at the hearing it is demonstrated to its satisfaction that the issuance thereof was contrary to the provisions of this subdivision or to applicable rules and regulations.&#xA0; The Community Development Department may direct the Sidewalk Vending Administrator to issue a permit if it is shown to the satisfaction of the Department that it was in error in denying the permit.

	(21)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; The permittee may amend his or her application with respect to the goods, wares and merchandise proposed to be sold and the hours during which vending is to occur by written notification thereof to and approval by the Sidewalk Vending Administrator, and the owner, tenant, or person in lawful control of the property immediately adjacent to the vending site.

	(22)	Operating Requirements.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)

	(A)	Vending shall be conducted only from pushcarts constructed for that purpose according to the requirements and specifications of the Community Development&#xA0; Department.&#xA0; Such pushcarts shall have a length of no greater than six feet and a width of no greater than 3 feet, 6 inches, and shall be no more than 6 feet, 6 inches in Height, including roof or awning.&#xA0; A decal so certifying shall be attached to each pushcart approved for use.

	(B)	All of the permittee&#x2019;s advertising must be attached to the pushcart and shall advertise only the goods, wares or merchandise being sold.&#xA0; Advertising signs shall not extend beyond the overall width or height of the pushcart.

	(C)	The permittee shall not conduct any portion of its vending business outside the boundaries of its vending location as described in the permit.

	(D)	One small, compact stool or chair may be utilized by the permittee.&#xA0; The stool or chair shall be placed within four feet of the pushcart and shall not block the safe passage of pedestrians.&#xA0; No advertising shall be placed on the stool or chair.&#xA0; Other than the pushcart and stool or chair, no other items or object of any kind shall be placed on the public sidewalk or parkway.

	(E)	No vending shall be conducted on the roadway portion of any street.

	(F)	The permittee shall provide a trash receptacle for the use of customers and shall pick up and dispose of any trash or litter left by customers before leaving the vending location.&#xA0; Full receptacles shall be immediately emptied by the permittee.

	(G)	The City vending permit shall be visibly displayed at all times while the permittee is engaged in vending activity.

	(H)	The permittee shall wear a vendor identification badge issued by the Sidewalk Vending Administrator at all times while engaged in vending.

	(I)	Pushcarts shall be positioned no less than 18 inches from the curb.

	(J)	No permittee shall knowingly allow, permit or authorize another person to vend from permittee&#x2019;s pushcart or at permittee&#x2019;s assigned location, other than designated co-permittees of that particular vendor.

	(K)	No pushcart shall be chained or fastened to any pole, sign, tree or other object in the public way.

	(23)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending Administrator may from time to time recommend rules and regulations to the Board.&#xA0; The Board may adopt such rules and regulations as it deems necessary to implement the provisions of this subsection.

	(24)	Revocation, Suspension or Non-renewal.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)

	(A)	After notice and hearing in accordance with Section 22.02 of the Municipal Code, the Community Development Department may revoke or suspend any permit issued pursuant to this subsection or decline to renew any such permit, if the permittee has:

	1.	Knowingly made any false, misleading or fraudulent statement of&#xA0; material fact in its application for a permit;

	2.	Been convicted of any criminal act in connection with the operation of the permitted activity, or any of the crimes set forth in Subdivision (13) of this subsection;

	3.	Violated any of the operating requirements set forth in Subdivision (22) of this subsection;

	4.	Violated any rule or regulation promulgated by the Board with respect to this subdivision;

	5.	Failed to comply with any order by the department to cease and desist from any violation; or

	6.	In any other way endangered the public health, safety or welfare in the conducting of its sidewalk vending activities.

	(B)	A permittee who has had his or her permit revoked or whose application for renewal has been declined shall not be eligible to apply for another permit under this subdivision until 12 months after the date of revocation or renewal declination.

	(C)	Any action revoking or suspending a license may be appealed to the Board within 60 days of the action of suspension or revocation.&#xA0; The Board shall hear and make a determination on the appeal.

	(25)	Enforcement and Penalties.

	(A)	Within each district the provisions of this Subsection (m) shall be enforced by the Street Use Inspection Division of the Bureau of Street Maintenance of the Department of Public Works.

	(B)	The Department may issue an order to immediately cease and desist from any violation of this Subsection (m) or any rule or regulation of the Board.

	(C)	It shall be a violation of law to fail to comply with any of the provisions of Subdivision (22) of this Subsection (m).&#xA0; The first, second and third violations of Subdivision (22) of Subsection (m) shall each be infractions.&#xA0; The commission of a fourth violation of any of the provisions of Subdivision (22) of Subsection (m) within a two-year period after the commission of the first violation shall be a misdemeanor.

	(D)	It shall be illegal for any person to display any imitation or facsimile of a vending permit, vendor identification badge or decal which has not been issued by the Department.</full_text><order_by>00</order_by><text><unit id="2758" prefix=""><text>&#xA0; REGULATION OF SOLICITING AND SALES IN STREETS.

	(a)	(Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)&#xA0; In this section, unless the context or subject matter otherwise requires:

	&#x201C;News racks&#x201D; shall mean any self-service or coin-operated box, container, storage unit or other dispenser installed, used, or maintained for the display and sale of newspapers, news periodicals or other news publications.

	&#x201C;Newsstand&#x201D; shall mean any stand, shelter, case, cabinet, box or other structure installed, used, or maintained for the display, sale or storage of newspapers, news periodicals or other news publications which is attended by the owner or his employee while making sales therefrom.
	&#x201C;Street&#x201D; shall mean all that area dedicated to public use for public street purposes and shall include, but not be limited to roadways, parkways, alleys and sidewalks.

	&#x201C;Roadway&#x201D; shall mean that portion of a street improved, designed, or ordinarily used for vehicular travel.

	&#x201C;Parkway&#x201D; shall mean that area between the edge of the roadway and the adjacent property line excluding that area occupied by the sidewalks. Parkway shall also include any area within a roadway which is not open to vehicular travel.

	&#x201C;Sidewalk&#x201D; shall mean any surface provided for the exclusive use of pedestrians.

	(b)	Street Sale of Goods Prohibited.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 169,319, Eff. 2/18/94.)&#xA0; No person, except as otherwise permitted by this section, shall on any sidewalk or street offer for sale, solicit the sale of, announce by any means the availability of, or have in his or her possession, control or custody, whether upon his or her person or upon some other animate or inanimate object, any goods, wares or merchandise which the public may purchase at any time.&#xA0; This subsection shall not apply to the sale of poppies, badges and labels as defined by Military and Veterans Code Section 1800 on a parkway or sidewalk by persons bearing a valid information card issued pursuant to Article 4 of this chapter authorizing such person to do so.

	(c)	Street-Soliciting Employment of Services Prohibited.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(1)	No person, except as otherwise permitted by this section, shall on any street offer for sale, solicit the employment of, or announce by any means the availability of, any goods, wares, merchandise, services or facilities, or solicit patrons for or advertise any show, exhibition, entertainment, tour, excursion, sight-seeing trip, or real estate viewing or inspection trip.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 169,319, Eff. 2/18/94.)

	(2)	No person who is visible or audible to any person on any street shall, in a loud, boisterous, raucous, offensive or insulting manner, offer for sale, solicit the purchase of, announce the availability of, or solicit the employment of any goods, wares, merchandise, services or facilities, or solicit patronage for or advertise any show, exhibition, entertainment tour, excursion sight-seeing trip, real estate, or oil well viewing or inspection trip.

	(3)	Nothing in Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be so construed as to apply to a sight-seeing tour operating under and by virtue of a permit from and regulations of the Public Utilities Commission of the State of California and for which tour a fixed charge is made to the person carried.

	(d)	Street-Sidewalk &#x2013; Advertising on.&#xA0; No person shall except as otherwise provided in Subsection (j) of this section have, bear, wear or carry upon any street, any advertising banner, flag, board, sign, transparency, wearing apparel or other device advertising, publicity announcing or calling attention to any goods, wares, merchandise, or commodities, or to any place of business, occupation, show, exhibition, event or entertainment. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to the wearing of apparel without remuneration for doing so or business identification on wearing apparel. (Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(e)	Streets News Venders.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(1)	No person shall sell or offer for sale any newspaper, magazine, periodical, news publication or other printed matter while upon the roadway of any street within the City of Los Angeles provided, however, that persons engaged in selling or offering for sale or disposing of newspapers, news periodicals or other news publications may sell, offer for sale, solicit the purchase of and advertise the same upon any portion of the sidewalk or parkway, subject to Subsections (f), (g), (h) and (j) of this section where applicable.

	(2)	No person, under the age of 10 years, shall sell or offer for sale any newspaper, magazine, periodical, news publication or other printed matter while upon any portion of a street. This subsection shall not prohibit persons, except as otherwise prohibited by law, from soliciting the sale of or delivery of newspapers, magazines, periodicals, news publications and other printed matter to residences or places of business fronting upon a street.

	(f)	Streets &#x2013; News Racks.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 176,339, Eff. 1/19/05.)

	(1)	Definitions:&#xA0; The following words, terms and phrases, when used in the following subsections shall have the meaning ascribed to them in this subsection, except where the context clearly indicates a different meaning:

	(A)	&#x201C;Equivalent newsrack&#x201D; means any newsrack that is of the same size and dimensions of the specified newsrack.

	(B)	If &#x201C;demand warrants&#x201D; or &#x201C;warranted demand&#x201D; means the measured stack height needed to meet the newspaper publisher&#x2019;s or distributor&#x2019;s peak daily distribution at the requested newsrack location, as proven to the Board by the newspaper publisher or distributor, exceeds (14) inches.

	(C)	&#x201C;Individual newsrack&#x201D; means and includes a newsrack designed with a single enclosed compartment to accommodate at any one time the display, sale, or free distribution of like copies of a single newspaper or other publication, or which has more than one (1) compartment and complies with the dimensions of an individual newsrack as provided in Subsection (7)(B).

	(D)	&#x201C;Newsrack&#x201D; or &#x201C;News Rack&#x201D; means any unstaffed, self-service, free, or coin-operated box, container, storage unit or other dispenser located in or upon, or projecting onto, or over, any part of the public right-of-way, and which is installed, used or maintained for the display, sale, or free distribution of newspapers and other publications.

	(E)	&#x201C;Modular newsrack&#x201D; means a newsrack which is designed with separate enclosed compartments to accommodate at any one time the display, sale or free distribution of multiple distinct and separate newspapers or other publications, and which exceeds the dimensions of an individual newsrack as provided in Subsection (7)(B).

	(F)	&#x201C;Modular newsrack provider&#x201D; means the person or other legal entity that is authorized under Subsection (4)(A)(7) to place and maintain modular newsracks upon the public right-of-way.

	(G)	&#x201C;Publisher&#x201D; means the person or other legal entity selling, displaying, or distributing free newspapers or other publications in a newsrack.

	(H)	&#x201C;News-Stand/Kiosk&#x201D; means any stand, shelter, or other structure installed, used, or maintained for the display, sale or storage of newspapers, news periodicals or other news publications.

	(I)	&#x201C;Public right-of-way&#x201D; means any public street, sidewalk, parkway, alley or other location owned or otherwise controlled by the City for the benefit of the general public.

	(J)	&#x201C;Block face&#x201D; means the sidewalk on one side of a street, between one intersection and the immediately adjacent intersection.&#xA0;

	(2)	Purpose and Criteria:&#xA0; The purpose of the following Subsections is to promote the public health, safety, and general welfare of the citizens and visitors to the City through the regulation of placement, type, appearance, and maintenance of newsracks on public rights-of-way so as to:

	(A)	Provide for pedestrian and driver safety and convenience.

	(B)	Restrict unreasonable interference with the flow of pedestrian or vehicular traffic, including, but not limited to, ingress into and egress from any residence or place of business, or from the street to the sidewalk, or from the sidewalk to the street by persons exiting or entering parked or standing vehicles.

	(C)	Provide for the safety of the general public and property during emergency conditions.

	(D)	Provide reasonable access for the use and maintenance of poles, posts, traffic signs and/or signals, hydrants, mailboxes, and access to locations used for public transportation purposes.

	(E)	Allow for the placement and maintenance of modular newsracks in the modular newsrack areas, as determined by the City Council, to be placed in locations throughout the city which afford easy, convenient service to pedestrians, but do not obstruct or interfere with access to abutting properties, and which do not impede or endanger pedestrian, bicycle, or vehicular traffic.

	(F)	Relocate and/or replace or remove newsracks which result in visual blight and/or are not installed according to this code on the public rights-of-way or which block or interfere with the aesthetics of store window displays, adjacent businesses, landscaping, street furniture, public or private, and other improvements as well as to allow the removal of abandoned newsracks.

	(G)	Maintain and protect the values of surrounding properties, and ensure that the aesthetics and historical attributes of adjacent businesses are not compromised by the unregulated placement of newsracks in the public right-of-way.

	(H)	Reduce unnecessary exposure of the public to personal injury or property damage.

	(I)	Maintain and preserve freedom of the press to distribute periodicals and newspapers.

	(J)	Reduce visual blight and improve the aesthetic appearance of the City&#x2019;s streets and sidewalks for the merchants, citizens and visitors to the City by coordinating the uniform color of all newsracks with the color of the City&#x2019;s extensive multi-million dollar street furniture program; and in Specific Plan Areas, Streetscape Plan Areas or other Special Planning Districts, which have a standard streetscape color, to allow for a uniform newsrack color from a limited palate of colors in order to coordinate the color of newsracks with their streetscape.

	(3)	Compliance Phase In:

	(A)	The provisions of this subdivision shall apply to all newsracks, whether installed and maintained prior to or after the effective date of this ordinance which in whole or in part rests upon, in, or over any dedicated sidewalk, right-of-way or parkway.&#xA0; Those newsracks installed prior to the effective date of this revised ordinance shall be brought into compliance with the all provisions of this code, except uniform color, as this revised ordinance is implemented by Street Services, area by area, within the City.&#xA0; In no event shall compliance be later than 12 months after the effective date hereof, except that, if the City&#x2019;s implementation schedule takes longer than 12 months, then compliance by the publishers shall follow the City&#x2019;s implementation schedule.&#xA0; If a publisher chooses not to come into compliance with the uniform color requirement of this ordinance at the time it obtains a valid permit and legally places its newsracks as required by the City&#x2019;s implementation schedule, then compliance with the uniform color requirement must be accomplished no later than 24 months after the effective date of this ordinance.&#xA0; However, Publishers experiencing financial hardship, solely due to compliance with LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f) as it applies to uniform color, may request the Board to approve one 12-month extension allowing them a total of 36 months to come into full compliance with the uniform color requirement of the Newsrack Ordinance, if evidence of financial hardship is proven to the satisfaction of the Board.&#xA0; Any newsrack not brought into compliance within the aforementioned time period shall be deemed to be in violation of LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f).

	(4)	Permit Required:&#xA0; No person shall install or maintain any newsrack upon any public right-of-way without first applying for and receiving a permit from the City&#x2019;s Board of Public Works, herein after referred to as &#x201C;Board&#x201D;.&#xA0; A permit will not be issued unless the application is completed in full, the requested installation meets all the appropriate placement criteria as set forth below, and the application is accompanied by the appropriate permit fee for the type of newsrack, single, pedestal, or modular, for each individual newsrack installation requested.&#xA0; Any permit granted pursuant to the provisions of this code shall only be valid as to the specific location specified in the permit application.&#xA0; Where application is made for the installation of two or more single newsracks, a separate permit shall be required for each individual newsrack.&#xA0; Upon this revised ordinance taking legal effect in the City of Los Angeles, any owner of a newsrack currently existing on any City right-of-way must apply for a permit pursuant to this ordinance within the time specified by the Board of Public Works in its Rules and Regulations for the implementation of this ordinance.&#xA0; Any newsrack which is not the subject of a valid permit application as required by the City&#x2019;s implementation Rules and Regulations will be deemed to be in violation of 42.00 (f) of this code and subject to removal from the right-of-way as set forth herein.

	(A)	Permit Application.&#xA0; Permit applications shall be in writing and on forms as provided by the Board.&#xA0; The permit application shall include the following information:

	(1)	The name, address, and telephone number of the applicant who is the owner and/or principal responsible for the newsrack.

	(2)	The name, address, and telephone number of a responsible person whom the City may notify or contact at any time concerning the applicant&#x2019;s newsrack(s).

	(3)	The specified number of newsracks and the detailed proposed location for each one, shown on a drawing of the location, or GIS/Address based program provided by applicant which is compatible with the City&#x2019;s GIS program and which indicates all existing buildings, existing newsracks at the location and general vicinity, and all other possible obstructions within 20 feet of the proposed location of the newsrack.

	(4)	Names of newspaper(s) or periodical(s) to be placed in each newsrack.&#xA0; One or more newspapers or periodicals may be dispensed from a single newsrack if the newsrack is manufactured for this purpose.

	(5)	Type or brand of newsrack, including an illustration and description of the newsrack and mount, if other than a single pedestal, size of base plate and whether the newsrack will have a coin-box attachment, or equivalent.

	(6)	A sworn statement under penalty of perjury, executed by an officer, director, or authorized agent of the applicant, agreeing that the applicant shall not sell, assign, or transfer by any method, the permit for the newsrack location to any other publisher, distributor, entity or individual.

	(7)	The Board, with Council approval, may designate areas of the City where only modular newsracks may be installed and maintained by a City vendor such as the City Hall Historical District, (the east block face on Spring Street between Temple Street and 1st Street, the south block face of Temple Street between Spring Street and Main Street, the west block face of Main Street between Temple Street and 1st Street, and the north block face of 1st Street between Spring Street and Main Street).&#xA0; No application for an individual newsrack permit may be submitted in a modular newsrack area. Upon the effective date of this ordinance, the total number of compartments in modular newsracks in any designated modular newsrack area, shall be substantially equivalent to the highest total number of individual newsracks known to have been legally maintained on the public right-of-way in the modular newsrack areas at any one time during the year preceding the introduction of this amended ordinance but in no event more than the total number of newsracks allowed by subparagraph (F)(4) below.

	(8)	Such other information as, from time to time, may be required by the Board.

	(B)	Expiration &#x2013; Renewal.&#xA0; Unless earlier revoked, newsrack permits issued pursuant to the provisions of this code shall expire on the 30th day of August following the date upon which each such permit is granted.&#xA0; Such permits may thereafter be renewed annually upon the payment of the fee hereinafter prescribed.&#xA0; Applications for renewal shall be made at least 30 days prior to the expiration of any permit issued, and must be accompanied by a permit renewal fee as set forth in Subsection (4)(C), below.&#xA0; Application for permit renewal and payment must be either presented in person to the Bureau of Street Services, via the Internet (if available), or mailed via certified mail, postmarked no later than 30 days prior to the date of permit expiration.&#xA0; Failure to renew an existing newsrack permit before its expiration will require the payment of a late renewal penalty as set forth in Subsection (4)(C), below, or the loss of the placement of the said rack at the subject location.

	(C)	Fees.&#xA0; The Board shall establish all fees, in accordance with the level of enforcement deemed appropriate by the Council, and shall only be used to defray the total expenses of operation of the newsrack program including: permitting, inspection, administration, and enforcement, required by this Ordinance as set forth in the preceding and following sections of this code.&#xA0; The Initial Permit Fee, the Renewal Permit Fee, the Site Inspection Fee, the Site Re-Inspection Fee, Late Renewal Penalty Fee, Impound Fees, and the Bar Code Decal Replacement Fee shall be determined and adopted from time to time by the Board.

	(D)	Insurance.

	(1)	Requirement-Content.&#xA0; As a condition of the City granting any person or persons one or more permits to maintain a newsrack or newsracks in the public right-of-way, any such permittee shall be required to maintain a policy of general liability insurance, naming the City of Los Angeles, the Board of Public Works and its employees, agents etc. as &#x201C;Additional Insureds&#x201D; for the specific purpose of indemnifying and holding harmless the City of Los Angeles, its officers, boards, employees, etc. from and against any and all losses, costs, damages, expenses, or liability, whatsoever, which may result from or arise out of the granting of a permit, and/or the installation and/or the maintenance of any newsrack or newsracks for which the permittee shall be responsible for paying any and all losses or damages that may be sustained by any person or persons as a result of, or which may be caused by or arise out of the installation and/or maintenance of the permitted newsrack or newsracks.&#xA0; The policy of insurance shall be maintained in its original amount by the permittee at permittee&#x2019;s expense at all times during the period for which the permittee holds a valid permit or permits.&#xA0; Should said policy be called upon to satisfy any liability for damages covered by said policy, the policy must be of such a nature that the original amount of coverage is restored after any payment of damages by the policy.&#xA0; In the event that two or more permits are issued to one permittee, the permittee shall only be required to maintain a single policy of insurance covering all such permits held by the permittee in the amount set forth below for the number of newsracks maintained by the permittee.

	(2)	Required Limits of Liability Insurance.&#xA0; The Board shall be responsible, from time to time, for adopting the limits of liability insurance required to be maintained by newsrack permittees under this code.&#xA0; The Board shall receive a recommendation from the City&#x2019;s Risk Manager prior to setting the limits of liability insurance based on the number of racks that each permittee maintains in the City&#x2019;s right-of-way.

	(E)	Every person who installs, uses or maintains any newsrack which in whole or in part rests upon, in, or over any dedicated sidewalk or parkway shall have his or her name, address and telephone number affixed thereto at a place where such information may be easily seen, in addition to a bar code decal issued by the Board for that specific newsrack.

	(5)	Prohibited Where Vehicles Permitted:&#xA0; No person shall install or maintain any newsrack which projects onto, into or over any part of the roadway of any public street, or which rests, wholly or in part, upon, along or over any portion of such roadway.

	(6)	Unlawful Obstructions:&#xA0; No person shall install, use or maintain any newsrack:

	(A)	Within 5 feet of any marked crosswalk;

	(B)	Within 5 feet of the curb return of any unmarked crosswalk;

	(C)	Within 5 feet of any fire hydrant, fire call box or other emergency facility;

	(D)	Within 5 feet ahead and 45 feet to the rear of any sign marking a designated bus stop.&#xA0; No newsrack shall be installed within the marked bus zone;

	(E)	Within 5 feet of any bus bench.

	(F)	Within 10 feet of any transit shelter.&#xA0;

	(G)	In front of an entrance to a business, including the curb area directly across from such entrance where the distance between the entry door and the newsrack is less than 10 feet;

	(H)	In any location used, marked or posted for public utility purpose, public transportation purpose or government use;

	(I)	Where placement unreasonably interferes with the use of poles, posts, traffic signs or signals, mail boxes or other objects legally permitted, but in no event shall the newsrack be closer than one foot from such objects;

	(J)	Where placement interferes with the reasonable use or utility for display purposes of any display window of any building abutting the sidewalk or parkway, but in no event within 4 feet of such window;

	(K)	Within 5 feet of any area improved with lawn, flowers shrubs, trees or street tree well;

	(L)	Within 5 feet of any driveway or driveway apron;

	(M)	Within 4 feet of any outdoor dining areas or patio dining areas;

	(N)	Within 20 feet of both sides of buildings officially designated Los Angeles Historical or Cultural Monuments.&#xA0; If there is a block in which all buildings have been so officially designated, then the Board, in consultation with the Cultural Heritage Commission, shall determine siting on such block face for up to four (4) newsracks.&#xA0; An owner of a building which has been designated as a Historical or Cultural Monument may petition the Board of Public Works to allow newsracks on the sidewalks in front of their building if the placement of such newsracks will not interfere with Historic or Cultural nature of the building.&#xA0; The Board shall listen to evidence from all interested parties and make its determination based on the totality of the evidence.

	(O)	Within 20 feet of both sides of visual public art work created, funded or managed through the City&#x2019;s Municipal Art Program including, but not limited to, murals, sculptures and fountains.

	(P)	Where placement impedes the flow of pedestrian traffic by reducing the clear space to less than 6 feet or, impedes access to or the use of abutting property, including, but not limited to, residences and places of business.

	(Q)	Notwithstanding any other paragraph of this subdivision, no person shall install, use or maintain any newsrack where placement endangers the safety of persons or property.

	(R)	No newsrack shall be installed within 4 feet from any permanently installed structure in the public Right-of-Way, which is not otherwise specifically identified in this subdivision.

	(S)	Within one foot of any utility cover, vent screen or other object that is flush mounted with the sidewalk, except that if the owner or person in control of the below grade sidewalk installation needs additional space for emergency or non-routine maintenance of the installation, any newsrack(s) which interferes with such maintenance may be requested to be temporarily removed to accommodate the required maintenance and then be reinstalled.

	(T)	Within 4 feet to the front and 10 feet to the rear of any parking meter and where there are no parking meters on the curb, 10 feet from the front of any marked parallel parking place.

	(7)	Size, Appearance, Placement, Installation and Construction of Newsracks:

	(A)	 Every newsrack shall be maintained in a neat and clean condition and be in good repair at all times.

	(B)	All newsracks shall be permanently mounted, except as provided in Subsection (7)(C), in accordance with specifications established by the Board as provided in Subsection (9) and adopted from time to time as revisions become necessary, including but not limited to: style, construction, coating, material and fabrication.&#xA0; Specifications for a newsrack shall be:

	(1)	Street tube pedestal, at least four inches by three inches in height;

	(2)	Overall height shall not be less than 46 inches and shall not exceed 52 inches; the overall width shall not be less than 20 inches and shall not exceed 30 inches; and the overall depth shall not be less than 12 inches and shall not exceed 20 inches.

	(3)	All newsracks shall be primarily constructed of metal and shall be &#x201C;Ivy Green&#x201D; in color (Tiger RAL 607 SM, Glossy, Code 28-50081), except as provided in &#xA7; 42.00 (f)(17) &#x201C;Specific Plan/Street Scape Plan Areas&#x201D;.

	(C)	Special Purpose Sidewalks; No Permanent Attachments.&#xA0; Each individual newsrack which is permitted to be placed on a special purpose sidewalk, such as terrazzo, brick, glass prism implanted, or where basements are located under the sidewalk, shall be on legs and shall be mobile and not affixed to the sidewalk in any way.

	(D)	Pedestals.&#xA0; No pedestals shall be maintained on a public right-of-way unless there is attached thereto a newsrack case as provided herein.

	(E)	Removal of Newsracks; Repair of Sidewalks.&#xA0; Upon the removal of any newsrack, the person so removing shall be responsible for the repair of any resulting condition, including filling in of any holes left in the sidewalk and/or the removal of any bolts or other devices used to affix the newsrack to the sidewalk such that there are no obstructions sticking above the grade of the sidewalk.&#xA0; Such work is to be done to the satisfaction of the Department of Public Works.

	(F)	Newsrack Location.

	(1)	Newsracks shall only be situated near a curb with the back of said newsrack situated not less than 18 inches nor more than 24 inches from the edge of the curb.&#xA0; If it is physically impossible to situate a newsrack near a curb, then the Board may authorize the placement of up to four (4) newsracks adjacent to the wall of a building on that block.&#xA0; If the newsrack is placed adjacent to the wall of a building, the back of said newsrack shall be situated parallel to and not more than 6 inches from such wall.&#xA0; No newsrack shall be installed, used or maintained on any sidewalk or parkway opposite a newsstand or other newsrack.

	(2)	Except as otherwise provided by this code, no newsrack placed on the public right-of-way shall be chained, bolted or otherwise attached to any property or to any permanently fixed object.

	(3)	Not more than four newsracks shall be placed immediately adjacent to each other.&#xA0; Any such group of up to four newsracks shall be separated by a space of not less than 48 inches from any other individual newsrack or group of newsracks.

	(4)	Not more than 16 newsracks shall be placed within 200 ft. of the same block face.&#xA0; However, the Board may establish a number greater or less than 16 in any specific block face by conducting an engineering study.&#xA0; In cases where a block face is longer than 200 ft., for every additional 50 ft. of block face greater than 200 ft., an additional four (4) newsracks may be installed.

	(5)	Not more than one permit for installation of a newsrack shall be issued for each publication on one side of a block or within 200 ft. of the same block face, whichever is less. One publication includes: differing geographic editions of the same publication (Orange County edition; Valley edition, etc.); and daily and Sunday editions of the same publication.&#xA0; In cases where a block face is longer than 200 ft., and there is space to legally install additional newsracks, then a permit for one publication to install a second newsrack on the same block face may be issued by the Board.

	(6)	Newsracks shall not be permitted on the public right-of-way adjacent to any property that is zoned exclusively for single-family residential use (R-1).

	(G)	Priorities Related to Placement of Newsracks.

	(1)	In determining in what order newsrack permittees may select their location on a particular block face during implementation of this revised newsrack ordinance, and in particular where there are more requests for newsrack spaces on any one block face than there are legal spaces available, the Board of Public Works shall, pursuant to its authority under paragraph (9) below, develop a content neutral criteria for determining the placement of newsracks applicable to each block face.

	(2)	Once this revised newsrack ordinance has been fully implemented citywide, all subsequent newsrack permits shall be issued on a first come first served basis.

	(8)	Unlawful Use:&#xA0; No newsrack shall be used for advertising signs or publicity purposes. External lettering is restricted to the following:

	(A)	If the newsrack is situated next to the curb, the side parallel to the curb, next to the lanes of traffic, may have external lettering replicating the publication masthead style and color, for the permitted publication in the subject newsrack, in a total area not to exceed 144 square inches.

	If an individual newsrack is used to distribute more than one publication, each publication distributed in that newsrack shall be entitled to have external lettering replicating the publication masthead style and color for the permitted publications in the subject newsrack.&#xA0; However, the total area for all such publication mastheads on that newsrack shall not exceed 144 square inches.

	(B)	The side of the newsrack facing pedestrian traffic, except in Specific Plan/Streetscape Plan Areas, as identified in Section (17), may have a &#x201C;Rack Card&#x201D;, with a total area not to exceed 238 square inches, which exclusively advertises the newspaper or periodical being dispensed, and shall not include any third party advertising.&#xA0; This &#x201C;Rack Card&#x201D; shall be located in the area immediately below the hood on the front access side of the newsrack.

	(C)	Other than as permitted in this section, no other lettering or advertising of any kind shall be permitted anywhere else on the newsrack, including the mount.

	(9)	Authority of the Board of Public Works to Promulgate Rules and Regulations for the Permitting, Installation and Maintenance of the Newsracks in the Public Right-of-Way:&#xA0; Consistent with the intent and requirements of LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f), et seq., the Board may adopt rules and regulations to administer the installation, placement, maintenance, size and material used for construction of newsracks.&#xA0; The Board may adopt any other rule and/or regulation for the protection of public safety, welfare, or property relative to permitting, installation, and maintenance of newsracks.&#xA0; Prior to adoption of any rules and/or regulations, the Board shall hold a public hearing.&#xA0; Once any rules and/or regulations are adopted, they shall be kept posted in the Board office and a copy thereof shall be furnished to any applicant for a newsrack permit.

	(10)	Noncompliance With LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f), et seq.; Tagging of Newsracks:&#xA0; Except as provided in Subsection (12) hereof, whenever any newsrack is found to be in violation of any Subsection of LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f), the Board shall cause a notice tag to be attached to said newsrack specifying the date and nature of the violation, and shall E-mail or fax to the permittee a copy of the violation.&#xA0; Permittee shall within ten (10) calendar days from the date on which the tag was attached, either cause the violation to be corrected or request a hearing pursuant to Subsection (13) hereof.&#xA0; If a hearing is requested, staff will not remove the non compliant newsrack until a final determination by the Board. However, if a newsrack installed within the City right-of-way has no visible evidence that it has been properly permitted (no City issued bar code decal, no visible contact information for the owner or no other evidence that would indicate that a valid permit for the newsrack had been issued) staff may confiscate the offending newsrack and follow the procedures in subparagraph (11)(B) below.&#xA0; There is hereby created a presumption that any newsrack within the City&#x2019;s right-of-way that does not have a city bar code decal, or visible identification and contact information for the owner of the newsrack, has been installed without a valid permit.

	(A)	A newsrack may be tagged for any violation of any requirement of LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f) including, but not limited to, the following:

	(1)	Where its installation, use or maintenance unreasonably interferes with or impedes the flow of vehicular or pedestrian traffic;

	(2)	Where its installation, use or maintenance interferes with the use of poles, posts, traffic signs or signals, hydrants, mailboxes or other objects legally permitted;

	(3)	Where its installation, use or maintenance unreasonably obstructs, interferes with or impedes access to or the use of abutting property, including, but not limited to, residences, places of business, or legally parked or stopped vehicles;

	(4)	When such newsrack does not have a name, address and telephone number affixed in a place where such information may be easily seen and the designee of such newsrack cannot be otherwise identified;

	(5)	When a newsrack is found in the public right-of-way which does not have a visible, city issued, bar code decal present indicating the correct permit number of the newsrack or the newsrack has no valid permit at all; and

	(6)	When a newsrack is found in the public right-of-way which is not maintained in a neat and clean condition and in good repair, in accordance with the following Maintenance Specifications:

	(a)	The newsrack permittee shall maintain all newsracks and the sidewalk surface immediately under and adjacent (within 2 feet) to the newsracks in a safe, clean, attractive and sanitary condition and in good order and repair, as determined by the Department of Public Works, Bureau of Street Services (BOSS).&#xA0; The permittee shall make routine inspection and maintenance calls on each newsrack once a week.&#xA0; Such inspection and maintenance calls may be incorporated with delivery of newspapers or other publications.&#xA0; The permittee shall make more frequent calls if conditions warrant.&#xA0; At each maintenance call, the permittee shall clean, wash and remove all graffiti, stickers, posters, litter, dust, dirt and weeds at each newsrack.&#xA0; The newsrack shall be maintained in a continual good and working condition.

	(b)	Maintenance &#x2013; Permittee shall respond to a request to secure a site or to perform maintenance within 24 hours of notification, but in no event more than 72 hours.&#xA0; The permittee shall use cleaning methods and procedures that have been demonstrated and approved and are environmentally safe, utilizing acceptable industry practices.

	(c)	Repair and Replacement &#x2013; The Permittee shall commence necessary repairs within one week when any damage or vandalism is found by BOSS.&#xA0; If the newsrack damage or vandalism is of an emergency or hazardous nature, the permittee will repair, replace, remove or secure the site within 24 hours of notification.&#xA0; If the newsrack is totally destroyed because of an accident, the Permittee will remove the newsrack and appurtenant structures within 24 hours, including repair of any damage to the public right-of- way, returning the site to its former condition prior to the newsrack installation.

	(d)	Graffiti Removal &#x2013; Permittee will upon notification by BOSS, or upon inspection, remove graffiti within 24 hours from any newsrack.&#xA0;

	(11)	Impounding of Newsracks:

	(A)	Notwithstanding the Department&#x2019;s right to tag newsracks in violation of any Subsection on LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f), the Department may cause any newsrack to be impounded:

	(1)	When the newsrack poses an immediate danger to persons or vehicles;

	(2)	Where its installation, use or maintenance endangers the safety of persons or property;

	(3)	When pursuant to Subsection (10), a tag has been attached to a newsrack and a written notice, such as fax, letter or E-mail has been sent to the owner, operator, or responsible person for the newsrack and the designee has neither caused the violation specified on said tag to be corrected nor requested a hearing pursuant to Subsection (14), hereof within the time permitted;

	(4)	When a hearing and appeal, if filed, have resulted in a final determination that the violation(s) specified on the tag attached to such newsrack has in fact occurred, and the designee has failed to correct such violation(s) within ten (10) calendar days from the date of said determination;

	(5)	When a request for a hearing or appeal has been withdrawn, such request shall be deemed withdrawn, either by actual withdrawal or by the failure of the designee to fully comply with Subsection (14) of this code;

	(6)	When such newsrack has been abandoned; and

	(7)	When such newsrack has been installed on the City&#x2019;s right-of-way without first applying for and receiving a permit as required by this code.

	Pursuant to this Subsection, a newsrack shall be deemed abandoned when it does not contain the newspaper or other publication specified therefor for more than four (4) consecutive days for a daily publication, eight (8) consecutive days for a weekly publication, sixteen (16) consecutive days for a biweekly publication, or thirty-four (34) days for a monthly publication.&#xA0; A newsstand shall be deemed abandoned if it is not open for a period of more than seven (7) consecutive days.

	(B)	Standard impound procedures:&#xA0; Within forty-eight (48) hours after removal of any newsrack, the Board shall notify the owner in writing, fax or E-mail of the removal and the reason for removal where ownership information is posted on the newsrack either through the City bar code decal or the required owner contact information.&#xA0; If ownership information is not readily available because there is no City bar code decal, or ownership identification information posted on the newsrack, or no newspaper or periodical in the newsrack with contact information, the City shall make every reasonable effort to comply with the notification procedure of this subsection.&#xA0; When notification is possible, the notice shall also inform the owner of the right to request, either in writing or in person, within five (5) business days of the date of the postmark of such written notice, a hearing by the Board or its designee pursuant to Subsection (14), to determine whether such removal was proper.

	(12)	Return of Impounded Newsracks:

	(A)	Any newsrack, together with its contents, which has been impounded pursuant to Subdivision (11) hereof, shall be returned to the permittee:

	(1)	Upon receipt of an impound fee as determined herein; or

	(2)	Upon a determination after hearing by the Board or its designee, pursuant to Subsection (14) hereof, that the newsrack should not have been impounded and should be returned to the permittee;

	(B)	In the event a hearing has not been requested pursuant to Subsection (14) within the time permitted following the impoundment of any newsrack, an impound fee as set forth herein shall be imposed upon the permittee and shall be paid before the impounded newsrack is returned.

	(C)	The fees herein shall be determined and adopted by the Board in order to collect sufficient money to defer the complete cost of the City&#x2019;s newsrack permitting and enforcement program as set forth in this code.&#xA0; The fees shall be adjusted from time to time by the Board to reflect any change in the cost of permitting and enforcement.&#xA0; At no time shall the fees adopted by the Board recover more than the actual cost of the program.

	(13)	Sale or Disposal After Impoundment:&#xA0; The Department may sell or otherwise dispose of any newsrack, together with its contents, and retain the proceeds, pursuant to California Government Code Section 50050 et seq., from any such sale or other disposition, and any monies contained in said newsrack at the time of its impoundment, provided that either:

	(A)	No hearing has been requested pursuant to Subsection (14) within the time permitted;

	(B)	A hearing and an appeal, if filed, have resulted in a final determination that said newsrack was properly impounded, and fees assessed pursuant to Subsection (12) have not been received within thirty (30) days from the date of the final determination.

	(14)	Hearings:

	(A)	Request for Hearing &#x2013; Any newsrack permittee may file a written request with the Department for a hearing, in person or by certified mail, for the purpose of demonstrating that a newsrack should not have been impounded, or that a violation as specified on the tag attached to a newsrack pursuant to Subsection (10) hereof has not in fact occurred.

	(B)	Notice of Hearing &#x2013; Within two (2) working days from the date on which the request for hearing is received, the Department shall set a hearing date and shall notify the designee by certified mail of the date, time and place of said hearing.&#xA0; Said hearing shall occur within ten (10) working days of the date of mailing the notice unless the person requesting the hearing wishes to have the hearing at a later date, and both parties agree on the date.

	(C)	Conduct of Hearing &#x2013; At the time set for such hearing, or at the date to which such hearing is continued, the Board or its designee shall receive all evidence relevant to the occurrence or non-occurrence of the specified violation(s), the compliance or noncompliance with any of the provisions of this Subsection, and any other relevant information.&#xA0; Such hearing need not be conducted according to technical rules relating to evidence and witnesses.&#xA0; Oral evidence shall be taken only on oath or affirmation.

	(D)	Decision after Hearing &#x2013; Within ten (10) working days after the conclusion of the hearing, the Board or its designee shall find and determine, from the facts adduced at said hearing, whether the newsrack should have been tagged and/or impounded, and whether said newsrack shall be returned except upon receipt of fees as specified in Subsection (12). The decision of the Board or its designee shall be in writing and shall contain findings of fact, a determination of the issues presented, and the amount of the fee, if any, to be imposed.

	(E)	Notice of Decision &#x2013; The Department shall send to the designee, by certified mail, a copy of its decision and order.

	(15)	No Criminal Sanctions:&#xA0; Notwithstanding any provision of Subsection 11.00 (m) of this Code, no person shall be subject to the imposition of criminal liability for any violation of LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f).

	(16)	No Newsrack Areas &#x2013; Regional Historic or Cultural Significance:

	(A)	No newsrack shall be installed in an area deemed by the City Cultural Heritage Commission and the City Council to be of municipal or regional historic significance or regional cultural significance, including any of the following locations:

	(1)	On the Hollywood Walk of Fame (both sides of Hollywood Boulevard between La Brea Avenue and Gower Street, and both sides of Vine Street between Yucca Street and Sunset Boulevard);

	(2)	On the sidewalks immediately contiguous to the restored City Hall (the east block face on Spring Street between Temple Street and 1st Street, the south block face of Temple Street between Spring Street and Main Street, the west block face of Main Street between Temple Street and 1st Street, and the north block face of 1st Street between Spring Street and Main Street);

	(3)	El Pueblo de Los Angeles (Olvera Street, the east block face of Main Street between Cesar Chavez Avenue and Aliso Street, the south block of Cesar Chavez between Main Street and Alameda Street, the west block face of Alameda Street between Cesar Chavez Avenue and Aliso Street, and the north block face of Aliso Street between Main Street and Alameda Street);

	(4)	On the sidewalks immediately contiguous to Disney Hall (the east block face of Hope Street between 1st Street and Upper 2nd Street; the west south block face of 1st Street between Hope Avenue and Grand Avenue; the west block face of Grand Avenue between 1st Street and Upper 2nd Street; and the north block face of Upper 2nd Street between Hope Avenue and Grand Avenue); or

	(5)	On the sidewalks on the block faces immediately to the west and east of the Music Center and Dorothy Chandler Pavilion (the west block face of Grand Avenue between 1st Street and Temple Street; and the east block face of Hope Street between 1st Street and Temple Street).

	(6)	On the Venice Boardwalk (both sides of Ocean Front Walk between Navy Street on the north and Venice Pier/Washington Boulevard on the south).

	(7)	On the sidewalks of the Westwood Village Broxton Avenue Promenade (both sides of Broxton Avenue between Le Conte Avenue and Kinross Avenue).

	(B)	In the event an area of the City which is deemed by the City Cultural Heritage Commission and the City Council to be of municipal regional historic significance, such an area may apply to the Board for designation as an area where no newsracks shall be installed, subject to the approval of the City Council.

	(17)	Specific Plan/Streetscape Plan Areas:&#xA0; Specific Plan Areas, Streetscape Plan Areas, or other Special Planning Districts approved by the Planning Department, which include a standard streetscape color, may request a uniform newsrack color other than Ivy Green, from the Board, with Council input, and if granted, the color shall be one of the following three colors: black (RAL 9017 &#x201C;Grotto Black&#x201D;), blue (Benjamin Moore No. 805 &#x201C;Westwood Blue&#x201D;) or gray (Marine Silver 38/90010).

	(18)	Severability:&#xA0; If any section or subsection of this ordinance is deemed to be void or unenforceable, such shall be severed from the whole and the remaining portions of the ordinance shall remain in full force and effect.

	(g)	Streets &#x2013; Newsstands.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(1)	No person shall install, use or maintain any newsstand which projects onto, into or over any part of the roadway of any public street, or which rests, wholly or in part, upon, along or over any portion of the roadway of any street.

	(2)	No person shall install, use or maintain any newsstand which in whole or in part rests upon, in or over any sidewalk or parkway when such installation, use or maintenance endangers the safety of persons or property, or when such site or location is used for public utility purposes, public transportation purposes or other governmental use, or when such newsstand unreasonably interferes with or impedes the flow of pedestrian or vehicular traffic, the ingress into or the egress from any residence or place of business, or the use of poles, posts, traffic signs or signals, hydrants, mailboxes, or other objects permitted at or near said locations.

	(3)	Any newsstand which in whole or in part rests upon, in or over any sidewalk or parkway, shall comply with the following standards:

	(A)	No newsstand shall exceed five feet in height, seventy-five inches in width and three feet in depth, except that if erected parallel and adjacent to the wall of a building, it shall not extend over that area of the sidewalk or parkway by more than twenty inches, shall not exceed a length of fifty feet, or a height of eight feet.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(B)	Except for a newsstand erected adjacent to the wall of a building, no newsstand shall be placed less than twelve inches nor more than eighteen inches from the edge of the curb.

	(C)	No newsstand shall be placed or maintained on the sidewalk or parkway opposite another newsstand.

	(D)	No seat, chair, rack, case, canopy, awning, overhang, or other object shall be attached to the exterior of any newsstand, nor shall any such object when attached to any part of a newsstand be permitted to extend beyond its exterior wall.

	(E)	No newsstand shall be so placed that the clear space for the passage of pedestrians upon the sidewalk and parkway is reduced to less than six feet.

	(F)	Newsstands shall be soundly constructed of wood, metal or other suitable permanent material, painted in a manner and color as prescribed by the Board of Public Works, and maintained at all times, in a clean, neat and attractive condition and in good repair and, as to the Central Traffic District, as defined in Section 80.00 of this Code, such newsstands shall be of design and construction approved by the Department of Cultural Affairs.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(G)	No newsstand shall be used for advertising signs or publicity purposes other than that dealing with the display, sale or purchase of newspapers or new periodicals.

	(H)	No newsstand shall be placed within three feet of any area improved with lawn, flowers, shrubs or trees or within three feet of any display window of any building abutting the street or in such manner as to impede or interfere with the reasonable use of such window for display purposes.

	(I)	No newsstand shall be utilized for the sale, or offer for sale, nor for the display for sale, of any article or item other than newspapers, magazines, periodicals and other similar newsprint publications.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(J)	Newsstands, in the Central Traffic District, as defined by Section 80.00 of this Code, shall be open and utilized for business at least six hours a day, five days a week and the holder of the permit shall be present at the newsstand and operating it himself or herself seventy-five percent (75%) of the time it is open, or thirty (30) hours a week, whichever is less. Waivers of such requirement may be granted by the Board of Public Works for good cause.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(4)	Every person placing or maintaining a newsstand on the streets of the City of Los Angeles shall have affixed thereto in a place readily visible to the public a telephone number or postal box number where the owner may be reached.

	(5)	(Amended by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)&#xA0; No person shall install, use or maintain any newsstand which in whole or in part rests upon, in, or over any dedicated sidewalk or parkway in the Central Traffic District, as defined by Section 80.00 of this Code, without first applying for and obtaining a permit from the Department. The issuance of such permit shall be subject to the provisions of this subdivision.

	(A)	Forms for Permit &#x2013; The Department shall prescribe and make available permit application forms. The applicant shall submit to the Department a completed form, on which the following information shall have been entered:

	(i)	The name, address and telephone number of the applicant;

	(ii)	The name, address and telephone number of the person whom the applicant designates to be notified concerning the applicant&#x2019;s newsstand;

	(iii)	The requested location for the newsstand.

	(B)	Issuance of Permit &#x2013; Upon proper application, the Department may, upon the payment of the fee provided below, issue a newsstand permit to the applicant in accordance with the provisions of this Subdivision (5). Such permit shall not be assignable nor shall more than one permit be issued to any one person. No more than two newsstands shall be allowed on any one block. As used herein &#x201C;block&#x201D; shall mean one side of a street between two consecutive intersecting streets.

	(C)	The Board shall enact regulations for the selection of permittees taking into consideration the length of time a newsstand has been operated by the applicant at a particular location, whether there has existed a business license for such newsstand, the number of violations an applicant has incurred in the operation of his or her newsstand and such other factors the Board deems appropriate.

	(D)	Validity of Permit &#x2013; Permits shall be valid from the issuance date until the May 31st following such date, and may be renewed annually thereafter. Such permits shall be issued initially for a period not to exceed one year and renewals thereof shall be for a maximum of one year periods thereafter.

	(E)	Permit Fee &#x2013; There shall be a permit fee for new, and renewal, permits in the amount of twenty-five (25) dollars for each newsstand. Whenever any permit is issued after May 31st, the amount of such fee shall be prorated on a quarterly basis. The permit fee may be increased by the Board if so justified by an increase in the cost of regulation.

	(F)	Permit Decals &#x2013; The Department shall issue to each permittee a permit decal for the newsstand covered by the permit. Permittees shall cause the decal to be affixed to the front face of the newsstand so as to be visible from the sidewalk.

	(6)	Prior to the issuance of a permit by the Department, the applicant shall furnish to the Department a certificate, in a form satisfactory to the Department and City Attorney, that the applicant has then in force public liability and property damage insurance, naming the City as an additional insured, in an amount and type as determined by the Board, subject to reasonable availability. The evidence of insurances filed shall include a statement by the insurance carrier that thirty (30) days notice will be given to the City Attorney before any cancellation of coverage. The City shall be named as an additional insured on any such insurance policy. Such insurance shall be maintained throughout the permit period.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(7)	Any newsstand installed, used or maintained in violation of this subsection shall be removed subject to the provisions of Subdivisions (7) through (12) of Subsection (f) of this section. In addition any violation of this subsection shall subject the applicant and/or violator to the imposition of criminal liability.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(8)	Upon the cessation and abandonment of operations of any newsstand the person holding the permit, or if no one is presently holding a permit the last one to hold a permit for the newsstand, shall be responsible for the removal of such newsstand. If the newsstand is not so removed the City shall so remove it pursuant to Subsection (f) hereof and assess the most recent holder of the permit for the costs incurred.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(9)	Violation of any provision of this subsection may result, after due notice and hearing, in the revocation of the permit by the Board.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(h)	Freeway On-Ramps and Off-Ramps &#x2013; Sales Prohibited.&#xA0; Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, no person on any street, or other public property of whatever nature or description, shall, within fifty feet of the roadway of any freeway on-ramp or off-ramp, distribute, deliver, sell, offer for sale or solicit the sale of any newspapers, magazines, periodicals, circulars, handbills or other printed matter or any goods, wares or merchandise regardless of type, nature, kind or description.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(i)	The provisions of this section shall not apply to the installation and maintenance of any bench installed and maintained in accordance with Article 8 of Chapter VI of this code, nor to the operation and maintenance of searchlights, generators and floodlights in accordance with the restrictions and requirements of Division T of Chapter VIII of this Code. Nor shall the provisions of this section prohibit the putting of business notices, signs or emblems upon ordinary business or carrier vehicles. Nor shall the provisions of this section apply to temporary selling activities and advertising related thereto conducted pursuant to a permit granted under Subsection (j) hereof. (Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(j)	Permit for Temporary Selling Activities Board of Public Works.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(1)	The Board of Public Works may issue upon written application, made upon a form prescribed by the Board, a permit authorizing temporary selling activities and advertising relative thereto, on sidewalks, parkways and roadways, provided that as to roadways such permit&#x2019;s issuance will, in addition to this section&#x2019;s requirements, be governed by the provisions of Section 41.20 of this Code, in connection with a community civic event sponsored and conducted by a nonprofit organization formed for charitable, educational, civic, veteran, philanthropic or other benevolent purposes, under the following conditions:&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 150,706, Eff. 5/13/78.)

	(A)	&#x201C;Community civic center&#x201D; means the sponsoring and conducting by a nonprofit organization of a civic, artistic, cultural, charitable, educational, veteran or benevolent activity of community interest. The Board shall require reasonable proof of the nonprofit status of the sponsoring organization and a sufficient showing of community interest, which showing shall consist of furnishing the Board with names and addresses of at least 100 persons who will support the activity, at least 50% of which either reside or work in the location specified in the application for permit where the activity is to take place.

	(B)	Each permit shall be valid for a period of three consecutive days only, two of which days shall be a Saturday or Sunday. &#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 158,731, Eff. 2/25/84.)

	(C)	Each application for a permit must be accompanied by a fee and must be presented to the Board not less than 40 nor more than 180 days before the commencing date of the proposed permit activities; provided that the Board may waive these time requirements if it determines such waiver to be in the public interest. The fee herein shall be determined and adopted in the same manner as provided in Section 12.37-I, 1 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code for establishing fees.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 165,675, Eff. 5/11/90.)

	(D)	No person or sponsoring organization shall fail to keep the permit, at all times, at the place where the selling activities are being conducted, nor fail, upon demand therefor, to exhibit such permit to any public officer.

	(E)	No selling or advertising activities shall be conducted in the roadway or within two feet of the curb of any sidewalk unless authorized by the Board of Public works.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 150,706, Eff. 5/13/78.)

	(F)	(Amended by Ord. No. 173,283, Eff. 6/26/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)&#xA0; Nor may such selling activities take place without an Information Card, written Notice of Intention, or professional fund-raiser&#x2019;s license if the activity is such that one would be required under Article 4, Chapter 4 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.

	(G)	The application for such permit shall contain:

	1.	The name of the applicant, the sponsoring organization, the event chairman and the addresses and telephone numbers of each.

	2.	The location and outside perimeter of the selling area, indicated upon a map of the area.

	3.	The date and times at which the selling activities are to take place.

	4.	A description of the selling activity which will be conducted.

	5.	A list of all persons who will be engaging in temporary selling activities at any time during the dates and times for which a temporary selling permit is granted. However this list may be furnished after the application has been submitted, so long as it is not furnished later than one week before the event is to take place.

	6.	An agreement to comply with the terms of the permit.

	(2)	Sponsoring organizations may be granted a temporary selling permit if the organization meets the following requirements:

	(A)	That the title of any real property in the City of Los Angeles owned by such organization is vested in the name of such organization, if it be a corporation, or else in the name or names of a responsible trustee or trustees under a declaration of trust or other written instrument setting forth the rights of said organization therein; and recorded in the records of the County Recorder of Los Angeles County.

	(B)	That the declared&#xA0; purposes for which such organization is organized are charitable, educational, civic, community service, veteran, benevolent or other philanthropic purposes, and not for the pecuniary profit of the members of the organization thereof or any of them.

	(C)	That for three months prior to its application for a temporary selling permit said organization has faithfully complied with the following provisions with reference to its accounts, namely: All funds received by it, and all disbursements made by it, have been entered upon the books of its treasurer or other financial officer, receipts have been given or tendered for all money or other property donated to it, whenever required by law or ordinance; all expenditures other than petty cash to a reasonable amount have been made by checks signed by at least two officers of such organization; that the bank book of such organization has been balanced and reconciled with the books of account at reasonable intervals.

	(D)	That no monies of said organization are on loan directly or indirectly to any&#xA0; officer, director, trustee, employee or member thereof, and that the organization has not invested any monies constituting part of its permanent endowment funds except in securities legal as investments for savings banks within the State of California, and has not diverted funds donated to it from an source to purposes other than those for which they were donated.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 156,941, Eff. 8/20/82.)

	(E)	That the work for which such organization has been formed has been faithfully performed.

	(F)	That the bylaws and other written rules and regulations of such organization define the powers and duties of the officers of such organization, and that a copy of the Articles of Incorporation, if it be a corporation, and a copy of the bylaws and other written rules and regulations of such organization have been filed with the Department of Public works.

	(G)	That within one year prior to its application such organization has not violated any law or ordinance applicable to it.

	(3)	The Board shall cause such application to be investigated and shall grant the permit if it determines: that the proposed activities will not disrupt to an unreasonable extent the movement of vehicular or pedestrian traffic or create a hazard to the public; that the proposed activities are not of a size or nature that require the diversion of so great a number of police personnel to regulate such activities that it prevents reasonable police protection for the City or for the councilmanic district where the temporary selling activity is to take place; that the concentration of persons, equipment and materials is not so great in the selling area that it would prevent proper fire, police and ambulance protection; that the applicant agrees to be responsible for cleanup necessitated by the proposed activities and the Board may, in its discretion, require a cleanup deposit to guarantee that cleanup takes place.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 160,175, Eff. 8/24/85.)

	(4)	The Board shall further condition the granting of such permit upon the permit applicant filing with the Board a policy of public liability insurance in which the City has been named as insured or co-insured with the permittee. The policy of insurance shall insure the City and its officers and employees against all claims arising out of or in connection with the issuance of the permit or the operation of the permittee, his agents or representatives pursuant to the permit. The policy of insurance shall provide coverage no less than $100,000 per occurrence of bodily injury and $25,000 per occurrence of property damage.

	(5)	The Board shall adopt uniform rules and regulations so as to carry out the purposes of this subsection and shall condition the granting of permits upon compliance therewith and also with such other conditions as the Board may deem necessary to impose for the proper protection of persons and property.

	(k)	The provisions of this section shall not prohibit sales that are otherwise permitted under the terms of Section 80.73 of this Code.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 150,561, Eff. 3/19/78.)

	(l)	Permit for Flower Vending Booths.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 159,008, Eff. 7/1/84.)

	(1)	The provisions of this section shall not apply to the sale of flowers from a flower vending booth operated pursuant to a permit granted by the Board of Public Works.

	(2)	The Board may issue a revocable permit for the installation and operation of a flower vending booth on a sidewalk pursuant to the one year pilot flower vending booth demonstration program authorized by the City Council in the downtown area.

	(3)	The issuance of any such permit does not preclude the requirements of any other permits or approval for any such installation.

	(m)	Establishment and Regulation of Special Sidewalk Vending Districts.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 169,319, Eff. 2/18/94.)

	(1)	The Board of Public Works, hereinafter referred to as &#x201C;Board,&#x201D; is authorized to form special sidewalk vending districts for the purpose of permitting vending of goods, wares and merchandise and announcing the availability thereof within such districts, and to promulgate rules and regulations with respect to the formation of such districts.&#xA0; The term &#x201C;district&#x201D; whenever used in this subdivision shall mean &#x201C;special sidewalk vending district.&#x201D;&#xA0; No more than eight districts shall be approved by the Board during the first two years following the effective date of this ordinance.&#xA0; Each district shall have a&#xA0; designated police liaison appointed by the Chief of Police.&#xA0; Before any proposed vending districts are established, the City Council shall adopt a humane and comprehensive enforcement policy regarding sidewalk vending both inside and outside the proposed districts.

	(2)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; A petition may be filed with the Sidewalk Vending Administrator of the Community Development Department, hereinafter referred to as &#x201C;Sidewalk Vending Administrator,&#x201D; by any person or persons, hereinafter referred to as &#x201C;applicant,&#x201D; interested in the formation of a special sidewalk vending district.&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall coordinate with the Board regarding the filing and processing of said application.&#xA0; The petition shall be subject to the following conditions and requirements:

	(A)	The applicant shall pay to the Sidewalk Vending Administrator a non refundable application fee to establish a district.&#xA0; However, such fee shall not be paid until after the City Council has approved the formation of the district pursuant to Subdivision (6) of this subsection.&#xA0; No license application in respect to said district shall be approved until the fee has been paid.&#xA0; Said fee shall be determined and adopted in the same manner as provided in Section 12.37-I,1 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code for establishing fees.

	(B)	The petition shall contain the name or names of the applicant(s) and names and signatures together with residence or business addresses within the district of persons endorsing the formation of the district.&#xA0; The endorsing list must consist of the owners or those in possession, such as tenants or lessees, of at least 20 percent of the businesses and 20 percent of the residents in each block or portion thereof to be included in the district.

	(C)	The petition shall set forth:

	1.	The proposed boundaries of the district, which shall only be in commercially zoned areas of the City;

	2.	The location and number of vending sites sought to be approved;

	3.	Any rules or regulations deemed necessary or desirable by the petitioners to organize vending activity within the district; and

	4.	The purpose for establishing the district.

	(D)	The petition shall be accompanied by a list provided by the Sidewalk Vending Administrator of the names and addresses of all property owners, businesses and residents within the district and within a 500-foot radius of the boundaries of the district, together with a cash deposit sufficient to cover the costs of preparing such a list and of mailing and publishing notifications as provided below.

	(E)	The district shall not be limited to any particular size and the proposed density of vending sites may vary from area-to-area within the district.

	(3)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; Upon receipt of said petition, the Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall notify the Council member or Council members in whose district or districts the special sidewalk vending district is proposed to be located, at which time the Council member or Council members shall appoint a Community Advisory Committee.&#xA0; The Community Advisory Committee must contain a Street Use Inspector, a Police Officer and the Sidewalk Vending Administrator.&#xA0; The committee shall have balanced representation of proponents of the district, fixed businesses, and residents within or adjacent to the proposed districts, as well as a representative of the Council office or offices.&#xA0; The committee will make recommendations on boundaries of the district, density and location of vendors, goods sold, design of carts and hours of operation.&#xA0; There shall be a limit of 90 days between filing this petition and a final decision by the Board.

	(4)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; After reviewing the petition for compliance with the provisions of this Code, the Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall transmit said petition to the Board which shall set the matter for public hearing in coordination with the Sidewalk Vending Administrator within 30 days after receipt thereof.&#xA0; Notice of the time, place and purpose of the public hearing shall be given by the Sidewalk Vending Administrator to each applicant by mailing a written notice of the hearing not less than 30 days prior to the date of such hearing.&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall at the same time mail such notice to all property owners, businesses and residents within the proposed district and within a 500-foot radius of the boundaries of the district.&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall further cause there to be published a notice of such public hearing in a newspaper of general circulation in the area wherein the sidewalk vending district is proposed to be established.&#xA0; The notice shall be published in both English and in any other language spoken as their primary language by a substantial number of the persons residing in the proposed district.&#xA0; The notice shall be published as provided for in Section 6064 of the Government Code of the State of California, and shall state the purpose of the proposed district, the boundaries thereof and the date, time and place of the public hearing.

	(5)	Any interested person may appear at such hearing and comment with respect to the proposed vending district.&#xA0; Comments may also be submitted in writing prior to the date of such hearing.&#xA0; The Board shall also consider recommendations of merchant associations, chambers of commerce, the Los Angeles Police Department and various other affected City departments.
	(6)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall refer the matter to the Council member or Council members in whose district or districts the special vending district is proposed to be located for review and recommendation, together with a summary of comments made at the hearing.&#xA0; Based upon the foregoing comments, recommendations of the Community Advisory Committee and Council member recommendations, the Board may make a finding that the public welfare would be served by the establishment of such a district.&#xA0; In so doing, the Board may for good cause alter the proposed district boundaries and the number, location and density of proposed vending sites.&#xA0; The Board shall transmit to the City Council its finding and the reasons therefor together with its recommendation that the district be established in the manner proposed in the petition or as modified by the Board.&#xA0; The City Council may approve, modify or disapprove the recommendation of the Board.&#xA0; The district shall be established upon approval, or approval as modified, of the Board&#x2019;s recommendation.&#xA0; For good cause, after due consideration of all comments and recommendations presented, the Board may make a finding that the public welfare would not be served by the establishment of the district.&#xA0; The Board&#x2019;s finding may be based on factors such as incompatibility of vending pushcarts with area architectural style, conflict with the area&#x2019;s specific plan, the presence of pushcarts as an impediment to the use of on-street parking locations in areas where an unusually heavy demand for such parking exists, or the presence of zoning restrictions prohibiting such vending activities on private property in the area.&#xA0; The Board shall transmit to the City Council its finding and the reasons therefor together with its recommendation that the district not be established.&#xA0; The City Council may approve or disapprove the recommendation of the Board.&#xA0; If disapproved, such disapproval shall establish the district and the Board shall be so informed, provided, however, that either the City Council, or the Board with approval of the Council, may modify district boundaries and number, location and density of proposed vending sites, as set forth in the petition.

	(7)	Upon petition of an interested party, a special district may be disestablished, or areas withdrawn therefrom, for good cause.&#xA0; Each such petition shall contain the signatures of at least 20 percent of the owners or persons in possession, such as tenants or lessees, of businesses in each block or portion thereof of the district or part thereof proposed to be withdrawn, and at least 20 percent of the residents of each such block or portion thereof.&#xA0; Each such petition shall comply with the requirements of Section 42.00(m)(2)(D).&#xA0; The Board shall hold a hearing into the matter preceded by notice as provided for in Subdivision (4) above.&#xA0; In the event the Board makes a finding that the public welfare would be served by disestablishment of the district or by withdrawal of an area, the Board shall transmit to the City Council its finding and the reasons therefor, together with its recommendation that district be disestablished or an area be withdrawn therefrom.&#xA0; The City Council may approve or disapprove the Board&#x2019;s recommendation.&#xA0; Approval disestablishes the district or withdraws the subject area therefrom.

	(8)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall review all rules and regulations proposed by petitioners, the Community Advisory Committee of the particular vending district, and any other interested parties provided that the Community Advisory Committee has had an opportunity to review them and transmit all such rules and regulations to the Board, together with his or her recommendations regarding adoption.&#xA0; The Board shall adopt all such rules and regulations for the district unless good cause exists for non-adoption.&#xA0; In addition, the Board, for good cause, may adopt such other rules and regulations for the district as would promote the public health, welfare and safety.&#xA0; Rules and regulations, when adopted, shall be binding upon all affected persons within the district.

	(9)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; No permit shall be issued, however, until a contract has been executed between the City, through the Community Development Department,&#xA0; and any organization selected to manage the special sidewalk vending district, referred to hereinafter as &#x201C;management organization&#x201D;, as provided for in Los Angeles Administrative Code Section 22.361.

	(10)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; The Community Development Department, through the Sidewalk Vending Administrator, shall determine the allocation of vending permits within the district, whether by lottery or otherwise, in a manner consistent with public health, safety and welfare.&#xA0; However, the Sidewalk Vending Administrator may by contract delegate that function to any organization selected to manage the district subject to the supervision of the Sidewalk Vending Administrator and approval by the Community Development Department as to method of allocation to assure that vending permits are allocated in a fair and impartial manner.

	(11)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; The Community Development Department, through the Sidewalk Vending Administrator, shall issue all sidewalk vending permits and collect all fees and charges in connection therewith.&#xA0; Any person desiring to be issued a permit for sidewalk vending within a district may make application to the Sidewalk Vending Administrator on forms provided.&#xA0; The application shall set forth the following information:

	(A)	The name, address and telephone number of the applicant;

	(B)	The exact location at which the vending is proposed to be conducted;

	(C)	A complete list of what is proposed to be sold;

	(D)	The hours per day and days per week during which sidewalk vending will be conducted; and

	(E)	Any other information required by the Community Development Department.

	(12)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; No permit or renewal permit shall be issued unless the applicant has complied with all of the following requirements:

	(A)	If any food or drink item is proposed to be sold, the applicant has obtained approval from the County Department of Health Services to engage in the vending of the item in the manner proposed;

	(B)	(Amended by Ord. No. 173,298, Eff. 6/30/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)&#xA0; All other necessary City, County and State licenses and permits have been obtained, including a Business Tax Registration Certificate from the Office of Finance.

	(C)	(Amended by Ord. No. 173,363, Eff. 7 /29/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)&#xA0; The applicant has filed with the Community Development Department a policy of public liability and property damage insurance, in a form satisfactory to it and to the City Attorney, in which the City is named as a co-insured with the applicant.&#xA0; The policy of insurance shall so insure the City and its officers and employees against all claims arising out of or in connection with the issuance of the permit or the operation of the permittee.&#xA0; The policy of insurance shall be in an amount and type as determined by the Community Development Department in consultation with the Director of the Office of Administrative and Research Services, subject to reasonable availability.&#xA0; The Community Development Department, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Administrative and Research Services, may waive the requirement of insurance if none is reasonably available.&#xA0; In lieu of individual policies of insurance, the Community Development Department may cause to be secured a general or blanket policy of insurance covering all applicants and thereafter determine the pro rata cost to each applicant, which shall be collected before approval of the application.&#xA0; Any policy of insurance shall contain a statement by the insurance carrier that thirty (30) days&#x2019; notice will be given to the City Attorney before any cancellation of coverage.&#xA0; Insurance shall be maintained throughout the permit period.&#xA0; The Community Development Department may for good cause increase the amount of required insurance.

	(D)	The applicant shows proof of ownership, lease or rental of a pushcart constructed for the purpose of vending goods, wares or merchandise according to the requirements and specifications of the Community Development Department.

	(E)	Approval in writing has been obtained from the owner, tenant or person in lawful possession or control of the property abutting upon the street immediately adjacent to the location where the vending is proposed to be conducted.&#xA0; Such approval may be secured by the management organization.

	(F)	The applicant has provided the City with two passport size photos of the applicant.

	(G)	The applicant has presented adequate identification of himself or herself.&#xA0; Adequate identification shall include, but not be limited to, a California driver&#x2019;s license or a California Department of Motor Vehicles identification card.

	(H)	The applicant is old enough under State law to engage in the vending activity.

	(I)	The applicant has submitted to fingerprinting, in connection with which applicant shall pay a fingerprint process fee.&#xA0; Such fee shall be determined and adopted in the same manner as is provided in Section 12.37-I,1 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code for establishing fees.

	(13)	No permit shall be issued to any applicant who has been convicted of any crime relating to fraudulent business practices, the receipt or sale of stolen property or the illegal sale of any controlled substance under the provisions of the California Controlled Substances Act within five (5) years prior to the date of application for permit.

	(14)	The applicant may designate up to two co-applicants who are authorized by the applicant to vend at the location for which the applicant&#x2019;s permit is issued in his or her temporary absence due to circumstances such as illness, injury or vacation.&#xA0; However, there must be provided the name, address and phone number of each co-applicant and two passport size photos of each co-applicant must be submitted.&#xA0; Each co-applicant must present adequate identification of himself or herself in the same manner as required for the applicant, and must be old enough under State law to engage in vending activity.&#xA0; Each co-applicant shall submit to fingerprinting and shall be subject to provisions of Subdivision 12 with respect to approval as a co-applicant and the provisions of Subdivision (22) with respect to operating requirements.&#xA0; Those approved shall be designated co-permittees and shall pay an application fee for the issuance of a co-permit.&#xA0; Such fee shall be determined and adopted in the same manner as is provided in Section 12.37-I,1 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code for establishing fees.

	(15)	A permit shall be issued only to a natural person and only for the days or hours of the day indicated on the application as days and hours of operation.&#xA0; Such permit shall not be transferable to any other person and shall be valid only for the location for which it is issued.

	(16)	Only one permit shall be issued to each permittee.

	(17)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; A non-refundable annual permit fee shall be paid before issuance of any permit provided, however, that the applicant may elect to pay said fee in semi-annual installments.&#xA0; Such election shall be stated in writing and installments shall be paid as directed by the Sidewalk Vending Administrator.&#xA0; If such election is made, a payment of one-half the annual permit fee shall be required before issuance of a permit.&#xA0; Permits shall be valid for one year from the date of issuance.&#xA0; If any installment fee is not paid on or before the date provided by the Sidewalk Vending Administrator for payment, a letter shall be sent to the permittee advising that such fee is due within 30 days of the date of such letter or the permit shall terminate.&#xA0; If the fee is not paid within the 30-day period, the permit shall terminate and the former permittee shall cease from vending.&#xA0; The permit may be reinstated upon payment of the fee.&#xA0; At the time of making any payment as provided for above, the applicant or permittee shall pay a supplemental fee which is a pro-rated amount determined by the Community Development Department as sufficient to cover the cost to the City of entering into a contract for management of the district.&#xA0; Supplemental fees collected shall be placed in a special fund established for such purpose.&#xA0; In addition fees will be charged for the following:

	Replacement of existing permit in the event of loss, name change or change of company;

	Replacement of existing permit decal; and

	Replacement of any vending identification badge.

	Fees herein shall be determined and adopted in the same manner as provided in Section 12.37-I,1 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code for establishing fees.

	(18)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; In the event an application for permit is denied, the applicant shall be so notified within 60 days, which notification shall also state the reason for denial and that the applicant has 45 days from the date of notice within which to request reconsideration of the denial.

	(19)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; Any permit issued shall be subject to the right of the Community Development Department to rescind issuance thereof in response to a request for reconsideration of its action in issuing the permit.

	(20)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; Either the applicant or any other person affected by the issuance of a vending permit may request reconsideration by the Community Development Department of its decision to grant or deny an application for permit.&#xA0; Such request must be in writing and must be received by the Sidewalk Vending Administrator within the 45 days from the date of issuance of the permit or notification of denial.&#xA0; Upon receipt of such request the Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall set a hearing date no less than 30 days from the date of the receipt of the request.&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall notify the requestor and, if the requestor is not the applicant, the applicant, of the hearing date.&#xA0; The Community Development Department shall rescind issuance of the permit if at the hearing it is demonstrated to its satisfaction that the issuance thereof was contrary to the provisions of this subdivision or to applicable rules and regulations.&#xA0; The Community Development Department may direct the Sidewalk Vending Administrator to issue a permit if it is shown to the satisfaction of the Department that it was in error in denying the permit.

	(21)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; The permittee may amend his or her application with respect to the goods, wares and merchandise proposed to be sold and the hours during which vending is to occur by written notification thereof to and approval by the Sidewalk Vending Administrator, and the owner, tenant, or person in lawful control of the property immediately adjacent to the vending site.

	(22)	Operating Requirements.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)

	(A)	Vending shall be conducted only from pushcarts constructed for that purpose according to the requirements and specifications of the Community Development&#xA0; Department.&#xA0; Such pushcarts shall have a length of no greater than six feet and a width of no greater than 3 feet, 6 inches, and shall be no more than 6 feet, 6 inches in Height, including roof or awning.&#xA0; A decal so certifying shall be attached to each pushcart approved for use.

	(B)	All of the permittee&#x2019;s advertising must be attached to the pushcart and shall advertise only the goods, wares or merchandise being sold.&#xA0; Advertising signs shall not extend beyond the overall width or height of the pushcart.

	(C)	The permittee shall not conduct any portion of its vending business outside the boundaries of its vending location as described in the permit.

	(D)	One small, compact stool or chair may be utilized by the permittee.&#xA0; The stool or chair shall be placed within four feet of the pushcart and shall not block the safe passage of pedestrians.&#xA0; No advertising shall be placed on the stool or chair.&#xA0; Other than the pushcart and stool or chair, no other items or object of any kind shall be placed on the public sidewalk or parkway.

	(E)	No vending shall be conducted on the roadway portion of any street.

	(F)	The permittee shall provide a trash receptacle for the use of customers and shall pick up and dispose of any trash or litter left by customers before leaving the vending location.&#xA0; Full receptacles shall be immediately emptied by the permittee.

	(G)	The City vending permit shall be visibly displayed at all times while the permittee is engaged in vending activity.

	(H)	The permittee shall wear a vendor identification badge issued by the Sidewalk Vending Administrator at all times while engaged in vending.

	(I)	Pushcarts shall be positioned no less than 18 inches from the curb.

	(J)	No permittee shall knowingly allow, permit or authorize another person to vend from permittee&#x2019;s pushcart or at permittee&#x2019;s assigned location, other than designated co-permittees of that particular vendor.

	(K)	No pushcart shall be chained or fastened to any pole, sign, tree or other object in the public way.

	(23)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending Administrator may from time to time recommend rules and regulations to the Board.&#xA0; The Board may adopt such rules and regulations as it deems necessary to implement the provisions of this subsection.

	(24)	Revocation, Suspension or Non-renewal.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)

	(A)	After notice and hearing in accordance with Section 22.02 of the Municipal Code, the Community Development Department may revoke or suspend any permit issued pursuant to this subsection or decline to renew any such permit, if the permittee has:

	1.	Knowingly made any false, misleading or fraudulent statement of&#xA0; material fact in its application for a permit;

	2.	Been convicted of any criminal act in connection with the operation of the permitted activity, or any of the crimes set forth in Subdivision (13) of this subsection;

	3.	Violated any of the operating requirements set forth in Subdivision (22) of this subsection;

	4.	Violated any rule or regulation promulgated by the Board with respect to this subdivision;

	5.	Failed to comply with any order by the department to cease and desist from any violation; or

	6.	In any other way endangered the public health, safety or welfare in the conducting of its sidewalk vending activities.

	(B)	A permittee who has had his or her permit revoked or whose application for renewal has been declined shall not be eligible to apply for another permit under this subdivision until 12 months after the date of revocation or renewal declination.

	(C)	Any action revoking or suspending a license may be appealed to the Board within 60 days of the action of suspension or revocation.&#xA0; The Board shall hear and make a determination on the appeal.

	(25)	Enforcement and Penalties.

	(A)	Within each district the provisions of this Subsection (m) shall be enforced by the Street Use Inspection Division of the Bureau of Street Maintenance of the Department of Public Works.

	(B)	The Department may issue an order to immediately cease and desist from any violation of this Subsection (m) or any rule or regulation of the Board.

	(C)	It shall be a violation of law to fail to comply with any of the provisions of Subdivision (22) of this Subsection (m).&#xA0; The first, second and third violations of Subdivision (22) of Subsection (m) shall each be infractions.&#xA0; The commission of a fourth violation of any of the provisions of Subdivision (22) of Subsection (m) within a two-year period after the commission of the first violation shall be a misdemeanor.

	(D)	It shall be illegal for any person to display any imitation or facsimile of a vending permit, vendor identification badge or decal which has not been issued by the Department.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><unit></unit></prefixes><entire_prefix></entire_prefix><prefix_anchor></prefix_anchor><level>1</level></unit></text><ancestry><unit id="21" label="article"><name>Soliciting &#x2013; Sales</name><identifier>2</identifier><url>/4/2/</url></unit><unit id="11" label="chapter"><name>Public Welfare</name><identifier>4</identifier><url>/4/</url></unit></ancestry><structure_contents><unit id="2783"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.00</section_number><catch_line>Regulation Of Soliciting And Sales In Streets.</catch_line><url>/42.00/</url><token>42.00</token></unit><unit id="1898"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.00.1</section_number><catch_line>Sales From Ice Cream Trucks.</catch_line><url>/42.00.1/</url><token>42.00.1</token></unit><unit id="25"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.01</section_number><catch_line>Street &#x2013; Sidewalk &#x2013; Pedestriansbuilding Setback.</catch_line><url>/42.01/</url><token>42.01</token></unit><unit id="2496"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.02</section_number><catch_line>Street &#x2013; Sidewalk &#x2013; Adjacent Property &#x2013; Soliciting Trade.</catch_line><url>/42.02/</url><token>42.02</token></unit><unit id="1038"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.03</section_number><catch_line>Selling Of Tickets Of Admission To Places Of Public Assemblage In Public Places And Places Open To The Public Prohibited &#x2013; Exceptions.</catch_line><url>/42.03/</url><token>42.03</token></unit><unit id="2448"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.04</section_number><catch_line>Street &#x2013; Sidewalk &#x2013; Soliciting Patronage.</catch_line><url>/42.04/</url><token>42.04</token></unit><unit id="2256"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.05</section_number><catch_line>Street &#x2013; Sidewalk &#x2013; Soliciting Patronage Transportation.</catch_line><url>/42.05/</url><token>42.05</token></unit><unit id="1089"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.06</section_number><catch_line>Railroad &#x2013; Stage Depot &#x2013; Soliciting Patronage.</catch_line><url>/42.06/</url><token>42.06</token></unit><unit id="137"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.07</section_number><catch_line>Common Carrier &#x2013; Soliciting Patronage On.</catch_line><url>/42.07/</url><token>42.07</token></unit><unit id="3152"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.08</section_number><catch_line>Street &#x2013; Sidewalk &#x2013; Soliciting Patronage Prohibited In Area.</catch_line><url>/42.08/</url><token>42.08</token></unit><unit id="697"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.09</section_number><catch_line>Soliciting Patronage &#x2013; Manner Of.</catch_line><url>/42.09/</url><token>42.09</token></unit><unit id="3012"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.10</section_number><catch_line>Solicitors Of Patronage &#x2013; Interference With.</catch_line><url>/42.10/</url><token>42.10</token></unit><unit id="1603"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.11</section_number><catch_line>Hotel &#x2013; Loitering.</catch_line><url>/42.11/</url><token>42.11</token></unit><unit id="3737"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.11.1</section_number><catch_line>Depots &#x2013; Stations &#x2013; Airports &#x2013; Loitering About Prohibited.</catch_line><url>/42.11.1/</url><token>42.11.1</token></unit><unit id="2115"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.12</section_number><catch_line>Alms &#x2013; Soliciting In Buildings.</catch_line><url>/42.12/</url><token>42.12</token></unit><unit id="999"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.13</section_number><catch_line>Peddlers &#x2013; Venders &#x2013; Hours.</catch_line><url>/42.13/</url><token>42.13</token></unit><unit id="1499"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.14</section_number><catch_line>Soliciting &#x2013; Use Of City Name.</catch_line><url>/42.14/</url><token>42.14</token></unit><unit id="397"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.14.1</section_number><catch_line>Soliciting On City Property.</catch_line><url>/42.14.1/</url><token>42.14.1</token></unit><unit id="536"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.15</section_number><catch_line>Vending And Excessive Noise On Beaches Prohibited.</catch_line><url>/42.15/</url><token>42.15</token></unit><unit id="518"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.19</section_number><catch_line>Magazine Subscriptions &#x2013; Sales For Future Delivery &#x2013; Where Solicitation Prohibited.</catch_line><url>/42.19/</url><token>42.19</token></unit><unit id="3319"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.20</section_number><catch_line>Food And Drink Establishments &#x2013; Annoyance Of Customers
Forbidden.</catch_line><url>/42.20/</url><token>42.20</token></unit></structure_contents><next_section id="1898"><structure_id>21</structure_id><section_number>42.00.1</section_number><catch_line>Sales From Ice Cream Trucks.</catch_line><url>/42.00.1/</url><token>42.00.1</token></next_section><metadata></metadata><references></references><url>/42.00/</url><token>42.00</token><formats><txt>/42.00.txt</txt><json>/42.00.xml</json></formats><dublin_core><Title>Regulation Of Soliciting And Sales In Streets.</Title><Type>Text</Type><Format>text/html</Format><Identifier>&#xA7; 42.00</Identifier><Relation>Los Angeles Municipal Code</Relation></dublin_core><plain_text>                            LOS ANGELES MUNICIPAL CODE

REGULATION OF SOLICITING AND SALES IN STREETS. (&#xA7; 42.00)

&#xA0; REGULATION OF SOLICITING AND SALES IN STREETS.

	(a)	(Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)&#xA0; In this section, unless the
context or subject matter otherwise requires:

	&#x201C;News racks&#x201D; shall mean any self-service or coin-operated box, container,
storage unit or other dispenser installed, used, or maintained for the display
and sale of newspapers, news periodicals or other news publications.

	&#x201C;Newsstand&#x201D; shall mean any stand, shelter, case, cabinet, box or other
structure installed, used, or maintained for the display, sale or storage of
newspapers, news periodicals or other news publications which is attended by the
owner or his employee while making sales therefrom.
	&#x201C;Street&#x201D; shall mean all that area dedicated to public use for public street
purposes and shall include, but not be limited to roadways, parkways, alleys and
sidewalks.

	&#x201C;Roadway&#x201D; shall mean that portion of a street improved, designed, or
ordinarily used for vehicular travel.

	&#x201C;Parkway&#x201D; shall mean that area between the edge of the roadway and the
adjacent property line excluding that area occupied by the sidewalks. Parkway
shall also include any area within a roadway which is not open to vehicular
travel.

	&#x201C;Sidewalk&#x201D; shall mean any surface provided for the exclusive use of
pedestrians.

	(b)	Street Sale of Goods Prohibited.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 169,319, Eff.
2/18/94.)&#xA0; No person, except as otherwise permitted by this section, shall on
any sidewalk or street offer for sale, solicit the sale of, announce by any
means the availability of, or have in his or her possession, control or custody,
whether upon his or her person or upon some other animate or inanimate object,
any goods, wares or merchandise which the public may purchase at any time.&#xA0;
This subsection shall not apply to the sale of poppies, badges and labels as
defined by Military and Veterans Code Section 1800 on a parkway or sidewalk by
persons bearing a valid information card issued pursuant to Article 4 of this
chapter authorizing such person to do so.

	(c)	Street-Soliciting Employment of Services Prohibited.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No.
145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(1)	No person, except as otherwise permitted by this section, shall on any
street offer for sale, solicit the employment of, or announce by any means the
availability of, any goods, wares, merchandise, services or facilities, or
solicit patrons for or advertise any show, exhibition, entertainment, tour,
excursion, sight-seeing trip, or real estate viewing or inspection trip.&#xA0;
(Amended by Ord. No. 169,319, Eff. 2/18/94.)

	(2)	No person who is visible or audible to any person on any street shall, in a
loud, boisterous, raucous, offensive or insulting manner, offer for sale,
solicit the purchase of, announce the availability of, or solicit the employment
of any goods, wares, merchandise, services or facilities, or solicit patronage
for or advertise any show, exhibition, entertainment tour, excursion
sight-seeing trip, real estate, or oil well viewing or inspection trip.

	(3)	Nothing in Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be so construed as to
apply to a sight-seeing tour operating under and by virtue of a permit from and
regulations of the Public Utilities Commission of the State of California and
for which tour a fixed charge is made to the person carried.

	(d)	Street-Sidewalk &#x2013; Advertising on.&#xA0; No person shall except as otherwise
provided in Subsection (j) of this section have, bear, wear or carry upon any
street, any advertising banner, flag, board, sign, transparency, wearing apparel
or other device advertising, publicity announcing or calling attention to any
goods, wares, merchandise, or commodities, or to any place of business,
occupation, show, exhibition, event or entertainment. The provisions of this
subsection shall not apply to the wearing of apparel without remuneration for
doing so or business identification on wearing apparel. (Amended by Ord. No.
145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(e)	Streets News Venders.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(1)	No person shall sell or offer for sale any newspaper, magazine, periodical,
news publication or other printed matter while upon the roadway of any street
within the City of Los Angeles provided, however, that persons engaged in
selling or offering for sale or disposing of newspapers, news periodicals or
other news publications may sell, offer for sale, solicit the purchase of and
advertise the same upon any portion of the sidewalk or parkway, subject to
Subsections (f), (g), (h) and (j) of this section where applicable.

	(2)	No person, under the age of 10 years, shall sell or offer for sale any
newspaper, magazine, periodical, news publication or other printed matter while
upon any portion of a street. This subsection shall not prohibit persons, except
as otherwise prohibited by law, from soliciting the sale of or delivery of
newspapers, magazines, periodicals, news publications and other printed matter
to residences or places of business fronting upon a street.

	(f)	Streets &#x2013; News Racks.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 176,339, Eff. 1/19/05.)

	(1)	Definitions:&#xA0; The following words, terms and phrases, when used in the
following subsections shall have the meaning ascribed to them in this
subsection, except where the context clearly indicates a different meaning:

	(A)	&#x201C;Equivalent newsrack&#x201D; means any newsrack that is of the same size and
dimensions of the specified newsrack.

	(B)	If &#x201C;demand warrants&#x201D; or &#x201C;warranted demand&#x201D; means the measured stack
height needed to meet the newspaper publisher&#x2019;s or distributor&#x2019;s peak daily
distribution at the requested newsrack location, as proven to the Board by the
newspaper publisher or distributor, exceeds (14) inches.

	(C)	&#x201C;Individual newsrack&#x201D; means and includes a newsrack designed with a
single enclosed compartment to accommodate at any one time the display, sale, or
free distribution of like copies of a single newspaper or other publication, or
which has more than one (1) compartment and complies with the dimensions of an
individual newsrack as provided in Subsection (7)(B).

	(D)	&#x201C;Newsrack&#x201D; or &#x201C;News Rack&#x201D; means any unstaffed, self-service, free,
or coin-operated box, container, storage unit or other dispenser located in or
upon, or projecting onto, or over, any part of the public right-of-way, and
which is installed, used or maintained for the display, sale, or free
distribution of newspapers and other publications.

	(E)	&#x201C;Modular newsrack&#x201D; means a newsrack which is designed with separate
enclosed compartments to accommodate at any one time the display, sale or free
distribution of multiple distinct and separate newspapers or other publications,
and which exceeds the dimensions of an individual newsrack as provided in
Subsection (7)(B).

	(F)	&#x201C;Modular newsrack provider&#x201D; means the person or other legal entity that
is authorized under Subsection (4)(A)(7) to place and maintain modular newsracks
upon the public right-of-way.

	(G)	&#x201C;Publisher&#x201D; means the person or other legal entity selling, displaying,
or distributing free newspapers or other publications in a newsrack.

	(H)	&#x201C;News-Stand/Kiosk&#x201D; means any stand, shelter, or other structure
installed, used, or maintained for the display, sale or storage of newspapers,
news periodicals or other news publications.

	(I)	&#x201C;Public right-of-way&#x201D; means any public street, sidewalk, parkway, alley
or other location owned or otherwise controlled by the City for the benefit of
the general public.

	(J)	&#x201C;Block face&#x201D; means the sidewalk on one side of a street, between one
intersection and the immediately adjacent intersection.&#xA0;

	(2)	Purpose and Criteria:&#xA0; The purpose of the following Subsections is to
promote the public health, safety, and general welfare of the citizens and
visitors to the City through the regulation of placement, type, appearance, and
maintenance of newsracks on public rights-of-way so as to:

	(A)	Provide for pedestrian and driver safety and convenience.

	(B)	Restrict unreasonable interference with the flow of pedestrian or vehicular
traffic, including, but not limited to, ingress into and egress from any
residence or place of business, or from the street to the sidewalk, or from the
sidewalk to the street by persons exiting or entering parked or standing
vehicles.

	(C)	Provide for the safety of the general public and property during emergency
conditions.

	(D)	Provide reasonable access for the use and maintenance of poles, posts,
traffic signs and/or signals, hydrants, mailboxes, and access to locations used
for public transportation purposes.

	(E)	Allow for the placement and maintenance of modular newsracks in the modular
newsrack areas, as determined by the City Council, to be placed in locations
throughout the city which afford easy, convenient service to pedestrians, but do
not obstruct or interfere with access to abutting properties, and which do not
impede or endanger pedestrian, bicycle, or vehicular traffic.

	(F)	Relocate and/or replace or remove newsracks which result in visual blight
and/or are not installed according to this code on the public rights-of-way or
which block or interfere with the aesthetics of store window displays, adjacent
businesses, landscaping, street furniture, public or private, and other
improvements as well as to allow the removal of abandoned newsracks.

	(G)	Maintain and protect the values of surrounding properties, and ensure that
the aesthetics and historical attributes of adjacent businesses are not
compromised by the unregulated placement of newsracks in the public
right-of-way.

	(H)	Reduce unnecessary exposure of the public to personal injury or property
damage.

	(I)	Maintain and preserve freedom of the press to distribute periodicals and
newspapers.

	(J)	Reduce visual blight and improve the aesthetic appearance of the City&#x2019;s
streets and sidewalks for the merchants, citizens and visitors to the City by
coordinating the uniform color of all newsracks with the color of the City&#x2019;s
extensive multi-million dollar street furniture program; and in Specific Plan
Areas, Streetscape Plan Areas or other Special Planning Districts, which have a
standard streetscape color, to allow for a uniform newsrack color from a limited
palate of colors in order to coordinate the color of newsracks with their
streetscape.

	(3)	Compliance Phase In:

	(A)	The provisions of this subdivision shall apply to all newsracks, whether
installed and maintained prior to or after the effective date of this ordinance
which in whole or in part rests upon, in, or over any dedicated sidewalk,
right-of-way or parkway.&#xA0; Those newsracks installed prior to the effective date
of this revised ordinance shall be brought into compliance with the all
provisions of this code, except uniform color, as this revised ordinance is
implemented by Street Services, area by area, within the City.&#xA0; In no event
shall compliance be later than 12 months after the effective date hereof, except
that, if the City&#x2019;s implementation schedule takes longer than 12 months, then
compliance by the publishers shall follow the City&#x2019;s implementation
schedule.&#xA0; If a publisher chooses not to come into compliance with the uniform
color requirement of this ordinance at the time it obtains a valid permit and
legally places its newsracks as required by the City&#x2019;s implementation
schedule, then compliance with the uniform color requirement must be
accomplished no later than 24 months after the effective date of this
ordinance.&#xA0; However, Publishers experiencing financial hardship, solely due to
compliance with LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f) as it applies to uniform color, may request
the Board to approve one 12-month extension allowing them a total of 36 months
to come into full compliance with the uniform color requirement of the Newsrack
Ordinance, if evidence of financial hardship is proven to the satisfaction of
the Board.&#xA0; Any newsrack not brought into compliance within the aforementioned
time period shall be deemed to be in violation of LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f).

	(4)	Permit Required:&#xA0; No person shall install or maintain any newsrack upon
any public right-of-way without first applying for and receiving a permit from
the City&#x2019;s Board of Public Works, herein after referred to as &#x201C;Board&#x201D;.&#xA0; A
permit will not be issued unless the application is completed in full, the
requested installation meets all the appropriate placement criteria as set forth
below, and the application is accompanied by the appropriate permit fee for the
type of newsrack, single, pedestal, or modular, for each individual newsrack
installation requested.&#xA0; Any permit granted pursuant to the provisions of this
code shall only be valid as to the specific location specified in the permit
application.&#xA0; Where application is made for the installation of two or more
single newsracks, a separate permit shall be required for each individual
newsrack.&#xA0; Upon this revised ordinance taking legal effect in the City of Los
Angeles, any owner of a newsrack currently existing on any City right-of-way
must apply for a permit pursuant to this ordinance within the time specified by
the Board of Public Works in its Rules and Regulations for the implementation of
this ordinance.&#xA0; Any newsrack which is not the subject of a valid permit
application as required by the City&#x2019;s implementation Rules and Regulations
will be deemed to be in violation of 42.00 (f) of this code and subject to
removal from the right-of-way as set forth herein.

	(A)	Permit Application.&#xA0; Permit applications shall be in writing and on forms
as provided by the Board.&#xA0; The permit application shall include the following
information:

	(1)	The name, address, and telephone number of the applicant who is the owner
and/or principal responsible for the newsrack.

	(2)	The name, address, and telephone number of a responsible person whom the
City may notify or contact at any time concerning the applicant&#x2019;s newsrack(s).

	(3)	The specified number of newsracks and the detailed proposed location for
each one, shown on a drawing of the location, or GIS/Address based program
provided by applicant which is compatible with the City&#x2019;s GIS program and
which indicates all existing buildings, existing newsracks at the location and
general vicinity, and all other possible obstructions within 20 feet of the
proposed location of the newsrack.

	(4)	Names of newspaper(s) or periodical(s) to be placed in each newsrack.&#xA0; One
or more newspapers or periodicals may be dispensed from a single newsrack if the
newsrack is manufactured for this purpose.

	(5)	Type or brand of newsrack, including an illustration and description of the
newsrack and mount, if other than a single pedestal, size of base plate and
whether the newsrack will have a coin-box attachment, or equivalent.

	(6)	A sworn statement under penalty of perjury, executed by an officer,
director, or authorized agent of the applicant, agreeing that the applicant
shall not sell, assign, or transfer by any method, the permit for the newsrack
location to any other publisher, distributor, entity or individual.

	(7)	The Board, with Council approval, may designate areas of the City where
only modular newsracks may be installed and maintained by a City vendor such as
the City Hall Historical District, (the east block face on Spring Street between
Temple Street and 1st Street, the south block face of Temple Street between
Spring Street and Main Street, the west block face of Main Street between Temple
Street and 1st Street, and the north block face of 1st Street between Spring
Street and Main Street).&#xA0; No application for an individual newsrack permit may
be submitted in a modular newsrack area. Upon the effective date of this
ordinance, the total number of compartments in modular newsracks in any
designated modular newsrack area, shall be substantially equivalent to the
highest total number of individual newsracks known to have been legally
maintained on the public right-of-way in the modular newsrack areas at any one
time during the year preceding the introduction of this amended ordinance but in
no event more than the total number of newsracks allowed by subparagraph (F)(4)
below.

	(8)	Such other information as, from time to time, may be required by the Board.

	(B)	Expiration &#x2013; Renewal.&#xA0; Unless earlier revoked, newsrack permits issued
pursuant to the provisions of this code shall expire on the 30th day of August
following the date upon which each such permit is granted.&#xA0; Such permits may
thereafter be renewed annually upon the payment of the fee hereinafter
prescribed.&#xA0; Applications for renewal shall be made at least 30 days prior to
the expiration of any permit issued, and must be accompanied by a permit renewal
fee as set forth in Subsection (4)(C), below.&#xA0; Application for permit renewal
and payment must be either presented in person to the Bureau of Street Services,
via the Internet (if available), or mailed via certified mail, postmarked no
later than 30 days prior to the date of permit expiration.&#xA0; Failure to renew an
existing newsrack permit before its expiration will require the payment of a
late renewal penalty as set forth in Subsection (4)(C), below, or the loss of
the placement of the said rack at the subject location.

	(C)	Fees.&#xA0; The Board shall establish all fees, in accordance with the level of
enforcement deemed appropriate by the Council, and shall only be used to defray
the total expenses of operation of the newsrack program including: permitting,
inspection, administration, and enforcement, required by this Ordinance as set
forth in the preceding and following sections of this code.&#xA0; The Initial Permit
Fee, the Renewal Permit Fee, the Site Inspection Fee, the Site Re-Inspection
Fee, Late Renewal Penalty Fee, Impound Fees, and the Bar Code Decal Replacement
Fee shall be determined and adopted from time to time by the Board.

	(D)	Insurance.

	(1)	Requirement-Content.&#xA0; As a condition of the City granting any person or
persons one or more permits to maintain a newsrack or newsracks in the public
right-of-way, any such permittee shall be required to maintain a policy of
general liability insurance, naming the City of Los Angeles, the Board of Public
Works and its employees, agents etc. as &#x201C;Additional Insureds&#x201D; for the
specific purpose of indemnifying and holding harmless the City of Los Angeles,
its officers, boards, employees, etc. from and against any and all losses,
costs, damages, expenses, or liability, whatsoever, which may result from or
arise out of the granting of a permit, and/or the installation and/or the
maintenance of any newsrack or newsracks for which the permittee shall be
responsible for paying any and all losses or damages that may be sustained by
any person or persons as a result of, or which may be caused by or arise out of
the installation and/or maintenance of the permitted newsrack or newsracks.&#xA0;
The policy of insurance shall be maintained in its original amount by the
permittee at permittee&#x2019;s expense at all times during the period for which the
permittee holds a valid permit or permits.&#xA0; Should said policy be called upon
to satisfy any liability for damages covered by said policy, the policy must be
of such a nature that the original amount of coverage is restored after any
payment of damages by the policy.&#xA0; In the event that two or more permits are
issued to one permittee, the permittee shall only be required to maintain a
single policy of insurance covering all such permits held by the permittee in
the amount set forth below for the number of newsracks maintained by the
permittee.

	(2)	Required Limits of Liability Insurance.&#xA0; The Board shall be responsible,
from time to time, for adopting the limits of liability insurance required to be
maintained by newsrack permittees under this code.&#xA0; The Board shall receive a
recommendation from the City&#x2019;s Risk Manager prior to setting the limits of
liability insurance based on the number of racks that each permittee maintains
in the City&#x2019;s right-of-way.

	(E)	Every person who installs, uses or maintains any newsrack which in whole or
in part rests upon, in, or over any dedicated sidewalk or parkway shall have his
or her name, address and telephone number affixed thereto at a place where such
information may be easily seen, in addition to a bar code decal issued by the
Board for that specific newsrack.

	(5)	Prohibited Where Vehicles Permitted:&#xA0; No person shall install or maintain
any newsrack which projects onto, into or over any part of the roadway of any
public street, or which rests, wholly or in part, upon, along or over any
portion of such roadway.

	(6)	Unlawful Obstructions:&#xA0; No person shall install, use or maintain any
newsrack:

	(A)	Within 5 feet of any marked crosswalk;

	(B)	Within 5 feet of the curb return of any unmarked crosswalk;

	(C)	Within 5 feet of any fire hydrant, fire call box or other emergency
facility;

	(D)	Within 5 feet ahead and 45 feet to the rear of any sign marking a
designated bus stop.&#xA0; No newsrack shall be installed within the marked bus
zone;

	(E)	Within 5 feet of any bus bench.

	(F)	Within 10 feet of any transit shelter.&#xA0;

	(G)	In front of an entrance to a business, including the curb area directly
across from such entrance where the distance between the entry door and the
newsrack is less than 10 feet;

	(H)	In any location used, marked or posted for public utility purpose, public
transportation purpose or government use;

	(I)	Where placement unreasonably interferes with the use of poles, posts,
traffic signs or signals, mail boxes or other objects legally permitted, but in
no event shall the newsrack be closer than one foot from such objects;

	(J)	Where placement interferes with the reasonable use or utility for display
purposes of any display window of any building abutting the sidewalk or parkway,
but in no event within 4 feet of such window;

	(K)	Within 5 feet of any area improved with lawn, flowers shrubs, trees or
street tree well;

	(L)	Within 5 feet of any driveway or driveway apron;

	(M)	Within 4 feet of any outdoor dining areas or patio dining areas;

	(N)	Within 20 feet of both sides of buildings officially designated Los Angeles
Historical or Cultural Monuments.&#xA0; If there is a block in which all buildings
have been so officially designated, then the Board, in consultation with the
Cultural Heritage Commission, shall determine siting on such block face for up
to four (4) newsracks.&#xA0; An owner of a building which has been designated as a
Historical or Cultural Monument may petition the Board of Public Works to allow
newsracks on the sidewalks in front of their building if the placement of such
newsracks will not interfere with Historic or Cultural nature of the building.&#xA0;
The Board shall listen to evidence from all interested parties and make its
determination based on the totality of the evidence.

	(O)	Within 20 feet of both sides of visual public art work created, funded or
managed through the City&#x2019;s Municipal Art Program including, but not limited
to, murals, sculptures and fountains.

	(P)	Where placement impedes the flow of pedestrian traffic by reducing the
clear space to less than 6 feet or, impedes access to or the use of abutting
property, including, but not limited to, residences and places of business.

	(Q)	Notwithstanding any other paragraph of this subdivision, no person shall
install, use or maintain any newsrack where placement endangers the safety of
persons or property.

	(R)	No newsrack shall be installed within 4 feet from any permanently installed
structure in the public Right-of-Way, which is not otherwise specifically
identified in this subdivision.

	(S)	Within one foot of any utility cover, vent screen or other object that is
flush mounted with the sidewalk, except that if the owner or person in control
of the below grade sidewalk installation needs additional space for emergency or
non-routine maintenance of the installation, any newsrack(s) which interferes
with such maintenance may be requested to be temporarily removed to accommodate
the required maintenance and then be reinstalled.

	(T)	Within 4 feet to the front and 10 feet to the rear of any parking meter and
where there are no parking meters on the curb, 10 feet from the front of any
marked parallel parking place.

	(7)	Size, Appearance, Placement, Installation and Construction of Newsracks:

	(A)	 Every newsrack shall be maintained in a neat and clean condition and be in
good repair at all times.

	(B)	All newsracks shall be permanently mounted, except as provided in
Subsection (7)(C), in accordance with specifications established by the Board as
provided in Subsection (9) and adopted from time to time as revisions become
necessary, including but not limited to: style, construction, coating, material
and fabrication.&#xA0; Specifications for a newsrack shall be:

	(1)	Street tube pedestal, at least four inches by three inches in height;

	(2)	Overall height shall not be less than 46 inches and shall not exceed 52
inches; the overall width shall not be less than 20 inches and shall not exceed
30 inches; and the overall depth shall not be less than 12 inches and shall not
exceed 20 inches.

	(3)	All newsracks shall be primarily constructed of metal and shall be &#x201C;Ivy
Green&#x201D; in color (Tiger RAL 607 SM, Glossy, Code 28-50081), except as provided
in &#xA7; 42.00 (f)(17) &#x201C;Specific Plan/Street Scape Plan Areas&#x201D;.

	(C)	Special Purpose Sidewalks; No Permanent Attachments.&#xA0; Each individual
newsrack which is permitted to be placed on a special purpose sidewalk, such as
terrazzo, brick, glass prism implanted, or where basements are located under the
sidewalk, shall be on legs and shall be mobile and not affixed to the sidewalk
in any way.

	(D)	Pedestals.&#xA0; No pedestals shall be maintained on a public right-of-way
unless there is attached thereto a newsrack case as provided herein.

	(E)	Removal of Newsracks; Repair of Sidewalks.&#xA0; Upon the removal of any
newsrack, the person so removing shall be responsible for the repair of any
resulting condition, including filling in of any holes left in the sidewalk
and/or the removal of any bolts or other devices used to affix the newsrack to
the sidewalk such that there are no obstructions sticking above the grade of the
sidewalk.&#xA0; Such work is to be done to the satisfaction of the Department of
Public Works.

	(F)	Newsrack Location.

	(1)	Newsracks shall only be situated near a curb with the back of said newsrack
situated not less than 18 inches nor more than 24 inches from the edge of the
curb.&#xA0; If it is physically impossible to situate a newsrack near a curb, then
the Board may authorize the placement of up to four (4) newsracks adjacent to
the wall of a building on that block.&#xA0; If the newsrack is placed adjacent to
the wall of a building, the back of said newsrack shall be situated parallel to
and not more than 6 inches from such wall.&#xA0; No newsrack shall be installed,
used or maintained on any sidewalk or parkway opposite a newsstand or other
newsrack.

	(2)	Except as otherwise provided by this code, no newsrack placed on the public
right-of-way shall be chained, bolted or otherwise attached to any property or
to any permanently fixed object.

	(3)	Not more than four newsracks shall be placed immediately adjacent to each
other.&#xA0; Any such group of up to four newsracks shall be separated by a space of
not less than 48 inches from any other individual newsrack or group of
newsracks.

	(4)	Not more than 16 newsracks shall be placed within 200 ft. of the same block
face.&#xA0; However, the Board may establish a number greater or less than 16 in any
specific block face by conducting an engineering study.&#xA0; In cases where a block
face is longer than 200 ft., for every additional 50 ft. of block face greater
than 200 ft., an additional four (4) newsracks may be installed.

	(5)	Not more than one permit for installation of a newsrack shall be issued for
each publication on one side of a block or within 200 ft. of the same block
face, whichever is less. One publication includes: differing geographic editions
of the same publication (Orange County edition; Valley edition, etc.); and daily
and Sunday editions of the same publication.&#xA0; In cases where a block face is
longer than 200 ft., and there is space to legally install additional newsracks,
then a permit for one publication to install a second newsrack on the same block
face may be issued by the Board.

	(6)	Newsracks shall not be permitted on the public right-of-way adjacent to any
property that is zoned exclusively for single-family residential use (R-1).

	(G)	Priorities Related to Placement of Newsracks.

	(1)	In determining in what order newsrack permittees may select their location
on a particular block face during implementation of this revised newsrack
ordinance, and in particular where there are more requests for newsrack spaces
on any one block face than there are legal spaces available, the Board of Public
Works shall, pursuant to its authority under paragraph (9) below, develop a
content neutral criteria for determining the placement of newsracks applicable
to each block face.

	(2)	Once this revised newsrack ordinance has been fully implemented citywide,
all subsequent newsrack permits shall be issued on a first come first served
basis.

	(8)	Unlawful Use:&#xA0; No newsrack shall be used for advertising signs or
publicity purposes. External lettering is restricted to the following:

	(A)	If the newsrack is situated next to the curb, the side parallel to the
curb, next to the lanes of traffic, may have external lettering replicating the
publication masthead style and color, for the permitted publication in the
subject newsrack, in a total area not to exceed 144 square inches.

	If an individual newsrack is used to distribute more than one publication, each
publication distributed in that newsrack shall be entitled to have external
lettering replicating the publication masthead style and color for the permitted
publications in the subject newsrack.&#xA0; However, the total area for all such
publication mastheads on that newsrack shall not exceed 144 square inches.

	(B)	The side of the newsrack facing pedestrian traffic, except in Specific
Plan/Streetscape Plan Areas, as identified in Section (17), may have a &#x201C;Rack
Card&#x201D;, with a total area not to exceed 238 square inches, which exclusively
advertises the newspaper or periodical being dispensed, and shall not include
any third party advertising.&#xA0; This &#x201C;Rack Card&#x201D; shall be located in the area
immediately below the hood on the front access side of the newsrack.

	(C)	Other than as permitted in this section, no other lettering or advertising
of any kind shall be permitted anywhere else on the newsrack, including the
mount.

	(9)	Authority of the Board of Public Works to Promulgate Rules and Regulations
for the Permitting, Installation and Maintenance of the Newsracks in the Public
Right-of-Way:&#xA0; Consistent with the intent and requirements of LAMC &#xA7; 42.00
(f), et seq., the Board may adopt rules and regulations to administer the
installation, placement, maintenance, size and material used for construction of
newsracks.&#xA0; The Board may adopt any other rule and/or regulation for the
protection of public safety, welfare, or property relative to permitting,
installation, and maintenance of newsracks.&#xA0; Prior to adoption of any rules
and/or regulations, the Board shall hold a public hearing.&#xA0; Once any rules
and/or regulations are adopted, they shall be kept posted in the Board office
and a copy thereof shall be furnished to any applicant for a newsrack permit.

	(10)	Noncompliance With LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f), et seq.; Tagging of Newsracks:&#xA0;
Except as provided in Subsection (12) hereof, whenever any newsrack is found to
be in violation of any Subsection of LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f), the Board shall cause a
notice tag to be attached to said newsrack specifying the date and nature of the
violation, and shall E-mail or fax to the permittee a copy of the violation.&#xA0;
Permittee shall within ten (10) calendar days from the date on which the tag was
attached, either cause the violation to be corrected or request a hearing
pursuant to Subsection (13) hereof.&#xA0; If a hearing is requested, staff will not
remove the non compliant newsrack until a final determination by the Board.
However, if a newsrack installed within the City right-of-way has no visible
evidence that it has been properly permitted (no City issued bar code decal, no
visible contact information for the owner or no other evidence that would
indicate that a valid permit for the newsrack had been issued) staff may
confiscate the offending newsrack and follow the procedures in subparagraph
(11)(B) below.&#xA0; There is hereby created a presumption that any newsrack within
the City&#x2019;s right-of-way that does not have a city bar code decal, or visible
identification and contact information for the owner of the newsrack, has been
installed without a valid permit.

	(A)	A newsrack may be tagged for any violation of any requirement of LAMC &#xA7;
42.00 (f) including, but not limited to, the following:

	(1)	Where its installation, use or maintenance unreasonably interferes with or
impedes the flow of vehicular or pedestrian traffic;

	(2)	Where its installation, use or maintenance interferes with the use of
poles, posts, traffic signs or signals, hydrants, mailboxes or other objects
legally permitted;

	(3)	Where its installation, use or maintenance unreasonably obstructs,
interferes with or impedes access to or the use of abutting property, including,
but not limited to, residences, places of business, or legally parked or stopped
vehicles;

	(4)	When such newsrack does not have a name, address and telephone number
affixed in a place where such information may be easily seen and the designee of
such newsrack cannot be otherwise identified;

	(5)	When a newsrack is found in the public right-of-way which does not have a
visible, city issued, bar code decal present indicating the correct permit
number of the newsrack or the newsrack has no valid permit at all; and

	(6)	When a newsrack is found in the public right-of-way which is not maintained
in a neat and clean condition and in good repair, in accordance with the
following Maintenance Specifications:

	(a)	The newsrack permittee shall maintain all newsracks and the sidewalk
surface immediately under and adjacent (within 2 feet) to the newsracks in a
safe, clean, attractive and sanitary condition and in good order and repair, as
determined by the Department of Public Works, Bureau of Street Services
(BOSS).&#xA0; The permittee shall make routine inspection and maintenance calls on
each newsrack once a week.&#xA0; Such inspection and maintenance calls may be
incorporated with delivery of newspapers or other publications.&#xA0; The permittee
shall make more frequent calls if conditions warrant.&#xA0; At each maintenance
call, the permittee shall clean, wash and remove all graffiti, stickers,
posters, litter, dust, dirt and weeds at each newsrack.&#xA0; The newsrack shall be
maintained in a continual good and working condition.

	(b)	Maintenance &#x2013; Permittee shall respond to a request to secure a site or to
perform maintenance within 24 hours of notification, but in no event more than
72 hours.&#xA0; The permittee shall use cleaning methods and procedures that have
been demonstrated and approved and are environmentally safe, utilizing
acceptable industry practices.

	(c)	Repair and Replacement &#x2013; The Permittee shall commence necessary repairs
within one week when any damage or vandalism is found by BOSS.&#xA0; If the newsrack
damage or vandalism is of an emergency or hazardous nature, the permittee will
repair, replace, remove or secure the site within 24 hours of notification.&#xA0; If
the newsrack is totally destroyed because of an accident, the Permittee will
remove the newsrack and appurtenant structures within 24 hours, including repair
of any damage to the public right-of- way, returning the site to its former
condition prior to the newsrack installation.

	(d)	Graffiti Removal &#x2013; Permittee will upon notification by BOSS, or upon
inspection, remove graffiti within 24 hours from any newsrack.&#xA0;

	(11)	Impounding of Newsracks:

	(A)	Notwithstanding the Department&#x2019;s right to tag newsracks in violation of
any Subsection on LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f), the Department may cause any newsrack to be
impounded:

	(1)	When the newsrack poses an immediate danger to persons or vehicles;

	(2)	Where its installation, use or maintenance endangers the safety of persons
or property;

	(3)	When pursuant to Subsection (10), a tag has been attached to a newsrack and
a written notice, such as fax, letter or E-mail has been sent to the owner,
operator, or responsible person for the newsrack and the designee has neither
caused the violation specified on said tag to be corrected nor requested a
hearing pursuant to Subsection (14), hereof within the time permitted;

	(4)	When a hearing and appeal, if filed, have resulted in a final determination
that the violation(s) specified on the tag attached to such newsrack has in fact
occurred, and the designee has failed to correct such violation(s) within ten
(10) calendar days from the date of said determination;

	(5)	When a request for a hearing or appeal has been withdrawn, such request
shall be deemed withdrawn, either by actual withdrawal or by the failure of the
designee to fully comply with Subsection (14) of this code;

	(6)	When such newsrack has been abandoned; and

	(7)	When such newsrack has been installed on the City&#x2019;s right-of-way without
first applying for and receiving a permit as required by this code.

	Pursuant to this Subsection, a newsrack shall be deemed abandoned when it does
not contain the newspaper or other publication specified therefor for more than
four (4) consecutive days for a daily publication, eight (8) consecutive days
for a weekly publication, sixteen (16) consecutive days for a biweekly
publication, or thirty-four (34) days for a monthly publication.&#xA0; A newsstand
shall be deemed abandoned if it is not open for a period of more than seven (7)
consecutive days.

	(B)	Standard impound procedures:&#xA0; Within forty-eight (48) hours after removal
of any newsrack, the Board shall notify the owner in writing, fax or E-mail of
the removal and the reason for removal where ownership information is posted on
the newsrack either through the City bar code decal or the required owner
contact information.&#xA0; If ownership information is not readily available because
there is no City bar code decal, or ownership identification information posted
on the newsrack, or no newspaper or periodical in the newsrack with contact
information, the City shall make every reasonable effort to comply with the
notification procedure of this subsection.&#xA0; When notification is possible, the
notice shall also inform the owner of the right to request, either in writing or
in person, within five (5) business days of the date of the postmark of such
written notice, a hearing by the Board or its designee pursuant to Subsection
(14), to determine whether such removal was proper.

	(12)	Return of Impounded Newsracks:

	(A)	Any newsrack, together with its contents, which has been impounded pursuant
to Subdivision (11) hereof, shall be returned to the permittee:

	(1)	Upon receipt of an impound fee as determined herein; or

	(2)	Upon a determination after hearing by the Board or its designee, pursuant
to Subsection (14) hereof, that the newsrack should not have been impounded and
should be returned to the permittee;

	(B)	In the event a hearing has not been requested pursuant to Subsection (14)
within the time permitted following the impoundment of any newsrack, an impound
fee as set forth herein shall be imposed upon the permittee and shall be paid
before the impounded newsrack is returned.

	(C)	The fees herein shall be determined and adopted by the Board in order to
collect sufficient money to defer the complete cost of the City&#x2019;s newsrack
permitting and enforcement program as set forth in this code.&#xA0; The fees shall
be adjusted from time to time by the Board to reflect any change in the cost of
permitting and enforcement.&#xA0; At no time shall the fees adopted by the Board
recover more than the actual cost of the program.

	(13)	Sale or Disposal After Impoundment:&#xA0; The Department may sell or otherwise
dispose of any newsrack, together with its contents, and retain the proceeds,
pursuant to California Government Code Section 50050 et seq., from any such sale
or other disposition, and any monies contained in said newsrack at the time of
its impoundment, provided that either:

	(A)	No hearing has been requested pursuant to Subsection (14) within the time
permitted;

	(B)	A hearing and an appeal, if filed, have resulted in a final determination
that said newsrack was properly impounded, and fees assessed pursuant to
Subsection (12) have not been received within thirty (30) days from the date of
the final determination.

	(14)	Hearings:

	(A)	Request for Hearing &#x2013; Any newsrack permittee may file a written request
with the Department for a hearing, in person or by certified mail, for the
purpose of demonstrating that a newsrack should not have been impounded, or that
a violation as specified on the tag attached to a newsrack pursuant to
Subsection (10) hereof has not in fact occurred.

	(B)	Notice of Hearing &#x2013; Within two (2) working days from the date on which
the request for hearing is received, the Department shall set a hearing date and
shall notify the designee by certified mail of the date, time and place of said
hearing.&#xA0; Said hearing shall occur within ten (10) working days of the date of
mailing the notice unless the person requesting the hearing wishes to have the
hearing at a later date, and both parties agree on the date.

	(C)	Conduct of Hearing &#x2013; At the time set for such hearing, or at the date to
which such hearing is continued, the Board or its designee shall receive all
evidence relevant to the occurrence or non-occurrence of the specified
violation(s), the compliance or noncompliance with any of the provisions of this
Subsection, and any other relevant information.&#xA0; Such hearing need not be
conducted according to technical rules relating to evidence and witnesses.&#xA0;
Oral evidence shall be taken only on oath or affirmation.

	(D)	Decision after Hearing &#x2013; Within ten (10) working days after the
conclusion of the hearing, the Board or its designee shall find and determine,
from the facts adduced at said hearing, whether the newsrack should have been
tagged and/or impounded, and whether said newsrack shall be returned except upon
receipt of fees as specified in Subsection (12). The decision of the Board or
its designee shall be in writing and shall contain findings of fact, a
determination of the issues presented, and the amount of the fee, if any, to be
imposed.

	(E)	Notice of Decision &#x2013; The Department shall send to the designee, by
certified mail, a copy of its decision and order.

	(15)	No Criminal Sanctions:&#xA0; Notwithstanding any provision of Subsection 11.00
(m) of this Code, no person shall be subject to the imposition of criminal
liability for any violation of LAMC &#xA7; 42.00 (f).

	(16)	No Newsrack Areas &#x2013; Regional Historic or Cultural Significance:

	(A)	No newsrack shall be installed in an area deemed by the City Cultural
Heritage Commission and the City Council to be of municipal or regional historic
significance or regional cultural significance, including any of the following
locations:

	(1)	On the Hollywood Walk of Fame (both sides of Hollywood Boulevard between La
Brea Avenue and Gower Street, and both sides of Vine Street between Yucca Street
and Sunset Boulevard);

	(2)	On the sidewalks immediately contiguous to the restored City Hall (the east
block face on Spring Street between Temple Street and 1st Street, the south
block face of Temple Street between Spring Street and Main Street, the west
block face of Main Street between Temple Street and 1st Street, and the north
block face of 1st Street between Spring Street and Main Street);

	(3)	El Pueblo de Los Angeles (Olvera Street, the east block face of Main Street
between Cesar Chavez Avenue and Aliso Street, the south block of Cesar Chavez
between Main Street and Alameda Street, the west block face of Alameda Street
between Cesar Chavez Avenue and Aliso Street, and the north block face of Aliso
Street between Main Street and Alameda Street);

	(4)	On the sidewalks immediately contiguous to Disney Hall (the east block face
of Hope Street between 1st Street and Upper 2nd Street; the west south block
face of 1st Street between Hope Avenue and Grand Avenue; the west block face of
Grand Avenue between 1st Street and Upper 2nd Street; and the north block face
of Upper 2nd Street between Hope Avenue and Grand Avenue); or

	(5)	On the sidewalks on the block faces immediately to the west and east of the
Music Center and Dorothy Chandler Pavilion (the west block face of Grand Avenue
between 1st Street and Temple Street; and the east block face of Hope Street
between 1st Street and Temple Street).

	(6)	On the Venice Boardwalk (both sides of Ocean Front Walk between Navy Street
on the north and Venice Pier/Washington Boulevard on the south).

	(7)	On the sidewalks of the Westwood Village Broxton Avenue Promenade (both
sides of Broxton Avenue between Le Conte Avenue and Kinross Avenue).

	(B)	In the event an area of the City which is deemed by the City Cultural
Heritage Commission and the City Council to be of municipal regional historic
significance, such an area may apply to the Board for designation as an area
where no newsracks shall be installed, subject to the approval of the City
Council.

	(17)	Specific Plan/Streetscape Plan Areas:&#xA0; Specific Plan Areas, Streetscape
Plan Areas, or other Special Planning Districts approved by the Planning
Department, which include a standard streetscape color, may request a uniform
newsrack color other than Ivy Green, from the Board, with Council input, and if
granted, the color shall be one of the following three colors: black (RAL 9017
&#x201C;Grotto Black&#x201D;), blue (Benjamin Moore No. 805 &#x201C;Westwood Blue&#x201D;) or gray
(Marine Silver 38/90010).

	(18)	Severability:&#xA0; If any section or subsection of this ordinance is deemed
to be void or unenforceable, such shall be severed from the whole and the
remaining portions of the ordinance shall remain in full force and effect.

	(g)	Streets &#x2013; Newsstands.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(1)	No person shall install, use or maintain any newsstand which projects onto,
into or over any part of the roadway of any public street, or which rests,
wholly or in part, upon, along or over any portion of the roadway of any street.

	(2)	No person shall install, use or maintain any newsstand which in whole or in
part rests upon, in or over any sidewalk or parkway when such installation, use
or maintenance endangers the safety of persons or property, or when such site or
location is used for public utility purposes, public transportation purposes or
other governmental use, or when such newsstand unreasonably interferes with or
impedes the flow of pedestrian or vehicular traffic, the ingress into or the
egress from any residence or place of business, or the use of poles, posts,
traffic signs or signals, hydrants, mailboxes, or other objects permitted at or
near said locations.

	(3)	Any newsstand which in whole or in part rests upon, in or over any sidewalk
or parkway, shall comply with the following standards:

	(A)	No newsstand shall exceed five feet in height, seventy-five inches in width
and three feet in depth, except that if erected parallel and adjacent to the
wall of a building, it shall not extend over that area of the sidewalk or
parkway by more than twenty inches, shall not exceed a length of fifty feet, or
a height of eight feet.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(B)	Except for a newsstand erected adjacent to the wall of a building, no
newsstand shall be placed less than twelve inches nor more than eighteen inches
from the edge of the curb.

	(C)	No newsstand shall be placed or maintained on the sidewalk or parkway
opposite another newsstand.

	(D)	No seat, chair, rack, case, canopy, awning, overhang, or other object shall
be attached to the exterior of any newsstand, nor shall any such object when
attached to any part of a newsstand be permitted to extend beyond its exterior
wall.

	(E)	No newsstand shall be so placed that the clear space for the passage of
pedestrians upon the sidewalk and parkway is reduced to less than six feet.

	(F)	Newsstands shall be soundly constructed of wood, metal or other suitable
permanent material, painted in a manner and color as prescribed by the Board of
Public Works, and maintained at all times, in a clean, neat and attractive
condition and in good repair and, as to the Central Traffic District, as defined
in Section 80.00 of this Code, such newsstands shall be of design and
construction approved by the Department of Cultural Affairs.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord.
No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(G)	No newsstand shall be used for advertising signs or publicity purposes
other than that dealing with the display, sale or purchase of newspapers or new
periodicals.

	(H)	No newsstand shall be placed within three feet of any area improved with
lawn, flowers, shrubs or trees or within three feet of any display window of any
building abutting the street or in such manner as to impede or interfere with
the reasonable use of such window for display purposes.

	(I)	No newsstand shall be utilized for the sale, or offer for sale, nor for the
display for sale, of any article or item other than newspapers, magazines,
periodicals and other similar newsprint publications.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No.
161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(J)	Newsstands, in the Central Traffic District, as defined by Section 80.00 of
this Code, shall be open and utilized for business at least six hours a day,
five days a week and the holder of the permit shall be present at the newsstand
and operating it himself or herself seventy-five percent (75%) of the time it is
open, or thirty (30) hours a week, whichever is less. Waivers of such
requirement may be granted by the Board of Public Works for good cause.&#xA0; (Added
by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(4)	Every person placing or maintaining a newsstand on the streets of the City
of Los Angeles shall have affixed thereto in a place readily visible to the
public a telephone number or postal box number where the owner may be reached.

	(5)	(Amended by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)&#xA0; No person shall install, use
or maintain any newsstand which in whole or in part rests upon, in, or over any
dedicated sidewalk or parkway in the Central Traffic District, as defined by
Section 80.00 of this Code, without first applying for and obtaining a permit
from the Department. The issuance of such permit shall be subject to the
provisions of this subdivision.

	(A)	Forms for Permit &#x2013; The Department shall prescribe and make available
permit application forms. The applicant shall submit to the Department a
completed form, on which the following information shall have been entered:

	(i)	The name, address and telephone number of the applicant;

	(ii)	The name, address and telephone number of the person whom the applicant
designates to be notified concerning the applicant&#x2019;s newsstand;

	(iii)	The requested location for the newsstand.

	(B)	Issuance of Permit &#x2013; Upon proper application, the Department may, upon
the payment of the fee provided below, issue a newsstand permit to the applicant
in accordance with the provisions of this Subdivision (5). Such permit shall not
be assignable nor shall more than one permit be issued to any one person. No
more than two newsstands shall be allowed on any one block. As used herein
&#x201C;block&#x201D; shall mean one side of a street between two consecutive intersecting
streets.

	(C)	The Board shall enact regulations for the selection of permittees taking
into consideration the length of time a newsstand has been operated by the
applicant at a particular location, whether there has existed a business license
for such newsstand, the number of violations an applicant has incurred in the
operation of his or her newsstand and such other factors the Board deems
appropriate.

	(D)	Validity of Permit &#x2013; Permits shall be valid from the issuance date until
the May 31st following such date, and may be renewed annually thereafter. Such
permits shall be issued initially for a period not to exceed one year and
renewals thereof shall be for a maximum of one year periods thereafter.

	(E)	Permit Fee &#x2013; There shall be a permit fee for new, and renewal, permits in
the amount of twenty-five (25) dollars for each newsstand. Whenever any permit
is issued after May 31st, the amount of such fee shall be prorated on a
quarterly basis. The permit fee may be increased by the Board if so justified by
an increase in the cost of regulation.

	(F)	Permit Decals &#x2013; The Department shall issue to each permittee a permit
decal for the newsstand covered by the permit. Permittees shall cause the decal
to be affixed to the front face of the newsstand so as to be visible from the
sidewalk.

	(6)	Prior to the issuance of a permit by the Department, the applicant shall
furnish to the Department a certificate, in a form satisfactory to the
Department and City Attorney, that the applicant has then in force public
liability and property damage insurance, naming the City as an additional
insured, in an amount and type as determined by the Board, subject to reasonable
availability. The evidence of insurances filed shall include a statement by the
insurance carrier that thirty (30) days notice will be given to the City
Attorney before any cancellation of coverage. The City shall be named as an
additional insured on any such insurance policy. Such insurance shall be
maintained throughout the permit period.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff.
5/3/86.)

	(7)	Any newsstand installed, used or maintained in violation of this subsection
shall be removed subject to the provisions of Subdivisions (7) through (12) of
Subsection (f) of this section. In addition any violation of this subsection
shall subject the applicant and/or violator to the imposition of criminal
liability.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(8)	Upon the cessation and abandonment of operations of any newsstand the
person holding the permit, or if no one is presently holding a permit the last
one to hold a permit for the newsstand, shall be responsible for the removal of
such newsstand. If the newsstand is not so removed the City shall so remove it
pursuant to Subsection (f) hereof and assess the most recent holder of the
permit for the costs incurred.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(9)	Violation of any provision of this subsection may result, after due notice
and hearing, in the revocation of the permit by the Board.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No.
161,043, Eff. 5/3/86.)

	(h)	Freeway On-Ramps and Off-Ramps &#x2013; Sales Prohibited.&#xA0; Notwithstanding any
other provision of this Code, no person on any street, or other public property
of whatever nature or description, shall, within fifty feet of the roadway of
any freeway on-ramp or off-ramp, distribute, deliver, sell, offer for sale or
solicit the sale of any newspapers, magazines, periodicals, circulars, handbills
or other printed matter or any goods, wares or merchandise regardless of type,
nature, kind or description.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(i)	The provisions of this section shall not apply to the installation and
maintenance of any bench installed and maintained in accordance with Article 8
of Chapter VI of this code, nor to the operation and maintenance of
searchlights, generators and floodlights in accordance with the restrictions and
requirements of Division T of Chapter VIII of this Code. Nor shall the
provisions of this section prohibit the putting of business notices, signs or
emblems upon ordinary business or carrier vehicles. Nor shall the provisions of
this section apply to temporary selling activities and advertising related
thereto conducted pursuant to a permit granted under Subsection (j) hereof.
(Amended by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(j)	Permit for Temporary Selling Activities Board of Public Works.&#xA0; (Amended
by Ord. No. 145,691, Eff. 5/2/74.)

	(1)	The Board of Public Works may issue upon written application, made upon a
form prescribed by the Board, a permit authorizing temporary selling activities
and advertising relative thereto, on sidewalks, parkways and roadways, provided
that as to roadways such permit&#x2019;s issuance will, in addition to this
section&#x2019;s requirements, be governed by the provisions of Section 41.20 of this
Code, in connection with a community civic event sponsored and conducted by a
nonprofit organization formed for charitable, educational, civic, veteran,
philanthropic or other benevolent purposes, under the following conditions:&#xA0;
(Amended by Ord. No. 150,706, Eff. 5/13/78.)

	(A)	&#x201C;Community civic center&#x201D; means the sponsoring and conducting by a
nonprofit organization of a civic, artistic, cultural, charitable, educational,
veteran or benevolent activity of community interest. The Board shall require
reasonable proof of the nonprofit status of the sponsoring organization and a
sufficient showing of community interest, which showing shall consist of
furnishing the Board with names and addresses of at least 100 persons who will
support the activity, at least 50% of which either reside or work in the
location specified in the application for permit where the activity is to take
place.

	(B)	Each permit shall be valid for a period of three consecutive days only, two
of which days shall be a Saturday or Sunday. &#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 158,731,
Eff. 2/25/84.)

	(C)	Each application for a permit must be accompanied by a fee and must be
presented to the Board not less than 40 nor more than 180 days before the
commencing date of the proposed permit activities; provided that the Board may
waive these time requirements if it determines such waiver to be in the public
interest. The fee herein shall be determined and adopted in the same manner as
provided in Section 12.37-I, 1 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code for
establishing fees.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 165,675, Eff. 5/11/90.)

	(D)	No person or sponsoring organization shall fail to keep the permit, at all
times, at the place where the selling activities are being conducted, nor fail,
upon demand therefor, to exhibit such permit to any public officer.

	(E)	No selling or advertising activities shall be conducted in the roadway or
within two feet of the curb of any sidewalk unless authorized by the Board of
Public works.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 150,706, Eff. 5/13/78.)

	(F)	(Amended by Ord. No. 173,283, Eff. 6/26/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)&#xA0; Nor may such
selling activities take place without an Information Card, written Notice of
Intention, or professional fund-raiser&#x2019;s license if the activity is such that
one would be required under Article 4, Chapter 4 of the Los Angeles Municipal
Code.

	(G)	The application for such permit shall contain:

	1.	The name of the applicant, the sponsoring organization, the event chairman
and the addresses and telephone numbers of each.

	2.	The location and outside perimeter of the selling area, indicated upon a map
of the area.

	3.	The date and times at which the selling activities are to take place.

	4.	A description of the selling activity which will be conducted.

	5.	A list of all persons who will be engaging in temporary selling activities
at any time during the dates and times for which a temporary selling permit is
granted. However this list may be furnished after the application has been
submitted, so long as it is not furnished later than one week before the event
is to take place.

	6.	An agreement to comply with the terms of the permit.

	(2)	Sponsoring organizations may be granted a temporary selling permit if the
organization meets the following requirements:

	(A)	That the title of any real property in the City of Los Angeles owned by
such organization is vested in the name of such organization, if it be a
corporation, or else in the name or names of a responsible trustee or trustees
under a declaration of trust or other written instrument setting forth the
rights of said organization therein; and recorded in the records of the County
Recorder of Los Angeles County.

	(B)	That the declared&#xA0; purposes for which such organization is organized are
charitable, educational, civic, community service, veteran, benevolent or other
philanthropic purposes, and not for the pecuniary profit of the members of the
organization thereof or any of them.

	(C)	That for three months prior to its application for a temporary selling
permit said organization has faithfully complied with the following provisions
with reference to its accounts, namely: All funds received by it, and all
disbursements made by it, have been entered upon the books of its treasurer or
other financial officer, receipts have been given or tendered for all money or
other property donated to it, whenever required by law or ordinance; all
expenditures other than petty cash to a reasonable amount have been made by
checks signed by at least two officers of such organization; that the bank book
of such organization has been balanced and reconciled with the books of account
at reasonable intervals.

	(D)	That no monies of said organization are on loan directly or indirectly to
any&#xA0; officer, director, trustee, employee or member thereof, and that the
organization has not invested any monies constituting part of its permanent
endowment funds except in securities legal as investments for savings banks
within the State of California, and has not diverted funds donated to it from an
source to purposes other than those for which they were donated.&#xA0; (Amended by
Ord. No. 156,941, Eff. 8/20/82.)

	(E)	That the work for which such organization has been formed has been
faithfully performed.

	(F)	That the bylaws and other written rules and regulations of such
organization define the powers and duties of the officers of such organization,
and that a copy of the Articles of Incorporation, if it be a corporation, and a
copy of the bylaws and other written rules and regulations of such organization
have been filed with the Department of Public works.

	(G)	That within one year prior to its application such organization has not
violated any law or ordinance applicable to it.

	(3)	The Board shall cause such application to be investigated and shall grant
the permit if it determines: that the proposed activities will not disrupt to an
unreasonable extent the movement of vehicular or pedestrian traffic or create a
hazard to the public; that the proposed activities are not of a size or nature
that require the diversion of so great a number of police personnel to regulate
such activities that it prevents reasonable police protection for the City or
for the councilmanic district where the temporary selling activity is to take
place; that the concentration of persons, equipment and materials is not so
great in the selling area that it would prevent proper fire, police and
ambulance protection; that the applicant agrees to be responsible for cleanup
necessitated by the proposed activities and the Board may, in its discretion,
require a cleanup deposit to guarantee that cleanup takes place.&#xA0; (Amended by
Ord. No. 160,175, Eff. 8/24/85.)

	(4)	The Board shall further condition the granting of such permit upon the
permit applicant filing with the Board a policy of public liability insurance in
which the City has been named as insured or co-insured with the permittee. The
policy of insurance shall insure the City and its officers and employees against
all claims arising out of or in connection with the issuance of the permit or
the operation of the permittee, his agents or representatives pursuant to the
permit. The policy of insurance shall provide coverage no less than $100,000 per
occurrence of bodily injury and $25,000 per occurrence of property damage.

	(5)	The Board shall adopt uniform rules and regulations so as to carry out the
purposes of this subsection and shall condition the granting of permits upon
compliance therewith and also with such other conditions as the Board may deem
necessary to impose for the proper protection of persons and property.

	(k)	The provisions of this section shall not prohibit sales that are otherwise
permitted under the terms of Section 80.73 of this Code.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No.
150,561, Eff. 3/19/78.)

	(l)	Permit for Flower Vending Booths.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 159,008, Eff.
7/1/84.)

	(1)	The provisions of this section shall not apply to the sale of flowers from
a flower vending booth operated pursuant to a permit granted by the Board of
Public Works.

	(2)	The Board may issue a revocable permit for the installation and operation
of a flower vending booth on a sidewalk pursuant to the one year pilot flower
vending booth demonstration program authorized by the City Council in the
downtown area.

	(3)	The issuance of any such permit does not preclude the requirements of any
other permits or approval for any such installation.

	(m)	Establishment and Regulation of Special Sidewalk Vending Districts.&#xA0;
(Added by Ord. No. 169,319, Eff. 2/18/94.)

	(1)	The Board of Public Works, hereinafter referred to as &#x201C;Board,&#x201D; is
authorized to form special sidewalk vending districts for the purpose of
permitting vending of goods, wares and merchandise and announcing the
availability thereof within such districts, and to promulgate rules and
regulations with respect to the formation of such districts.&#xA0; The term
&#x201C;district&#x201D; whenever used in this subdivision shall mean &#x201C;special sidewalk
vending district.&#x201D;&#xA0; No more than eight districts shall be approved by the
Board during the first two years following the effective date of this
ordinance.&#xA0; Each district shall have a&#xA0; designated police liaison appointed by
the Chief of Police.&#xA0; Before any proposed vending districts are established,
the City Council shall adopt a humane and comprehensive enforcement policy
regarding sidewalk vending both inside and outside the proposed districts.

	(2)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; A petition may be filed with
the Sidewalk Vending Administrator of the Community Development Department,
hereinafter referred to as &#x201C;Sidewalk Vending Administrator,&#x201D; by any person
or persons, hereinafter referred to as &#x201C;applicant,&#x201D; interested in the
formation of a special sidewalk vending district.&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending
Administrator shall coordinate with the Board regarding the filing and
processing of said application.&#xA0; The petition shall be subject to the following
conditions and requirements:

	(A)	The applicant shall pay to the Sidewalk Vending Administrator a non
refundable application fee to establish a district.&#xA0; However, such fee shall
not be paid until after the City Council has approved the formation of the
district pursuant to Subdivision (6) of this subsection.&#xA0; No license
application in respect to said district shall be approved until the fee has been
paid.&#xA0; Said fee shall be determined and adopted in the same manner as provided
in Section 12.37-I,1 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code for establishing fees.

	(B)	The petition shall contain the name or names of the applicant(s) and names
and signatures together with residence or business addresses within the district
of persons endorsing the formation of the district.&#xA0; The endorsing list must
consist of the owners or those in possession, such as tenants or lessees, of at
least 20 percent of the businesses and 20 percent of the residents in each block
or portion thereof to be included in the district.

	(C)	The petition shall set forth:

	1.	The proposed boundaries of the district, which shall only be in commercially
zoned areas of the City;

	2.	The location and number of vending sites sought to be approved;

	3.	Any rules or regulations deemed necessary or desirable by the petitioners to
organize vending activity within the district; and

	4.	The purpose for establishing the district.

	(D)	The petition shall be accompanied by a list provided by the Sidewalk
Vending Administrator of the names and addresses of all property owners,
businesses and residents within the district and within a 500-foot radius of the
boundaries of the district, together with a cash deposit sufficient to cover the
costs of preparing such a list and of mailing and publishing notifications as
provided below.

	(E)	The district shall not be limited to any particular size and the proposed
density of vending sites may vary from area-to-area within the district.

	(3)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; Upon receipt of said
petition, the Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall notify the Council member or
Council members in whose district or districts the special sidewalk vending
district is proposed to be located, at which time the Council member or Council
members shall appoint a Community Advisory Committee.&#xA0; The Community Advisory
Committee must contain a Street Use Inspector, a Police Officer and the Sidewalk
Vending Administrator.&#xA0; The committee shall have balanced representation of
proponents of the district, fixed businesses, and residents within or adjacent
to the proposed districts, as well as a representative of the Council office or
offices.&#xA0; The committee will make recommendations on boundaries of the
district, density and location of vendors, goods sold, design of carts and hours
of operation.&#xA0; There shall be a limit of 90 days between filing this petition
and a final decision by the Board.

	(4)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; After reviewing the petition
for compliance with the provisions of this Code, the Sidewalk Vending
Administrator shall transmit said petition to the Board which shall set the
matter for public hearing in coordination with the Sidewalk Vending
Administrator within 30 days after receipt thereof.&#xA0; Notice of the time, place
and purpose of the public hearing shall be given by the Sidewalk Vending
Administrator to each applicant by mailing a written notice of the hearing not
less than 30 days prior to the date of such hearing.&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending
Administrator shall at the same time mail such notice to all property owners,
businesses and residents within the proposed district and within a 500-foot
radius of the boundaries of the district.&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending Administrator
shall further cause there to be published a notice of such public hearing in a
newspaper of general circulation in the area wherein the sidewalk vending
district is proposed to be established.&#xA0; The notice shall be published in both
English and in any other language spoken as their primary language by a
substantial number of the persons residing in the proposed district.&#xA0; The
notice shall be published as provided for in Section 6064 of the Government Code
of the State of California, and shall state the purpose of the proposed
district, the boundaries thereof and the date, time and place of the public
hearing.

	(5)	Any interested person may appear at such hearing and comment with respect
to the proposed vending district.&#xA0; Comments may also be submitted in writing
prior to the date of such hearing.&#xA0; The Board shall also consider
recommendations of merchant associations, chambers of commerce, the Los Angeles
Police Department and various other affected City departments.
	(6)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending
Administrator shall refer the matter to the Council member or Council members in
whose district or districts the special vending district is proposed to be
located for review and recommendation, together with a summary of comments made
at the hearing.&#xA0; Based upon the foregoing comments, recommendations of the
Community Advisory Committee and Council member recommendations, the Board may
make a finding that the public welfare would be served by the establishment of
such a district.&#xA0; In so doing, the Board may for good cause alter the proposed
district boundaries and the number, location and density of proposed vending
sites.&#xA0; The Board shall transmit to the City Council its finding and the
reasons therefor together with its recommendation that the district be
established in the manner proposed in the petition or as modified by the
Board.&#xA0; The City Council may approve, modify or disapprove the recommendation
of the Board.&#xA0; The district shall be established upon approval, or approval as
modified, of the Board&#x2019;s recommendation.&#xA0; For good cause, after due
consideration of all comments and recommendations presented, the Board may make
a finding that the public welfare would not be served by the establishment of
the district.&#xA0; The Board&#x2019;s finding may be based on factors such as
incompatibility of vending pushcarts with area architectural style, conflict
with the area&#x2019;s specific plan, the presence of pushcarts as an impediment to
the use of on-street parking locations in areas where an unusually heavy demand
for such parking exists, or the presence of zoning restrictions prohibiting such
vending activities on private property in the area.&#xA0; The Board shall transmit
to the City Council its finding and the reasons therefor together with its
recommendation that the district not be established.&#xA0; The City Council may
approve or disapprove the recommendation of the Board.&#xA0; If disapproved, such
disapproval shall establish the district and the Board shall be so informed,
provided, however, that either the City Council, or the Board with approval of
the Council, may modify district boundaries and number, location and density of
proposed vending sites, as set forth in the petition.

	(7)	Upon petition of an interested party, a special district may be
disestablished, or areas withdrawn therefrom, for good cause.&#xA0; Each such
petition shall contain the signatures of at least 20 percent of the owners or
persons in possession, such as tenants or lessees, of businesses in each block
or portion thereof of the district or part thereof proposed to be withdrawn, and
at least 20 percent of the residents of each such block or portion thereof.&#xA0;
Each such petition shall comply with the requirements of Section
42.00(m)(2)(D).&#xA0; The Board shall hold a hearing into the matter preceded by
notice as provided for in Subdivision (4) above.&#xA0; In the event the Board makes
a finding that the public welfare would be served by disestablishment of the
district or by withdrawal of an area, the Board shall transmit to the City
Council its finding and the reasons therefor, together with its recommendation
that district be disestablished or an area be withdrawn therefrom.&#xA0; The City
Council may approve or disapprove the Board&#x2019;s recommendation.&#xA0; Approval
disestablishes the district or withdraws the subject area therefrom.

	(8)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending
Administrator shall review all rules and regulations proposed by petitioners,
the Community Advisory Committee of the particular vending district, and any
other interested parties provided that the Community Advisory Committee has had
an opportunity to review them and transmit all such rules and regulations to the
Board, together with his or her recommendations regarding adoption.&#xA0; The Board
shall adopt all such rules and regulations for the district unless good cause
exists for non-adoption.&#xA0; In addition, the Board, for good cause, may adopt
such other rules and regulations for the district as would promote the public
health, welfare and safety.&#xA0; Rules and regulations, when adopted, shall be
binding upon all affected persons within the district.

	(9)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; No permit shall be issued,
however, until a contract has been executed between the City, through the
Community Development Department,&#xA0; and any organization selected to manage the
special sidewalk vending district, referred to hereinafter as &#x201C;management
organization&#x201D;, as provided for in Los Angeles Administrative Code Section
22.361.

	(10)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; The Community Development
Department, through the Sidewalk Vending Administrator, shall determine the
allocation of vending permits within the district, whether by lottery or
otherwise, in a manner consistent with public health, safety and welfare.&#xA0;
However, the Sidewalk Vending Administrator may by contract delegate that
function to any organization selected to manage the district subject to the
supervision of the Sidewalk Vending Administrator and approval by the Community
Development Department as to method of allocation to assure that vending permits
are allocated in a fair and impartial manner.

	(11)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; The Community Development
Department, through the Sidewalk Vending Administrator, shall issue all sidewalk
vending permits and collect all fees and charges in connection therewith.&#xA0; Any
person desiring to be issued a permit for sidewalk vending within a district may
make application to the Sidewalk Vending Administrator on forms provided.&#xA0; The
application shall set forth the following information:

	(A)	The name, address and telephone number of the applicant;

	(B)	The exact location at which the vending is proposed to be conducted;

	(C)	A complete list of what is proposed to be sold;

	(D)	The hours per day and days per week during which sidewalk vending will be
conducted; and

	(E)	Any other information required by the Community Development Department.

	(12)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; No permit or renewal permit
shall be issued unless the applicant has complied with all of the following
requirements:

	(A)	If any food or drink item is proposed to be sold, the applicant has
obtained approval from the County Department of Health Services to engage in the
vending of the item in the manner proposed;

	(B)	(Amended by Ord. No. 173,298, Eff. 6/30/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)&#xA0; All other
necessary City, County and State licenses and permits have been obtained,
including a Business Tax Registration Certificate from the Office of Finance.

	(C)	(Amended by Ord. No. 173,363, Eff. 7 /29/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)&#xA0; The applicant
has filed with the Community Development Department a policy of public liability
and property damage insurance, in a form satisfactory to it and to the City
Attorney, in which the City is named as a co-insured with the applicant.&#xA0; The
policy of insurance shall so insure the City and its officers and employees
against all claims arising out of or in connection with the issuance of the
permit or the operation of the permittee.&#xA0; The policy of insurance shall be in
an amount and type as determined by the Community Development Department in
consultation with the Director of the Office of Administrative and Research
Services, subject to reasonable availability.&#xA0; The Community Development
Department, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Administrative
and Research Services, may waive the requirement of insurance if none is
reasonably available.&#xA0; In lieu of individual policies of insurance, the
Community Development Department may cause to be secured a general or blanket
policy of insurance covering all applicants and thereafter determine the pro
rata cost to each applicant, which shall be collected before approval of the
application.&#xA0; Any policy of insurance shall contain a statement by the
insurance carrier that thirty (30) days&#x2019; notice will be given to the City
Attorney before any cancellation of coverage.&#xA0; Insurance shall be maintained
throughout the permit period.&#xA0; The Community Development Department may for
good cause increase the amount of required insurance.

	(D)	The applicant shows proof of ownership, lease or rental of a pushcart
constructed for the purpose of vending goods, wares or merchandise according to
the requirements and specifications of the Community Development Department.

	(E)	Approval in writing has been obtained from the owner, tenant or person in
lawful possession or control of the property abutting upon the street
immediately adjacent to the location where the vending is proposed to be
conducted.&#xA0; Such approval may be secured by the management organization.

	(F)	The applicant has provided the City with two passport size photos of the
applicant.

	(G)	The applicant has presented adequate identification of himself or
herself.&#xA0; Adequate identification shall include, but not be limited to, a
California driver&#x2019;s license or a California Department of Motor Vehicles
identification card.

	(H)	The applicant is old enough under State law to engage in the vending
activity.

	(I)	The applicant has submitted to fingerprinting, in connection with which
applicant shall pay a fingerprint process fee.&#xA0; Such fee shall be determined
and adopted in the same manner as is provided in Section 12.37-I,1 of the Los
Angeles Municipal Code for establishing fees.

	(13)	No permit shall be issued to any applicant who has been convicted of any
crime relating to fraudulent business practices, the receipt or sale of stolen
property or the illegal sale of any controlled substance under the provisions of
the California Controlled Substances Act within five (5) years prior to the date
of application for permit.

	(14)	The applicant may designate up to two co-applicants who are authorized by
the applicant to vend at the location for which the applicant&#x2019;s permit is
issued in his or her temporary absence due to circumstances such as illness,
injury or vacation.&#xA0; However, there must be provided the name, address and
phone number of each co-applicant and two passport size photos of each
co-applicant must be submitted.&#xA0; Each co-applicant must present adequate
identification of himself or herself in the same manner as required for the
applicant, and must be old enough under State law to engage in vending
activity.&#xA0; Each co-applicant shall submit to fingerprinting and shall be
subject to provisions of Subdivision 12 with respect to approval as a
co-applicant and the provisions of Subdivision (22) with respect to operating
requirements.&#xA0; Those approved shall be designated co-permittees and shall pay
an application fee for the issuance of a co-permit.&#xA0; Such fee shall be
determined and adopted in the same manner as is provided in Section 12.37-I,1 of
the Los Angeles Municipal Code for establishing fees.

	(15)	A permit shall be issued only to a natural person and only for the days or
hours of the day indicated on the application as days and hours of operation.&#xA0;
Such permit shall not be transferable to any other person and shall be valid
only for the location for which it is issued.

	(16)	Only one permit shall be issued to each permittee.

	(17)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; A non-refundable annual
permit fee shall be paid before issuance of any permit provided, however, that
the applicant may elect to pay said fee in semi-annual installments.&#xA0; Such
election shall be stated in writing and installments shall be paid as directed
by the Sidewalk Vending Administrator.&#xA0; If such election is made, a payment of
one-half the annual permit fee shall be required before issuance of a permit.&#xA0;
Permits shall be valid for one year from the date of issuance.&#xA0; If any
installment fee is not paid on or before the date provided by the Sidewalk
Vending Administrator for payment, a letter shall be sent to the permittee
advising that such fee is due within 30 days of the date of such letter or the
permit shall terminate.&#xA0; If the fee is not paid within the 30-day period, the
permit shall terminate and the former permittee shall cease from vending.&#xA0; The
permit may be reinstated upon payment of the fee.&#xA0; At the time of making any
payment as provided for above, the applicant or permittee shall pay a
supplemental fee which is a pro-rated amount determined by the Community
Development Department as sufficient to cover the cost to the City of entering
into a contract for management of the district.&#xA0; Supplemental fees collected
shall be placed in a special fund established for such purpose.&#xA0; In addition
fees will be charged for the following:

	Replacement of existing permit in the event of loss, name change or change of
company;

	Replacement of existing permit decal; and

	Replacement of any vending identification badge.

	Fees herein shall be determined and adopted in the same manner as provided in
Section 12.37-I,1 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code for establishing fees.

	(18)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; In the event an application
for permit is denied, the applicant shall be so notified within 60 days, which
notification shall also state the reason for denial and that the applicant has
45 days from the date of notice within which to request reconsideration of the
denial.

	(19)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; Any permit issued shall be
subject to the right of the Community Development Department to rescind issuance
thereof in response to a request for reconsideration of its action in issuing
the permit.

	(20)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; Either the applicant or any
other person affected by the issuance of a vending permit may request
reconsideration by the Community Development Department of its decision to grant
or deny an application for permit.&#xA0; Such request must be in writing and must be
received by the Sidewalk Vending Administrator within the 45 days from the date
of issuance of the permit or notification of denial.&#xA0; Upon receipt of such
request the Sidewalk Vending Administrator shall set a hearing date no less than
30 days from the date of the receipt of the request.&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending
Administrator shall notify the requestor and, if the requestor is not the
applicant, the applicant, of the hearing date.&#xA0; The Community Development
Department shall rescind issuance of the permit if at the hearing it is
demonstrated to its satisfaction that the issuance thereof was contrary to the
provisions of this subdivision or to applicable rules and regulations.&#xA0; The
Community Development Department may direct the Sidewalk Vending Administrator
to issue a permit if it is shown to the satisfaction of the Department that it
was in error in denying the permit.

	(21)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; The permittee may amend his
or her application with respect to the goods, wares and merchandise proposed to
be sold and the hours during which vending is to occur by written notification
thereof to and approval by the Sidewalk Vending Administrator, and the owner,
tenant, or person in lawful control of the property immediately adjacent to the
vending site.

	(22)	Operating Requirements.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)

	(A)	Vending shall be conducted only from pushcarts constructed for that purpose
according to the requirements and specifications of the Community Development&#xA0;
Department.&#xA0; Such pushcarts shall have a length of no greater than six feet and
a width of no greater than 3 feet, 6 inches, and shall be no more than 6 feet, 6
inches in Height, including roof or awning.&#xA0; A decal so certifying shall be
attached to each pushcart approved for use.

	(B)	All of the permittee&#x2019;s advertising must be attached to the pushcart and
shall advertise only the goods, wares or merchandise being sold.&#xA0; Advertising
signs shall not extend beyond the overall width or height of the pushcart.

	(C)	The permittee shall not conduct any portion of its vending business outside
the boundaries of its vending location as described in the permit.

	(D)	One small, compact stool or chair may be utilized by the permittee.&#xA0; The
stool or chair shall be placed within four feet of the pushcart and shall not
block the safe passage of pedestrians.&#xA0; No advertising shall be placed on the
stool or chair.&#xA0; Other than the pushcart and stool or chair, no other items or
object of any kind shall be placed on the public sidewalk or parkway.

	(E)	No vending shall be conducted on the roadway portion of any street.

	(F)	The permittee shall provide a trash receptacle for the use of customers and
shall pick up and dispose of any trash or litter left by customers before
leaving the vending location.&#xA0; Full receptacles shall be immediately emptied by
the permittee.

	(G)	The City vending permit shall be visibly displayed at all times while the
permittee is engaged in vending activity.

	(H)	The permittee shall wear a vendor identification badge issued by the
Sidewalk Vending Administrator at all times while engaged in vending.

	(I)	Pushcarts shall be positioned no less than 18 inches from the curb.

	(J)	No permittee shall knowingly allow, permit or authorize another person to
vend from permittee&#x2019;s pushcart or at permittee&#x2019;s assigned location, other
than designated co-permittees of that particular vendor.

	(K)	No pushcart shall be chained or fastened to any pole, sign, tree or other
object in the public way.

	(23)	(Amended by Ord. No. 171,913, Eff. 3/15/98.)&#xA0; The Sidewalk Vending
Administrator may from time to time recommend rules and regulations to the
Board.&#xA0; The Board may adopt such rules and regulations as it deems necessary to
implement the provisions of this subsection.

	(24)	Revocation, Suspension or Non-renewal.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 171,913,
Eff. 3/15/98.)

	(A)	After notice and hearing in accordance with Section 22.02 of the Municipal
Code, the Community Development Department may revoke or suspend any permit
issued pursuant to this subsection or decline to renew any such permit, if the
permittee has:

	1.	Knowingly made any false, misleading or fraudulent statement of&#xA0; material
fact in its application for a permit;

	2.	Been convicted of any criminal act in connection with the operation of the
permitted activity, or any of the crimes set forth in Subdivision (13) of this
subsection;

	3.	Violated any of the operating requirements set forth in Subdivision (22) of
this subsection;

	4.	Violated any rule or regulation promulgated by the Board with respect to
this subdivision;

	5.	Failed to comply with any order by the department to cease and desist from
any violation; or

	6.	In any other way endangered the public health, safety or welfare in the
conducting of its sidewalk vending activities.

	(B)	A permittee who has had his or her permit revoked or whose application for
renewal has been declined shall not be eligible to apply for another permit
under this subdivision until 12 months after the date of revocation or renewal
declination.

	(C)	Any action revoking or suspending a license may be appealed to the Board
within 60 days of the action of suspension or revocation.&#xA0; The Board shall hear
and make a determination on the appeal.

	(25)	Enforcement and Penalties.

	(A)	Within each district the provisions of this Subsection (m) shall be
enforced by the Street Use Inspection Division of the Bureau of Street
Maintenance of the Department of Public Works.

	(B)	The Department may issue an order to immediately cease and desist from any
violation of this Subsection (m) or any rule or regulation of the Board.

	(C)	It shall be a violation of law to fail to comply with any of the provisions
of Subdivision (22) of this Subsection (m).&#xA0; The first, second and third
violations of Subdivision (22) of Subsection (m) shall each be infractions.&#xA0;
The commission of a fourth violation of any of the provisions of Subdivision
(22) of Subsection (m) within a two-year period after the commission of the
first violation shall be a misdemeanor.

	(D)	It shall be illegal for any person to display any imitation or facsimile of
a vending permit, vendor identification badge or decal which has not been issued
by the Department.
</plain_text><html></html></law>
