<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><section_number>43.05.1</section_number><edition_id>1</edition_id><section_id>2716</section_id><structure_id>15</structure_id><catch_line>Coin Games And Similar Contrivances &#x2013; Possession Prohibited.</catch_line><history></history><full_text>&#xA0; COIN GAMES AND SIMILAR CONTRIVANCES &#x2013; POSSESSION PROHIBITED.

	A.	Definitions. For the purposes of this section, the following terms are defined as hereinafter set forth:

	1.	&#x201C;Pin Game&#x201D;: Any table, cabinet, or mechanism equipped for the playing of any game whereby any marble, ball, pellet or other moving object is propelled, released, rolled or shot along, over or above a surface set with pins, pegs or other obstructions or irregularities which deflect or impede the course of the moving object or which may divert or direct it beyond the control of the player.

	2.	&#x201C;Marble Game&#x201D;: Any table, cabinet or stand equipped for the playing of a game whereby marbles or balls are, with the aid of a mechanical plunger or other affixed device, propelled, released, shot or rolled so as to drop or come to rest in holes, slots, cups or traps, resulting in a score or tally being electrically or otherwise registered or shown which score or tally depends upon the course followed or point reached by the marble or ball or upon the contact points touched by it along its course, or upon any combination of such factors.

	3.	The phrase &#x201C;Any game similar to a marble game&#x201D; shall mean: &#x201C;Balley-Alley&#x201D; and any other miniature mechanical bowling game device, by whatever name called; any table, cabinet or mechanical device equipped for the playing of any game whereby any marble, ball, pellet or any moving object is propelled, rolled, shot or released toward a goal, pin, set of pins, or other objective by means of any plunger, ejector, mechanical bat, mechanical hand or by means of any other striking or releasing mechanism which is affixed or attached to the table or cabinet, or which is an integral part of the mechanical device or which is mechanically manipulated, controlled or guided, and which game is so contrived that, at the conclusion of the operation or play thereof the score or result of play thereof is visible or otherwise discernible so as to permit or make practicable the playing off or the awarding of a prize or reward upon the operation or play of the game.

	4.	&#x201C;Claw, Hook, or Grab Machine&#x201D;: Any amusement machine or device so designed that articles placed or heaped therein for the purpose of the game may be grabbed, hooked, or otherwise displaced, recovered or removed by the operation of any contrivance simulating in miniature a power shovel, clam shell, dragline or similar excavating tool or machine.

	5.	&#x201C;Horse Racing Machine&#x201D;: Any mechanically operated amusement machine or device contrived to simulate in miniature the running of a horse race or any other race run by beasts, humans or machines, or which is contrived to put in motion any number of objects or symbols which then do, or appear to, run or move against each other in the manner of a miniature race, or which is designed to represent, by symbols, the running of any race and the order of the finish thereof.

	B.	It shall be unlawful for any person to keep, maintain or possess in any place of business or in any place of public resort:

	1.	Any pin game, any marble game or any game similar to a marble game, any claw, hook or grab machine or any horse race machine, the operation of which game or machine is controlled, permitted or made available by placing therein a coin, plug, disc, key or token, or which is let for use, operation or play upon the payment or delivery of anything of value therefor, or upon the making of any purchase.

	2.	Any mechanical device or mechanically operated contrivance for the playing of any game of chance, the use or operation of which is controlled, permitted or made available by placing therein any coin, plug, disk, key or token, or which is let for use, operation or play upon the payment or delivery of anything of value therefor, or upon the making of any purchase.

	C.	The provisions of this section shall not apply to the keeping, possessing or exhibiting of any such mechanical contrivance or device at or in any mercantile store in which such mechanical contrivances or devices are kept solely for sale and which mechanical contrivances or devices members of the public are not permitted or allowed to operate, manipulate or play except as incident to a demonstration for the purpose of sale.

	This section is not unconstitutional, although it pertains to machines in which a degree of skill may be developed.
	People v. Hambro, CR A 1856
	People v. Eisenberg CR A 1900
	People v. Chuba CR A 2391</full_text><order_by>05.1</order_by><ancestry><unit id="15" label="article"><name>Gambling, Fraud And Deceit (*)</name><identifier>3</identifier><url>/4/3/</url></unit><unit id="11" label="chapter"><name>Public Welfare</name><identifier>4</identifier><url>/4/</url></unit></ancestry><structure_contents><unit id="1980"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.00</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/43.00/</url><token>43.00</token></unit><unit id="1804"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.01</section_number><catch_line>Gambling &#x2013; Dice Shaking.</catch_line><url>/43.01/</url><token>43.01</token></unit><unit id="443"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.01.1</section_number><catch_line>Bingo For Charitable Purposes.</catch_line><url>/43.01.1/</url><token>43.01.1</token></unit><unit id="2716"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.05.1</section_number><catch_line>Coin Games And Similar Contrivances &#x2013; Possession Prohibited.</catch_line><url>/43.05.1/</url><token>43.05.1</token></unit><unit id="2519"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.05.2</section_number><catch_line>Games &#x2013; Unlawful Possession &#x2013; Declared To Be A Nuisance.</catch_line><url>/43.05.2/</url><token>43.05.2</token></unit><unit id="2515"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.12</section_number><catch_line>Lottery &#x2013; Visiting.</catch_line><url>/43.12/</url><token>43.12</token></unit><unit id="1766"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.13</section_number><catch_line>Exhibiting Gambling Equipment.</catch_line><url>/43.13/</url><token>43.13</token></unit><unit id="119"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.13.1</section_number><catch_line>Visiting Gambling Rooms.</catch_line><url>/43.13.1/</url><token>43.13.1</token></unit><unit id="870"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.13.2</section_number><catch_line>Present At Gambling.</catch_line><url>/43.13.2/</url><token>43.13.2</token></unit><unit id="3312"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.13.3</section_number><catch_line>Gambling House.</catch_line><url>/43.13.3/</url><token>43.13.3</token></unit><unit id="961"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.17</section_number><catch_line>Taxicabs &#x2013; Cars For Hire &#x2013; Defrauding.</catch_line><url>/43.17/</url><token>43.17</token></unit><unit id="271"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.18</section_number><catch_line>Taxicab &#x2013; Misrepresenting Identity.</catch_line><url>/43.18/</url><token>43.18</token></unit><unit id="1158"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.20</section_number><catch_line>Water Mains &#x2013; Interference With.</catch_line><url>/43.20/</url><token>43.20</token></unit><unit id="3756"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.21</section_number><catch_line>Civil Service &#x2013; Giving False Information.</catch_line><url>/43.21/</url><token>43.21</token></unit><unit id="1586"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.22</section_number><catch_line>Clearing House Certificates &#x2013; Imitating.</catch_line><url>/43.22/</url><token>43.22</token></unit><unit id="2495"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.24</section_number><catch_line>Shoe Shine Parlors &#x2013; Signs Required.</catch_line><url>/43.24/</url><token>43.24</token></unit><unit id="708"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.25</section_number><catch_line>Restaurant &#x2013; Menus Required.</catch_line><url>/43.25/</url><token>43.25</token></unit><unit id="13"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.26</section_number><catch_line>Retail Grocery Price Marking.</catch_line><url>/43.26/</url><token>43.26</token></unit><unit id="2300"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.28</section_number><catch_line>Tort Claims &#x2013; Soliciting.</catch_line><url>/43.28/</url><token>43.28</token></unit><unit id="3591"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.29</section_number><catch_line>Employers &#x2013; Requiring Employees To Wear Service Uniforms.</catch_line><url>/43.29/</url><token>43.29</token></unit><unit id="4142"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.30</section_number><catch_line>Fortune Telling.</catch_line><url>/43.30/</url><token>43.30</token></unit><unit id="1672"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.31</section_number><catch_line>Fortune Telling &#x2013; Exemptions.</catch_line><url>/43.31/</url><token>43.31</token></unit><unit id="3450"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.32</section_number><catch_line>Petitions &#x2013; Misrepresentation Of Contents.</catch_line><url>/43.32/</url><token>43.32</token></unit><unit id="2206"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.39</section_number><catch_line>Examinations &#x2013; Impersonation Prohibited.</catch_line><url>/43.39/</url><token>43.39</token></unit></structure_contents><next_section id="2519"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.05.2</section_number><catch_line>Games &#x2013; Unlawful Possession &#x2013; Declared To Be A Nuisance.</catch_line><url>/43.05.2/</url><token>43.05.2</token></next_section><metadata></metadata><references></references><url>/43.05.1/</url><token>43.05.1</token><formats><txt>/43.05.1.txt</txt><json>/43.05.1.xml</json></formats><dublin_core><Title>Coin Games And Similar Contrivances &#x2013; Possession Prohibited.</Title><Type>Text</Type><Format>text/html</Format><Identifier>&#xA7; 43.05.1</Identifier><Relation>Los Angeles Municipal Code</Relation></dublin_core><plain_text>                            LOS ANGELES MUNICIPAL CODE

COIN GAMES AND SIMILAR CONTRIVANCES &#x2013; POSSESSION PROHIBITED. (&#xA7; 43.05.1)

&#xA0; COIN GAMES AND SIMILAR CONTRIVANCES &#x2013; POSSESSION
PROHIBITED.	A.	Definitions. For the purposes of this section, the following
terms are defined as hereinafter set forth:	1.	&#x201C;Pin Game&#x201D;: Any table,
cabinet, or mechanism equipped for the playing of any game whereby any marble,
ball, pellet or other moving object is propelled, released, rolled or shot
along, over or above a surface set with pins, pegs or other obstructions or
irregularities which deflect or impede the course of the moving object or which
may divert or direct it beyond the control of the player.	2.	&#x201C;Marble Game&#x201D;:
Any table, cabinet or stand equipped for the playing of a game whereby marbles
or balls are, with the aid of a mechanical plunger or other affixed device,
propelled, released, shot or rolled so as to drop or come to rest in holes,
slots, cups or traps, resulting in a score or tally being electrically or
otherwise registered or shown which score or tally depends upon the course
followed or point reached by the marble or ball or upon the contact points
touched by it along its course, or upon any combination of such factors.	3.	The
phrase &#x201C;Any game similar to a marble game&#x201D; shall mean: &#x201C;Balley-Alley&#x201D;
and any other miniature mechanical bowling game device, by whatever name called;
any table, cabinet or mechanical device equipped for the playing of any game
whereby any marble, ball, pellet or any moving object is propelled, rolled, shot
or released toward a goal, pin, set of pins, or other objective by means of any
plunger, ejector, mechanical bat, mechanical hand or by means of any other
striking or releasing mechanism which is affixed or attached to the table or
cabinet, or which is an integral part of the mechanical device or which is
mechanically manipulated, controlled or guided, and which game is so contrived
that, at the conclusion of the operation or play thereof the score or result of
play thereof is visible or otherwise discernible so as to permit or make
practicable the playing off or the awarding of a prize or reward upon the
operation or play of the game.	4.	&#x201C;Claw, Hook, or Grab Machine&#x201D;: Any
amusement machine or device so designed that articles placed or heaped therein
for the purpose of the game may be grabbed, hooked, or otherwise displaced,
recovered or removed by the operation of any contrivance simulating in miniature
a power shovel, clam shell, dragline or similar excavating tool or
machine.	5.	&#x201C;Horse Racing Machine&#x201D;: Any mechanically operated amusement
machine or device contrived to simulate in miniature the running of a horse race
or any other race run by beasts, humans or machines, or which is contrived to
put in motion any number of objects or symbols which then do, or appear to, run
or move against each other in the manner of a miniature race, or which is
designed to represent, by symbols, the running of any race and the order of the
finish thereof.	B.	It shall be unlawful for any person to keep, maintain or
possess in any place of business or in any place of public resort:	1.	Any pin
game, any marble game or any game similar to a marble game, any claw, hook or
grab machine or any horse race machine, the operation of which game or machine
is controlled, permitted or made available by placing therein a coin, plug,
disc, key or token, or which is let for use, operation or play upon the payment
or delivery of anything of value therefor, or upon the making of any
purchase.	2.	Any mechanical device or mechanically operated contrivance for the
playing of any game of chance, the use or operation of which is controlled,
permitted or made available by placing therein any coin, plug, disk, key or
token, or which is let for use, operation or play upon the payment or delivery
of anything of value therefor, or upon the making of any purchase.	C.	The
provisions of this section shall not apply to the keeping, possessing or
exhibiting of any such mechanical contrivance or device at or in any mercantile
store in which such mechanical contrivances or devices are kept solely for sale
and which mechanical contrivances or devices members of the public are not
permitted or allowed to operate, manipulate or play except as incident to a
demonstration for the purpose of sale.	This section is not unconstitutional,
although it pertains to machines in which a degree of skill may be developed.
	People v. Hambro, CR A 1856
	People v. Eisenberg CR A 1900
	People v. Chuba CR A 2391
</plain_text><html>
					&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#xA0; COIN GAMES AND SIMILAR CONTRIVANCES &#x2013; &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;POSSESSION&lt;/span&gt; PROHIBITED.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	A.	Definitions. For the purposes of this section, the following terms are defined as hereinafter set forth:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	&#x201C;Pin Game&#x201D;: Any table, cabinet, or mechanism equipped for the playing of any game whereby any marble, ball, pellet or other moving &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;object&lt;/span&gt; is propelled, released, rolled or shot along, over or above a surface set with pins, pegs or other obstructions or irregularities which deflect or impede the course of the moving &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;object&lt;/span&gt; or which may divert or direct it beyond the control of the player.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	&#x201C;Marble Game&#x201D;: Any table, cabinet or stand equipped for the playing of a game whereby marbles or balls are, with the aid of a mechanical plunger or other affixed device, propelled, released, shot or rolled so as to drop or come to rest in holes, slots, cups or traps, resulting in a score or tally being electrically or otherwise registered or shown which score or tally depends upon the course followed or point reached by the marble or ball or upon the contact points touched by it along its course, or upon any combination of such factors.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	The phrase &#x201C;Any game similar to a marble game&#x201D; shall mean: &#x201C;Balley-Alley&#x201D; and any other miniature mechanical bowling game device, by whatever name called; any table, cabinet or mechanical device equipped for the playing of any game whereby any marble, ball, pellet or any moving &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;object&lt;/span&gt; is propelled, rolled, shot or released toward a goal, pin, set of pins, or other objective by means of any plunger, ejector, mechanical bat, mechanical hand or by means of any other striking or releasing mechanism which is affixed or attached to the table or cabinet, or which is an integral part of the mechanical device or which is mechanically manipulated, controlled or guided, and which game is so contrived that, at the conclusion of the operation or play thereof the score or result of play thereof is visible or otherwise discernible so as to permit or make practicable the playing off or the awarding of a prize or reward upon the operation or play of the game.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	4.	&#x201C;Claw, Hook, or Grab Machine&#x201D;: Any amusement machine or device so designed that articles placed or heaped therein for the purpose of the game may be grabbed, hooked, or otherwise displaced, recovered or removed by the operation of any contrivance simulating in miniature a power shovel, clam shell, dragline or similar excavating tool or machine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	5.	&#x201C;Horse Racing Machine&#x201D;: Any mechanically operated amusement machine or device contrived to simulate in miniature the running of a horse race or any other race run by beasts, humans or machines, or which is contrived to put in &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;motion&lt;/span&gt; any number of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;objects&lt;/span&gt; or symbols which then do, or appear to, run or move against each other in the manner of a miniature race, or which is designed to represent, by symbols, the running of any race and the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; of the finish thereof.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	B.	It shall be unlawful for any person to keep, maintain or possess in any place of business or in any place of public resort:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	Any pin game, any marble game or any game similar to a marble game, any claw, hook or grab machine or any horse race machine, the operation of which game or machine is controlled, permitted or made available by placing therein a coin, plug, disc, key or token, or which is let for use, operation or play upon the payment or delivery of anything of value therefor, or upon the making of any purchase.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	Any mechanical device or mechanically operated contrivance for the playing of any game of chance, the use or operation of which is controlled, permitted or made available by placing therein any coin, plug, disk, key or token, or which is let for use, operation or play upon the payment or delivery of anything of value therefor, or upon the making of any purchase.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	C.	The provisions of this section shall not apply to the keeping, possessing or exhibiting of any such mechanical contrivance or device at or in any mercantile store in which such mechanical contrivances or devices are kept solely for sale and which mechanical contrivances or devices members of the public are not permitted or allowed to operate, manipulate or play except as incident to a demonstration for the purpose of sale.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	This section is not unconstitutional, although it pertains to machines in which a degree of skill may be developed.
	People v. Hambro, CR A 1856
	People v. Eisenberg CR A 1900
	People v. Chuba CR A 2391&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</html><previous_section id="443"><structure_id>15</structure_id><section_number>43.01.1</section_number><catch_line>Bingo For Charitable Purposes.</catch_line><url>/43.01.1/</url><token>43.01.1</token></previous_section><text><unit id="2691" prefix=""><text>&#xA0; COIN GAMES AND SIMILAR CONTRIVANCES &#x2013; POSSESSION PROHIBITED.	A.	Definitions. For the purposes of this section, the following terms are defined as hereinafter set forth:	1.	&#x201C;Pin Game&#x201D;: Any table, cabinet, or mechanism equipped for the playing of any game whereby any marble, ball, pellet or other moving object is propelled, released, rolled or shot along, over or above a surface set with pins, pegs or other obstructions or irregularities which deflect or impede the course of the moving object or which may divert or direct it beyond the control of the player.	2.	&#x201C;Marble Game&#x201D;: Any table, cabinet or stand equipped for the playing of a game whereby marbles or balls are, with the aid of a mechanical plunger or other affixed device, propelled, released, shot or rolled so as to drop or come to rest in holes, slots, cups or traps, resulting in a score or tally being electrically or otherwise registered or shown which score or tally depends upon the course followed or point reached by the marble or ball or upon the contact points touched by it along its course, or upon any combination of such factors.	3.	The phrase &#x201C;Any game similar to a marble game&#x201D; shall mean: &#x201C;Balley-Alley&#x201D; and any other miniature mechanical bowling game device, by whatever name called; any table, cabinet or mechanical device equipped for the playing of any game whereby any marble, ball, pellet or any moving object is propelled, rolled, shot or released toward a goal, pin, set of pins, or other objective by means of any plunger, ejector, mechanical bat, mechanical hand or by means of any other striking or releasing mechanism which is affixed or attached to the table or cabinet, or which is an integral part of the mechanical device or which is mechanically manipulated, controlled or guided, and which game is so contrived that, at the conclusion of the operation or play thereof the score or result of play thereof is visible or otherwise discernible so as to permit or make practicable the playing off or the awarding of a prize or reward upon the operation or play of the game.	4.	&#x201C;Claw, Hook, or Grab Machine&#x201D;: Any amusement machine or device so designed that articles placed or heaped therein for the purpose of the game may be grabbed, hooked, or otherwise displaced, recovered or removed by the operation of any contrivance simulating in miniature a power shovel, clam shell, dragline or similar excavating tool or machine.	5.	&#x201C;Horse Racing Machine&#x201D;: Any mechanically operated amusement machine or device contrived to simulate in miniature the running of a horse race or any other race run by beasts, humans or machines, or which is contrived to put in motion any number of objects or symbols which then do, or appear to, run or move against each other in the manner of a miniature race, or which is designed to represent, by symbols, the running of any race and the order of the finish thereof.	B.	It shall be unlawful for any person to keep, maintain or possess in any place of business or in any place of public resort:	1.	Any pin game, any marble game or any game similar to a marble game, any claw, hook or grab machine or any horse race machine, the operation of which game or machine is controlled, permitted or made available by placing therein a coin, plug, disc, key or token, or which is let for use, operation or play upon the payment or delivery of anything of value therefor, or upon the making of any purchase.	2.	Any mechanical device or mechanically operated contrivance for the playing of any game of chance, the use or operation of which is controlled, permitted or made available by placing therein any coin, plug, disk, key or token, or which is let for use, operation or play upon the payment or delivery of anything of value therefor, or upon the making of any purchase.	C.	The provisions of this section shall not apply to the keeping, possessing or exhibiting of any such mechanical contrivance or device at or in any mercantile store in which such mechanical contrivances or devices are kept solely for sale and which mechanical contrivances or devices members of the public are not permitted or allowed to operate, manipulate or play except as incident to a demonstration for the purpose of sale.	This section is not unconstitutional, although it pertains to machines in which a degree of skill may be developed.
	People v. Hambro, CR A 1856
	People v. Eisenberg CR A 1900
	People v. Chuba CR A 2391</text><type>section</type><prefixes><unit></unit></prefixes><entire_prefix></entire_prefix><prefix_anchor></prefix_anchor><level>1</level></unit></text></law>
