<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><section_number>49.84.11</section_number><edition_id>1</edition_id><section_id>3782</section_id><structure_id>47</structure_id><catch_line>Nuisance Abatement Lien.</catch_line><history></history><full_text>&#xA0; NUISANCE ABATEMENT LIEN.

	(A)	Summary Abatement.&#xA0; The City may summarily abate any nuisance resulting from the defacement of the property of another by graffiti or any other inscribed material at the expense of the minor or other person creating, causing, or committing the nuisance and make the expense of abatement of the nuisance a lien against the property of the person and a personal obligation against that person.

	(1)	The determination of responsibility shall be presumed by any confession, admission, guilty plea, or plea of nolo contendere to any violation of Section 594, 594.3, 640.5, 640.6, or 640.7 of the California Penal Code.

	(2)	In the case of a minor, responsibility shall be presumed by any confession, admission, or by the minor being declared a ward of the juvenile court pursuant to Section 602 of the Welfare and Institutions Code by reason of the commission of an act prohibited by Section 594, 594.3, 640.5, 640.6 or 640.7 of the Penal Code

	(B)	Joint and Several Liability of Parent(s) or Guardian(s).&#xA0; The parent or guardian having custody and control of a minor committing a nuisance described in Subsection (A), shall be jointly and severally liable with the minor for the expense of abatement.&#xA0; The unpaid expense of abatement of any nuisance resulting from the defacement of the property of another by graffiti or any other inscribed material shall become a lien against the property of a parent or guardian having custody and control of the minor, and a personal obligation against the parent or guardian having custody and control of the minor.

	(C)	Definitions.&#xA0; For purposes of this Section, the following definitions apply:

	(1)	&#x201C;Expense of abatement&#x201D; includes, but is not limited to, court costs, attorney&#x2019;s fees, costs of removal of the graffiti or other inscribed material, costs of repair and replacement of defaced property, and the law enforcement costs incurred by the City in identifying and apprehending the minor or other person.

	(2)	&#x201C;Minor&#x201D; or &#x201C;other person&#x201D; means a minor or other person who has confessed to, admitted to, or pled guilty or nolo contendere to a violation of&#xA0; Section 594, 594.3, 640.5, 640.6, or 640.7 of the California Penal Code; or a minor convicted by final judgment of a violation of Section 594, 594.3, 640.5, 640.6, or 640.7 of the California Penal Code; or a minor declared a ward of the juvenile court pursuant to Section 602 of the Welfare and Institutions Code by reason of the commission of an act prohibited by Section 594, 594.3, 640.5, 640.6 or 640.7 of the Penal Code.

	(D)	Procedures.

	(1)	Collection of Expenses of Abatement.&#xA0; Upon the determination of the expense of abatement, the City, Board of Public Works or its designated representative, shall send an abatement expense statement to the responsible person(s) pursuant to Subsection (A), and if applicable, Subsection (B), above.&#xA0; Payment shall be due fifteen (15) calendar days from the service of the abatement expense statement.

	(2)	Notice and Hearing.

	(a)	Within ten (10) calendar days of the mailing of the abatement expense statement, any person served with an abatement expense statement may file with the City representative who issued the statement, a written request for a hearing on the correctness, reasonableness, or both of such claim of abatement costs.

	(b)	Upon receipt of the written request for a hearing, the City representative who issued the statement shall send notice describing the time and place of such hearing by the United States mail, postage prepaid, addressed to the requesting party&#x2019;s last-known address at least five days in advance of the hearing.&#xA0;

	(c)	At the hearing, upon request, the city representative shall receive all evidence presented by the responsible person and by the City.&#xA0; Thereupon, the City representative shall make such revision, correction, and modification to the statement as deemed warranted, after which the statement as submitted, or as revised, corrected, or modified, shall be confirmed.&#xA0; The decision of the City representative shall be final.

	(d)	Suspension of Abatement Costs.&#xA0; The obligation to pay the expenses of abatement otherwise required under subsection (D)(1) of this section shall be suspended during the pendency of any hearing provided for under this Subsection.&#xA0; Upon the City representative rendering his or her decision following a hearing, payment of the confirmed or otherwise revised, corrected, or modified abatement expense statement shall be made within ten (10) calendar days following service of the City representative&#x2019;s decision upon the responsible person.

	(3)	Lien Against Property for Unpaid Expenses.

	(a)	The City may make the unpaid expenses of abatement a lien against the property of the person committing a nuisance described in Subsection (A), above, and, where such person is a minor, against the property of the parent or guardian having custody and control of such minor.

	(b)	Notice of Intent to Lien.&#xA0; Notice of Intent to record a lien shall be given to the minor or other person and to the parent or guardian having custody and control of the minor prior to the recordation of any lien.&#xA0; Said notice shall be served in the same manner as a civil action in accordance with the Code of Civil Procedure Section 415.10.&#xA0; If the minor or other person, and/or the parent or guardian having custody and control of the minor, after diligent search, cannot be found, the notice may be served by posting a copy of the Notice in a conspicuous place upon the property for a period ten (10) days and publication thereof in a newspaper of general circulation published in the county in which the property is located pursuant to Government Code Section 6062.

	(c)	Recordation.&#xA0; A graffiti nuisance abatement lien shall be recorded in the County Recorder&#x2019;s Office in the county in which the parcel of land is located and from the date of recording shall have the force, effect, and priority of a judgment lien.

	(d)	Specific Data.&#xA0; A graffiti nuisance abatement lien authorized by this section shall specify the amount of the lien; the name of the agency on whose behalf the lien is imposed; the date of the abatement order; the street address, legal description, and assessor&#x2019;s parcel number of the parcel on which the lien is imposed; and the name and address of the recorded owner of the parcel.

	(e)	Discharge.&#xA0; If the lien is discharged, released, or satisfied through payment or foreclosure, notice of the discharge containing the information specified in Subsection (d), above, shall be recorded by the governmental agency.&#xA0; A graffiti nuisance abatement lien and the release of the lien shall be indexed in the grantor-grantee index.

	(f)	A graffiti nuisance abatement lien may be satisfied through foreclosure in an action brought by the City.

	(g)	The City may recover from the property owner any costs incurred regarding the processing and recording of the lien and providing notice to the property owner as part of its foreclosure action to enforce the lien.

	(E)	Alternative Procedure for Assessment.

	(1)	As an alternative to the nuisance lien described in subsection (A) and (B), above, the City may make the costs associated with the expense of abatement, as defined in Subsection (C), above, a special assessment against the parcel of land owned by the person committing a nuisance described in Subsection (A), above, and, where such person is a minor, against the property of the parent or guardian having custody and control of such minor.

	(2)	The assessment may be collected at the same time and in the same manner as ordinary municipal taxes are collected and shall be subject to the same penalties and the same procedure and sale in case of delinquency as provided for ordinary municipal taxes pursuant to Government Code Section 38773.7.

	(F)	Second or Subsequent Civil or Criminal Judgment.

	(1)	Upon the entry of a second or subsequent civil or criminal judgment within a two-year period finding that an owner of property or a minor or other person as defined in this Section is responsible for a condition that may be abated in accordance with this provision, except of conditions abated pursuant to Section 17980 of the Health and Safety Code, the court may order that person to pay treble the costs of the abatement.</full_text><order_by>84.11</order_by><ancestry><unit id="47" label="article"><name>Graffiti Removal And Recovery</name><identifier>14</identifier><url>/4/14/</url></unit><unit id="11" label="chapter"><name>Public Welfare</name><identifier>4</identifier><url>/4/</url></unit></ancestry><structure_contents><unit id="435"><structure_id>47</structure_id><section_number>49.84.1</section_number><catch_line>Purpose And Intent.</catch_line><url>/49.84.1/</url><token>49.84.1</token></unit><unit id="1916"><structure_id>47</structure_id><section_number>49.84.10</section_number><catch_line>Administrative Hearing.</catch_line><url>/49.84.10/</url><token>49.84.10</token></unit><unit id="3782"><structure_id>47</structure_id><section_number>49.84.11</section_number><catch_line>Nuisance Abatement Lien.</catch_line><url>/49.84.11/</url><token>49.84.11</token></unit><unit id="288"><structure_id>47</structure_id><section_number>49.84.12</section_number><catch_line>Penalties.</catch_line><url>/49.84.12/</url><token>49.84.12</token></unit><unit id="235"><structure_id>47</structure_id><section_number>49.84.13</section_number><catch_line>Severability.</catch_line><url>/49.84.13/</url><token>49.84.13</token></unit><unit id="903"><structure_id>47</structure_id><section_number>49.84.2</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/49.84.2/</url><token>49.84.2</token></unit><unit id="300"><structure_id>47</structure_id><section_number>49.84.3</section_number><catch_line>Graffiti Prohibited.</catch_line><url>/49.84.3/</url><token>49.84.3</token></unit><unit id="304"><structure_id>47</structure_id><section_number>49.84.4</section_number><catch_line>Display Of Aerosol Paint Containers And Marker Pens.</catch_line><url>/49.84.4/</url><token>49.84.4</token></unit><unit id="522"><structure_id>47</structure_id><section_number>49.84.5</section_number><catch_line>Possession Of Specified Graffiti Implements Prohibited In Designated Areas.</catch_line><url>/49.84.5/</url><token>49.84.5</token></unit><unit id="3245"><structure_id>47</structure_id><section_number>49.84.6</section_number><catch_line>Graffiti Declared A Public Nuisance.</catch_line><url>/49.84.6/</url><token>49.84.6</token></unit><unit id="3297"><structure_id>47</structure_id><section_number>49.84.7</section_number><catch_line>Graffiti Removal At City Expense.</catch_line><url>/49.84.7/</url><token>49.84.7</token></unit><unit id="89"><structure_id>47</structure_id><section_number>49.84.8</section_number><catch_line>Remedies When Owner Refuses To Consent.</catch_line><url>/49.84.8/</url><token>49.84.8</token></unit><unit id="396"><structure_id>47</structure_id><section_number>49.84.9</section_number><catch_line>City Funds To Be Recovered.</catch_line><url>/49.84.9/</url><token>49.84.9</token></unit></structure_contents><next_section id="288"><structure_id>47</structure_id><section_number>49.84.12</section_number><catch_line>Penalties.</catch_line><url>/49.84.12/</url><token>49.84.12</token></next_section><metadata></metadata><references></references><url>/49.84.11/</url><token>49.84.11</token><formats><txt>/49.84.11.txt</txt><json>/49.84.11.xml</json></formats><dublin_core><Title>Nuisance Abatement Lien.</Title><Type>Text</Type><Format>text/html</Format><Identifier>&#xA7; 49.84.11</Identifier><Relation>Los Angeles Municipal Code</Relation></dublin_core><plain_text>                            LOS ANGELES MUNICIPAL CODE

NUISANCE ABATEMENT LIEN. (&#xA7; 49.84.11)

&#xA0; NUISANCE ABATEMENT LIEN.	(A)	Summary Abatement.&#xA0; The City may summarily
abate any nuisance resulting from the defacement of the property of another by
graffiti or any other inscribed material at the expense of the minor or other
person creating, causing, or committing the nuisance and make the expense of
abatement of the nuisance a lien against the property of the person and a
personal obligation against that person.	(1)	The determination of responsibility
shall be presumed by any confession, admission, guilty plea, or plea of nolo
contendere to any violation of Section 594, 594.3, 640.5, 640.6, or 640.7 of the
California Penal Code.	(2)	In the case of a minor, responsibility shall be
presumed by any confession, admission, or by the minor being declared a ward of
the juvenile court pursuant to Section 602 of the Welfare and Institutions Code
by reason of the commission of an act prohibited by Section 594, 594.3, 640.5,
640.6 or 640.7 of the Penal Code	(B)	Joint and Several Liability of Parent(s) or
Guardian(s).&#xA0; The parent or guardian having custody and control of a minor
committing a nuisance described in Subsection (A), shall be jointly and
severally liable with the minor for the expense of abatement.&#xA0; The unpaid
expense of abatement of any nuisance resulting from the defacement of the
property of another by graffiti or any other inscribed material shall become a
lien against the property of a parent or guardian having custody and control of
the minor, and a personal obligation against the parent or guardian having
custody and control of the minor.	(C)	Definitions.&#xA0; For purposes of this
Section, the following definitions apply:	(1)	&#x201C;Expense of abatement&#x201D;
includes, but is not limited to, court costs, attorney&#x2019;s fees, costs of
removal of the graffiti or other inscribed material, costs of repair and
replacement of defaced property, and the law enforcement costs incurred by the
City in identifying and apprehending the minor or other person.	(2)	&#x201C;Minor&#x201D;
or &#x201C;other person&#x201D; means a minor or other person who has confessed to,
admitted to, or pled guilty or nolo contendere to a violation of&#xA0; Section 594,
594.3, 640.5, 640.6, or 640.7 of the California Penal Code; or a minor convicted
by final judgment of a violation of Section 594, 594.3, 640.5, 640.6, or 640.7
of the California Penal Code; or a minor declared a ward of the juvenile court
pursuant to Section 602 of the Welfare and Institutions Code by reason of the
commission of an act prohibited by Section 594, 594.3, 640.5, 640.6 or 640.7 of
the Penal Code.	(D)	Procedures.	(1)	Collection of Expenses of Abatement.&#xA0; Upon
the determination of the expense of abatement, the City, Board of Public Works
or its designated representative, shall send an abatement expense statement to
the responsible person(s) pursuant to Subsection (A), and if applicable,
Subsection (B), above.&#xA0; Payment shall be due fifteen (15) calendar days from
the service of the abatement expense statement.	(2)	Notice and
Hearing.	(a)	Within ten (10) calendar days of the mailing of the abatement
expense statement, any person served with an abatement expense statement may
file with the City representative who issued the statement, a written request
for a hearing on the correctness, reasonableness, or both of such claim of
abatement costs.	(b)	Upon receipt of the written request for a hearing, the City
representative who issued the statement shall send notice describing the time
and place of such hearing by the United States mail, postage prepaid, addressed
to the requesting party&#x2019;s last-known address at least five days in advance of
the hearing.&#xA0;	(c)	At the hearing, upon request, the city representative shall
receive all evidence presented by the responsible person and by the City.&#xA0;
Thereupon, the City representative shall make such revision, correction, and
modification to the statement as deemed warranted, after which the statement as
submitted, or as revised, corrected, or modified, shall be confirmed.&#xA0; The
decision of the City representative shall be final.	(d)	Suspension of Abatement
Costs.&#xA0; The obligation to pay the expenses of abatement otherwise required
under subsection (D)(1) of this section shall be suspended during the pendency
of any hearing provided for under this Subsection.&#xA0; Upon the City
representative rendering his or her decision following a hearing, payment of the
confirmed or otherwise revised, corrected, or modified abatement expense
statement shall be made within ten (10) calendar days following service of the
City representative&#x2019;s decision upon the responsible person.	(3)	Lien Against
Property for Unpaid Expenses.	(a)	The City may make the unpaid expenses of
abatement a lien against the property of the person committing a nuisance
described in Subsection (A), above, and, where such person is a minor, against
the property of the parent or guardian having custody and control of such
minor.	(b)	Notice of Intent to Lien.&#xA0; Notice of Intent to record a lien shall
be given to the minor or other person and to the parent or guardian having
custody and control of the minor prior to the recordation of any lien.&#xA0; Said
notice shall be served in the same manner as a civil action in accordance with
the Code of Civil Procedure Section 415.10.&#xA0; If the minor or other person,
and/or the parent or guardian having custody and control of the minor, after
diligent search, cannot be found, the notice may be served by posting a copy of
the Notice in a conspicuous place upon the property for a period ten (10) days
and publication thereof in a newspaper of general circulation published in the
county in which the property is located pursuant to Government Code Section
6062.	(c)	Recordation.&#xA0; A graffiti nuisance abatement lien shall be recorded in
the County Recorder&#x2019;s Office in the county in which the parcel of land is
located and from the date of recording shall have the force, effect, and
priority of a judgment lien.	(d)	Specific Data.&#xA0; A graffiti nuisance abatement
lien authorized by this section shall specify the amount of the lien; the name
of the agency on whose behalf the lien is imposed; the date of the abatement
order; the street address, legal description, and assessor&#x2019;s parcel number of
the parcel on which the lien is imposed; and the name and address of the
recorded owner of the parcel.	(e)	Discharge.&#xA0; If the lien is discharged,
released, or satisfied through payment or foreclosure, notice of the discharge
containing the information specified in Subsection (d), above, shall be recorded
by the governmental agency.&#xA0; A graffiti nuisance abatement lien and the release
of the lien shall be indexed in the grantor-grantee index.	(f)	A graffiti
nuisance abatement lien may be satisfied through foreclosure in an action
brought by the City.	(g)	The City may recover from the property owner any costs
incurred regarding the processing and recording of the lien and providing notice
to the property owner as part of its foreclosure action to enforce the
lien.	(E)	Alternative Procedure for Assessment.	(1)	As an alternative to the
nuisance lien described in subsection (A) and (B), above, the City may make the
costs associated with the expense of abatement, as defined in Subsection (C),
above, a special assessment against the parcel of land owned by the person
committing a nuisance described in Subsection (A), above, and, where such person
is a minor, against the property of the parent or guardian having custody and
control of such minor.	(2)	The assessment may be collected at the same time and
in the same manner as ordinary municipal taxes are collected and shall be
subject to the same penalties and the same procedure and sale in case of
delinquency as provided for ordinary municipal taxes pursuant to Government Code
Section 38773.7.	(F)	Second or Subsequent Civil or Criminal Judgment.	(1)	Upon
the entry of a second or subsequent civil or criminal judgment within a two-year
period finding that an owner of property or a minor or other person as defined
in this Section is responsible for a condition that may be abated in accordance
with this provision, except of conditions abated pursuant to Section 17980 of
the Health and Safety Code, the court may order that person to pay treble the
costs of the abatement.
</plain_text><html>
					&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#xA0; NUISANCE ABATEMENT &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;LIEN&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(A)	Summary Abatement.&#xA0; The City may summarily abate any nuisance resulting from the defacement of the property of another by graffiti or any other inscribed &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;material&lt;/span&gt; at the expense of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt; or other person creating, causing, or committing the nuisance and make the expense of abatement of the nuisance a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt; against the property of the person and a personal obligation against that person.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(1)	The determination of responsibility shall be presumed by any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;confession&lt;/span&gt;, admission, guilty &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;plea&lt;/span&gt;, or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;plea&lt;/span&gt; of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;nolo contendere&lt;/span&gt; to any violation of Section 594, 594.3, 640.5, 640.6, or 640.7 of the California Penal Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(2)	In the case of a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt;, responsibility shall be presumed by any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;confession&lt;/span&gt;, admission, or by the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt; being declared a ward of the juvenile &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;court&lt;/span&gt; pursuant to Section 602 of the Welfare and Institutions Code by reason of the commission of an act prohibited by Section 594, 594.3, 640.5, 640.6 or 640.7 of the Penal Code&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(B)	Joint and Several Liability of Parent(s) or Guardian(s).&#xA0; The parent or guardian having &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;custody&lt;/span&gt; and control of a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt; committing a nuisance described in Subsection (A), shall be jointly and severally liable with the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt; for the expense of abatement.&#xA0; The unpaid expense of abatement of any nuisance resulting from the defacement of the property of another by graffiti or any other inscribed &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;material&lt;/span&gt; shall become a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt; against the property of a parent or guardian having &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;custody&lt;/span&gt; and control of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt;, and a personal obligation against the parent or guardian having &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;custody&lt;/span&gt; and control of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(C)	Definitions.&#xA0; For purposes of this Section, the following definitions apply:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(1)	&#x201C;Expense of abatement&#x201D; includes, but is not limited to, &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;court&lt;/span&gt; costs, attorney&#x2019;s fees, costs of removal of the graffiti or other inscribed &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;material&lt;/span&gt;, costs of repair and replacement of defaced property, and the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;law&lt;/span&gt; enforcement costs incurred by the City in identifying and apprehending the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt; or other person.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(2)	&#x201C;&lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Minor&lt;/span&gt;&#x201D; or &#x201C;other person&#x201D; means a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt; or other person who has confessed to, admitted to, or pled guilty or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;nolo contendere&lt;/span&gt; to a violation of&#xA0; Section 594, 594.3, 640.5, 640.6, or 640.7 of the California Penal Code; or a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt; convicted by final &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;judgment&lt;/span&gt; of a violation of Section 594, 594.3, 640.5, 640.6, or 640.7 of the California Penal Code; or a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt; declared a ward of the juvenile &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;court&lt;/span&gt; pursuant to Section 602 of the Welfare and Institutions Code by reason of the commission of an act prohibited by Section 594, 594.3, 640.5, 640.6 or 640.7 of the Penal Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(D)	Procedures.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(1)	Collection of Expenses of Abatement.&#xA0; Upon the determination of the expense of abatement, the City, Board of Public Works or its designated representative, shall send an abatement expense statement to the responsible person(s) pursuant to Subsection (A), and if applicable, Subsection (B), above.&#xA0; Payment shall be due fifteen (15) calendar days from the service of the abatement expense statement.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(2)	Notice and &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Hearing&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(a)	Within ten (10) calendar days of the mailing of the abatement expense statement, any person served with an abatement expense statement may file with the City representative who issued the statement, a written request for a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; on the correctness, reasonableness, or both of such claim of abatement costs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(b)	Upon receipt of the written request for a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt;, the City representative who issued the statement shall send notice describing the time and place of such &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; by the United States mail, postage prepaid, addressed to the requesting &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;party&lt;/span&gt;&#x2019;s last-known address at least five days in advance of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(c)	At the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt;, upon request, the city representative shall receive all &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;evidence&lt;/span&gt; presented by the responsible person and by the City.&#xA0; Thereupon, the City representative shall make such revision, correction, and modification to the statement as deemed warranted, after which the statement as submitted, or as revised, corrected, or modified, shall be confirmed.&#xA0; The decision of the City representative shall be final.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(d)	Suspension of Abatement Costs.&#xA0; The obligation to pay the expenses of abatement otherwise required under subsection (D)(1) of this section shall be suspended during the pendency of any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; provided for under this Subsection.&#xA0; Upon the City representative rendering his or her decision following a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt;, payment of the confirmed or otherwise revised, corrected, or modified abatement expense statement shall be made within ten (10) calendar days following service of the City representative&#x2019;s decision upon the responsible person.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(3)	&lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Lien&lt;/span&gt; Against Property for Unpaid Expenses.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(a)	The City may make the unpaid expenses of abatement a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt; against the property of the person committing a nuisance described in Subsection (A), above, and, where such person is a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt;, against the property of the parent or guardian having &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;custody&lt;/span&gt; and control of such &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(b)	Notice of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Intent&lt;/span&gt; to &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Lien&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; Notice of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Intent&lt;/span&gt; to record a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt; shall be given to the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt; or other person and to the parent or guardian having &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;custody&lt;/span&gt; and control of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt; prior to the recordation of any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; Said notice shall be served in the same manner as a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;civil action&lt;/span&gt; in accordance with the Code of Civil Procedure Section 415.10.&#xA0; If the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt; or other person, and/or the parent or guardian having &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;custody&lt;/span&gt; and control of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt;, after diligent search, cannot be found, the notice may be served by posting a copy of the Notice in a conspicuous place upon the property for a period ten (10) days and publication thereof in a newspaper of general circulation published in the county in which the property is located pursuant to Government Code Section 6062.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(c)	Recordation.&#xA0; A graffiti nuisance abatement &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt; shall be recorded in the County Recorder&#x2019;s Office in the county in which the parcel of land is located and from the date of recording shall have the force, effect, and priority of a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;judgment&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(d)	Specific Data.&#xA0; A graffiti nuisance abatement &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt; authorized by this section shall specify the amount of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt;; the name of the agency on whose behalf the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt; is imposed; the date of the abatement &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt;; the street address, legal description, and assessor&#x2019;s parcel number of the parcel on which the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt; is imposed; and the name and address of the recorded owner of the parcel.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(e)	Discharge.&#xA0; If the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt; is discharged, released, or satisfied through payment or foreclosure, notice of the discharge containing the information specified in Subsection (d), above, shall be recorded by the governmental agency.&#xA0; A graffiti nuisance abatement &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt; and the release of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt; shall be indexed in the grantor-grantee index.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(f)	A graffiti nuisance abatement &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt; may be satisfied through foreclosure in an action brought by the City.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(g)	The City may recover from the property owner any costs incurred regarding the processing and recording of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt; and providing notice to the property owner as part of its foreclosure action to enforce the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(E)	Alternative Procedure for Assessment.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(1)	As an alternative to the nuisance &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;lien&lt;/span&gt; described in subsection (A) and (B), above, the City may make the costs associated with the expense of abatement, as defined in Subsection (C), above, a special assessment against the parcel of land owned by the person committing a nuisance described in Subsection (A), above, and, where such person is a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt;, against the property of the parent or guardian having &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;custody&lt;/span&gt; and control of such &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(2)	The assessment may be collected at the same time and in the same manner as ordinary municipal taxes are collected and shall be subject to the same penalties and the same procedure and sale in case of delinquency as provided for ordinary municipal taxes pursuant to Government Code Section 38773.7.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(F)	Second or Subsequent Civil or Criminal &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Judgment&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(1)	Upon the entry of a second or subsequent civil or criminal &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;judgment&lt;/span&gt; within a two-year period &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;finding&lt;/span&gt; that an owner of property or a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;minor&lt;/span&gt; or other person as defined in this Section is responsible for a condition that may be abated in accordance with this provision, except of conditions abated pursuant to Section 17980 of the Health and Safety Code, the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;court&lt;/span&gt; may &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; that person to pay treble the costs of the abatement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</html><previous_section id="1916"><structure_id>47</structure_id><section_number>49.84.10</section_number><catch_line>Administrative Hearing.</catch_line><url>/49.84.10/</url><token>49.84.10</token></previous_section><text><unit id="3756" prefix=""><text>&#xA0; NUISANCE ABATEMENT LIEN.	(A)	Summary Abatement.&#xA0; The City may summarily abate any nuisance resulting from the defacement of the property of another by graffiti or any other inscribed material at the expense of the minor or other person creating, causing, or committing the nuisance and make the expense of abatement of the nuisance a lien against the property of the person and a personal obligation against that person.	(1)	The determination of responsibility shall be presumed by any confession, admission, guilty plea, or plea of nolo contendere to any violation of Section 594, 594.3, 640.5, 640.6, or 640.7 of the California Penal Code.	(2)	In the case of a minor, responsibility shall be presumed by any confession, admission, or by the minor being declared a ward of the juvenile court pursuant to Section 602 of the Welfare and Institutions Code by reason of the commission of an act prohibited by Section 594, 594.3, 640.5, 640.6 or 640.7 of the Penal Code	(B)	Joint and Several Liability of Parent(s) or Guardian(s).&#xA0; The parent or guardian having custody and control of a minor committing a nuisance described in Subsection (A), shall be jointly and severally liable with the minor for the expense of abatement.&#xA0; The unpaid expense of abatement of any nuisance resulting from the defacement of the property of another by graffiti or any other inscribed material shall become a lien against the property of a parent or guardian having custody and control of the minor, and a personal obligation against the parent or guardian having custody and control of the minor.	(C)	Definitions.&#xA0; For purposes of this Section, the following definitions apply:	(1)	&#x201C;Expense of abatement&#x201D; includes, but is not limited to, court costs, attorney&#x2019;s fees, costs of removal of the graffiti or other inscribed material, costs of repair and replacement of defaced property, and the law enforcement costs incurred by the City in identifying and apprehending the minor or other person.	(2)	&#x201C;Minor&#x201D; or &#x201C;other person&#x201D; means a minor or other person who has confessed to, admitted to, or pled guilty or nolo contendere to a violation of&#xA0; Section 594, 594.3, 640.5, 640.6, or 640.7 of the California Penal Code; or a minor convicted by final judgment of a violation of Section 594, 594.3, 640.5, 640.6, or 640.7 of the California Penal Code; or a minor declared a ward of the juvenile court pursuant to Section 602 of the Welfare and Institutions Code by reason of the commission of an act prohibited by Section 594, 594.3, 640.5, 640.6 or 640.7 of the Penal Code.	(D)	Procedures.	(1)	Collection of Expenses of Abatement.&#xA0; Upon the determination of the expense of abatement, the City, Board of Public Works or its designated representative, shall send an abatement expense statement to the responsible person(s) pursuant to Subsection (A), and if applicable, Subsection (B), above.&#xA0; Payment shall be due fifteen (15) calendar days from the service of the abatement expense statement.	(2)	Notice and Hearing.	(a)	Within ten (10) calendar days of the mailing of the abatement expense statement, any person served with an abatement expense statement may file with the City representative who issued the statement, a written request for a hearing on the correctness, reasonableness, or both of such claim of abatement costs.	(b)	Upon receipt of the written request for a hearing, the City representative who issued the statement shall send notice describing the time and place of such hearing by the United States mail, postage prepaid, addressed to the requesting party&#x2019;s last-known address at least five days in advance of the hearing.&#xA0;	(c)	At the hearing, upon request, the city representative shall receive all evidence presented by the responsible person and by the City.&#xA0; Thereupon, the City representative shall make such revision, correction, and modification to the statement as deemed warranted, after which the statement as submitted, or as revised, corrected, or modified, shall be confirmed.&#xA0; The decision of the City representative shall be final.	(d)	Suspension of Abatement Costs.&#xA0; The obligation to pay the expenses of abatement otherwise required under subsection (D)(1) of this section shall be suspended during the pendency of any hearing provided for under this Subsection.&#xA0; Upon the City representative rendering his or her decision following a hearing, payment of the confirmed or otherwise revised, corrected, or modified abatement expense statement shall be made within ten (10) calendar days following service of the City representative&#x2019;s decision upon the responsible person.	(3)	Lien Against Property for Unpaid Expenses.	(a)	The City may make the unpaid expenses of abatement a lien against the property of the person committing a nuisance described in Subsection (A), above, and, where such person is a minor, against the property of the parent or guardian having custody and control of such minor.	(b)	Notice of Intent to Lien.&#xA0; Notice of Intent to record a lien shall be given to the minor or other person and to the parent or guardian having custody and control of the minor prior to the recordation of any lien.&#xA0; Said notice shall be served in the same manner as a civil action in accordance with the Code of Civil Procedure Section 415.10.&#xA0; If the minor or other person, and/or the parent or guardian having custody and control of the minor, after diligent search, cannot be found, the notice may be served by posting a copy of the Notice in a conspicuous place upon the property for a period ten (10) days and publication thereof in a newspaper of general circulation published in the county in which the property is located pursuant to Government Code Section 6062.	(c)	Recordation.&#xA0; A graffiti nuisance abatement lien shall be recorded in the County Recorder&#x2019;s Office in the county in which the parcel of land is located and from the date of recording shall have the force, effect, and priority of a judgment lien.	(d)	Specific Data.&#xA0; A graffiti nuisance abatement lien authorized by this section shall specify the amount of the lien; the name of the agency on whose behalf the lien is imposed; the date of the abatement order; the street address, legal description, and assessor&#x2019;s parcel number of the parcel on which the lien is imposed; and the name and address of the recorded owner of the parcel.	(e)	Discharge.&#xA0; If the lien is discharged, released, or satisfied through payment or foreclosure, notice of the discharge containing the information specified in Subsection (d), above, shall be recorded by the governmental agency.&#xA0; A graffiti nuisance abatement lien and the release of the lien shall be indexed in the grantor-grantee index.	(f)	A graffiti nuisance abatement lien may be satisfied through foreclosure in an action brought by the City.	(g)	The City may recover from the property owner any costs incurred regarding the processing and recording of the lien and providing notice to the property owner as part of its foreclosure action to enforce the lien.	(E)	Alternative Procedure for Assessment.	(1)	As an alternative to the nuisance lien described in subsection (A) and (B), above, the City may make the costs associated with the expense of abatement, as defined in Subsection (C), above, a special assessment against the parcel of land owned by the person committing a nuisance described in Subsection (A), above, and, where such person is a minor, against the property of the parent or guardian having custody and control of such minor.	(2)	The assessment may be collected at the same time and in the same manner as ordinary municipal taxes are collected and shall be subject to the same penalties and the same procedure and sale in case of delinquency as provided for ordinary municipal taxes pursuant to Government Code Section 38773.7.	(F)	Second or Subsequent Civil or Criminal Judgment.	(1)	Upon the entry of a second or subsequent civil or criminal judgment within a two-year period finding that an owner of property or a minor or other person as defined in this Section is responsible for a condition that may be abated in accordance with this provision, except of conditions abated pursuant to Section 17980 of the Health and Safety Code, the court may order that person to pay treble the costs of the abatement.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><unit></unit></prefixes><entire_prefix></entire_prefix><prefix_anchor></prefix_anchor><level>1</level></unit></text></law>
