<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><section_number>62.132</section_number><edition_id>1</edition_id><section_id>3417</section_id><structure_id>36</structure_id><catch_line>Street Banners.</catch_line><history></history><full_text>&#xA0; STREET BANNERS.
	(Added by Ord. No. 86,614, Eff. 7/31/42.)

	(a)	Purpose.&#xA0; The purpose of this ordinance is to provide a limited availability for charitable and non-profit entities to advertise their event or a series of events utilizing the City of Los Angeles&#x2019; street light poles according to the criteria set forth below.&#xA0; It is not the intent of the City to provide a general public forum or to allow non-City entities or persons to post messages on the City&#x2019;s light poles by the use of street banners.&#xA0; The City shall not discriminate based on the content of the requested event banner, nor based on the nature of the event, provided that the requested banner meets all requirements of this ordinance.&#xA0; In no way shall this ordinance be construed to limit the City&#x2019;s inherent right to hang City sponsored street banners from municipal street light poles.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	(b)	Definitions.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (a) Redesignated as Subsec. (b) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	1.	&#x201C;Street Banner.&#x201D;&#xA0; Any pennant, streamer, flag, sign, picture, figure or other object, regardless of the material of which it is made, which is suspended or otherwise displayed over any public street, way or place, designed for decoration or advertisement, or to attract the attention of passersby; except, however, official warning devices, public service facilities, street lights and the like. The term shall not include signs the installation and maintenance of which is regulated by Article 1, Chapter 9 of this Code.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 89,977, Eff. 1/28/46.)

	2.	&#x201C;Each Installation.&#x201D;&#xA0; Each wire or rope from which one or more street banner are suspended shall be deemed to be one &#x201C;installation&#x201D;.&#xA0; Multiple banners suspended from a single pole shall also be deemed one installation, provided that the multiple banners comply with all other laws, rules and regulations covering street banners.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 172,899, Eff. 12/23/99.)

	3.	&#x201C;Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as something that takes place within the City of Los Angeles at a venue that is open for attendance by the City&#x2019;s citizens regardless of their age, gender, race, religion or physical disability.&#xA0; A telethon or phone-a-thon shall be considered an &#x201C;event&#x201D; under this definition if it meets all other requirements of this ordinance.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	4.	&#x201C;Community Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as an event, or a series of events that promotes civic pride in a local community within the City of Los Angeles or the City of Los Angeles as a whole, and that is not a purely commercial enterprise and where the proceeds, if any, will directly benefit either a charitable or non-profit organization.&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	5.	&#x201C;Charitable Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as an event, or a series of events where the proceeds, if any, will directly benefit a charitable organization that maintains its charitable status under Internal Revenue Code &#xA7; 501(c)(3).&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	6.	&#x201C;Non-Profit Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as an event, or series of events that is sponsored by an organization that is incorporated or otherwise organized as a non-profit organization under the laws of the State of California or the Internal Revenue Code and where the proceeds, if any, will directly benefit either a charitable or non-profit organization.&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	7.	&#x201C;City of Los Angeles Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as an event, or series of events that is organized and administered by the City of Los Angeles or by any of its operating departments, boards, commissions or bureaus and that has been approved by the City Council.&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	8.	&#x201C;Citywide Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as an event for which organizers will install in excess of 200 banners.&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	9.	&#x201C;Non-Event Banner.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as a banner that identifies or denotes on the banner an area, community, district or other recognized geographic portion of the City of Los Angeles, such as a Business Improvement District, or contains a public service announcement from the City and meets all other requirements of this ordinance.&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	(c)	&#x2013; General Prohibition.&#xA0; No street banners shall be installed in the public right of way except for street banners expressly authorized by subsection (d) below.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (b) Redesignated as Subsec. (c) and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	(d)	Street Banners &#x2013; Exemptions from General Prohibition. (Former Subsec. (c) Redesignated as Subsec. (d) and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	(1)	The City of Los Angeles may hang, or authorize a third party to hang on its behalf, street banners that announce a City of Los Angeles event.&#xA0; The City Council may also authorize the hanging of City of Los Angeles sponsored non-event street banners, including street banners requested by any of the City&#x2019;s operating departments, boards, commissions, bureaus or requested by other governmental entities, that do not announce a specific event but that contain public service announcements or that identify or denote on the banner an area, community, district or other recognized geographic portion of the City of Los Angeles, such as a Business Improvement District.&#xA0; All banners requested by other governmental entities, other than the City of Los Angeles, shall be subject to the applicable fees as authorized in this code.

	(2)	The City of Los Angeles may issue a permit to hang event street banners that announce either a Community event, a Charitable event or a Non-Profit event or non-event street banners requested by a charitable or nonprofit entity that identify or denote on the banner an area, community, district or other recognized geographic portion of the City of Los Angeles, such as a Business Improvement District.

	(e)	Street Banners &#x2013; Content.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	(1)	The text on all event street banners that announce Community, Charitable or Non-Profit events shall be limited to the following content: the name of the event; the name of the charitable or non-profit organization who is the permit applicant, and, if the name of the organization is in a language other than English, the English translation of the name; the date of the event; the time of the event; the location of the event and, if desired by the applicant, either a telephone number or web address for persons to obtain additional information concerning the event. The name of any event shall be no more than 8 words and contain no more than 50 letters.

	(2)	The content of all community identity non-event street banners shall be limited to the name of the area, community, district or other recognized geographic portion of the City of Los Angeles such as a Business Improvement District and may contain an introductory word or words, such as &#x201C;Welcome to&#x201D; or &#x201C;Entering.&#x201D; City of Los Angeles non-event banners may contain public service information or messages.

	(f)	Permit Required.&#xA0; No person shall install or maintain any street banner without a permit therefor from the Board of Public Works.&#xA0; A separate permit shall be required for each banner design and location, but all street banners suspended in one city block, or in a number of contiguous city blocks, by one permittee, shall be deemed to be at the same location.&#xA0; Permits shall not be issued for light poles on streets where the adjoining land use is primarily single-family residential.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (d) Redesignated as Subsec. (f) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	(g)	Application and Fee.&#xA0; Applications for permits shall be made jointly by the primary event sponsor and the commercial entity installing the banners upon forms prescribed by the Board.&#xA0; The application must include a clear replica of the proposed banner or banners, including any text on said banners, for each proposed installation, and said application shall also include all other information required by the Board for the protection of public safety, welfare and property.&#xA0; One application may include any number of locations, provided that the applicant must submit replicas of all different banners proposed to be installed under the single application.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (f) Redesignated as Subsec. (g) and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	(h)	Insurance Policy to be Posted.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (g) Redesignated as Subsec. (h) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&#xA0; No permit shall be issued hereunder unless the commercial entity installing the street banners has on file with the Board a satisfactory policy of insurance so conditioned as to insure the City, its officers and employees against any loss, cost, expense, injury, damage or liability incurred by reason of any personal injury or property damage sustained by any person, caused by or resulting from or which may be claimed to have been caused by or to have resulted from, the installation or maintenance of any street banner or appurtenance installed under the permit, or from any failure to install or maintain any such street banner or appurtenance in the manner required by this ordinance or by rule, regulation or order of the Board, or from any dangerous or defective condition or nuisance created thereby or resulting therefrom.&#xA0; Furthermore, by the policy, the City, its officers and employees as named assures, must be insured against any property damage or personal injury resulting from any such cause.

	In addition, the policy shall be so conditioned as to assure the ability of the applicant to respond in damages, in any action brought for personal injury or property damage sustained by any person, based upon any ground mentioned above.

	The limit of liability upon any policy posted or maintained hereunder shall not be less than $500,000.

	(i)	Bond or Cash Deposit.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (h) Redesignated as Subsec. (i) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&#xA0; No permit shall be issued hereunder unless in addition to the insurance policy herein above required, the applicant commercial entity installing street banners posts or has on file with the Board a surety bond or cash deposit so conditioned as to assure that the City shall be reimbursed for any expense that may be incurred by the Board in removing any street banner or appurtenance installed pursuant to the permit, in repairing damage to street lighting equipment resulting from the banner installation, or in otherwise enforcing any order, rule or relation of the Board.&#xA0; Upon the face of each application received, the Board shall indicate the amount of indemnity required upon each permit requested, which shall be at the reasonable discretion of the Board.&#xA0; The amount of the bond or cash deposit shall not be less than the amount so indicated.&#xA0; The unused portion of any cash, or other deposit shall be returned to the applicant.

	The applicant commercial entity installing street banners shall be required as a condition to obtaining a permit, to indemnify and hold harmless the City, the Department, its officers and employees, from any liability resulting from the applicant&#x2019;s use of the public property and shall execute the necessary agreements satisfactory to the City Attorney.

	(j)	Term Bond or Continuing Cash Deposit Acceptable.&#xA0; A separate bond or cash deposit may be posted in connection with each particular, but in lieu thereof, the Board may accept a term bond or a continuing cash deposit conditioned to cover all permits which may be issued to any one applicant commercial entity installing street banners during a specified period of not to exceed one year, provided, however, that when the total aggregate required indemnity on all permits requested by the applicant commercial street banner installation company is greater than the limit of liability on the term bond, or greater than the cash deposit maintained, no additional permits shall be issued to the applicant commercial street banner installation company until sufficient additional indemnity to cover the same is furnished.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (i) Redesignated as Subsec. (j) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	(k)	Permits &#x2013; Issuance &#x2013; Denial.&#xA0; Provided that any application for a permit to hang a street banner or banners meets the eligibility requirements of this ordinance, the Board shall issue, in whole or in part, a permit authorizing the installation of the requested street banner or banners, as long as the required fees, bond, insurance policy and other protection prescribed above have been posted and approved and provided the installation of such banner or banners will not damage public property, unreasonably interfere with its proper use, or endanger public safety or welfare, as determined by the Board of Public Works.&#xA0; Each street banner permit application shall be reviewed by staff in consultation with the City Attorney to determine if the request complies with all the requirements of this ordinance.&#xA0; If staff determines that the request is in full compliance with this ordinance, the permit shall be issued.&#xA0; If staff determines that the application is not in compliance with this ordinance, staff shall timely notify the applicant of the reason or reasons for non-compliance and, if possible, suggest what could be done to bring the street banner request into compliance with the ordinance.&#xA0; If a street banner request is ultimately denied by the City, staff shall e-mail or fax the basis of the denial to the applicant.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (j) Redesignated as Subsec. (k) and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	(l)	Permit &#x2013; Duration.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (k) Redesignated as Subsec. (l) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	(1)	Single Event.&#xA0; The term of each permit shall be specified on the permit by the Board.&#xA0; The term of the permit for street banners announcing a single event shall not exceed 30 days.&#xA0; A permit may be renewed or extended for up to two additional 30 day terms. A permit may not be renewed or extended at any of the 30 day intervals when the City has on file, at the time of the requested extension, a permit application from a different entity seeking a permit for the same light poles occupied by the entity seeking the permit extension.&#xA0; The entity seeking the permit extension may request different light poles, if available, in instances where the original light poles are used by a new permittee.&#xA0; Under no circumstances shall a street banner announcing a single event installed pursuant to a permit issued pursuant to this code remain on the City&#x2019;s light standards for more than 90 days in a 12 month period.

	(2)	Series of Events.&#xA0; The term of each permit shall be specified on the permit by the Board.&#xA0; The term of the initial permit for street banners announcing a series of events shall not exceed 60 days.&#xA0; An initial permit may be renewed or extended for one additional 30 day term.&#xA0; After 90 days, pursuant to an initial permit with two renewals, a second permit application may be submitted for a term of 30 days to maintain the already installed street banners.&#xA0; The second permit may be renewed for up to two additional 30 day terms. A permit may not be renewed or extended at any of the 30 day intervals when the City has on file, at the time of the requested extension, a permit application from a different entity seeking a permit for the same light poles occupied by the entity seeking the permit extension.&#xA0; The entity seeking the permit extension may request different light poles, if available, in instances where the original light poles are used by a new permittee. Under no circumstances shall a street banner announcing a series of events installed pursuant to a permit issued pursuant to this code remain on the City&#x2019;s light standards for more than 180 days in a 12 month period.

	(3)	Non-Event.&#xA0; The term of each permit shall be specified on the permit by the Board.&#xA0; The term of the initial permit for non-event street banners shall not exceed 90 days.&#xA0; An initial permit may be renewed or extended for up to three additional 90 day terms.&#xA0; A permit may not be renewed or extended at any of the 90 day intervals when the City has on file, at the time of the requested extension, a permit application from a different entity seeking a permit for the same light poles occupied by the entity seeking the permit extension.&#xA0; The entity seeking the permit extension may request different light poles, if available, in instances where the original light poles are used by a new permittee.

	(m)	Permits &#x2013; Location of Street Banners Announcing an Event or Series of Events.&#xA0; All street banners announcing an event or series of events must be placed on all usable streetlight poles on one City block.&#xA0; Any permit to hang street banners announcing an event or series of events pursuant to this code shall be deemed a &#x201C;City-wide&#x201D; permit request if the number of light poles involved is 200 or more.&#xA0; If a permittee requests 200 or more light poles, the party requesting the permit may place a maximum of 50 street banners in the vicinity of the event venue and must place the remaining street banners equally in all Council districts.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (l) Redesignated as Subsec. (m) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	(n)	Permits &#x2013; Revocation.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (m) Redesignated as Subsec. (n) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&#xA0; Permits may be revoked by the Board in whole or in part on one or more of the following grounds:

	1.	The maintenance of any street banner endangers public welfare, safety or property;

	2.	Failure or refusal to observe any provision of this section or any rule promulgated by the Board pursuant to authority granted by this section; or

	3.	A material misrepresentation in the application.

	(o)	Removal of Street Banner.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (n) Redesignated as Subsec. (o) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&#xA0; Upon expiration of any permit, any street banner covered thereby must be removed by the permittee within 72 hours of the date of expiration unless a renewal or written extension is granted by the Board.&#xA0; Any street banner not so removed may be removed by the Board without notice to the permittee.&#xA0; Upon whole or partial revocation of any permit, all street banners covered thereby must be removed on the same date of revocation unless a renewal or written extension is granted by the Board.&#xA0; Any street banner not so removed shall, upon reasonable notice to the permittee, be removed by the Board.&#xA0; Where any street banner presents an immediate threat of harm to the public health, welfare or safety, the Board shall summarily cause its removal.

	The costs of all Board removals shall be collected by the Board from the permittee or from his surety.

	(p)	Installation and Maintenance of Street Banners.&#xA0; Every street banner must be installed and maintained so as to be safe at all times; it must not include a print size for any text smaller than that adopted by the Board of Public Works in its rules and regulations; it must not obstruct the clear view of traffic signals by pedestrians or operators of bicycles, motor bikes, cars, trucks or any other type of vehicle or mode of transportation; it must have a minimum clearance of 22 feet over rails used by freight cars, of 16 feet above roadways.&#xA0; The Board may prescribe other needed clearance requirements.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (o) Redesignated as Subsec. (p) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	(q)	Rules and Regulations.&#xA0; Consistent with this section, the Board may adopt rules or regulations to administer the installation, maintenance and removal of street banners including rules or regulations pertaining to their location, size, suspension and construction. The Board may adopt any other rule or regulation for the protection of public safety, welfare or property. (Former Subsec. (p) Redesignated as Subsec. (q) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	(r)	Commercial Content on Street Banners.&#xA0; Nothing in the general prohibition on street banners shall prevent a for-profit entity from receiving recognition on the street banners announcing an otherwise allowable Community, Charitable or Non-Profit event, or on permitted non-event street banners, provided that the recognition of the for-profit sponsorship shall be limited to the name and or logo of one for-profit sponsoring entity per street banner and the size of said name or logo shall be limited to less than 20% of the total area of the street banner.&#xA0; The City of Los Angeles may defray the cost of City of Los Angeles organized and administered events, and the cost of non-event street banners by allowing for-profit entities to co-sponsor City organized and administered events and non-event street banners, provided that the recognition of the for-profit entity&#x2019;s co-sponsorship of City events, or non-event street banners is limited to the same size and content as for allowable Community, Charitable, or Non-Profit events or permitted non-event street banners.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (q) Redesignated as Subsec. (r) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	(s)	The provisions of Article 7, Chapter 6, prohibiting certain outdoor advertising structures, post signs and advertising statuary adjacent to freeways, and establishing the procedure for the consideration and issuance of permits for such structures, signs and statuary, shall also apply in the same manner and degree to &#x201C;Street Banner&#x201D;.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (r) Redesignated as Subsec. (s) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)

	(t)	Street Banners &#x2013; City Ownership after 30 Days.&#xA0; Up to 3% of the street banners included in any permit application and hung in the City of Los Angeles for more than 30 days may become the property of the City of Los Angeles, if a permittee is notified, at least three days prior to the expiration of the permit, that the City wishes to take possession of the street banners once they are removed from the City&#x2019;s poles by the permittee. If so notified, the permittee shall return the banners to the City once they are removed from the City&#x2019;s poles.&#xA0; If the City fails to notify the permittee at least three days before the expiration of the permit that it wishes to take possession of the banners, the City shall forfeit its right of ownership over said banners.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (s) Redesignated as Subsec. (t) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)</full_text><order_by>132</order_by><ancestry><unit id="36" label="article"><name>Streets And Sidewalks</name><identifier>2</identifier><url>/6/2/</url></unit><unit id="5" label="chapter"><name>Public Works and Property</name><identifier>6</identifier><url>/6/</url></unit></ancestry><structure_contents><unit id="503"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.00</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/62.00/</url><token>62.00</token></unit><unit id="4003"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.01</section_number><catch_line>Removal Of Obstructing Structures.</catch_line><url>/62.01/</url><token>62.01</token></unit><unit id="1092"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.02</section_number><catch_line>Excavations In And Adjacent To Streets &#x2013; Permits.</catch_line><url>/62.02/</url><token>62.02</token></unit><unit id="257"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.03</section_number><catch_line>Excavations In And Adjacent To Streets &#x2013; Locations And Restrictions.</catch_line><url>/62.03/</url><token>62.03</token></unit><unit id="354"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.03.1</section_number><catch_line>Notification And Location Requirements.</catch_line><url>/62.03.1/</url><token>62.03.1</token></unit><unit id="633"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.03.2</section_number><catch_line>Specifications And Procedures For Above Ground Facilities Installations In The Public Rights-Of-Way.</catch_line><url>/62.03.2/</url><token>62.03.2</token></unit><unit id="2577"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.03.3</section_number><catch_line>Fine For Non-Compliance.</catch_line><url>/62.03.3/</url><token>62.03.3</token></unit><unit id="2901"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.03.4</section_number><catch_line>Appeal For Violation Of Above Ground Facility, Specification And Procedures.</catch_line><url>/62.03.4/</url><token>62.03.4</token></unit><unit id="1074"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.04</section_number><catch_line>Excavation In And Adjacent To Streets - Performance Of The Work</catch_line><url>/62.04/</url><token>62.04</token></unit><unit id="2911"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.05</section_number><catch_line>Excavations In And Adjacent To Streets &#x2013; Charges.</catch_line><url>/62.05/</url><token>62.05</token></unit><unit id="254"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.06</section_number><catch_line>Establishment Of A Street Damage Restoration Fee.</catch_line><url>/62.06/</url><token>62.06</token></unit><unit id="1012"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.08</section_number><catch_line>Specifications And Procedures For Above Ground Facilities Installations In The Public Rights-Of-Way.</catch_line><url>/62.08/</url><token>62.08</token></unit><unit id="1855"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.09</section_number><catch_line>Fine For Non-Compliance.</catch_line><url>/62.09/</url><token>62.09</token></unit><unit id="4089"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.10</section_number><catch_line>Appeal For Violation Of Above Ground Facility, Specification And Procedures.</catch_line><url>/62.10/</url><token>62.10</token></unit><unit id="2015"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.40</section_number><catch_line>Maintenance Holes &#x2013; Permit For Opening.</catch_line><url>/62.40/</url><token>62.40</token></unit><unit id="3718"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.41</section_number><catch_line>Maintenance Hole Permit Fees.</catch_line><url>/62.41/</url><token>62.41</token></unit><unit id="3596"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.42</section_number><catch_line>Manholes &#x2013; Emergency Openings.</catch_line><url>/62.42/</url><token>62.42</token></unit><unit id="3577"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.43</section_number><catch_line>Manholes &#x2013; Warning Signs.</catch_line><url>/62.43/</url><token>62.43</token></unit><unit id="1391"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.44</section_number><catch_line>Exemptions.</catch_line><url>/62.44/</url><token>62.44</token></unit><unit id="860"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.45</section_number><catch_line>Materials Or Equipment In Streets &#x2013; Permits, Regulations, Fees.</catch_line><url>/62.45/</url><token>62.45</token></unit><unit id="2971"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.46</section_number><catch_line>Permits &#x2013; Conditions.</catch_line><url>/62.46/</url><token>62.46</token></unit><unit id="622"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.47</section_number><catch_line>Permits &#x2013; Revocation.</catch_line><url>/62.47/</url><token>62.47</token></unit><unit id="1871"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.48</section_number><catch_line>Revocation Of Permits &#x2013; Work To Cease.</catch_line><url>/62.48/</url><token>62.48</token></unit><unit id="1616"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.49</section_number><catch_line>Building Material &#x2013; Deposit In Streets.</catch_line><url>/62.49/</url><token>62.49</token></unit><unit id="1540"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.50</section_number><catch_line>Building Material &#x2013; Illumination.</catch_line><url>/62.50/</url><token>62.50</token></unit><unit id="2758"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.51</section_number><catch_line>Building Material Deposits &#x2013; Cranes &#x2013; Restrictions.</catch_line><url>/62.51/</url><token>62.51</token></unit><unit id="4183"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.52</section_number><catch_line>Plaster &#x2013; Mixing On Street.</catch_line><url>/62.52/</url><token>62.52</token></unit><unit id="1409"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.53</section_number><catch_line>Permit To Be Exhibited.</catch_line><url>/62.53/</url><token>62.53</token></unit><unit id="3602"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.54</section_number><catch_line>Building Material &#x2013; Removal Of.</catch_line><url>/62.54/</url><token>62.54</token></unit><unit id="1162"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.55</section_number><catch_line>Permits &#x2013; Duration Of.</catch_line><url>/62.55/</url><token>62.55</token></unit><unit id="3343"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.56</section_number><catch_line>Building Material Permit Fees Exemptions.</catch_line><url>/62.56/</url><token>62.56</token></unit><unit id="191"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.57</section_number><catch_line>Elevated Sidewalks &#x2013; Permits.</catch_line><url>/62.57/</url><token>62.57</token></unit><unit id="2130"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.58</section_number><catch_line>Elevated Sidewalks &#x2013; Application.</catch_line><url>/62.58/</url><token>62.58</token></unit><unit id="838"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.59</section_number><catch_line>Elevated Sidewalks &#x2013; Where Permitted.</catch_line><url>/62.59/</url><token>62.59</token></unit><unit id="1596"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.60</section_number><catch_line>Revocation Of Permits.</catch_line><url>/62.60/</url><token>62.60</token></unit><unit id="2885"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.61</section_number><catch_line>Work Within Or On A Public Street Or Right-Of-Way, Obstruction Of A Public Street Or Right-Of-Way &#x2013; Permit Required, Regulations, Penalties For Non-Compliance.</catch_line><url>/62.61/</url><token>62.61</token></unit><unit id="2100"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.62</section_number><catch_line>Electric Wires On Streets &#x2013; Permit Required.</catch_line><url>/62.62/</url><token>62.62</token></unit><unit id="1747"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.63</section_number><catch_line>Electric Wires On Streets &#x2013; Power Of Board Over.</catch_line><url>/62.63/</url><token>62.63</token></unit><unit id="629"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.64</section_number><catch_line>Permit &#x2013; Contents Of.</catch_line><url>/62.64/</url><token>62.64</token></unit><unit id="3887"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.65</section_number><catch_line>Electric Wiring Must Be Safe.</catch_line><url>/62.65/</url><token>62.65</token></unit><unit id="2167"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.66</section_number><catch_line>Board &#x2013; Power To Decide Questions.</catch_line><url>/62.66/</url><token>62.66</token></unit><unit id="2632"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.67</section_number><catch_line>Permits &#x2013; Duration Of.</catch_line><url>/62.67/</url><token>62.67</token></unit><unit id="348"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.68</section_number><catch_line>Exemption &#x2013; Franchises.</catch_line><url>/62.68/</url><token>62.68</token></unit><unit id="2456"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.69</section_number><catch_line>Oil Pipe Lines &#x2013; Permits.</catch_line><url>/62.69/</url><token>62.69</token></unit><unit id="1850"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.70</section_number><catch_line>Oil Pipe Line &#x2013; Permit Application.</catch_line><url>/62.70/</url><token>62.70</token></unit><unit id="270"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.71</section_number><catch_line>Oil Pipe Line &#x2013; Permit &#x2013; Contents.</catch_line><url>/62.71/</url><token>62.71</token></unit><unit id="1310"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.72</section_number><catch_line>Oil Pipe Lines &#x2013; Regulations.</catch_line><url>/62.72/</url><token>62.72</token></unit><unit id="2994"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.73</section_number><catch_line>Oil Pipe Lines &#x2013; Permits &#x2013; Revocability Of.</catch_line><url>/62.73/</url><token>62.73</token></unit><unit id="228"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.74</section_number><catch_line>Oil Cables &#x2013; Permits.</catch_line><url>/62.74/</url><token>62.74</token></unit><unit id="4158"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.75</section_number><catch_line>Oil Cables &#x2013; Permit Applications.</catch_line><url>/62.75/</url><token>62.75</token></unit><unit id="1811"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.76</section_number><catch_line>Oil Cables &#x2013; Permit Contents.</catch_line><url>/62.76/</url><token>62.76</token></unit><unit id="3117"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.77</section_number><catch_line>Oil Cables &#x2013; Regulations.</catch_line><url>/62.77/</url><token>62.77</token></unit><unit id="4063"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.78</section_number><catch_line>Oil Cables &#x2013; Permits &#x2013; Revocability Of.</catch_line><url>/62.78/</url><token>62.78</token></unit><unit id="1489"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.79</section_number><catch_line>Oil &#x2013; Spilling On Streets.</catch_line><url>/62.79/</url><token>62.79</token></unit><unit id="1472"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.80</section_number><catch_line>Drainage Of Water Into Streets.</catch_line><url>/62.80/</url><token>62.80</token></unit><unit id="644"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.81</section_number><catch_line>Washing Private Alleys.</catch_line><url>/62.81/</url><token>62.81</token></unit><unit id="3007"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.82</section_number><catch_line>Public Utility Defined.</catch_line><url>/62.82/</url><token>62.82</token></unit><unit id="61"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.83.1</section_number><catch_line>House Movers &#x2013; Permits &#x2013; Conditions.</catch_line><url>/62.83.1/</url><token>62.83.1</token></unit><unit id="3081"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.84</section_number><catch_line>Board Of Public Works &#x2013; House Movers&#x2019; Permit/Issuance.</catch_line><url>/62.84/</url><token>62.84</token></unit><unit id="2544"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.85</section_number><catch_line>House Movers &#x2013; Compensation To Public Utilities.</catch_line><url>/62.85/</url><token>62.85</token></unit><unit id="232"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.86</section_number><catch_line>House Movers &#x2013; Interference With Utility Property.</catch_line><url>/62.86/</url><token>62.86</token></unit><unit id="4029"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.87</section_number><catch_line>House Mover &#x2013; Must Pay License.</catch_line><url>/62.87/</url><token>62.87</token></unit><unit id="3156"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.88</section_number><catch_line>House Movers &#x2013; Deposits.</catch_line><url>/62.88/</url><token>62.88</token></unit><unit id="2079"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.89</section_number><catch_line>House Movers &#x2013; Inspection.</catch_line><url>/62.89/</url><token>62.89</token></unit><unit id="783"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.90</section_number><catch_line>House Movers &#x2013; Methods Of Moving &#x2013; Rules And Regulations.</catch_line><url>/62.90/</url><token>62.90</token></unit><unit id="193"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.90.1</section_number><catch_line>House Movers &#x2013; Posting Of Relocation Permit.</catch_line><url>/62.90.1/</url><token>62.90.1</token></unit><unit id="988"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.91</section_number><catch_line>House Movers &#x2013; Damage To Streets.</catch_line><url>/62.91/</url><token>62.91</token></unit><unit id="2327"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.92</section_number><catch_line>House Movers - Deposit Deductions.</catch_line><url>/62.92/</url><token>62.92</token></unit><unit id="3755"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.93</section_number><catch_line>Housemoving &#x2013; Lights Required.</catch_line><url>/62.93/</url><token>62.93</token></unit><unit id="942"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.94</section_number><catch_line>Protection Of Sidewalks.</catch_line><url>/62.94/</url><token>62.94</token></unit><unit id="1875"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.94.1</section_number><catch_line>Protection Of Streets &#x2013; Tractors, Etc. Prohibited On.</catch_line><url>/62.94.1/</url><token>62.94.1</token></unit><unit id="1051"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.95</section_number><catch_line>Animals &#x2013; Driving On Streets &#x2013; Permit.</catch_line><url>/62.95/</url><token>62.95</token></unit><unit id="1583"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.95.1</section_number><catch_line>Horseback Riding Prohibited On Medians.</catch_line><url>/62.95.1/</url><token>62.95.1</token></unit><unit id="87"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.96</section_number><catch_line>Painting House Numbers On Curbs &#x2013; Permit Required.</catch_line><url>/62.96/</url><token>62.96</token></unit><unit id="161"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.97</section_number><catch_line>Vibroseis Surveys In Public Streets.</catch_line><url>/62.97/</url><token>62.97</token></unit><unit id="1526"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.103</section_number><catch_line>Parkways In Commercial And Industrial Zones &#x2013; Paving.</catch_line><url>/62.103/</url><token>62.103</token></unit><unit id="1564"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.104</section_number><catch_line>Curb And Sidewalk Repairs.</catch_line><url>/62.104/</url><token>62.104</token></unit><unit id="973"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.105</section_number><catch_line>Streets, Sidewalks And Other Improvements &#x2013; Permits Required.</catch_line><url>/62.105/</url><token>62.105</token></unit><unit id="3155"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.105.1</section_number><catch_line>Locations Of Driveway Approaches.</catch_line><url>/62.105.1/</url><token>62.105.1</token></unit><unit id="130"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.105.2</section_number><catch_line>Width Of Driveway Approach Apron.</catch_line><url>/62.105.2/</url><token>62.105.2</token></unit><unit id="1025"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.105.3</section_number><catch_line>Length Of Curb Space.</catch_line><url>/62.105.3/</url><token>62.105.3</token></unit><unit id="1464"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.105.4</section_number><catch_line>Slope Of Driveway Approaches.</catch_line><url>/62.105.4/</url><token>62.105.4</token></unit><unit id="3309"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.105.5</section_number><catch_line>Application For Deviations From The Provisions Of Sections 62.105.1(A), (B), (C) And (D), 62.105.2, 62.105.3 And 62.105.4.</catch_line><url>/62.105.5/</url><token>62.105.5</token></unit><unit id="613"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.105.6</section_number><catch_line>Testing And Analysis Of Materials Products, Services, Processes And Technologies.</catch_line><url>/62.105.6/</url><token>62.105.6</token></unit><unit id="2114"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.106</section_number><catch_line>Permits &#x2013; Classification Of.</catch_line><url>/62.106/</url><token>62.106</token></unit><unit id="3562"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.106.1</section_number><catch_line>Fees Charges For Preparation Of Required Reports By The City Engineer In Conjunction With Land Use Reviews.</catch_line><url>/62.106.1/</url><token>62.106.1</token></unit><unit id="2722"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.107</section_number><catch_line>Work Requirements.</catch_line><url>/62.107/</url><token>62.107</token></unit><unit id="2384"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.108</section_number><catch_line>Application &#x2013; Contents Of.</catch_line><url>/62.108/</url><token>62.108</token></unit><unit id="2745"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.109</section_number><catch_line>Class &#x201C;A&#x201D; Permit Fees.</catch_line><url>/62.109/</url><token>62.109</token></unit><unit id="124"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.109.1</section_number><catch_line>Class &#x201C;A&#x201D; Permit &#x2013; Fee Waiver Program.</catch_line><url>/62.109.1/</url><token>62.109.1</token></unit><unit id="1573"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.110</section_number><catch_line>Class &#x201C;B&#x201D; Permit Fees.</catch_line><url>/62.110/</url><token>62.110</token></unit><unit id="1129"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.111</section_number><catch_line>Class &#x201C;B&#x201D; Permits &#x2013; Plans &#x2013; Bonds &#x2013; Insurance.</catch_line><url>/62.111/</url><token>62.111</token></unit><unit id="924"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.112</section_number><catch_line>Inspector &#x2013; Application For.</catch_line><url>/62.112/</url><token>62.112</token></unit><unit id="1202"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.113</section_number><catch_line>Completion Of Work &#x2013; Certificate Of Acceptance.</catch_line><url>/62.113/</url><token>62.113</token></unit><unit id="1519"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.114</section_number><catch_line>Permits &#x2013; Duration &#x2013; Expiration &#x2013;Cancellation.</catch_line><url>/62.114/</url><token>62.114</token></unit><unit id="562"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.115</section_number><catch_line>Class "A" Permit Fee Refunds.</catch_line><url>/62.115/</url><token>62.115</token></unit><unit id="2116"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.116</section_number><catch_line>Permits &#x2013; Amount Of Work Allowed.</catch_line><url>/62.116/</url><token>62.116</token></unit><unit id="118"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.117</section_number><catch_line>Removal Of Debris.</catch_line><url>/62.117/</url><token>62.117</token></unit><unit id="2659"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.118</section_number><catch_line>Exemptions.</catch_line><url>/62.118/</url><token>62.118</token></unit><unit id="1429"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.118.1</section_number><catch_line>Special Improvements &#x2013; Payment &#x2013; Performance By Department.</catch_line><url>/62.118.1/</url><token>62.118.1</token></unit><unit id="3549"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.118.2</section_number><catch_line>Improvement In Public Streets &#x2013; Issuance Of Revocable Permits.</catch_line><url>/62.118.2/</url><token>62.118.2</token></unit><unit id="1962"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.119</section_number><catch_line>Railroads &#x2013; Street Paving.</catch_line><url>/62.119/</url><token>62.119</token></unit><unit id="1726"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.120</section_number><catch_line>Railroads &#x2013; Manner Of Asphalt Paving.</catch_line><url>/62.120/</url><token>62.120</token></unit><unit id="766"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.121</section_number><catch_line>Railroads &#x2013; Manner Of Improving Streets.</catch_line><url>/62.121/</url><token>62.121</token></unit><unit id="337"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.122</section_number><catch_line>Railroads &#x2013; Type Of Rails.</catch_line><url>/62.122/</url><token>62.122</token></unit><unit id="3298"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.123</section_number><catch_line>Railroads &#x2013; Change Of Rails.</catch_line><url>/62.123/</url><token>62.123</token></unit><unit id="496"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.124</section_number><catch_line>Railroad Rails &#x2013; Exemptions.</catch_line><url>/62.124/</url><token>62.124</token></unit><unit id="2368"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.125</section_number><catch_line>Railroads &#x2013; Time Of Completion Of Work.</catch_line><url>/62.125/</url><token>62.125</token></unit><unit id="3356"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.126</section_number><catch_line>Railroads &#x2013; Procedure For Replacing Rails.</catch_line><url>/62.126/</url><token>62.126</token></unit><unit id="1331"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.127</section_number><catch_line>Railroad &#x2013; Board May Order Repairs To Roadbed.</catch_line><url>/62.127/</url><token>62.127</token></unit><unit id="4163"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.128</section_number><catch_line>Railroads &#x2013; Hours Of Repair In Central Traffic District.</catch_line><url>/62.128/</url><token>62.128</token></unit><unit id="819"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.129</section_number><catch_line>Public Boulevards &#x2013; Use Of.</catch_line><url>/62.129/</url><token>62.129</token></unit><unit id="1141"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.130</section_number><catch_line>Sand &#x2013; Gravel On Streets.</catch_line><url>/62.130/</url><token>62.130</token></unit><unit id="1057"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.131</section_number><catch_line>Decorative Lights Over Streets And Sidewalks.</catch_line><url>/62.131/</url><token>62.131</token></unit><unit id="3417"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.132</section_number><catch_line>Street Banners.</catch_line><url>/62.132/</url><token>62.132</token></unit><unit id="105"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.133</section_number><catch_line>Canopies.</catch_line><url>/62.133/</url><token>62.133</token></unit><unit id="292"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.135</section_number><catch_line>Overloads &#x2013; Definitions.</catch_line><url>/62.135/</url><token>62.135</token></unit><unit id="2082"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.136</section_number><catch_line>Overloads &#x2013; Permits Required.</catch_line><url>/62.136/</url><token>62.136</token></unit><unit id="3499"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.137</section_number><catch_line>Overloads &#x2013; When Unlawful To Move Without Inspection.</catch_line><url>/62.137/</url><token>62.137</token></unit><unit id="1358"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.138</section_number><catch_line>Overloads, When Unlawful To Move In Any Event.</catch_line><url>/62.138/</url><token>62.138</token></unit><unit id="906"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.139</section_number><catch_line>Unattended Parking &#x2013; Prohibited.</catch_line><url>/62.139/</url><token>62.139</token></unit><unit id="1829"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.140</section_number><catch_line>Overloads &#x2013; Night Moving.</catch_line><url>/62.140/</url><token>62.140</token></unit><unit id="631"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.141</section_number><catch_line>Overloads &#x2013; Application For Permits.</catch_line><url>/62.141/</url><token>62.141</token></unit><unit id="3115"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.142</section_number><catch_line>Overloads &#x2013; Issuance Of Permits.</catch_line><url>/62.142/</url><token>62.142</token></unit><unit id="850"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.143</section_number><catch_line>Overloads &#x2013; 30 Day And Annual Permits.</catch_line><url>/62.143/</url><token>62.143</token></unit><unit id="1705"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.144</section_number><catch_line>Overloads &#x2013; Permits &#x2013; Limitations And Requirements.</catch_line><url>/62.144/</url><token>62.144</token></unit><unit id="723"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.145</section_number><catch_line>Overloads &#x2013; Insurance &#x2013; Bonds.</catch_line><url>/62.145/</url><token>62.145</token></unit><unit id="2533"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.146</section_number><catch_line>Overloads - Inspection.</catch_line><url>/62.146/</url><token>62.146</token></unit><unit id="3149"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.147</section_number><catch_line>Overloads &#x2013; Assignment Of Inspectors.</catch_line><url>/62.147/</url><token>62.147</token></unit><unit id="2718"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.148</section_number><catch_line>Overloads &#x2013; Displacement Of Property Of Public Utility.</catch_line><url>/62.148/</url><token>62.148</token></unit><unit id="2719"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.149</section_number><catch_line>Overloads &#x2013; Movement Of By Governmental Authorities.</catch_line><url>/62.149/</url><token>62.149</token></unit><unit id="1939"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.150</section_number><catch_line>Overloads &#x2013; Where Exceptions Are Permissible.</catch_line><url>/62.150/</url><token>62.150</token></unit><unit id="997"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.151</section_number><catch_line>Overloads &#x2013; Special Engineering Services For Large Or Heavy Loads.</catch_line><url>/62.151/</url><token>62.151</token></unit><unit id="2405"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.161</section_number><catch_line>Planting, Maintenance And Care Of Plants In City Streets &#x2013; Jurisdiction Of Board.</catch_line><url>/62.161/</url><token>62.161</token></unit><unit id="2498"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.162</section_number><catch_line>Power To Plant, Maintain And Issue Permits.</catch_line><url>/62.162/</url><token>62.162</token></unit><unit id="887"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.163</section_number><catch_line>Duties Regarding Maintenance Of Plants.</catch_line><url>/62.163/</url><token>62.163</token></unit><unit id="3453"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.164</section_number><catch_line>Tree Planting Records &#x2013; Plans.</catch_line><url>/62.164/</url><token>62.164</token></unit><unit id="390"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.165</section_number><catch_line>Board To Prepare Reports.</catch_line><url>/62.165/</url><token>62.165</token></unit><unit id="696"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.166</section_number><catch_line>Street Obstructions By Trees &#x2013; Jurisdiction.</catch_line><url>/62.166/</url><token>62.166</token></unit><unit id="2766"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.167</section_number><catch_line>Assessment Levy For Planting.</catch_line><url>/62.167/</url><token>62.167</token></unit><unit id="2022"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.168</section_number><catch_line>Removal Of Obstructing Plants.</catch_line><url>/62.168/</url><token>62.168</token></unit><unit id="1418"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.169</section_number><catch_line>Permit Required To Plant In Streets.</catch_line><url>/62.169/</url><token>62.169</token></unit><unit id="2735"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.170</section_number><catch_line>Conditional Permit To Remove Or Destroy Trees.</catch_line><url>/62.170/</url><token>62.170</token></unit><unit id="2494"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.171</section_number><catch_line>Permit Fees For Tree Removal.</catch_line><url>/62.171/</url><token>62.171</token></unit><unit id="1068"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.172</section_number><catch_line>House Moving &#x2013; Permit.</catch_line><url>/62.172/</url><token>62.172</token></unit><unit id="3134"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.173</section_number><catch_line>Tree Stakes Or Guards.</catch_line><url>/62.173/</url><token>62.173</token></unit><unit id="2703"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.174</section_number><catch_line>Injury To Trees.</catch_line><url>/62.174/</url><token>62.174</token></unit><unit id="917"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.175</section_number><catch_line>Tree Maintenance.</catch_line><url>/62.175/</url><token>62.175</token></unit><unit id="1236"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.176</section_number><catch_line>Street Maintenance Fee.</catch_line><url>/62.176/</url><token>62.176</token></unit><unit id="623"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.200</section_number><catch_line>Street Intersections &#x2013; Obstructions To Visibility.</catch_line><url>/62.200/</url><token>62.200</token></unit><unit id="2162"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.201</section_number><catch_line>Import And Export Of Earth Materials &#x2013; Fees Required.</catch_line><url>/62.201/</url><token>62.201</token></unit><unit id="2172"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.202</section_number><catch_line>Import And Export Of Earth Materials &#x2013; Bonded Requirement.</catch_line><url>/62.202/</url><token>62.202</token></unit><unit id="2628"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.203</section_number><catch_line>Special Event Permit Procedure For Westwood
Village.</catch_line><url>/62.203/</url><token>62.203</token></unit></structure_contents><next_section id="105"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.133</section_number><catch_line>Canopies.</catch_line><url>/62.133/</url><token>62.133</token></next_section><metadata></metadata><references></references><url>/62.132/</url><token>62.132</token><formats><txt>/62.132.txt</txt><json>/62.132.xml</json></formats><dublin_core><Title>Street Banners.</Title><Type>Text</Type><Format>text/html</Format><Identifier>&#xA7; 62.132</Identifier><Relation>Los Angeles Municipal Code</Relation></dublin_core><plain_text>                            LOS ANGELES MUNICIPAL CODE

STREET BANNERS. (&#xA7; 62.132)

&#xA0; STREET BANNERS.
	(Added by Ord. No. 86,614, Eff. 7/31/42.)	(a)	Purpose.&#xA0; The purpose of this
ordinance is to provide a limited availability for charitable and non-profit
entities to advertise their event or a series of events utilizing the City of
Los Angeles&#x2019; street light poles according to the criteria set forth below.&#xA0;
It is not the intent of the City to provide a general public forum or to allow
non-City entities or persons to post messages on the City&#x2019;s light poles by the
use of street banners.&#xA0; The City shall not discriminate based on the content of
the requested event banner, nor based on the nature of the event, provided that
the requested banner meets all requirements of this ordinance.&#xA0; In no way shall
this ordinance be construed to limit the City&#x2019;s inherent right to hang City
sponsored street banners from municipal street light poles.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No.
176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(b)	Definitions.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (a) Redesignated as
Subsec. (b) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	1.	&#x201C;Street Banner.&#x201D;&#xA0; Any
pennant, streamer, flag, sign, picture, figure or other object, regardless of
the material of which it is made, which is suspended or otherwise displayed over
any public street, way or place, designed for decoration or advertisement, or to
attract the attention of passersby; except, however, official warning devices,
public service facilities, street lights and the like. The term shall not
include signs the installation and maintenance of which is regulated by Article
1, Chapter 9 of this Code.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 89,977, Eff.
1/28/46.)	2.	&#x201C;Each Installation.&#x201D;&#xA0; Each wire or rope from which one or more
street banner are suspended shall be deemed to be one &#x201C;installation&#x201D;.&#xA0;
Multiple banners suspended from a single pole shall also be deemed one
installation, provided that the multiple banners comply with all other laws,
rules and regulations covering street banners.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 172,899,
Eff. 12/23/99.)	3.	&#x201C;Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as something that takes place
within the City of Los Angeles at a venue that is open for attendance by the
City&#x2019;s citizens regardless of their age, gender, race, religion or physical
disability.&#xA0; A telethon or phone-a-thon shall be considered an &#x201C;event&#x201D;
under this definition if it meets all other requirements of this ordinance.&#xA0;
(Added by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	4.	&#x201C;Community Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be
defined as an event, or a series of events that promotes civic pride in a local
community within the City of Los Angeles or the City of Los Angeles as a whole,
and that is not a purely commercial enterprise and where the proceeds, if any,
will directly benefit either a charitable or non-profit organization.&#xA0;
(Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	5.	&#x201C;Charitable
Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as an event, or a series of events where the
proceeds, if any, will directly benefit a charitable organization that maintains
its charitable status under Internal Revenue Code &#xA7; 501(c)(3).&#xA0; (Renumbered
and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	6.	&#x201C;Non-Profit Event.&#x201D;&#xA0;
Shall be defined as an event, or series of events that is sponsored by an
organization that is incorporated or otherwise organized as a non-profit
organization under the laws of the State of California or the Internal Revenue
Code and where the proceeds, if any, will directly benefit either a charitable
or non-profit organization.&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff.
6/14/05.)	7.	&#x201C;City of Los Angeles Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as an event, or
series of events that is organized and administered by the City of Los Angeles
or by any of its operating departments, boards, commissions or bureaus and that
has been approved by the City Council.&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No.
176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	8.	&#x201C;Citywide Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as an event
for which organizers will install in excess of 200 banners.&#xA0; (Renumbered and
Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	9.	&#x201C;Non-Event Banner.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall
be defined as a banner that identifies or denotes on the banner an area,
community, district or other recognized geographic portion of the City of Los
Angeles, such as a Business Improvement District, or contains a public service
announcement from the City and meets all other requirements of this ordinance.&#xA0;
(Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(c)	&#x2013; General
Prohibition.&#xA0; No street banners shall be installed in the public right of way
except for street banners expressly authorized by subsection (d) below.&#xA0;
(Former Subsec. (b) Redesignated as Subsec. (c) and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630,
Eff. 6/14/05.)	(d)	Street Banners &#x2013; Exemptions from General Prohibition.
(Former Subsec. (c) Redesignated as Subsec. (d) and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630,
Eff. 6/14/05.)	(1)	The City of Los Angeles may hang, or authorize a third party
to hang on its behalf, street banners that announce a City of Los Angeles
event.&#xA0; The City Council may also authorize the hanging of City of Los Angeles
sponsored non-event street banners, including street banners requested by any of
the City&#x2019;s operating departments, boards, commissions, bureaus or requested by
other governmental entities, that do not announce a specific event but that
contain public service announcements or that identify or denote on the banner an
area, community, district or other recognized geographic portion of the City of
Los Angeles, such as a Business Improvement District.&#xA0; All banners requested by
other governmental entities, other than the City of Los Angeles, shall be
subject to the applicable fees as authorized in this code.	(2)	The City of Los
Angeles may issue a permit to hang event street banners that announce either a
Community event, a Charitable event or a Non-Profit event or non-event street
banners requested by a charitable or nonprofit entity that identify or denote on
the banner an area, community, district or other recognized geographic portion
of the City of Los Angeles, such as a Business Improvement District.	(e)	Street
Banners &#x2013; Content.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(1)	The text
on all event street banners that announce Community, Charitable or Non-Profit
events shall be limited to the following content: the name of the event; the
name of the charitable or non-profit organization who is the permit applicant,
and, if the name of the organization is in a language other than English, the
English translation of the name; the date of the event; the time of the event;
the location of the event and, if desired by the applicant, either a telephone
number or web address for persons to obtain additional information concerning
the event. The name of any event shall be no more than 8 words and contain no
more than 50 letters.	(2)	The content of all community identity non-event street
banners shall be limited to the name of the area, community, district or other
recognized geographic portion of the City of Los Angeles such as a Business
Improvement District and may contain an introductory word or words, such as
&#x201C;Welcome to&#x201D; or &#x201C;Entering.&#x201D; City of Los Angeles non-event banners may
contain public service information or messages.	(f)	Permit Required.&#xA0; No person
shall install or maintain any street banner without a permit therefor from the
Board of Public Works.&#xA0; A separate permit shall be required for each banner
design and location, but all street banners suspended in one city block, or in a
number of contiguous city blocks, by one permittee, shall be deemed to be at the
same location.&#xA0; Permits shall not be issued for light poles on streets where
the adjoining land use is primarily single-family residential.&#xA0; (Former Subsec.
(d) Redesignated as Subsec. (f) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff.
6/14/05.)	(g)	Application and Fee.&#xA0; Applications for permits shall be made
jointly by the primary event sponsor and the commercial entity installing the
banners upon forms prescribed by the Board.&#xA0; The application must include a
clear replica of the proposed banner or banners, including any text on said
banners, for each proposed installation, and said application shall also include
all other information required by the Board for the protection of public safety,
welfare and property.&#xA0; One application may include any number of locations,
provided that the applicant must submit replicas of all different banners
proposed to be installed under the single application.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (f)
Redesignated as Subsec. (g) and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff.
6/14/05.)	(h)	Insurance Policy to be Posted.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (g) Redesignated
as Subsec. (h) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&#xA0; No permit shall be issued
hereunder unless the commercial entity installing the street banners has on file
with the Board a satisfactory policy of insurance so conditioned as to insure
the City, its officers and employees against any loss, cost, expense, injury,
damage or liability incurred by reason of any personal injury or property damage
sustained by any person, caused by or resulting from or which may be claimed to
have been caused by or to have resulted from, the installation or maintenance of
any street banner or appurtenance installed under the permit, or from any
failure to install or maintain any such street banner or appurtenance in the
manner required by this ordinance or by rule, regulation or order of the Board,
or from any dangerous or defective condition or nuisance created thereby or
resulting therefrom.&#xA0; Furthermore, by the policy, the City, its officers and
employees as named assures, must be insured against any property damage or
personal injury resulting from any such cause.	In addition, the policy shall be
so conditioned as to assure the ability of the applicant to respond in damages,
in any action brought for personal injury or property damage sustained by any
person, based upon any ground mentioned above.	The limit of liability upon any
policy posted or maintained hereunder shall not be less than $500,000.	(i)	Bond
or Cash Deposit.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (h) Redesignated as Subsec. (i) by Ord. No.
176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&#xA0; No permit shall be issued hereunder unless in addition
to the insurance policy herein above required, the applicant commercial entity
installing street banners posts or has on file with the Board a surety bond or
cash deposit so conditioned as to assure that the City shall be reimbursed for
any expense that may be incurred by the Board in removing any street banner or
appurtenance installed pursuant to the permit, in repairing damage to street
lighting equipment resulting from the banner installation, or in otherwise
enforcing any order, rule or relation of the Board.&#xA0; Upon the face of each
application received, the Board shall indicate the amount of indemnity required
upon each permit requested, which shall be at the reasonable discretion of the
Board.&#xA0; The amount of the bond or cash deposit shall not be less than the
amount so indicated.&#xA0; The unused portion of any cash, or other deposit shall be
returned to the applicant.	The applicant commercial entity installing street
banners shall be required as a condition to obtaining a permit, to indemnify and
hold harmless the City, the Department, its officers and employees, from any
liability resulting from the applicant&#x2019;s use of the public property and shall
execute the necessary agreements satisfactory to the City Attorney.	(j)	Term
Bond or Continuing Cash Deposit Acceptable.&#xA0; A separate bond or cash deposit
may be posted in connection with each particular, but in lieu thereof, the Board
may accept a term bond or a continuing cash deposit conditioned to cover all
permits which may be issued to any one applicant commercial entity installing
street banners during a specified period of not to exceed one year, provided,
however, that when the total aggregate required indemnity on all permits
requested by the applicant commercial street banner installation company is
greater than the limit of liability on the term bond, or greater than the cash
deposit maintained, no additional permits shall be issued to the applicant
commercial street banner installation company until sufficient additional
indemnity to cover the same is furnished.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (i) Redesignated as
Subsec. (j) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(k)	Permits &#x2013; Issuance &#x2013;
Denial.&#xA0; Provided that any application for a permit to hang a street banner or
banners meets the eligibility requirements of this ordinance, the Board shall
issue, in whole or in part, a permit authorizing the installation of the
requested street banner or banners, as long as the required fees, bond,
insurance policy and other protection prescribed above have been posted and
approved and provided the installation of such banner or banners will not damage
public property, unreasonably interfere with its proper use, or endanger public
safety or welfare, as determined by the Board of Public Works.&#xA0; Each street
banner permit application shall be reviewed by staff in consultation with the
City Attorney to determine if the request complies with all the requirements of
this ordinance.&#xA0; If staff determines that the request is in full compliance
with this ordinance, the permit shall be issued.&#xA0; If staff determines that the
application is not in compliance with this ordinance, staff shall timely notify
the applicant of the reason or reasons for non-compliance and, if possible,
suggest what could be done to bring the street banner request into compliance
with the ordinance.&#xA0; If a street banner request is ultimately denied by the
City, staff shall e-mail or fax the basis of the denial to the applicant.&#xA0;
(Former Subsec. (j) Redesignated as Subsec. (k) and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630,
Eff. 6/14/05.)	(l)	Permit &#x2013; Duration.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (k) Redesignated as
Subsec. (l) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(1)	Single Event.&#xA0; The term of
each permit shall be specified on the permit by the Board.&#xA0; The term of the
permit for street banners announcing a single event shall not exceed 30 days.&#xA0;
A permit may be renewed or extended for up to two additional 30 day terms. A
permit may not be renewed or extended at any of the 30 day intervals when the
City has on file, at the time of the requested extension, a permit application
from a different entity seeking a permit for the same light poles occupied by
the entity seeking the permit extension.&#xA0; The entity seeking the permit
extension may request different light poles, if available, in instances where
the original light poles are used by a new permittee.&#xA0; Under no circumstances
shall a street banner announcing a single event installed pursuant to a permit
issued pursuant to this code remain on the City&#x2019;s light standards for more
than 90 days in a 12 month period.	(2)	Series of Events.&#xA0; The term of each
permit shall be specified on the permit by the Board.&#xA0; The term of the initial
permit for street banners announcing a series of events shall not exceed 60
days.&#xA0; An initial permit may be renewed or extended for one additional 30 day
term.&#xA0; After 90 days, pursuant to an initial permit with two renewals, a second
permit application may be submitted for a term of 30 days to maintain the
already installed street banners.&#xA0; The second permit may be renewed for up to
two additional 30 day terms. A permit may not be renewed or extended at any of
the 30 day intervals when the City has on file, at the time of the requested
extension, a permit application from a different entity seeking a permit for the
same light poles occupied by the entity seeking the permit extension.&#xA0; The
entity seeking the permit extension may request different light poles, if
available, in instances where the original light poles are used by a new
permittee. Under no circumstances shall a street banner announcing a series of
events installed pursuant to a permit issued pursuant to this code remain on the
City&#x2019;s light standards for more than 180 days in a 12 month
period.	(3)	Non-Event.&#xA0; The term of each permit shall be specified on the
permit by the Board.&#xA0; The term of the initial permit for non-event street
banners shall not exceed 90 days.&#xA0; An initial permit may be renewed or extended
for up to three additional 90 day terms.&#xA0; A permit may not be renewed or
extended at any of the 90 day intervals when the City has on file, at the time
of the requested extension, a permit application from a different entity seeking
a permit for the same light poles occupied by the entity seeking the permit
extension.&#xA0; The entity seeking the permit extension may request different light
poles, if available, in instances where the original light poles are used by a
new permittee.	(m)	Permits &#x2013; Location of Street Banners Announcing an Event or
Series of Events.&#xA0; All street banners announcing an event or series of events
must be placed on all usable streetlight poles on one City block.&#xA0; Any permit
to hang street banners announcing an event or series of events pursuant to this
code shall be deemed a &#x201C;City-wide&#x201D; permit request if the number of light
poles involved is 200 or more.&#xA0; If a permittee requests 200 or more light
poles, the party requesting the permit may place a maximum of 50 street banners
in the vicinity of the event venue and must place the remaining street banners
equally in all Council districts.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (l) Redesignated as Subsec.
(m) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(n)	Permits &#x2013; Revocation.&#xA0; (Former
Subsec. (m) Redesignated as Subsec. (n) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&#xA0;
Permits may be revoked by the Board in whole or in part on one or more of the
following grounds:	1.	The maintenance of any street banner endangers public
welfare, safety or property;	2.	Failure or refusal to observe any provision of
this section or any rule promulgated by the Board pursuant to authority granted
by this section; or	3.	A material misrepresentation in the
application.	(o)	Removal of Street Banner.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (n) Redesignated as
Subsec. (o) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&#xA0; Upon expiration of any permit,
any street banner covered thereby must be removed by the permittee within 72
hours of the date of expiration unless a renewal or written extension is granted
by the Board.&#xA0; Any street banner not so removed may be removed by the Board
without notice to the permittee.&#xA0; Upon whole or partial revocation of any
permit, all street banners covered thereby must be removed on the same date of
revocation unless a renewal or written extension is granted by the Board.&#xA0; Any
street banner not so removed shall, upon reasonable notice to the permittee, be
removed by the Board.&#xA0; Where any street banner presents an immediate threat of
harm to the public health, welfare or safety, the Board shall summarily cause
its removal.	The costs of all Board removals shall be collected by the Board
from the permittee or from his surety.	(p)	Installation and Maintenance of
Street Banners.&#xA0; Every street banner must be installed and maintained so as to
be safe at all times; it must not include a print size for any text smaller than
that adopted by the Board of Public Works in its rules and regulations; it must
not obstruct the clear view of traffic signals by pedestrians or operators of
bicycles, motor bikes, cars, trucks or any other type of vehicle or mode of
transportation; it must have a minimum clearance of 22 feet over rails used by
freight cars, of 16 feet above roadways.&#xA0; The Board may prescribe other needed
clearance requirements.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (o) Redesignated as Subsec. (p) by
Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(q)	Rules and Regulations.&#xA0; Consistent with
this section, the Board may adopt rules or regulations to administer the
installation, maintenance and removal of street banners including rules or
regulations pertaining to their location, size, suspension and construction. The
Board may adopt any other rule or regulation for the protection of public
safety, welfare or property. (Former Subsec. (p) Redesignated as Subsec. (q) by
Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(r)	Commercial Content on Street Banners.&#xA0;
Nothing in the general prohibition on street banners shall prevent a for-profit
entity from receiving recognition on the street banners announcing an otherwise
allowable Community, Charitable or Non-Profit event, or on permitted non-event
street banners, provided that the recognition of the for-profit sponsorship
shall be limited to the name and or logo of one for-profit sponsoring entity per
street banner and the size of said name or logo shall be limited to less than
20% of the total area of the street banner.&#xA0; The City of Los Angeles may defray
the cost of City of Los Angeles organized and administered events, and the cost
of non-event street banners by allowing for-profit entities to co-sponsor City
organized and administered events and non-event street banners, provided that
the recognition of the for-profit entity&#x2019;s co-sponsorship of City events, or
non-event street banners is limited to the same size and content as for
allowable Community, Charitable, or Non-Profit events or permitted non-event
street banners.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (q) Redesignated as Subsec. (r) by Ord. No.
176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(s)	The provisions of Article 7, Chapter 6, prohibiting
certain outdoor advertising structures, post signs and advertising statuary
adjacent to freeways, and establishing the procedure for the consideration and
issuance of permits for such structures, signs and statuary, shall also apply in
the same manner and degree to &#x201C;Street Banner&#x201D;.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (r)
Redesignated as Subsec. (s) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(t)	Street
Banners &#x2013; City Ownership after 30 Days.&#xA0; Up to 3% of the street banners
included in any permit application and hung in the City of Los Angeles for more
than 30 days may become the property of the City of Los Angeles, if a permittee
is notified, at least three days prior to the expiration of the permit, that the
City wishes to take possession of the street banners once they are removed from
the City&#x2019;s poles by the permittee. If so notified, the permittee shall return
the banners to the City once they are removed from the City&#x2019;s poles.&#xA0; If the
City fails to notify the permittee at least three days before the expiration of
the permit that it wishes to take possession of the banners, the City shall
forfeit its right of ownership over said banners.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (s)
Redesignated as Subsec. (t) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)
</plain_text><html>
					&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#xA0; STREET BANNERS.
	(Added by Ord. No. 86,614, Eff. 7/31/42.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(a)	Purpose.&#xA0; The purpose of this &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt; is to provide a limited availability for charitable and non-profit entities to advertise their event or a series of events utilizing the City of Los Angeles&#x2019; street light poles according to the criteria set forth below.&#xA0; It is not the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;intent&lt;/span&gt; of the City to provide a general public forum or to allow non-City entities or persons to post messages on the City&#x2019;s light poles by the use of street banners.&#xA0; The City shall not discriminate based on the content of the requested event banner, nor based on the nature of the event, provided that the requested banner meets all requirements of this &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; In no way shall this &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt; be construed to limit the City&#x2019;s inherent right to hang City sponsored street banners from municipal street light poles.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(b)	Definitions.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (a) Redesignated as Subsec. (b) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	&#x201C;Street Banner.&#x201D;&#xA0; Any pennant, streamer, flag, sign, picture, figure or other &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;object&lt;/span&gt;, regardless of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;material&lt;/span&gt; of which it is made, which is suspended or otherwise displayed over any public street, way or place, designed for decoration or advertisement, or to attract the attention of passersby; except, however, official warning devices, public service facilities, street lights and the like. The term shall not include signs the installation and maintenance of which is regulated by Article 1, Chapter 9 of this Code.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 89,977, Eff. 1/28/46.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	&#x201C;Each Installation.&#x201D;&#xA0; Each wire or rope from which one or more street banner are suspended shall be deemed to be one &#x201C;installation&#x201D;.&#xA0; Multiple banners suspended from a single pole shall also be deemed one installation, provided that the multiple banners comply with all other &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;laws&lt;/span&gt;, rules and regulations covering street banners.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 172,899, Eff. 12/23/99.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	&#x201C;Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as something that takes place within the City of Los Angeles at a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;venue&lt;/span&gt; that is open for attendance by the City&#x2019;s citizens regardless of their age, gender, race, religion or physical disability.&#xA0; A telethon or phone-a-thon shall be considered an &#x201C;event&#x201D; under this definition if it meets all other requirements of this &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	4.	&#x201C;Community Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as an event, or a series of events that promotes civic pride in a local community within the City of Los Angeles or the City of Los Angeles as a whole, and that is not a purely commercial enterprise and where the proceeds, if any, will directly benefit either a charitable or non-profit organization.&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	5.	&#x201C;Charitable Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as an event, or a series of events where the proceeds, if any, will directly benefit a charitable organization that maintains its charitable status under Internal Revenue Code &#xA7;&#xA0;501(c)(3).&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	6.	&#x201C;Non-Profit Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as an event, or series of events that is sponsored by an organization that is incorporated or otherwise organized as a non-profit organization under the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;laws&lt;/span&gt; of the State of California or the Internal Revenue Code and where the proceeds, if any, will directly benefit either a charitable or non-profit organization.&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	7.	&#x201C;City of Los Angeles Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as an event, or series of events that is organized and administered by the City of Los Angeles or by any of its operating departments, boards, commissions or bureaus and that has been approved by the City Council.&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	8.	&#x201C;Citywide Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as an event for which organizers will install in excess of 200 banners.&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	9.	&#x201C;Non-Event Banner.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as a banner that identifies or denotes on the banner an area, community, district or other recognized geographic portion of the City of Los Angeles, such as a Business Improvement District, or contains a public service announcement from the City and meets all other requirements of this &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(c)	&#x2013; General Prohibition.&#xA0; No street banners shall be installed in the public right of way except for street banners expressly authorized by subsection (d) below.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (b) Redesignated as Subsec. (c) and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(d)	Street Banners &#x2013; Exemptions from General Prohibition. (Former Subsec. (c) Redesignated as Subsec. (d) and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(1)	The City of Los Angeles may hang, or authorize a third &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;party&lt;/span&gt; to hang on its behalf, street banners that announce a City of Los Angeles event.&#xA0; The City Council may also authorize the hanging of City of Los Angeles sponsored non-event street banners, including street banners requested by any of the City&#x2019;s operating departments, boards, commissions, bureaus or requested by other governmental entities, that do not announce a specific event but that contain public service announcements or that identify or denote on the banner an area, community, district or other recognized geographic portion of the City of Los Angeles, such as a Business Improvement District.&#xA0; All banners requested by other governmental entities, other than the City of Los Angeles, shall be subject to the applicable fees as authorized in this code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(2)	The City of Los Angeles may &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;issue&lt;/span&gt; a permit to hang event street banners that announce either a Community event, a Charitable event or a Non-Profit event or non-event street banners requested by a charitable or nonprofit entity that identify or denote on the banner an area, community, district or other recognized geographic portion of the City of Los Angeles, such as a Business Improvement District.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(e)	Street Banners &#x2013; Content.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(1)	The text on all event street banners that announce Community, Charitable or Non-Profit events shall be limited to the following content: the name of the event; the name of the charitable or non-profit organization who is the permit applicant, and, if the name of the organization is in a language other than English, the English translation of the name; the date of the event; the time of the event; the location of the event and, if desired by the applicant, either a telephone number or web address for persons to obtain additional information concerning the event. The name of any event shall be no more than 8 words and contain no more than 50 letters.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(2)	The content of all community identity non-event street banners shall be limited to the name of the area, community, district or other recognized geographic portion of the City of Los Angeles such as a Business Improvement District and may contain an introductory word or words, such as &#x201C;Welcome to&#x201D; or &#x201C;Entering.&#x201D; City of Los Angeles non-event banners may contain public service information or messages.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(f)	Permit Required.&#xA0; No person shall install or maintain any street banner without a permit therefor from the Board of Public Works.&#xA0; A separate permit shall be required for each banner design and location, but all street banners suspended in one city block, or in a number of contiguous city blocks, by one permittee, shall be deemed to be at the same location.&#xA0; Permits shall not be issued for light poles on streets where the adjoining land use is primarily single-family residential.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (d) Redesignated as Subsec. (f) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(g)	Application and Fee.&#xA0; Applications for permits shall be made jointly by the primary event sponsor and the commercial entity installing the banners upon forms prescribed by the Board.&#xA0; The application must include a clear replica of the proposed banner or banners, including any text on said banners, for each proposed installation, and said application shall also include all other information required by the Board for the protection of public safety, welfare and property.&#xA0; One application may include any number of locations, provided that the applicant must submit replicas of all different banners proposed to be installed under the single application.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (f) Redesignated as Subsec. (g) and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(h)	Insurance Policy to be Posted.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (g) Redesignated as Subsec. (h) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&#xA0; No permit shall be issued hereunder unless the commercial entity installing the street banners has on file with the Board a satisfactory policy of insurance so conditioned as to insure the City, its officers and employees against any loss, cost, expense, injury, damage or liability incurred by reason of any personal injury or property damage sustained by any person, caused by or resulting from or which may be claimed to have been caused by or to have resulted from, the installation or maintenance of any street banner or appurtenance installed under the permit, or from any failure to install or maintain any such street banner or appurtenance in the manner required by this &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt; or by rule, regulation or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; of the Board, or from any dangerous or defective condition or nuisance created thereby or resulting therefrom.&#xA0; Furthermore, by the policy, the City, its officers and employees as named assures, must be insured against any property damage or personal injury resulting from any such cause.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	In addition, the policy shall be so conditioned as to assure the ability of the applicant to respond in &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;damages&lt;/span&gt;, in any action brought for personal injury or property damage sustained by any person, based upon any ground mentioned above.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	The limit of liability upon any policy posted or maintained hereunder shall not be less than $500,000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(i)	&lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Bond&lt;/span&gt; or Cash Deposit.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (h) Redesignated as Subsec. (i) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&#xA0; No permit shall be issued hereunder unless in addition to the insurance policy herein above required, the applicant commercial entity installing street banners posts or has on file with the Board a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;surety&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;bond&lt;/span&gt; or cash deposit so conditioned as to assure that the City shall be reimbursed for any expense that may be incurred by the Board in removing any street banner or appurtenance installed pursuant to the permit, in repairing damage to street lighting equipment resulting from the banner installation, or in otherwise enforcing any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt;, rule or relation of the Board.&#xA0; Upon the face of each application received, the Board shall indicate the amount of indemnity required upon each permit requested, which shall be at the reasonable discretion of the Board.&#xA0; The amount of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;bond&lt;/span&gt; or cash deposit shall not be less than the amount so indicated.&#xA0; The unused portion of any cash, or other deposit shall be returned to the applicant.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	The applicant commercial entity installing street banners shall be required as a condition to obtaining a permit, to indemnify and hold harmless the City, the Department, its officers and employees, from any liability resulting from the applicant&#x2019;s use of the public property and shall execute the necessary agreements satisfactory to the City Attorney.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(j)	Term &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Bond&lt;/span&gt; or Continuing Cash Deposit Acceptable.&#xA0; A separate &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;bond&lt;/span&gt; or cash deposit may be posted in connection with each particular, but in lieu thereof, the Board may accept a term &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;bond&lt;/span&gt; or a continuing cash deposit conditioned to cover all permits which may be issued to any one applicant commercial entity installing street banners during a specified period of not to exceed one year, provided, however, that when the total aggregate required indemnity on all permits requested by the applicant commercial street banner installation company is greater than the limit of liability on the term &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;bond&lt;/span&gt;, or greater than the cash deposit maintained, no additional permits shall be issued to the applicant commercial street banner installation company until sufficient additional indemnity to cover the same is furnished.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (i) Redesignated as Subsec. (j) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(k)	Permits &#x2013; Issuance &#x2013; Denial.&#xA0; Provided that any application for a permit to hang a street banner or banners meets the eligibility requirements of this &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt;, the Board shall &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;issue&lt;/span&gt;, in whole or in part, a permit authorizing the installation of the requested street banner or banners, as long as the required fees, &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;bond&lt;/span&gt;, insurance policy and other protection prescribed above have been posted and approved and provided the installation of such banner or banners will not damage public property, unreasonably interfere with its proper use, or endanger public safety or welfare, as determined by the Board of Public Works.&#xA0; Each street banner permit application shall be reviewed by staff in consultation with the City Attorney to determine if the request complies with all the requirements of this &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; If staff determines that the request is in full compliance with this &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt;, the permit shall be issued.&#xA0; If staff determines that the application is not in compliance with this &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt;, staff shall timely notify the applicant of the reason or reasons for non-compliance and, if possible, suggest what could be done to bring the street banner request into compliance with the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; If a street banner request is ultimately denied by the City, staff shall e-mail or fax the basis of the denial to the applicant.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (j) Redesignated as Subsec. (k) and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(l)	Permit &#x2013; Duration.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (k) Redesignated as Subsec. (l) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(1)	Single Event.&#xA0; The term of each permit shall be specified on the permit by the Board.&#xA0; The term of the permit for street banners announcing a single event shall not exceed 30 days.&#xA0; A permit may be renewed or extended for up to two additional 30 day terms. A permit may not be renewed or extended at any of the 30 day intervals when the City has on file, at the time of the requested extension, a permit application from a different entity seeking a permit for the same light poles occupied by the entity seeking the permit extension.&#xA0; The entity seeking the permit extension may request different light poles, if available, in instances where the original light poles are used by a new permittee.&#xA0; Under no circumstances shall a street banner announcing a single event installed pursuant to a permit issued pursuant to this code remain on the City&#x2019;s light standards for more than 90 days in a 12 month period.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(2)	Series of Events.&#xA0; The term of each permit shall be specified on the permit by the Board.&#xA0; The term of the initial permit for street banners announcing a series of events shall not exceed 60 days.&#xA0; An initial permit may be renewed or extended for one additional 30 day term.&#xA0; After 90 days, pursuant to an initial permit with two renewals, a second permit application may be submitted for a term of 30 days to maintain the already installed street banners.&#xA0; The second permit may be renewed for up to two additional 30 day terms. A permit may not be renewed or extended at any of the 30 day intervals when the City has on file, at the time of the requested extension, a permit application from a different entity seeking a permit for the same light poles occupied by the entity seeking the permit extension.&#xA0; The entity seeking the permit extension may request different light poles, if available, in instances where the original light poles are used by a new permittee. Under no circumstances shall a street banner announcing a series of events installed pursuant to a permit issued pursuant to this code remain on the City&#x2019;s light standards for more than 180 days in a 12 month period.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(3)	Non-Event.&#xA0; The term of each permit shall be specified on the permit by the Board.&#xA0; The term of the initial permit for non-event street banners shall not exceed 90 days.&#xA0; An initial permit may be renewed or extended for up to three additional 90 day terms.&#xA0; A permit may not be renewed or extended at any of the 90 day intervals when the City has on file, at the time of the requested extension, a permit application from a different entity seeking a permit for the same light poles occupied by the entity seeking the permit extension.&#xA0; The entity seeking the permit extension may request different light poles, if available, in instances where the original light poles are used by a new permittee.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(m)	Permits &#x2013; Location of Street Banners Announcing an Event or Series of Events.&#xA0; All street banners announcing an event or series of events must be placed on all usable streetlight poles on one City block.&#xA0; Any permit to hang street banners announcing an event or series of events pursuant to this code shall be deemed a &#x201C;City-wide&#x201D; permit request if the number of light poles involved is 200 or more.&#xA0; If a permittee requests 200 or more light poles, the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;party&lt;/span&gt; requesting the permit may place a maximum of 50 street banners in the vicinity of the event &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;venue&lt;/span&gt; and must place the remaining street banners equally in all Council districts.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (l) Redesignated as Subsec. (m) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(n)	Permits &#x2013; &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Revocation&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (m) Redesignated as Subsec. (n) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&#xA0; Permits may be revoked by the Board in whole or in part on one or more of the following grounds:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	The maintenance of any street banner endangers public welfare, safety or property;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	Failure or refusal to observe any provision of this section or any rule promulgated by the Board pursuant to authority granted by this section; or&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	A &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;material&lt;/span&gt; misrepresentation in the application.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(o)	Removal of Street Banner.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (n) Redesignated as Subsec. (o) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&#xA0; Upon expiration of any permit, any street banner covered thereby must be removed by the permittee within 72 hours of the date of expiration unless a renewal or written extension is granted by the Board.&#xA0; Any street banner not so removed may be removed by the Board without notice to the permittee.&#xA0; Upon whole or partial &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;revocation&lt;/span&gt; of any permit, all street banners covered thereby must be removed on the same date of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;revocation&lt;/span&gt; unless a renewal or written extension is granted by the Board.&#xA0; Any street banner not so removed shall, upon reasonable notice to the permittee, be removed by the Board.&#xA0; Where any street banner presents an immediate threat of harm to the public health, welfare or safety, the Board shall summarily cause its removal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	The costs of all Board removals shall be collected by the Board from the permittee or from his &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;surety&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(p)	Installation and Maintenance of Street Banners.&#xA0; Every street banner must be installed and maintained so as to be safe at all times; it must not include a print size for any text smaller than that adopted by the Board of Public Works in its rules and regulations; it must not obstruct the clear view of traffic signals by pedestrians or operators of bicycles, motor bikes, cars, trucks or any other type of vehicle or mode of transportation; it must have a minimum clearance of 22 feet over rails used by freight cars, of 16 feet above roadways.&#xA0; The Board may prescribe other needed clearance requirements.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (o) Redesignated as Subsec. (p) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(q)	Rules and Regulations.&#xA0; Consistent with this section, the Board may adopt rules or regulations to administer the installation, maintenance and removal of street banners including rules or regulations pertaining to their location, size, suspension and construction. The Board may adopt any other rule or regulation for the protection of public safety, welfare or property. (Former Subsec. (p) Redesignated as Subsec. (q) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(r)	Commercial Content on Street Banners.&#xA0; Nothing in the general prohibition on street banners shall prevent a for-profit entity from receiving recognition on the street banners announcing an otherwise allowable Community, Charitable or Non-Profit event, or on permitted non-event street banners, provided that the recognition of the for-profit sponsorship shall be limited to the name and or logo of one for-profit sponsoring entity per street banner and the size of said name or logo shall be limited to less than 20% of the total area of the street banner.&#xA0; The City of Los Angeles may defray the cost of City of Los Angeles organized and administered events, and the cost of non-event street banners by allowing for-profit entities to co-sponsor City organized and administered events and non-event street banners, provided that the recognition of the for-profit entity&#x2019;s co-sponsorship of City events, or non-event street banners is limited to the same size and content as for allowable Community, Charitable, or Non-Profit events or permitted non-event street banners.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (q) Redesignated as Subsec. (r) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(s)	The provisions of Article 7, Chapter 6, prohibiting certain outdoor advertising structures, post signs and advertising statuary adjacent to freeways, and establishing the procedure for the consideration and issuance of permits for such structures, signs and statuary, shall also apply in the same manner and degree to &#x201C;Street Banner&#x201D;.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (r) Redesignated as Subsec. (s) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(t)	Street Banners &#x2013; City Ownership after 30 Days.&#xA0; Up to 3% of the street banners included in any permit application and hung in the City of Los Angeles for more than 30 days may become the property of the City of Los Angeles, if a permittee is notified, at least three days prior to the expiration of the permit, that the City wishes to take &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;possession&lt;/span&gt; of the street banners once they are removed from the City&#x2019;s poles by the permittee. If so notified, the permittee shall return the banners to the City once they are removed from the City&#x2019;s poles.&#xA0; If the City fails to notify the permittee at least three days before the expiration of the permit that it wishes to take &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;possession&lt;/span&gt; of the banners, the City shall forfeit its right of ownership over said banners.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (s) Redesignated as Subsec. (t) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</html><previous_section id="1057"><structure_id>36</structure_id><section_number>62.131</section_number><catch_line>Decorative Lights Over Streets And Sidewalks.</catch_line><url>/62.131/</url><token>62.131</token></previous_section><text><unit id="3391" prefix=""><text>&#xA0; STREET BANNERS.
	(Added by Ord. No. 86,614, Eff. 7/31/42.)	(a)	Purpose.&#xA0; The purpose of this ordinance is to provide a limited availability for charitable and non-profit entities to advertise their event or a series of events utilizing the City of Los Angeles&#x2019; street light poles according to the criteria set forth below.&#xA0; It is not the intent of the City to provide a general public forum or to allow non-City entities or persons to post messages on the City&#x2019;s light poles by the use of street banners.&#xA0; The City shall not discriminate based on the content of the requested event banner, nor based on the nature of the event, provided that the requested banner meets all requirements of this ordinance.&#xA0; In no way shall this ordinance be construed to limit the City&#x2019;s inherent right to hang City sponsored street banners from municipal street light poles.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(b)	Definitions.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (a) Redesignated as Subsec. (b) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	1.	&#x201C;Street Banner.&#x201D;&#xA0; Any pennant, streamer, flag, sign, picture, figure or other object, regardless of the material of which it is made, which is suspended or otherwise displayed over any public street, way or place, designed for decoration or advertisement, or to attract the attention of passersby; except, however, official warning devices, public service facilities, street lights and the like. The term shall not include signs the installation and maintenance of which is regulated by Article 1, Chapter 9 of this Code.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 89,977, Eff. 1/28/46.)	2.	&#x201C;Each Installation.&#x201D;&#xA0; Each wire or rope from which one or more street banner are suspended shall be deemed to be one &#x201C;installation&#x201D;.&#xA0; Multiple banners suspended from a single pole shall also be deemed one installation, provided that the multiple banners comply with all other laws, rules and regulations covering street banners.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 172,899, Eff. 12/23/99.)	3.	&#x201C;Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as something that takes place within the City of Los Angeles at a venue that is open for attendance by the City&#x2019;s citizens regardless of their age, gender, race, religion or physical disability.&#xA0; A telethon or phone-a-thon shall be considered an &#x201C;event&#x201D; under this definition if it meets all other requirements of this ordinance.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	4.	&#x201C;Community Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as an event, or a series of events that promotes civic pride in a local community within the City of Los Angeles or the City of Los Angeles as a whole, and that is not a purely commercial enterprise and where the proceeds, if any, will directly benefit either a charitable or non-profit organization.&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	5.	&#x201C;Charitable Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as an event, or a series of events where the proceeds, if any, will directly benefit a charitable organization that maintains its charitable status under Internal Revenue Code &#xA7; 501(c)(3).&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	6.	&#x201C;Non-Profit Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as an event, or series of events that is sponsored by an organization that is incorporated or otherwise organized as a non-profit organization under the laws of the State of California or the Internal Revenue Code and where the proceeds, if any, will directly benefit either a charitable or non-profit organization.&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	7.	&#x201C;City of Los Angeles Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as an event, or series of events that is organized and administered by the City of Los Angeles or by any of its operating departments, boards, commissions or bureaus and that has been approved by the City Council.&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	8.	&#x201C;Citywide Event.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as an event for which organizers will install in excess of 200 banners.&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	9.	&#x201C;Non-Event Banner.&#x201D;&#xA0; Shall be defined as a banner that identifies or denotes on the banner an area, community, district or other recognized geographic portion of the City of Los Angeles, such as a Business Improvement District, or contains a public service announcement from the City and meets all other requirements of this ordinance.&#xA0; (Renumbered and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(c)	&#x2013; General Prohibition.&#xA0; No street banners shall be installed in the public right of way except for street banners expressly authorized by subsection (d) below.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (b) Redesignated as Subsec. (c) and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(d)	Street Banners &#x2013; Exemptions from General Prohibition. (Former Subsec. (c) Redesignated as Subsec. (d) and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(1)	The City of Los Angeles may hang, or authorize a third party to hang on its behalf, street banners that announce a City of Los Angeles event.&#xA0; The City Council may also authorize the hanging of City of Los Angeles sponsored non-event street banners, including street banners requested by any of the City&#x2019;s operating departments, boards, commissions, bureaus or requested by other governmental entities, that do not announce a specific event but that contain public service announcements or that identify or denote on the banner an area, community, district or other recognized geographic portion of the City of Los Angeles, such as a Business Improvement District.&#xA0; All banners requested by other governmental entities, other than the City of Los Angeles, shall be subject to the applicable fees as authorized in this code.	(2)	The City of Los Angeles may issue a permit to hang event street banners that announce either a Community event, a Charitable event or a Non-Profit event or non-event street banners requested by a charitable or nonprofit entity that identify or denote on the banner an area, community, district or other recognized geographic portion of the City of Los Angeles, such as a Business Improvement District.	(e)	Street Banners &#x2013; Content.&#xA0; (Added by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(1)	The text on all event street banners that announce Community, Charitable or Non-Profit events shall be limited to the following content: the name of the event; the name of the charitable or non-profit organization who is the permit applicant, and, if the name of the organization is in a language other than English, the English translation of the name; the date of the event; the time of the event; the location of the event and, if desired by the applicant, either a telephone number or web address for persons to obtain additional information concerning the event. The name of any event shall be no more than 8 words and contain no more than 50 letters.	(2)	The content of all community identity non-event street banners shall be limited to the name of the area, community, district or other recognized geographic portion of the City of Los Angeles such as a Business Improvement District and may contain an introductory word or words, such as &#x201C;Welcome to&#x201D; or &#x201C;Entering.&#x201D; City of Los Angeles non-event banners may contain public service information or messages.	(f)	Permit Required.&#xA0; No person shall install or maintain any street banner without a permit therefor from the Board of Public Works.&#xA0; A separate permit shall be required for each banner design and location, but all street banners suspended in one city block, or in a number of contiguous city blocks, by one permittee, shall be deemed to be at the same location.&#xA0; Permits shall not be issued for light poles on streets where the adjoining land use is primarily single-family residential.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (d) Redesignated as Subsec. (f) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(g)	Application and Fee.&#xA0; Applications for permits shall be made jointly by the primary event sponsor and the commercial entity installing the banners upon forms prescribed by the Board.&#xA0; The application must include a clear replica of the proposed banner or banners, including any text on said banners, for each proposed installation, and said application shall also include all other information required by the Board for the protection of public safety, welfare and property.&#xA0; One application may include any number of locations, provided that the applicant must submit replicas of all different banners proposed to be installed under the single application.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (f) Redesignated as Subsec. (g) and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(h)	Insurance Policy to be Posted.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (g) Redesignated as Subsec. (h) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&#xA0; No permit shall be issued hereunder unless the commercial entity installing the street banners has on file with the Board a satisfactory policy of insurance so conditioned as to insure the City, its officers and employees against any loss, cost, expense, injury, damage or liability incurred by reason of any personal injury or property damage sustained by any person, caused by or resulting from or which may be claimed to have been caused by or to have resulted from, the installation or maintenance of any street banner or appurtenance installed under the permit, or from any failure to install or maintain any such street banner or appurtenance in the manner required by this ordinance or by rule, regulation or order of the Board, or from any dangerous or defective condition or nuisance created thereby or resulting therefrom.&#xA0; Furthermore, by the policy, the City, its officers and employees as named assures, must be insured against any property damage or personal injury resulting from any such cause.	In addition, the policy shall be so conditioned as to assure the ability of the applicant to respond in damages, in any action brought for personal injury or property damage sustained by any person, based upon any ground mentioned above.	The limit of liability upon any policy posted or maintained hereunder shall not be less than $500,000.	(i)	Bond or Cash Deposit.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (h) Redesignated as Subsec. (i) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&#xA0; No permit shall be issued hereunder unless in addition to the insurance policy herein above required, the applicant commercial entity installing street banners posts or has on file with the Board a surety bond or cash deposit so conditioned as to assure that the City shall be reimbursed for any expense that may be incurred by the Board in removing any street banner or appurtenance installed pursuant to the permit, in repairing damage to street lighting equipment resulting from the banner installation, or in otherwise enforcing any order, rule or relation of the Board.&#xA0; Upon the face of each application received, the Board shall indicate the amount of indemnity required upon each permit requested, which shall be at the reasonable discretion of the Board.&#xA0; The amount of the bond or cash deposit shall not be less than the amount so indicated.&#xA0; The unused portion of any cash, or other deposit shall be returned to the applicant.	The applicant commercial entity installing street banners shall be required as a condition to obtaining a permit, to indemnify and hold harmless the City, the Department, its officers and employees, from any liability resulting from the applicant&#x2019;s use of the public property and shall execute the necessary agreements satisfactory to the City Attorney.	(j)	Term Bond or Continuing Cash Deposit Acceptable.&#xA0; A separate bond or cash deposit may be posted in connection with each particular, but in lieu thereof, the Board may accept a term bond or a continuing cash deposit conditioned to cover all permits which may be issued to any one applicant commercial entity installing street banners during a specified period of not to exceed one year, provided, however, that when the total aggregate required indemnity on all permits requested by the applicant commercial street banner installation company is greater than the limit of liability on the term bond, or greater than the cash deposit maintained, no additional permits shall be issued to the applicant commercial street banner installation company until sufficient additional indemnity to cover the same is furnished.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (i) Redesignated as Subsec. (j) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(k)	Permits &#x2013; Issuance &#x2013; Denial.&#xA0; Provided that any application for a permit to hang a street banner or banners meets the eligibility requirements of this ordinance, the Board shall issue, in whole or in part, a permit authorizing the installation of the requested street banner or banners, as long as the required fees, bond, insurance policy and other protection prescribed above have been posted and approved and provided the installation of such banner or banners will not damage public property, unreasonably interfere with its proper use, or endanger public safety or welfare, as determined by the Board of Public Works.&#xA0; Each street banner permit application shall be reviewed by staff in consultation with the City Attorney to determine if the request complies with all the requirements of this ordinance.&#xA0; If staff determines that the request is in full compliance with this ordinance, the permit shall be issued.&#xA0; If staff determines that the application is not in compliance with this ordinance, staff shall timely notify the applicant of the reason or reasons for non-compliance and, if possible, suggest what could be done to bring the street banner request into compliance with the ordinance.&#xA0; If a street banner request is ultimately denied by the City, staff shall e-mail or fax the basis of the denial to the applicant.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (j) Redesignated as Subsec. (k) and Amended by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(l)	Permit &#x2013; Duration.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (k) Redesignated as Subsec. (l) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(1)	Single Event.&#xA0; The term of each permit shall be specified on the permit by the Board.&#xA0; The term of the permit for street banners announcing a single event shall not exceed 30 days.&#xA0; A permit may be renewed or extended for up to two additional 30 day terms. A permit may not be renewed or extended at any of the 30 day intervals when the City has on file, at the time of the requested extension, a permit application from a different entity seeking a permit for the same light poles occupied by the entity seeking the permit extension.&#xA0; The entity seeking the permit extension may request different light poles, if available, in instances where the original light poles are used by a new permittee.&#xA0; Under no circumstances shall a street banner announcing a single event installed pursuant to a permit issued pursuant to this code remain on the City&#x2019;s light standards for more than 90 days in a 12 month period.	(2)	Series of Events.&#xA0; The term of each permit shall be specified on the permit by the Board.&#xA0; The term of the initial permit for street banners announcing a series of events shall not exceed 60 days.&#xA0; An initial permit may be renewed or extended for one additional 30 day term.&#xA0; After 90 days, pursuant to an initial permit with two renewals, a second permit application may be submitted for a term of 30 days to maintain the already installed street banners.&#xA0; The second permit may be renewed for up to two additional 30 day terms. A permit may not be renewed or extended at any of the 30 day intervals when the City has on file, at the time of the requested extension, a permit application from a different entity seeking a permit for the same light poles occupied by the entity seeking the permit extension.&#xA0; The entity seeking the permit extension may request different light poles, if available, in instances where the original light poles are used by a new permittee. Under no circumstances shall a street banner announcing a series of events installed pursuant to a permit issued pursuant to this code remain on the City&#x2019;s light standards for more than 180 days in a 12 month period.	(3)	Non-Event.&#xA0; The term of each permit shall be specified on the permit by the Board.&#xA0; The term of the initial permit for non-event street banners shall not exceed 90 days.&#xA0; An initial permit may be renewed or extended for up to three additional 90 day terms.&#xA0; A permit may not be renewed or extended at any of the 90 day intervals when the City has on file, at the time of the requested extension, a permit application from a different entity seeking a permit for the same light poles occupied by the entity seeking the permit extension.&#xA0; The entity seeking the permit extension may request different light poles, if available, in instances where the original light poles are used by a new permittee.	(m)	Permits &#x2013; Location of Street Banners Announcing an Event or Series of Events.&#xA0; All street banners announcing an event or series of events must be placed on all usable streetlight poles on one City block.&#xA0; Any permit to hang street banners announcing an event or series of events pursuant to this code shall be deemed a &#x201C;City-wide&#x201D; permit request if the number of light poles involved is 200 or more.&#xA0; If a permittee requests 200 or more light poles, the party requesting the permit may place a maximum of 50 street banners in the vicinity of the event venue and must place the remaining street banners equally in all Council districts.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (l) Redesignated as Subsec. (m) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(n)	Permits &#x2013; Revocation.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (m) Redesignated as Subsec. (n) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&#xA0; Permits may be revoked by the Board in whole or in part on one or more of the following grounds:	1.	The maintenance of any street banner endangers public welfare, safety or property;	2.	Failure or refusal to observe any provision of this section or any rule promulgated by the Board pursuant to authority granted by this section; or	3.	A material misrepresentation in the application.	(o)	Removal of Street Banner.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (n) Redesignated as Subsec. (o) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)&#xA0; Upon expiration of any permit, any street banner covered thereby must be removed by the permittee within 72 hours of the date of expiration unless a renewal or written extension is granted by the Board.&#xA0; Any street banner not so removed may be removed by the Board without notice to the permittee.&#xA0; Upon whole or partial revocation of any permit, all street banners covered thereby must be removed on the same date of revocation unless a renewal or written extension is granted by the Board.&#xA0; Any street banner not so removed shall, upon reasonable notice to the permittee, be removed by the Board.&#xA0; Where any street banner presents an immediate threat of harm to the public health, welfare or safety, the Board shall summarily cause its removal.	The costs of all Board removals shall be collected by the Board from the permittee or from his surety.	(p)	Installation and Maintenance of Street Banners.&#xA0; Every street banner must be installed and maintained so as to be safe at all times; it must not include a print size for any text smaller than that adopted by the Board of Public Works in its rules and regulations; it must not obstruct the clear view of traffic signals by pedestrians or operators of bicycles, motor bikes, cars, trucks or any other type of vehicle or mode of transportation; it must have a minimum clearance of 22 feet over rails used by freight cars, of 16 feet above roadways.&#xA0; The Board may prescribe other needed clearance requirements.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (o) Redesignated as Subsec. (p) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(q)	Rules and Regulations.&#xA0; Consistent with this section, the Board may adopt rules or regulations to administer the installation, maintenance and removal of street banners including rules or regulations pertaining to their location, size, suspension and construction. The Board may adopt any other rule or regulation for the protection of public safety, welfare or property. (Former Subsec. (p) Redesignated as Subsec. (q) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(r)	Commercial Content on Street Banners.&#xA0; Nothing in the general prohibition on street banners shall prevent a for-profit entity from receiving recognition on the street banners announcing an otherwise allowable Community, Charitable or Non-Profit event, or on permitted non-event street banners, provided that the recognition of the for-profit sponsorship shall be limited to the name and or logo of one for-profit sponsoring entity per street banner and the size of said name or logo shall be limited to less than 20% of the total area of the street banner.&#xA0; The City of Los Angeles may defray the cost of City of Los Angeles organized and administered events, and the cost of non-event street banners by allowing for-profit entities to co-sponsor City organized and administered events and non-event street banners, provided that the recognition of the for-profit entity&#x2019;s co-sponsorship of City events, or non-event street banners is limited to the same size and content as for allowable Community, Charitable, or Non-Profit events or permitted non-event street banners.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (q) Redesignated as Subsec. (r) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(s)	The provisions of Article 7, Chapter 6, prohibiting certain outdoor advertising structures, post signs and advertising statuary adjacent to freeways, and establishing the procedure for the consideration and issuance of permits for such structures, signs and statuary, shall also apply in the same manner and degree to &#x201C;Street Banner&#x201D;.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (r) Redesignated as Subsec. (s) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)	(t)	Street Banners &#x2013; City Ownership after 30 Days.&#xA0; Up to 3% of the street banners included in any permit application and hung in the City of Los Angeles for more than 30 days may become the property of the City of Los Angeles, if a permittee is notified, at least three days prior to the expiration of the permit, that the City wishes to take possession of the street banners once they are removed from the City&#x2019;s poles by the permittee. If so notified, the permittee shall return the banners to the City once they are removed from the City&#x2019;s poles.&#xA0; If the City fails to notify the permittee at least three days before the expiration of the permit that it wishes to take possession of the banners, the City shall forfeit its right of ownership over said banners.&#xA0; (Former Subsec. (s) Redesignated as Subsec. (t) by Ord. No. 176,630, Eff. 6/14/05.)</text><type>section</type><prefixes><unit></unit></prefixes><entire_prefix></entire_prefix><prefix_anchor></prefix_anchor><level>1</level></unit></text></law>
