<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><section_number>91.105</section_number><edition_id>1</edition_id><section_id>2331</section_id><structure_id>31</structure_id><catch_line>Appeals.</catch_line><history></history><full_text>&#xA0; APPEALS.

91.105.1.&#xA0; General.&#xA0; or requests for slight modifications in individual cases from the requirements of this Code shall be made in accordance with the procedure established in Section 98.0403.2 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.

91.105.2.&#xA0; Building Advisory Appeal Board.&#xA0; The Building Advisory Appeal Board is hereby abolished. Any duties assigned to the Building Advisory Appeal Board by any provision of law shall be performed as determined by the Superintendent of Building.

91.105.3.&#xA0; Engineering Geology Advisory Committee.

91.105.3.1.&#xA0; Function of the Committee.&#xA0; It shall be the function of the Engineering Geology Advisory Committee to advise and counsel the board on appeals involving technical questions of soils engineering, geology, geology/seismology and related matters.

91.105.3.2.&#xA0; Establishment of the Committee Member List.&#xA0; The Board of Building and Safety Commissioners shall establish an Engineering Geology Advisory Committee member list (hereinafter in this section referred to as the &#x201C;committee member list&#x201D;) which shall consist of not less than 10 soils engineers and engineering geologists who are available to serve as members of the Engineering Geology Advisory Committee.&#xA0; At least two of the engineering geologist members and two of the soils engineer members shall have experience in the field of seismic design and safety. Members of said committee shall be exempt from all Civil Service provisions.

91.105.3.3.&#xA0; Procedure.&#xA0; When an appeal is made to the Board, and the Board determines that the subject of the appeal involves a problem of soils engineering, geology, geology/seismology or a related matter on which it desires further technical advice before it renders a decision thereon, the Board may select three or more persons from the Engineering Geology Advisory Committee member list to serve on a committee for the purpose of assisting the Board in seeking a solution to said problem, and may refer the matter to such committee members for report and recommendation. At least one member of the committee so designated shall be a soils engineer and one shall be an engineering geologist. The members of the committee so meeting shall review the matter and shall then submit to the board a recommendation. When a matter is referred to the committee as in this section provided, the board shall consider, but is not bound to accept, the recommendation of the committee.

91.105.3.4.&#xA0; Compensation of Members.&#xA0; Each member of the committee who is in actual attendance at a meeting requested by the board shall be compensated at the rate of $50.00 for each four hours or fraction thereof of service. However, in no case shall the compensation of the committee members exceed the fee paid by the appellant under Section 91.105.3.6 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.

91.105.3.5.&#xA0; Self insurance by the City for Committee Members.&#xA0; The provisions of Sections 11.36 through 11.44, inclusive, City of Los Angeles Administrative Code, entitled &#x201C;Self Insurance by the City for Officers and Employees of Said City&#x201D;, shall apply to each Engineering Geology Advisory Committee member while the member is acting as such, and committee members shall be deemed to be fully covered by the provisions of said sections even though each committee member is retained as an independent person and not as an officer or employee of the city.

91.105.3.6.&#xA0; Fees.&#xA0; When a matter is referred to the committee as provided in this section, the appellant in said matter shall pay a referral fee of $50.00 and shall also pay a fee as follows:

	1.	Where no more than two lots are involved in the appeal, $150.00;

	2.	Where not less than three or more than 10 lots are involved in the appeal, $300.00;

	3.	Where more than 10 lots are involved in the appeal, $600.00.

91.105.4.&#xA0; Sign Advisory Committee.

91.105.4.1.&#xA0; Function of the Committee.&#xA0; It shall be the function of a Sign Advisory Committee to advise, counsel and provide recommendations to the Board of Building and Safety Commissioners on matters involving sign regulations.

91.105.4.2.&#xA0; Establishment of the Committee Member List.&#xA0; The Board of Building and Safety Commissioners shall establish a Sign Advisory Committee member list representing the various required fields of interest of persons who are available to serve as members of a Sign Advisory Committee. Persons selected for the Sign Advisory Committee list shall possess experience in the design, fabrication, the use or application of signs, or shall have demonstrated a background in the social and environment impacts of signs or the development of sign regulations. Members of said committee shall be exempt from all civil service requirements.

91.105.4.3.&#xA0; Procedure.&#xA0; When the board determines that a matter is significant in nature, the board may refer the matter to a Sign Advisory Committee for evaluation and recommendation before it renders a decision thereon. When the matter is referred to a Sign Advisory Committee, the board shall consider, but is not bound to accept, the recommendation of the committee.

91.105.4.4.&#xA0; Composition of the Committee.&#xA0; The board shall select five persons from the Sign Advisory Committee member list to serve on a committee. The committee shall be composed of one member from each of the following interests:

	1.	One member of or designated by the Board of Building and Safety Commissioners;

	2.	One member of or designated by the City Planning Commission; and

	3.	Three public members, one each from the following interests: architecture, sign industry and community groups.

91.105.4.5.&#xA0; Compensation of Members.&#xA0; Each member of the committee who is in actual attendance at a meeting requested by the board shall be compensated at the rate of $50.00 for each four hours or fraction thereof of service. However, in no case shall the compensation of the committee members exceed the fee paid by the applicant under Section 91.105.4.7.

91.105.4.6.&#xA0; Self-insurance by the City for Committee Members.&#xA0; The provisions of Sections 11.36 through 11.44, inclusive, of the Los Angeles Administrative Code shall apply to each Sign Advisory Committee member while the member is acting as such, and committee members shall be deemed to be fully covered by the provisions of said sections even though each committee member is retained as an independent person and not as an officer or employee of the city.

91.105.4.7.&#xA0; Fees.&#xA0; When a matter is referred to the committee as provided in this section, the applicant in said matter shall pay a referral fee of $300.00.

91.105.5.&#xA0; Disabled Access Appeals Commission.

91.105.5.1.&#xA0; Creation of the Commission.&#xA0; There is hereby established a commission known as the Disabled Access Appeals Commission.

91.105.5.2.&#xA0; Membership of the Commission.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 173,238, Eff. 6/19/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)&#xA0; The Disabled Access Appeals Commission shall be composed of five qualified persons.&#xA0; Two members of the commission shall be physically disabled persons, and two members shall be persons experienced in construction. The fifth member may be any resident of the City of Los Angeles. Commission members shall be appointed by the Mayor, subject to Council approval, and may be removed by the Mayor.&#xA0; In the case of a vacancy during the term of office of any member, the same shall be filled by appointment by the mayor for the period of the unexpired term subject to the approval of the council by a majority vote. The members of the commission shall be exempt from all Civil Service provisions.

91.105.5.3.&#xA0; Compensation and Term of Office.&#xA0; Each member of the commission shall be paid $50.00 per meeting attended, but not to exceed $250.00 in any one calendar month.

	The term of office of the members of the commission shall be five years beginning with the first day of July of the respective years, except that the terms of office of the original five members of the commission appointed pursuant to this subsection shall be such that one term shall expire on the first June 30, one term shall expire on the second June 30, one term shall expire on the third June 30, one term shall expire on the fourth June 30, and one term shall expire on the fifth June 30 next following the effective date of the appointment of the original five members. Thereafter, the terms of the succeeding members shall be so designated that the term of office of one member shall expire each year. The period of term of each member shall be designated in the appointment.

	Each member of the commission shall have the power to administer oaths.

91.105.5.4.&#xA0; Authority of the Commission.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. 181,758, Eff. 8/8/11.)&#xA0; The commission shall have and exercise the following powers:

	1.	To hear and determine written appeals brought by any person from actions taken by the Department of Building and Safety (department) in the enforcement of the requirements of Section 19955, et seq., of the California Health and Safety Code, the provisions of state law dealing with access to public accommodations by physically disabled persons.

	2.	To hear and determine written appeals brought by any person from the rulings, decisions and determinations of the department granting or denying applications for exceptions pursuant to Health and Safety Code Section 19957.

	3.	To hear and determine written appeals brought by any persons where it is alleged that there is error or abuse of discretion in any order, requirement, decision, interpretation or other determination made by the department in the enforcement or administration of Section 1.8 et seq., Chapter 1, Division I of California Building Code and any other federal, state or municipal handicapped access and adaptability requirements.&#xA0;

	All appeals shall be reviewed by the department.&#xA0; The department may reverse or modify the action appealed from at any time prior to final action by the commission.&#xA0; Any such new action may then be appealed to the commission.

	4.	To respond to the department&#x2019;s request for advice on any matter within the department&#x2019;s jurisdiction relating to access to public accommodations and housing by the physically disabled.

	5.	To exercise the authority granted in Section 91.105.6.

91.105.5.5.&#xA0; Appeals.

91.105.5.5.1.&#xA0; Procedures.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 172,592, Eff. 6/28/99, Oper. 7/1/99.)&#xA0; An appeal to the commission may be filed by any person aggrieved, or by an officer, Board, Department or Bureau of the City. An appeal shall be in writing and shall be filed in the Office of the Board of Building and Safety Commissioners upon appropriate forms provided by the Department. An appeal shall set forth specifically the points at issue, the reasons for the appeal, and wherein the appellant believes there was an error or an abuse of discretion by the Department.

	When considering an appeal from an action by the Department, the commission shall make its determination within 30 days from the filing of the appeal. This time limit may be extended by mutual written consent of the applicant and the commission.&#xA0; Upon receipt of the appeal, the commission shall set the matter for hearing and give notice by mail of the time, place and purpose thereof to the appellant, to the applicant, to the owner or owners of the property involved, and to any interested party who has requested in writing to be so notified.&#xA0; Such notice shall be in writing and mailed at least 10 days prior to said hearing.&#xA0; No other notice thereof need be given except in those cases hereinafter mentioned.

	The commission may grant, conditionally grant, or deny any appeal.&#xA0; All actions of the commission shall be final.&#xA0; Any action within the jurisdiction of the commission shall be final and conclusive as to the Department in the absence of fraud or abuse of discretion.

	A separate appeal shall be filed for each single building as described in Section 98.0403.2 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code. Appeals to the Appeals Commission shall be accompanied by a filing fee as set forth in Table 4-A of Division 4 of Article 8, Chapter IX, of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.

	If the commission fails to act on any appeal within the time limit specified in this section, then the action of the Department on the matter shall be final.

91.105.5.5.2.&#xA0; Decision.&#xA0; The decision upon an appeal shall be concurred in by at least three members of the commission. The commission may modify or reverse a ruling, decision or determination appealed from only upon making written findings setting forth specifically wherein the action of the department was in error or constituted an abuse of discretion. The commission shall make specific written findings supporting any modification or reversal.

	Upon making a decision, a copy of the findings and determination shall be furnished the applicant, the appellant and the Department of Building and Safety.

91.105.5.5.3.&#xA0; Special Findings.&#xA0; Before granting or affirming the grant of an exception pursuant to Health and Safety Code Section 19957, the commission must find that the application involves a case of practical difficulty, unnecessary hardship, or extreme differences, and that it is clearly evident that equivalent facilitation and protection will be secured.

91.105.5.5.4.&#xA0; Revocation of Approvals.&#xA0; The commission shall revoke or rescind any determination, including the grant of an appeal or&#xA0; exception, if made in error in violation of any provision of law, or in reliance on any false statement or misrepresentation as to a material fact.

91.105.5.5.5.&#xA0; Time Limits.&#xA0; The rights and privileges granted by the commission pursuant to any decision, determination, approval, appeal or exception shall be void if all required building permits are not secured within one year of the effective date of such action, or if the permit expires under any of the conditions specified in Section 98.0602 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.

	However, the commission, and the superintendent acting on behalf of the commission, may grant extensions of time if the applicant submits in writing substantial evidence that unusual conditions or circumstances either precluded the securing of all required permits within the allocated time or caused the permit to expire as specified in Section 98.0602 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.

	Requests for extensions of time shall be made not later than 30 days after the expiration times specified in this section.

91.105.5.5.6.&#xA0; Additional Authority.&#xA0; In considering appeals, the commission may exercise the following powers:

	1.	To appoint one or more hearing officers to conduct hearings and make recommendations to the same extent and in the same manner as the Superintendent of Building acting pursuant to LAMC Section 98.0601 (a).&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 180,619, Eff. 5/12/09.)

	2.	To request the attendance of witnesses and the production of evidence before it.

	3.	To request the city attorney, or an assistant or deputy designated by the city attorney to appear at any hearing before the commission.

	4.	To adopt rules regarding the filing of appeals, the conduct of its hearings and any other procedural rules in keeping with the provisions of this Division.

91.105.5.5.7.&#xA0; Limitations on Jurisdiction.&#xA0; Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, the commission&#x2019;s jurisdiction shall not include the right to hear and determine an appeal from a department determination, order or action if such appeal is filed:

	1.	On or after the date a criminal citation is issued, charging the appellant with a violation of law based on the facts underlying such determination, order or action; or

	2.	On or after the date a criminal complaint is filed, charging the appellant with a violation of state laws based on such determination, order or action.

	Further, the commission&#x2019;s jurisdiction shall not include the right to hear appeals from or otherwise review any action, order or determination of the Board of Building and Safety Commissioners.

91.105.6.&#xA0; Administrative Penalties for Disabled Access Violations.

91.105.6.1.&#xA0; Order of Abatement and Notice of Proposed Penalty.&#xA0; If the superintendent determines that a person has violated or failed to comply with any requirement of the law relating to access to public accommodations and housing by the physically disabled, then the superintendent may issue an order of abatement and notice of proposed penalty to that person.

	The order and notice shall be in writing and shall describe with particularity the nature of the violation, including a reference to the provision of law that has been violated. The order shall fix a reasonable time for correction of the violation, and the notice of proposed penalty shall set forth the amount of the penalty.

	The order of abatement and notice of proposed penalty shall be served upon the person either personally, or by deposit in the United States mail in a sealed envelope, postage prepaid to the person&#x2019;s last known address.

	The order and notice shall also set forth the person&#x2019;s right to a hearing as described in Section 91.105.6.2.

91.105.6.2.&#xA0; Right to Hearing.&#xA0; Any person served with an order of abatement or notice of proposed penalty, may apply in writing to the Disabled Access Appeals Commission for a hearing with respect to the violation alleged, the abatement period, and the amount of the penalty. This request shall be filed within 15 days after the date of service.

	If the person does not request a hearing within the prescribed time, then the notice of proposed penalty shall be final, and the amount of any penalty included in the notice shall immediately be due and owing to the City of Los Angeles. The city then shall have the right to bring an action in any court of competent jurisdiction to enforce the order and collect the amount of the penalty.

	If the department determines that there has been compliance with the order of abatement within the time for correction, then the department may rescind the notice of penalty.

91.105.6.3.&#xA0; Time of Hearing; Notice.&#xA0; If the person requests a hearing, the superintendent shall cause the matter to be set for hearing before the Disabled Access Appeals Commission. The hearing shall be scheduled not later than 30 days after the date of the application for hearing. This time limit may be extended with the mutual consent of the person and the commission. It shall be a defense to the affirmation of any penalty that the person complied with the order of abatement within the time for correction.

	The decision of the commission on the order of abatement and notice of proposed penalty shall be final, and the amount of any penalty affirmed by the commission shall immediately be due and owing to the City of Los Angeles. The city then shall have the right to bring an action in any court of competent jurisdiction to enforce the order and collect the amount of penalty.

91.105.6.4&#xA0; Civil Penalties.&#xA0; Any penalty required to be paid under the provisions of this section is a debt owed to the City of Los Angeles. Any person owing a penalty due under the provisions of this section shall be liable in an action brought in the name of the City of Los Angeles in any court of competent jurisdiction for recovery of any such amount.

	The conviction of any person for violating any law shall not relieve the person from the obligation to pay any penalty that the person may owe the city, nor shall such payment prevent a prosecution under appropriate provisions of law for any violation of the law. The remedies provided in this section are cumulative. The use of one or more of the remedies prescribed in this section shall not bar the use of any other remedy provided for the enforcement of law.

91.105.6.5.&#xA0; Fee Schedules.&#xA0; The Superintendent shall submit a schedule for the assessment of civil penalties under this section to council for the approval by ordinance.

	This schedule shall give due consideration to the appropriateness of the penalty with respect to the following factors:

	1.	The gravity of the violation;

	2.	The good faith of the violator being charged; and

	3.	The history of previous violations.</full_text><order_by>105</order_by><ancestry><unit id="31" label="article"><name>Buildings
Building Code</name><identifier>1</identifier><url>/9/1/</url></unit><unit id="3" label="chapter"><name>Building Regulations</name><identifier>9</identifier><url>/9/</url></unit></ancestry><structure_contents><unit id="2853"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.101</section_number><catch_line>Title, Purpose, And Scope.</catch_line><url>/91.101/</url><token>91.101</token></unit><unit id="3256"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.102</section_number><catch_line>Unsafe Buildings Or Structures.</catch_line><url>/91.102/</url><token>91.102</token></unit><unit id="3122"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.103</section_number><catch_line>Violations.</catch_line><url>/91.103/</url><token>91.103</token></unit><unit id="2872"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.104</section_number><catch_line>Organization And Enforcement.</catch_line><url>/91.104/</url><token>91.104</token></unit><unit id="2331"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.105</section_number><catch_line>Appeals.</catch_line><url>/91.105/</url><token>91.105</token></unit><unit id="1085"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.106</section_number><catch_line>Permits.</catch_line><url>/91.106/</url><token>91.106</token></unit><unit id="167"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.107</section_number><catch_line>Fees.</catch_line><url>/91.107/</url><token>91.107</token></unit><unit id="2271"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.108</section_number><catch_line>Inspection.</catch_line><url>/91.108/</url><token>91.108</token></unit><unit id="599"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.109</section_number><catch_line>Certificate Of Occupancy.</catch_line><url>/91.109/</url><token>91.109</token></unit><unit id="1493"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.110</section_number><catch_line>Responsibility Of Permittee.</catch_line><url>/91.110/</url><token>91.110</token></unit><unit id="1948"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.111</section_number><catch_line>Code Revision.</catch_line><url>/91.111/</url><token>91.111</token></unit><unit id="3017"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.112</section_number><catch_line>Grading Certificate.</catch_line><url>/91.112/</url><token>91.112</token></unit><unit id="3299"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.200</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/91.200/</url><token>91.200</token></unit><unit id="914"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.202</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/91.202/</url><token>91.202</token></unit><unit id="526"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.300</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.300/</url><token>91.300</token></unit><unit id="2739"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.400</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.400/</url><token>91.400</token></unit><unit id="907"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.500</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.500/</url><token>91.500</token></unit><unit id="2530"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.600</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.600/</url><token>91.600</token></unit><unit id="234"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.700</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.700/</url><token>91.700</token></unit><unit id="2933"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.703</section_number><catch_line>Fire-Resistance Ratings And Fire Tests.</catch_line><url>/91.703/</url><token>91.703</token></unit><unit id="108"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.800</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.800/</url><token>91.800</token></unit><unit id="2861"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.900</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.900/</url><token>91.900</token></unit><unit id="700"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.909</section_number><catch_line>Smoke Control Systems.</catch_line><url>/91.909/</url><token>91.909</token></unit><unit id="223"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1000</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.1000/</url><token>91.1000</token></unit><unit id="3826"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1100</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.1100/</url><token>91.1100</token></unit><unit id="1343"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1200</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.1200/</url><token>91.1200</token></unit><unit id="3724"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1207</section_number><catch_line>Sound Transmission.</catch_line><url>/91.1207/</url><token>91.1207</token></unit><unit id="2466"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1300</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/91.1300/</url><token>91.1300</token></unit><unit id="2493"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1301</section_number><catch_line>Solar Energy Collectors.</catch_line><url>/91.1301/</url><token>91.1301</token></unit><unit id="4023"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1400</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.1400/</url><token>91.1400</token></unit><unit id="412"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1403</section_number><catch_line>Performance Requirements.</catch_line><url>/91.1403/</url><token>91.1403</token></unit><unit id="3406"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1405</section_number><catch_line>Installation Of Wall Coverings.</catch_line><url>/91.1405/</url><token>91.1405</token></unit><unit id="2965"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1500</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.1500/</url><token>91.1500</token></unit><unit id="2559"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1505</section_number><catch_line>Fire Classification.</catch_line><url>/91.1505/</url><token>91.1505</token></unit><unit id="538"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1507</section_number><catch_line>Requirements For Roof Coverings.</catch_line><url>/91.1507/</url><token>91.1507</token></unit><unit id="897"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1510</section_number><catch_line>Reroofing.</catch_line><url>/91.1510/</url><token>91.1510</token></unit><unit id="281"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1600</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.1600/</url><token>91.1600</token></unit><unit id="1561"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1603</section_number><catch_line>Construction Documents.</catch_line><url>/91.1603/</url><token>91.1603</token></unit><unit id="1482"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1609</section_number><catch_line>Wind Loads.</catch_line><url>/91.1609/</url><token>91.1609</token></unit><unit id="1027"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1612</section_number><catch_line>Flood Loads.</catch_line><url>/91.1612/</url><token>91.1612</token></unit><unit id="876"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1613</section_number><catch_line>Earthquake Loads.</catch_line><url>/91.1613/</url><token>91.1613</token></unit><unit id="1949"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1616</section_number><catch_line>Modifications To Asce 7.</catch_line><url>/91.1616/</url><token>91.1616</token></unit><unit id="3547"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1700</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.1700/</url><token>91.1700</token></unit><unit id="2160"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1702</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/91.1702/</url><token>91.1702</token></unit><unit id="4049"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1703</section_number><catch_line>Approvals.</catch_line><url>/91.1703/</url><token>91.1703</token></unit><unit id="1545"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1704</section_number><catch_line>Special Inspections.</catch_line><url>/91.1704/</url><token>91.1704</token></unit><unit id="1592"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1705</section_number><catch_line>Statement Of Special Inspections.</catch_line><url>/91.1705/</url><token>91.1705</token></unit><unit id="3633"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1707</section_number><catch_line>Special Inspections For Seismic Resistance.</catch_line><url>/91.1707/</url><token>91.1707</token></unit><unit id="1397"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1708</section_number><catch_line>Structural Testing For Seismic Resistance.</catch_line><url>/91.1708/</url><token>91.1708</token></unit><unit id="1425"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1709</section_number><catch_line>Contractors Responsibility.</catch_line><url>/91.1709/</url><token>91.1709</token></unit><unit id="570"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1710</section_number><catch_line>Structural Observations.</catch_line><url>/91.1710/</url><token>91.1710</token></unit><unit id="1953"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1711</section_number><catch_line>Alternative Test Procedure.</catch_line><url>/91.1711/</url><token>91.1711</token></unit><unit id="2084"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1712</section_number><catch_line>Alternative Test Procedure.</catch_line><url>/91.1712/</url><token>91.1712</token></unit><unit id="1655"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1715</section_number><catch_line>Material And Test Standards.</catch_line><url>/91.1715/</url><token>91.1715</token></unit><unit id="3711"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1716</section_number><catch_line>Material And Test Standards.</catch_line><url>/91.1716/</url><token>91.1716</token></unit><unit id="2263"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1717</section_number><catch_line>Certified Security Bar Installer.</catch_line><url>/91.1717/</url><token>91.1717</token></unit><unit id="4088"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1718</section_number><catch_line>Prefabricated Construction.</catch_line><url>/91.1718/</url><token>91.1718</token></unit><unit id="868"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1800</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.1800/</url><token>91.1800</token></unit><unit id="2813"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1801</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/91.1801/</url><token>91.1801</token></unit><unit id="3798"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1802</section_number><catch_line>Foundation And Soils Investigations.</catch_line><url>/91.1802/</url><token>91.1802</token></unit><unit id="908"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1803</section_number><catch_line>Geotechnical Investigation.</catch_line><url>/91.1803/</url><token>91.1803</token></unit><unit id="2732"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1804</section_number><catch_line>Allowable Load-Bearing Values Of Soils.</catch_line><url>/91.1804/</url><token>91.1804</token></unit><unit id="3068"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1805</section_number><catch_line>Dampproofing And Waterproofing.</catch_line><url>/91.1805/</url><token>91.1805</token></unit><unit id="3377"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1806</section_number><catch_line>Presumptive Load Bearing Values Of Soils.</catch_line><url>/91.1806/</url><token>91.1806</token></unit><unit id="245"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1807</section_number><catch_line>Foundation Walls, Retaining Walls, And Embedded Post And Poles.</catch_line><url>/91.1807/</url><token>91.1807</token></unit><unit id="985"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1808</section_number><catch_line>Pier And Pile Foundations.</catch_line><url>/91.1808/</url><token>91.1808</token></unit><unit id="1115"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1809</section_number><catch_line>Shallow Foundations.</catch_line><url>/91.1809/</url><token>91.1809</token></unit><unit id="2671"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1810</section_number><catch_line>Deep Foundations..</catch_line><url>/91.1810/</url><token>91.1810</token></unit><unit id="1195"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.1900</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.1900/</url><token>91.1900</token></unit><unit id="705"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.2000</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.2000/</url><token>91.2000</token></unit><unit id="3588"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.2100</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.2100/</url><token>91.2100</token></unit><unit id="2590"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.2113</section_number><catch_line>Masonry Chimneys.</catch_line><url>/91.2113/</url><token>91.2113</token></unit><unit id="3481"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.2200</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.2200/</url><token>91.2200</token></unit><unit id="473"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.2204</section_number><catch_line>Connections.</catch_line><url>/91.2204/</url><token>91.2204</token></unit><unit id="3742"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.2300</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.2300/</url><token>91.2300</token></unit><unit id="2404"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.2301</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/91.2301/</url><token>91.2301</token></unit><unit id="1279"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.2304</section_number><catch_line>General Construction Requirements.</catch_line><url>/91.2304/</url><token>91.2304</token></unit><unit id="2712"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.2305</section_number><catch_line>General Design Requirements For Lateral Force-Resisting System.</catch_line><url>/91.2305/</url><token>91.2305</token></unit><unit id="2825"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.2306</section_number><catch_line>Allowable Stress Design.</catch_line><url>/91.2306/</url><token>91.2306</token></unit><unit id="1924"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.2308</section_number><catch_line>Conventional Light-Frame Construction.</catch_line><url>/91.2308/</url><token>91.2308</token></unit><unit id="2821"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.2400</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.2400/</url><token>91.2400</token></unit><unit id="3669"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.2503</section_number><catch_line>No title</catch_line><url>/91.2503/</url><token>91.2503</token></unit><unit id="140"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.2600</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.2600/</url><token>91.2600</token></unit><unit id="3651"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.2700</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.2700/</url><token>91.2700</token></unit><unit id="1636"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.2800</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.2800/</url><token>91.2800</token></unit><unit id="468"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.2900</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.2900/</url><token>91.2900</token></unit><unit id="1724"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3000</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.3000/</url><token>91.3000</token></unit><unit id="452"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3001</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/91.3001/</url><token>91.3001</token></unit><unit id="2241"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3002</section_number><catch_line>Hoistway Enclosures.</catch_line><url>/91.3002/</url><token>91.3002</token></unit><unit id="3526"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3003</section_number><catch_line>Emergency Operations.</catch_line><url>/91.3003/</url><token>91.3003</token></unit><unit id="1580"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3005</section_number><catch_line>Conveying Systems.</catch_line><url>/91.3005/</url><token>91.3005</token></unit><unit id="1731"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3007</section_number><catch_line>Fire Service Access Elevator.</catch_line><url>/91.3007/</url><token>91.3007</token></unit><unit id="901"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3008</section_number><catch_line>Occupant Evacuation Elevators.</catch_line><url>/91.3008/</url><token>91.3008</token></unit><unit id="3501"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3100</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.3100/</url><token>91.3100</token></unit><unit id="665"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3106</section_number><catch_line>Marquees.</catch_line><url>/91.3106/</url><token>91.3106</token></unit><unit id="2449"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3110</section_number><catch_line>Patio Covers.</catch_line><url>/91.3110/</url><token>91.3110</token></unit><unit id="1647"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3111</section_number><catch_line>Patio Covers.</catch_line><url>/91.3111/</url><token>91.3111</token></unit><unit id="2362"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3200</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.3200/</url><token>91.3200</token></unit><unit id="1572"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3201</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/91.3201/</url><token>91.3201</token></unit><unit id="1188"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3202</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/91.3202/</url><token>91.3202</token></unit><unit id="147"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3300</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.3300/</url><token>91.3300</token></unit><unit id="4035"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3301</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/91.3301/</url><token>91.3301</token></unit><unit id="1111"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3304</section_number><catch_line>Site Work.</catch_line><url>/91.3304/</url><token>91.3304</token></unit><unit id="152"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3305</section_number><catch_line>Toilet Facilities During Construction.</catch_line><url>/91.3305/</url><token>91.3305</token></unit><unit id="3930"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3306</section_number><catch_line>Protection Of Pedestrians.</catch_line><url>/91.3306/</url><token>91.3306</token></unit><unit id="4116"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3307</section_number><catch_line>Protection Of Adjoining Property.</catch_line><url>/91.3307/</url><token>91.3307</token></unit><unit id="421"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3401</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/91.3401/</url><token>91.3401</token></unit><unit id="614"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.3500</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.3500/</url><token>91.3500</token></unit><unit id="3462"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6101</section_number><catch_line>Impact Hazard Glazing In Existing Buildings.</catch_line><url>/91.6101/</url><token>91.6101</token></unit><unit id="3380"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6102</section_number><catch_line>Rubbish Rooms.</catch_line><url>/91.6102/</url><token>91.6102</token></unit><unit id="3997"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6103</section_number><catch_line>Shafts, Pits And Similar Excavation &#x2013; Misdemeanor.</catch_line><url>/91.6103/</url><token>91.6103</token></unit><unit id="895"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6104</section_number><catch_line>Fire Districts.</catch_line><url>/91.6104/</url><token>91.6104</token></unit><unit id="3554"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6105</section_number><catch_line>Separation From Oil Wells.</catch_line><url>/91.6105/</url><token>91.6105</token></unit><unit id="3862"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6107</section_number><catch_line>Transformer Vaults.</catch_line><url>/91.6107/</url><token>91.6107</token></unit><unit id="3484"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6109</section_number><catch_line>Swimming Pools And Other Bodies Of Water &#x2013; Protective Devices Required.</catch_line><url>/91.6109/</url><token>91.6109</token></unit><unit id="1909"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6201</section_number><catch_line>General Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.6201/</url><token>91.6201</token></unit><unit id="1048"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6202</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/91.6202/</url><token>91.6202</token></unit><unit id="3093"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6203</section_number><catch_line>Location.</catch_line><url>/91.6203/</url><token>91.6203</token></unit><unit id="2989"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6204</section_number><catch_line>Identification.</catch_line><url>/91.6204/</url><token>91.6204</token></unit><unit id="1238"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6205</section_number><catch_line>Design And Construction.</catch_line><url>/91.6205/</url><token>91.6205</token></unit><unit id="1439"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6206</section_number><catch_line>Electrical.</catch_line><url>/91.6206/</url><token>91.6206</token></unit><unit id="1625"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6207</section_number><catch_line>Combustible Materials.</catch_line><url>/91.6207/</url><token>91.6207</token></unit><unit id="2354"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6208</section_number><catch_line>Animated Devices.</catch_line><url>/91.6208/</url><token>91.6208</token></unit><unit id="539"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6209</section_number><catch_line>Ground Signs.</catch_line><url>/91.6209/</url><token>91.6209</token></unit><unit id="1010"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6210</section_number><catch_line>Roof Signs.</catch_line><url>/91.6210/</url><token>91.6210</token></unit><unit id="3890"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6211</section_number><catch_line>Wall Signs.</catch_line><url>/91.6211/</url><token>91.6211</token></unit><unit id="3021"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6212</section_number><catch_line>Projecting Signs.</catch_line><url>/91.6212/</url><token>91.6212</token></unit><unit id="2568"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6213</section_number><catch_line>Marquee Signs.</catch_line><url>/91.6213/</url><token>91.6213</token></unit><unit id="1235"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6214</section_number><catch_line>Portable Signs.</catch_line><url>/91.6214/</url><token>91.6214</token></unit><unit id="2906"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6215</section_number><catch_line>Referenced Standards.</catch_line><url>/91.6215/</url><token>91.6215</token></unit><unit id="793"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6216</section_number><catch_line>Existing Signs.</catch_line><url>/91.6216/</url><token>91.6216</token></unit><unit id="508"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6301</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/91.6301/</url><token>91.6301</token></unit><unit id="374"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6302</section_number><catch_line>Food Establishment.</catch_line><url>/91.6302/</url><token>91.6302</token></unit><unit id="678"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6303</section_number><catch_line>Service Stations.</catch_line><url>/91.6303/</url><token>91.6303</token></unit><unit id="1695"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6304</section_number><catch_line>Residential Uses.</catch_line><url>/91.6304/</url><token>91.6304</token></unit><unit id="3817"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6305</section_number><catch_line>Parking Garages Serving Residential Uses.</catch_line><url>/91.6305/</url><token>91.6305</token></unit><unit id="2217"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6306</section_number><catch_line>Anti-Graffiti Finish To Exterior Walls.</catch_line><url>/91.6306/</url><token>91.6306</token></unit><unit id="4050"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6307</section_number><catch_line>Shower And Locker Facilities.</catch_line><url>/91.6307/</url><token>91.6307</token></unit><unit id="3103"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6701</section_number><catch_line>Purpose.</catch_line><url>/91.6701/</url><token>91.6701</token></unit><unit id="1137"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6702</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/91.6702/</url><token>91.6702</token></unit><unit id="454"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6703</section_number><catch_line>Limitations.</catch_line><url>/91.6703/</url><token>91.6703</token></unit><unit id="2121"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6704</section_number><catch_line>Alternate Security Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.6704/</url><token>91.6704</token></unit><unit id="3405"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6705</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/91.6705/</url><token>91.6705</token></unit><unit id="3503"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6706</section_number><catch_line>Entry Vision.</catch_line><url>/91.6706/</url><token>91.6706</token></unit><unit id="2163"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6707</section_number><catch_line>Appurtenant Access.</catch_line><url>/91.6707/</url><token>91.6707</token></unit><unit id="2420"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6708</section_number><catch_line>Doors &#x2013; General.</catch_line><url>/91.6708/</url><token>91.6708</token></unit><unit id="3771"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6709</section_number><catch_line>Swinging Doors.</catch_line><url>/91.6709/</url><token>91.6709</token></unit><unit id="2626"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6710</section_number><catch_line>Sliding Glass Doors.</catch_line><url>/91.6710/</url><token>91.6710</token></unit><unit id="1882"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6711</section_number><catch_line>Overhead And Sliding Doors.</catch_line><url>/91.6711/</url><token>91.6711</token></unit><unit id="63"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6712</section_number><catch_line>Metal Accordion-Grate Or Grille-Type Doors.</catch_line><url>/91.6712/</url><token>91.6712</token></unit><unit id="4119"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6713</section_number><catch_line>Glazed Opening &#x2013; General.</catch_line><url>/91.6713/</url><token>91.6713</token></unit><unit id="2953"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6714</section_number><catch_line>Glazing.</catch_line><url>/91.6714/</url><token>91.6714</token></unit><unit id="4128"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6715</section_number><catch_line>Windows.</catch_line><url>/91.6715/</url><token>91.6715</token></unit><unit id="4020"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6716</section_number><catch_line>Openings Other Than Doors Or Glazed Openings.</catch_line><url>/91.6716/</url><token>91.6716</token></unit><unit id="4008"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.6717</section_number><catch_line>Tests &#x2013; General.</catch_line><url>/91.6717/</url><token>91.6717</token></unit><unit id="3041"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7001</section_number><catch_line>Purpose.</catch_line><url>/91.7001/</url><token>91.7001</token></unit><unit id="1161"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7002</section_number><catch_line>Scope.</catch_line><url>/91.7002/</url><token>91.7002</token></unit><unit id="2566"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7003</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/91.7003/</url><token>91.7003</token></unit><unit id="588"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7004</section_number><catch_line>Grading Designation.</catch_line><url>/91.7004/</url><token>91.7004</token></unit><unit id="1918"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7005</section_number><catch_line>General Requirements.</catch_line><url>/91.7005/</url><token>91.7005</token></unit><unit id="3963"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7006</section_number><catch_line>Conditions Precedent To Issuing A Grading Permit.</catch_line><url>/91.7006/</url><token>91.7006</token></unit><unit id="3848"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7007</section_number><catch_line>Safety Precautions During Grading.</catch_line><url>/91.7007/</url><token>91.7007</token></unit><unit id="371"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7008</section_number><catch_line>Professional Inspection And Certification For Engineered Grading.</catch_line><url>/91.7008/</url><token>91.7008</token></unit><unit id="1173"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7009</section_number><catch_line>Professional Inspection For Regular Grading.</catch_line><url>/91.7009/</url><token>91.7009</token></unit><unit id="1796"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7010</section_number><catch_line>Excavations.</catch_line><url>/91.7010/</url><token>91.7010</token></unit><unit id="2641"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7011</section_number><catch_line>Fills.</catch_line><url>/91.7011/</url><token>91.7011</token></unit><unit id="2520"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7012</section_number><catch_line>Planting And Irrigation Of Cut And Fill Slopes In Hillside Areas.</catch_line><url>/91.7012/</url><token>91.7012</token></unit><unit id="2147"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7013</section_number><catch_line>Erosion Control And Drainage Devices.</catch_line><url>/91.7013/</url><token>91.7013</token></unit><unit id="419"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7014</section_number><catch_line>Construction Requirements And Limitations.</catch_line><url>/91.7014/</url><token>91.7014</token></unit><unit id="4104"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7015</section_number><catch_line>Buttress Fills.</catch_line><url>/91.7015/</url><token>91.7015</token></unit><unit id="79"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7016</section_number><catch_line>Areas Subjected To Slides And Unstable Soil.</catch_line><url>/91.7016/</url><token>91.7016</token></unit><unit id="1597"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7101</section_number><catch_line>Purpose.</catch_line><url>/91.7101/</url><token>91.7101</token></unit><unit id="3702"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7102</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/91.7102/</url><token>91.7102</token></unit><unit id="3674"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7103</section_number><catch_line>General Methane Mitigation Requirements.</catch_line><url>/91.7103/</url><token>91.7103</token></unit><unit id="420"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7104</section_number><catch_line>General Methane Requirements.</catch_line><url>/91.7104/</url><token>91.7104</token></unit><unit id="1436"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7105</section_number><catch_line>Existing Buildings.</catch_line><url>/91.7105/</url><token>91.7105</token></unit><unit id="3904"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7106</section_number><catch_line>Testing, Maintenance And Service Of Gas-Detection And Mechanical Ventilation Systems.</catch_line><url>/91.7106/</url><token>91.7106</token></unit><unit id="1211"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7107</section_number><catch_line>Emergency Procedures.</catch_line><url>/91.7107/</url><token>91.7107</token></unit><unit id="1937"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7108</section_number><catch_line>Application Of Methane Seepage Regulations To Locations Or Areas Outside The Methane Zone And Methane Buffer Zone Boundaries.</catch_line><url>/91.7108/</url><token>91.7108</token></unit><unit id="3382"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7109</section_number><catch_line>Additional Remedial Measures.</catch_line><url>/91.7109/</url><token>91.7109</token></unit><unit id="607"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7200</section_number><catch_line>Purpose.</catch_line><url>/91.7200/</url><token>91.7200</token></unit><unit id="2819"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7201</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/91.7201/</url><token>91.7201</token></unit><unit id="2083"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7202</section_number><catch_line>Additions To Buildings.</catch_line><url>/91.7202/</url><token>91.7202</token></unit><unit id="1678"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7203</section_number><catch_line>General Requirements.</catch_line><url>/91.7203/</url><token>91.7203</token></unit><unit id="506"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7204</section_number><catch_line>Special Requirements For Fire District Number 1.</catch_line><url>/91.7204/</url><token>91.7204</token></unit><unit id="2563"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7205</section_number><catch_line>Provisional Structures.</catch_line><url>/91.7205/</url><token>91.7205</token></unit><unit id="3151"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7206</section_number><catch_line>Special Requirements For Fire District Number 2.</catch_line><url>/91.7206/</url><token>91.7206</token></unit><unit id="804"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7207</section_number><catch_line>Special Requirements For The Very High Fire Hazard Severity Zone.</catch_line><url>/91.7207/</url><token>91.7207</token></unit><unit id="933"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7208</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited Vehicles.</catch_line><url>/91.7208/</url><token>91.7208</token></unit><unit id="2867"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.7209</section_number><catch_line>Special Requirements For Fire Buffer Zone.</catch_line><url>/91.7209/</url><token>91.7209</token></unit><unit id="217"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8101</section_number><catch_line>General Provisions.</catch_line><url>/91.8101/</url><token>91.8101</token></unit><unit id="368"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8102</section_number><catch_line>Enforcement.</catch_line><url>/91.8102/</url><token>91.8102</token></unit><unit id="1185"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8103</section_number><catch_line>Existing Building Rights.</catch_line><url>/91.8103/</url><token>91.8103</token></unit><unit id="56"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8104</section_number><catch_line>Basic Maintenance And Repair Of Existing Buildings And Premises.</catch_line><url>/91.8104/</url><token>91.8104</token></unit><unit id="1159"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8105</section_number><catch_line>Illegal Buildings, Construction And Use.</catch_line><url>/91.8105/</url><token>91.8105</token></unit><unit id="3215"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8106</section_number><catch_line>Fire District Requirements.</catch_line><url>/91.8106/</url><token>91.8106</token></unit><unit id="3064"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8107</section_number><catch_line>Requirements Outside Of A Fire District.</catch_line><url>/91.8107/</url><token>91.8107</token></unit><unit id="139"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8108</section_number><catch_line>Nuisances, Hazardous Buildings And Substandard Residential Buildings.</catch_line><url>/91.8108/</url><token>91.8108</token></unit><unit id="138"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8109</section_number><catch_line>Relocated Buildings.</catch_line><url>/91.8109/</url><token>91.8109</token></unit><unit id="2049"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8110</section_number><catch_line>Unreinforced Masonry Bearing Wall Buildings.</catch_line><url>/91.8110/</url><token>91.8110</token></unit><unit id="3586"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8111</section_number><catch_line>Residential Heating.</catch_line><url>/91.8111/</url><token>91.8111</token></unit><unit id="2383"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8112</section_number><catch_line>Residential Plumbing.</catch_line><url>/91.8112/</url><token>91.8112</token></unit><unit id="55"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8113</section_number><catch_line>Rod Bracing Systems.</catch_line><url>/91.8113/</url><token>91.8113</token></unit><unit id="825"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8114</section_number><catch_line>Parapets And Appendages.</catch_line><url>/91.8114/</url><token>91.8114</token></unit><unit id="880"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8115</section_number><catch_line>Sandblasting.</catch_line><url>/91.8115/</url><token>91.8115</token></unit><unit id="769"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8116</section_number><catch_line>Special Provisions For Light-Housekeeping Rooms.</catch_line><url>/91.8116/</url><token>91.8116</token></unit><unit id="153"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8117</section_number><catch_line>Fire Watch.</catch_line><url>/91.8117/</url><token>91.8117</token></unit><unit id="3493"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8118</section_number><catch_line>Pool Water Clarity.</catch_line><url>/91.8118/</url><token>91.8118</token></unit><unit id="3611"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8119</section_number><catch_line>Historical Buildings And Structures.</catch_line><url>/91.8119/</url><token>91.8119</token></unit><unit id="3592"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8201</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/91.8201/</url><token>91.8201</token></unit><unit id="3344"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8202</section_number><catch_line>Change Of Rating Classification.</catch_line><url>/91.8202/</url><token>91.8202</token></unit><unit id="1463"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8203</section_number><catch_line>Change Of Occupancy Group Or Group Division.</catch_line><url>/91.8203/</url><token>91.8203</token></unit><unit id="3011"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8204</section_number><catch_line>Change Of Use.</catch_line><url>/91.8204/</url><token>91.8204</token></unit><unit id="2534"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8205</section_number><catch_line>Certificate Of Building Compliance.</catch_line><url>/91.8205/</url><token>91.8205</token></unit><unit id="931"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8301</section_number><catch_line>General Application.</catch_line><url>/91.8301/</url><token>91.8301</token></unit><unit id="262"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8302</section_number><catch_line>Permits Required &#x2013; General Considerations.</catch_line><url>/91.8302/</url><token>91.8302</token></unit><unit id="1619"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8303</section_number><catch_line>Permit Application &#x2013; Plans And Specifications.</catch_line><url>/91.8303/</url><token>91.8303</token></unit><unit id="1143"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8304</section_number><catch_line>Special Conditions Under Which A Permit Will Not Be Issued.</catch_line><url>/91.8304/</url><token>91.8304</token></unit><unit id="1828"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8305</section_number><catch_line>Guarantee Of Completion Required.</catch_line><url>/91.8305/</url><token>91.8305</token></unit><unit id="500"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8306</section_number><catch_line>Terms Of Permit.</catch_line><url>/91.8306/</url><token>91.8306</token></unit><unit id="1658"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8307</section_number><catch_line>Default In Performance Of Conditions Or Terms Of Permits &#x2013; Failure To Complete.</catch_line><url>/91.8307/</url><token>91.8307</token></unit><unit id="2618"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8308</section_number><catch_line>Permit Fees.</catch_line><url>/91.8308/</url><token>91.8308</token></unit><unit id="1064"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8309</section_number><catch_line>Entry Upon Premises.</catch_line><url>/91.8309/</url><token>91.8309</token></unit><unit id="1333"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8501</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/91.8501/</url><token>91.8501</token></unit><unit id="1595"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8502</section_number><catch_line>Alternative Standards.</catch_line><url>/91.8502/</url><token>91.8502</token></unit><unit id="3262"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8601</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/91.8601/</url><token>91.8601</token></unit><unit id="2797"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8602</section_number><catch_line>Group E Occupancies.</catch_line><url>/91.8602/</url><token>91.8602</token></unit><unit id="2928"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8603</section_number><catch_line>Fire Protection &#x2013; Warning System.</catch_line><url>/91.8603/</url><token>91.8603</token></unit><unit id="492"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8604</section_number><catch_line>Fire Safety Standards.</catch_line><url>/91.8604/</url><token>91.8604</token></unit><unit id="683"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8605</section_number><catch_line>Emergency Homeless Shelters.</catch_line><url>/91.8605/</url><token>91.8605</token></unit><unit id="2592"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8606</section_number><catch_line>Emergency Lighting Standards For Existing Residential Buildings, Group R, Division 1 Occupancies.</catch_line><url>/91.8606/</url><token>91.8606</token></unit><unit id="3686"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8607</section_number><catch_line>Tenant Safety For Apartment Houses, Except For Residential Condominiums.</catch_line><url>/91.8607/</url><token>91.8607</token></unit><unit id="3585"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8801</section_number><catch_line>Purpose.</catch_line><url>/91.8801/</url><token>91.8801</token></unit><unit id="2521"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8802</section_number><catch_line>Scope.</catch_line><url>/91.8802/</url><token>91.8802</token></unit><unit id="1316"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8803</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/91.8803/</url><token>91.8803</token></unit><unit id="369"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8804</section_number><catch_line>Rating Classifications.</catch_line><url>/91.8804/</url><token>91.8804</token></unit><unit id="1639"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8805</section_number><catch_line>General Requirements.</catch_line><url>/91.8805/</url><token>91.8805</token></unit><unit id="3640"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8806</section_number><catch_line>Administration.</catch_line><url>/91.8806/</url><token>91.8806</token></unit><unit id="1824"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8807</section_number><catch_line>Historical Buildings.</catch_line><url>/91.8807/</url><token>91.8807</token></unit><unit id="1415"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8808</section_number><catch_line>Analysis And Design.</catch_line><url>/91.8808/</url><token>91.8808</token></unit><unit id="3279"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8809</section_number><catch_line>Materials Of Construction.</catch_line><url>/91.8809/</url><token>91.8809</token></unit><unit id="3321"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8810</section_number><catch_line>Information Required On Plans.</catch_line><url>/91.8810/</url><token>91.8810</token></unit><unit id="807"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8811</section_number><catch_line>Design Check &#x2013; Compatibility Of Roof Diaphragm Stiffness To Unreinforced Masonry Wall Out-Of-Plane Stability.</catch_line><url>/91.8811/</url><token>91.8811</token></unit><unit id="867"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8812</section_number><catch_line>Violations.</catch_line><url>/91.8812/</url><token>91.8812</token></unit><unit id="3941"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8813</section_number><catch_line>Special Requirements For Vacant Buildings.</catch_line><url>/91.8813/</url><token>91.8813</token></unit><unit id="67"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8901</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/91.8901/</url><token>91.8901</token></unit><unit id="3410"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8902</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/91.8902/</url><token>91.8902</token></unit><unit id="1512"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8903</section_number><catch_line>Abatement Procedures.</catch_line><url>/91.8903/</url><token>91.8903</token></unit><unit id="1660"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8904</section_number><catch_line>Special Provisions For Vacant Property Graffiti Removal.</catch_line><url>/91.8904/</url><token>91.8904</token></unit><unit id="176"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8905</section_number><catch_line>Special Provisions For Vacating, Barricading, Removing Or Demolishing Buildings Or Structures Without Notice.</catch_line><url>/91.8905/</url><token>91.8905</token></unit><unit id="2186"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8906</section_number><catch_line>Payment And Recovery Of Repair And Demolition Funds.</catch_line><url>/91.8906/</url><token>91.8906</token></unit><unit id="3603"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8907</section_number><catch_line>Abatement Of Public Nuisance Conditions Related To A Declared Local Emergency.</catch_line><url>/91.8907/</url><token>91.8907</token></unit><unit id="3276"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8908</section_number><catch_line>Special Provisions For The Repair Of Welded Steel Moment Frame Buildings Located In High Earthquake Damaged Areas.</catch_line><url>/91.8908/</url><token>91.8908</token></unit><unit id="3128"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.8910</section_number><catch_line>Procedure For Abatement Of Nuisance; Recovery Of Attorney Fees; Assessment; Notice To Owner; Sale Of Property.</catch_line><url>/91.8910/</url><token>91.8910</token></unit><unit id="3109"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9001</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/91.9001/</url><token>91.9001</token></unit><unit id="2363"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9002</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/91.9002/</url><token>91.9002</token></unit><unit id="1110"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9003</section_number><catch_line>Abatement Procedures.</catch_line><url>/91.9003/</url><token>91.9003</token></unit><unit id="1220"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9101</section_number><catch_line>Purpose.</catch_line><url>/91.9101/</url><token>91.9101</token></unit><unit id="1426"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9102</section_number><catch_line>Scope.</catch_line><url>/91.9102/</url><token>91.9102</token></unit><unit id="3977"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9103</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/91.9103/</url><token>91.9103</token></unit><unit id="584"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9104</section_number><catch_line>Rating Classifications.</catch_line><url>/91.9104/</url><token>91.9104</token></unit><unit id="2344"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9105</section_number><catch_line>General Requirements.</catch_line><url>/91.9105/</url><token>91.9105</token></unit><unit id="3966"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9106</section_number><catch_line>Administration.</catch_line><url>/91.9106/</url><token>91.9106</token></unit><unit id="1935"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9107</section_number><catch_line>Historical Buildings.</catch_line><url>/91.9107/</url><token>91.9107</token></unit><unit id="2806"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9108</section_number><catch_line>Analysis And Design.</catch_line><url>/91.9108/</url><token>91.9108</token></unit><unit id="702"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9109</section_number><catch_line>Materials Of Construction.</catch_line><url>/91.9109/</url><token>91.9109</token></unit><unit id="2917"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9110</section_number><catch_line>Information Required On Plans.</catch_line><url>/91.9110/</url><token>91.9110</token></unit><unit id="558"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9111</section_number><catch_line>Required Building Maintenance.</catch_line><url>/91.9111/</url><token>91.9111</token></unit><unit id="1071"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9112</section_number><catch_line>Violations &#x2013; Penalties For Disregarding Department Orders.</catch_line><url>/91.9112/</url><token>91.9112</token></unit><unit id="3070"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9201</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/91.9201/</url><token>91.9201</token></unit><unit id="279"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9202</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/91.9202/</url><token>91.9202</token></unit><unit id="1378"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9203</section_number><catch_line>Structural Weaknesses.</catch_line><url>/91.9203/</url><token>91.9203</token></unit><unit id="3743"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9204</section_number><catch_line>Strengthening Requirements.</catch_line><url>/91.9204/</url><token>91.9204</token></unit><unit id="129"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9205</section_number><catch_line>Quality Control.</catch_line><url>/91.9205/</url><token>91.9205</token></unit><unit id="1277"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9301</section_number><catch_line>Purpose.</catch_line><url>/91.9301/</url><token>91.9301</token></unit><unit id="2007"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9302</section_number><catch_line>Scope.</catch_line><url>/91.9302/</url><token>91.9302</token></unit><unit id="2891"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9303</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/91.9303/</url><token>91.9303</token></unit><unit id="1925"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9304</section_number><catch_line>General Requirements For Phased Construction.</catch_line><url>/91.9304/</url><token>91.9304</token></unit><unit id="1783"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9305</section_number><catch_line>Analysis And Design.</catch_line><url>/91.9305/</url><token>91.9305</token></unit><unit id="1410"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9306</section_number><catch_line>Materials Of Construction.</catch_line><url>/91.9306/</url><token>91.9306</token></unit><unit id="86"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9307</section_number><catch_line>Required Information On Plans.</catch_line><url>/91.9307/</url><token>91.9307</token></unit><unit id="2675"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9401</section_number><catch_line>Purpose.</catch_line><url>/91.9401/</url><token>91.9401</token></unit><unit id="1654"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9402</section_number><catch_line>Scope.</catch_line><url>/91.9402/</url><token>91.9402</token></unit><unit id="3132"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9403</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/91.9403/</url><token>91.9403</token></unit><unit id="146"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9404</section_number><catch_line>General Requirements.</catch_line><url>/91.9404/</url><token>91.9404</token></unit><unit id="3075"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9405</section_number><catch_line>Pre-Design Investigation.</catch_line><url>/91.9405/</url><token>91.9405</token></unit><unit id="3186"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9406</section_number><catch_line>Analysis And Design.</catch_line><url>/91.9406/</url><token>91.9406</token></unit><unit id="3281"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9407</section_number><catch_line>Historical Buildings.</catch_line><url>/91.9407/</url><token>91.9407</token></unit><unit id="875"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9408</section_number><catch_line>Quality Control.</catch_line><url>/91.9408/</url><token>91.9408</token></unit><unit id="248"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9409</section_number><catch_line>Information Required On Plans.</catch_line><url>/91.9409/</url><token>91.9409</token></unit><unit id="2126"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9501</section_number><catch_line>Purpose.</catch_line><url>/91.9501/</url><token>91.9501</token></unit><unit id="3288"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9502</section_number><catch_line>Scope.</catch_line><url>/91.9502/</url><token>91.9502</token></unit><unit id="46"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9503</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/91.9503/</url><token>91.9503</token></unit><unit id="650"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9504</section_number><catch_line>Reserved.</catch_line><url>/91.9504/</url><token>91.9504</token></unit><unit id="1272"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9505</section_number><catch_line>General Requirements.</catch_line><url>/91.9505/</url><token>91.9505</token></unit><unit id="2573"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9508</section_number><catch_line>Criteria Selection.</catch_line><url>/91.9508/</url><token>91.9508</token></unit><unit id="3797"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9509</section_number><catch_line>Dynamic Lateral Analysis Procedure.</catch_line><url>/91.9509/</url><token>91.9509</token></unit><unit id="1668"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9510</section_number><catch_line>Equivalent Lateral Force Procedure.</catch_line><url>/91.9510/</url><token>91.9510</token></unit><unit id="2400"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9511</section_number><catch_line>Simplified Analysis Procedure.</catch_line><url>/91.9511/</url><token>91.9511</token></unit><unit id="1341"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9512</section_number><catch_line>Minimum Requirements For A Limited Structural Analysis.</catch_line><url>/91.9512/</url><token>91.9512</token></unit><unit id="249"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9513</section_number><catch_line>Determination Of The Stress-Strain Relationship Of Existing Unreinforced Masonry.</catch_line><url>/91.9513/</url><token>91.9513</token></unit><unit id="4005"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9514</section_number><catch_line>Evaluation Of Existing Structural Conditions.</catch_line><url>/91.9514/</url><token>91.9514</token></unit><unit id="3874"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9515</section_number><catch_line>Materials Of Construction.</catch_line><url>/91.9515/</url><token>91.9515</token></unit><unit id="3063"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9516</section_number><catch_line>Information Required On The Plans.</catch_line><url>/91.9516/</url><token>91.9516</token></unit><unit id="1286"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9601</section_number><catch_line>Purpose.</catch_line><url>/91.9601/</url><token>91.9601</token></unit><unit id="3639"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9602</section_number><catch_line>Scope.</catch_line><url>/91.9602/</url><token>91.9602</token></unit><unit id="2223"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9603</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line><url>/91.9603/</url><token>91.9603</token></unit><unit id="1846"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9604</section_number><catch_line>Analysis And Design.</catch_line><url>/91.9604/</url><token>91.9604</token></unit><unit id="529"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9605</section_number><catch_line>Materials Of Construction.</catch_line><url>/91.9605/</url><token>91.9605</token></unit><unit id="1955"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.9606</section_number><catch_line>Information Required On Plans.</catch_line><url>/91.9606/</url><token>91.9606</token></unit></structure_contents><previous_section id="2872"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.104</section_number><catch_line>Organization And Enforcement.</catch_line><url>/91.104/</url><token>91.104</token></previous_section><next_section id="1085"><structure_id>31</structure_id><section_number>91.106</section_number><catch_line>Permits.</catch_line><url>/91.106/</url><token>91.106</token></next_section><metadata></metadata><references></references><url>/91.105/</url><token>91.105</token><formats><txt>/91.105.txt</txt><json>/91.105.xml</json></formats><dublin_core><Title>Appeals.</Title><Type>Text</Type><Format>text/html</Format><Identifier>&#xA7; 91.105</Identifier><Relation>Los Angeles Municipal Code</Relation></dublin_core><plain_text>                            LOS ANGELES MUNICIPAL CODE

APPEALS. (&#xA7; 91.105)

&#xA0; APPEALS.91.105.1.&#xA0; General.&#xA0; or requests for slight modifications in
individual cases from the requirements of this Code shall be made in accordance
with the procedure established in Section 98.0403.2 of the Los Angeles Municipal
Code.91.105.2.&#xA0; Building Advisory Appeal Board.&#xA0; The Building Advisory Appeal
Board is hereby abolished. Any duties assigned to the Building Advisory Appeal
Board by any provision of law shall be performed as determined by the
Superintendent of Building.91.105.3.&#xA0; Engineering Geology Advisory
Committee.91.105.3.1.&#xA0; Function of the Committee.&#xA0; It shall be the function of
the Engineering Geology Advisory Committee to advise and counsel the board on
appeals involving technical questions of soils engineering, geology,
geology/seismology and related matters.91.105.3.2.&#xA0; Establishment of the
Committee Member List.&#xA0; The Board of Building and Safety Commissioners shall
establish an Engineering Geology Advisory Committee member list (hereinafter in
this section referred to as the &#x201C;committee member list&#x201D;) which shall consist
of not less than 10 soils engineers and engineering geologists who are available
to serve as members of the Engineering Geology Advisory Committee.&#xA0; At least
two of the engineering geologist members and two of the soils engineer members
shall have experience in the field of seismic design and safety. Members of said
committee shall be exempt from all Civil Service provisions.91.105.3.3.&#xA0;
Procedure.&#xA0; When an appeal is made to the Board, and the Board determines that
the subject of the appeal involves a problem of soils engineering, geology,
geology/seismology or a related matter on which it desires further technical
advice before it renders a decision thereon, the Board may select three or more
persons from the Engineering Geology Advisory Committee member list to serve on
a committee for the purpose of assisting the Board in seeking a solution to said
problem, and may refer the matter to such committee members for report and
recommendation. At least one member of the committee so designated shall be a
soils engineer and one shall be an engineering geologist. The members of the
committee so meeting shall review the matter and shall then submit to the board
a recommendation. When a matter is referred to the committee as in this section
provided, the board shall consider, but is not bound to accept, the
recommendation of the committee.91.105.3.4.&#xA0; Compensation of Members.&#xA0; Each
member of the committee who is in actual attendance at a meeting requested by
the board shall be compensated at the rate of $50.00 for each four hours or
fraction thereof of service. However, in no case shall the compensation of the
committee members exceed the fee paid by the appellant under Section 91.105.3.6
of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.91.105.3.5.&#xA0; Self insurance by the City for
Committee Members.&#xA0; The provisions of Sections 11.36 through 11.44, inclusive,
City of Los Angeles Administrative Code, entitled &#x201C;Self Insurance by the City
for Officers and Employees of Said City&#x201D;, shall apply to each Engineering
Geology Advisory Committee member while the member is acting as such, and
committee members shall be deemed to be fully covered by the provisions of said
sections even though each committee member is retained as an independent person
and not as an officer or employee of the city.91.105.3.6.&#xA0; Fees.&#xA0; When a
matter is referred to the committee as provided in this section, the appellant
in said matter shall pay a referral fee of $50.00 and shall also pay a fee as
follows:	1.	Where no more than two lots are involved in the appeal,
$150.00;	2.	Where not less than three or more than 10 lots are involved in the
appeal, $300.00;	3.	Where more than 10 lots are involved in the appeal,
$600.00.91.105.4.&#xA0; Sign Advisory Committee.91.105.4.1.&#xA0; Function of the
Committee.&#xA0; It shall be the function of a Sign Advisory Committee to advise,
counsel and provide recommendations to the Board of Building and Safety
Commissioners on matters involving sign regulations.91.105.4.2.&#xA0; Establishment
of the Committee Member List.&#xA0; The Board of Building and Safety Commissioners
shall establish a Sign Advisory Committee member list representing the various
required fields of interest of persons who are available to serve as members of
a Sign Advisory Committee. Persons selected for the Sign Advisory Committee list
shall possess experience in the design, fabrication, the use or application of
signs, or shall have demonstrated a background in the social and environment
impacts of signs or the development of sign regulations. Members of said
committee shall be exempt from all civil service requirements.91.105.4.3.&#xA0;
Procedure.&#xA0; When the board determines that a matter is significant in nature,
the board may refer the matter to a Sign Advisory Committee for evaluation and
recommendation before it renders a decision thereon. When the matter is referred
to a Sign Advisory Committee, the board shall consider, but is not bound to
accept, the recommendation of the committee.91.105.4.4.&#xA0; Composition of the
Committee.&#xA0; The board shall select five persons from the Sign Advisory
Committee member list to serve on a committee. The committee shall be composed
of one member from each of the following interests:	1.	One member of or
designated by the Board of Building and Safety Commissioners;	2.	One member of
or designated by the City Planning Commission; and	3.	Three public members, one
each from the following interests: architecture, sign industry and community
groups.91.105.4.5.&#xA0; Compensation of Members.&#xA0; Each member of the committee who
is in actual attendance at a meeting requested by the board shall be compensated
at the rate of $50.00 for each four hours or fraction thereof of service.
However, in no case shall the compensation of the committee members exceed the
fee paid by the applicant under Section 91.105.4.7.91.105.4.6.&#xA0; Self-insurance
by the City for Committee Members.&#xA0; The provisions of Sections 11.36 through
11.44, inclusive, of the Los Angeles Administrative Code shall apply to each
Sign Advisory Committee member while the member is acting as such, and committee
members shall be deemed to be fully covered by the provisions of said sections
even though each committee member is retained as an independent person and not
as an officer or employee of the city.91.105.4.7.&#xA0; Fees.&#xA0; When a matter is
referred to the committee as provided in this section, the applicant in said
matter shall pay a referral fee of $300.00.91.105.5.&#xA0; Disabled Access Appeals
Commission.91.105.5.1.&#xA0; Creation of the Commission.&#xA0; There is hereby
established a commission known as the Disabled Access Appeals
Commission.91.105.5.2.&#xA0; Membership of the Commission.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No.
173,238, Eff. 6/19/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)&#xA0; The Disabled Access Appeals Commission
shall be composed of five qualified persons.&#xA0; Two members of the commission
shall be physically disabled persons, and two members shall be persons
experienced in construction. The fifth member may be any resident of the City of
Los Angeles. Commission members shall be appointed by the Mayor, subject to
Council approval, and may be removed by the Mayor.&#xA0; In the case of a vacancy
during the term of office of any member, the same shall be filled by appointment
by the mayor for the period of the unexpired term subject to the approval of the
council by a majority vote. The members of the commission shall be exempt from
all Civil Service provisions.91.105.5.3.&#xA0; Compensation and Term of Office.&#xA0;
Each member of the commission shall be paid $50.00 per meeting attended, but not
to exceed $250.00 in any one calendar month.	The term of office of the members
of the commission shall be five years beginning with the first day of July of
the respective years, except that the terms of office of the original five
members of the commission appointed pursuant to this subsection shall be such
that one term shall expire on the first June 30, one term shall expire on the
second June 30, one term shall expire on the third June 30, one term shall
expire on the fourth June 30, and one term shall expire on the fifth June 30
next following the effective date of the appointment of the original five
members. Thereafter, the terms of the succeeding members shall be so designated
that the term of office of one member shall expire each year. The period of term
of each member shall be designated in the appointment.	Each member of the
commission shall have the power to administer oaths.91.105.5.4.&#xA0; Authority of
the Commission.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. 181,758, Eff. 8/8/11.)&#xA0; The commission shall
have and exercise the following powers:	1.	To hear and determine written appeals
brought by any person from actions taken by the Department of Building and
Safety (department) in the enforcement of the requirements of Section 19955, et
seq., of the California Health and Safety Code, the provisions of state law
dealing with access to public accommodations by physically disabled
persons.	2.	To hear and determine written appeals brought by any person from the
rulings, decisions and determinations of the department granting or denying
applications for exceptions pursuant to Health and Safety Code Section
19957.	3.	To hear and determine written appeals brought by any persons where it
is alleged that there is error or abuse of discretion in any order, requirement,
decision, interpretation or other determination made by the department in the
enforcement or administration of Section 1.8 et seq., Chapter 1, Division I of
California Building Code and any other federal, state or municipal handicapped
access and adaptability requirements.&#xA0;	All appeals shall be reviewed by the
department.&#xA0; The department may reverse or modify the action appealed from at
any time prior to final action by the commission.&#xA0; Any such new action may then
be appealed to the commission.	4.	To respond to the department&#x2019;s request for
advice on any matter within the department&#x2019;s jurisdiction relating to access
to public accommodations and housing by the physically disabled.	5.	To exercise
the authority granted in Section 91.105.6.91.105.5.5.&#xA0; Appeals.91.105.5.5.1.&#xA0;
Procedures.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 172,592, Eff. 6/28/99, Oper. 7/1/99.)&#xA0; An
appeal to the commission may be filed by any person aggrieved, or by an officer,
Board, Department or Bureau of the City. An appeal shall be in writing and shall
be filed in the Office of the Board of Building and Safety Commissioners upon
appropriate forms provided by the Department. An appeal shall set forth
specifically the points at issue, the reasons for the appeal, and wherein the
appellant believes there was an error or an abuse of discretion by the
Department.	When considering an appeal from an action by the Department, the
commission shall make its determination within 30 days from the filing of the
appeal. This time limit may be extended by mutual written consent of the
applicant and the commission.&#xA0; Upon receipt of the appeal, the commission shall
set the matter for hearing and give notice by mail of the time, place and
purpose thereof to the appellant, to the applicant, to the owner or owners of
the property involved, and to any interested party who has requested in writing
to be so notified.&#xA0; Such notice shall be in writing and mailed at least 10 days
prior to said hearing.&#xA0; No other notice thereof need be given except in those
cases hereinafter mentioned.	The commission may grant, conditionally grant, or
deny any appeal.&#xA0; All actions of the commission shall be final.&#xA0; Any action
within the jurisdiction of the commission shall be final and conclusive as to
the Department in the absence of fraud or abuse of discretion.	A separate appeal
shall be filed for each single building as described in Section 98.0403.2 of the
Los Angeles Municipal Code. Appeals to the Appeals Commission shall be
accompanied by a filing fee as set forth in Table 4-A of Division 4 of Article
8, Chapter IX, of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.	If the commission fails to act
on any appeal within the time limit specified in this section, then the action
of the Department on the matter shall be final.91.105.5.5.2.&#xA0; Decision.&#xA0; The
decision upon an appeal shall be concurred in by at least three members of the
commission. The commission may modify or reverse a ruling, decision or
determination appealed from only upon making written findings setting forth
specifically wherein the action of the department was in error or constituted an
abuse of discretion. The commission shall make specific written findings
supporting any modification or reversal.	Upon making a decision, a copy of the
findings and determination shall be furnished the applicant, the appellant and
the Department of Building and Safety.91.105.5.5.3.&#xA0; Special Findings.&#xA0; Before
granting or affirming the grant of an exception pursuant to Health and Safety
Code Section 19957, the commission must find that the application involves a
case of practical difficulty, unnecessary hardship, or extreme differences, and
that it is clearly evident that equivalent facilitation and protection will be
secured.91.105.5.5.4.&#xA0; Revocation of Approvals.&#xA0; The commission shall revoke
or rescind any determination, including the grant of an appeal or&#xA0; exception,
if made in error in violation of any provision of law, or in reliance on any
false statement or misrepresentation as to a material fact.91.105.5.5.5.&#xA0; Time
Limits.&#xA0; The rights and privileges granted by the commission pursuant to any
decision, determination, approval, appeal or exception shall be void if all
required building permits are not secured within one year of the effective date
of such action, or if the permit expires under any of the conditions specified
in Section 98.0602 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.	However, the commission,
and the superintendent acting on behalf of the commission, may grant extensions
of time if the applicant submits in writing substantial evidence that unusual
conditions or circumstances either precluded the securing of all required
permits within the allocated time or caused the permit to expire as specified in
Section 98.0602 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.	Requests for extensions of
time shall be made not later than 30 days after the expiration times specified
in this section.91.105.5.5.6.&#xA0; Additional Authority.&#xA0; In considering appeals,
the commission may exercise the following powers:	1.	To appoint one or more
hearing officers to conduct hearings and make recommendations to the same extent
and in the same manner as the Superintendent of Building acting pursuant to LAMC
Section 98.0601 (a).&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 180,619, Eff. 5/12/09.)	2.	To
request the attendance of witnesses and the production of evidence before
it.	3.	To request the city attorney, or an assistant or deputy designated by the
city attorney to appear at any hearing before the commission.	4.	To adopt rules
regarding the filing of appeals, the conduct of its hearings and any other
procedural rules in keeping with the provisions of this Division.91.105.5.5.7.&#xA0;
Limitations on Jurisdiction.&#xA0; Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code,
the commission&#x2019;s jurisdiction shall not include the right to hear and
determine an appeal from a department determination, order or action if such
appeal is filed:	1.	On or after the date a criminal citation is issued, charging
the appellant with a violation of law based on the facts underlying such
determination, order or action; or	2.	On or after the date a criminal complaint
is filed, charging the appellant with a violation of state laws based on such
determination, order or action.	Further, the commission&#x2019;s jurisdiction shall
not include the right to hear appeals from or otherwise review any action, order
or determination of the Board of Building and Safety Commissioners.91.105.6.&#xA0;
Administrative Penalties for Disabled Access Violations.91.105.6.1.&#xA0; Order of
Abatement and Notice of Proposed Penalty.&#xA0; If the superintendent determines
that a person has violated or failed to comply with any requirement of the law
relating to access to public accommodations and housing by the physically
disabled, then the superintendent may issue an order of abatement and notice of
proposed penalty to that person.	The order and notice shall be in writing and
shall describe with particularity the nature of the violation, including a
reference to the provision of law that has been violated. The order shall fix a
reasonable time for correction of the violation, and the notice of proposed
penalty shall set forth the amount of the penalty.	The order of abatement and
notice of proposed penalty shall be served upon the person either personally, or
by deposit in the United States mail in a sealed envelope, postage prepaid to
the person&#x2019;s last known address.	The order and notice shall also set forth the
person&#x2019;s right to a hearing as described in Section 91.105.6.2.91.105.6.2.&#xA0;
Right to Hearing.&#xA0; Any person served with an order of abatement or notice of
proposed penalty, may apply in writing to the Disabled Access Appeals Commission
for a hearing with respect to the violation alleged, the abatement period, and
the amount of the penalty. This request shall be filed within 15 days after the
date of service.	If the person does not request a hearing within the prescribed
time, then the notice of proposed penalty shall be final, and the amount of any
penalty included in the notice shall immediately be due and owing to the City of
Los Angeles. The city then shall have the right to bring an action in any court
of competent jurisdiction to enforce the order and collect the amount of the
penalty.	If the department determines that there has been compliance with the
order of abatement within the time for correction, then the department may
rescind the notice of penalty.91.105.6.3.&#xA0; Time of Hearing; Notice.&#xA0; If the
person requests a hearing, the superintendent shall cause the matter to be set
for hearing before the Disabled Access Appeals Commission. The hearing shall be
scheduled not later than 30 days after the date of the application for hearing.
This time limit may be extended with the mutual consent of the person and the
commission. It shall be a defense to the affirmation of any penalty that the
person complied with the order of abatement within the time for correction.	The
decision of the commission on the order of abatement and notice of proposed
penalty shall be final, and the amount of any penalty affirmed by the commission
shall immediately be due and owing to the City of Los Angeles. The city then
shall have the right to bring an action in any court of competent jurisdiction
to enforce the order and collect the amount of penalty.91.105.6.4&#xA0; Civil
Penalties.&#xA0; Any penalty required to be paid under the provisions of this
section is a debt owed to the City of Los Angeles. Any person owing a penalty
due under the provisions of this section shall be liable in an action brought in
the name of the City of Los Angeles in any court of competent jurisdiction for
recovery of any such amount.	The conviction of any person for violating any law
shall not relieve the person from the obligation to pay any penalty that the
person may owe the city, nor shall such payment prevent a prosecution under
appropriate provisions of law for any violation of the law. The remedies
provided in this section are cumulative. The use of one or more of the remedies
prescribed in this section shall not bar the use of any other remedy provided
for the enforcement of law.91.105.6.5.&#xA0; Fee Schedules.&#xA0; The Superintendent
shall submit a schedule for the assessment of civil penalties under this section
to council for the approval by ordinance.	This schedule shall give due
consideration to the appropriateness of the penalty with respect to the
following factors:	1.	The gravity of the violation;	2.	The good faith of the
violator being charged; and	3.	The history of previous violations.
</plain_text><html>
					&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#xA0; &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;APPEALS&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.1.&#xA0; General.&#xA0; or requests for slight modifications in individual cases from the requirements of this Code shall be made in accordance with the procedure established in Section 98.0403.2 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.2.&#xA0; Building Advisory &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Appeal&lt;/span&gt; Board.&#xA0; The Building Advisory &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Appeal&lt;/span&gt; Board is hereby abolished. Any duties assigned to the Building Advisory &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Appeal&lt;/span&gt; Board by any provision of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;law&lt;/span&gt; shall be performed as determined by the Superintendent of Building.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.3.&#xA0; Engineering Geology Advisory Committee.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.3.1.&#xA0; Function of the Committee.&#xA0; It shall be the function of the Engineering Geology Advisory Committee to advise and &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;counsel&lt;/span&gt; the board on &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeals&lt;/span&gt; involving technical questions of soils engineering, geology, geology/seismology and related matters.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.3.2.&#xA0; Establishment of the Committee Member List.&#xA0; The Board of Building and Safety Commissioners shall establish an Engineering Geology Advisory Committee member list (hereinafter in this section referred to as the &#x201C;committee member list&#x201D;) which shall consist of not less than 10 soils engineers and engineering geologists who are available to serve as members of the Engineering Geology Advisory Committee.&#xA0; At least two of the engineering geologist members and two of the soils engineer members shall have experience in the field of seismic design and safety. Members of said committee shall be exempt from all Civil Service provisions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.3.3.&#xA0; Procedure.&#xA0; When an &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; is made to the Board, and the Board determines that the subject of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; involves a problem of soils engineering, geology, geology/seismology or a related matter on which it desires further technical advice before it renders a decision thereon, the Board may select three or more persons from the Engineering Geology Advisory Committee member list to serve on a committee for the purpose of assisting the Board in seeking a solution to said problem, and may refer the matter to such committee members for report and recommendation. At least one member of the committee so designated shall be a soils engineer and one shall be an engineering geologist. The members of the committee so meeting shall review the matter and shall then submit to the board a recommendation. When a matter is referred to the committee as in this section provided, the board shall consider, but is not bound to accept, the recommendation of the committee.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.3.4.&#xA0; Compensation of Members.&#xA0; Each member of the committee who is in actual attendance at a meeting requested by the board shall be compensated at the rate of $50.00 for each four hours or fraction thereof of service. However, in no case shall the compensation of the committee members exceed the fee paid by the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appellant&lt;/span&gt; under Section 91.105.3.6 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.3.5.&#xA0; Self insurance by the City for Committee Members.&#xA0; The provisions of Sections 11.36 through 11.44, inclusive, City of Los Angeles Administrative Code, entitled &#x201C;Self Insurance by the City for Officers and Employees of Said City&#x201D;, shall apply to each Engineering Geology Advisory Committee member while the member is acting as such, and committee members shall be deemed to be fully covered by the provisions of said sections even though each committee member is retained as an independent person and not as an officer or employee of the city.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.3.6.&#xA0; Fees.&#xA0; When a matter is referred to the committee as provided in this section, the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appellant&lt;/span&gt; in said matter shall pay a referral fee of $50.00 and shall also pay a fee as follows:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	Where no more than two lots are involved in the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt;, $150.00;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	Where not less than three or more than 10 lots are involved in the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt;, $300.00;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	Where more than 10 lots are involved in the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt;, $600.00.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.4.&#xA0; Sign Advisory Committee.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.4.1.&#xA0; Function of the Committee.&#xA0; It shall be the function of a Sign Advisory Committee to advise, &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;counsel&lt;/span&gt; and provide recommendations to the Board of Building and Safety Commissioners on matters involving sign regulations.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.4.2.&#xA0; Establishment of the Committee Member List.&#xA0; The Board of Building and Safety Commissioners shall establish a Sign Advisory Committee member list representing the various required fields of interest of persons who are available to serve as members of a Sign Advisory Committee. Persons selected for the Sign Advisory Committee list shall possess experience in the design, fabrication, the use or application of signs, or shall have demonstrated a background in the social and environment impacts of signs or the development of sign regulations. Members of said committee shall be exempt from all civil service requirements.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.4.3.&#xA0; Procedure.&#xA0; When the board determines that a matter is significant in nature, the board may refer the matter to a Sign Advisory Committee for evaluation and recommendation before it renders a decision thereon. When the matter is referred to a Sign Advisory Committee, the board shall consider, but is not bound to accept, the recommendation of the committee.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.4.4.&#xA0; Composition of the Committee.&#xA0; The board shall select five persons from the Sign Advisory Committee member list to serve on a committee. The committee shall be composed of one member from each of the following interests:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	One member of or designated by the Board of Building and Safety Commissioners;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	One member of or designated by the City Planning Commission; and&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	Three public members, one each from the following interests: architecture, sign industry and community groups.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.4.5.&#xA0; Compensation of Members.&#xA0; Each member of the committee who is in actual attendance at a meeting requested by the board shall be compensated at the rate of $50.00 for each four hours or fraction thereof of service. However, in no case shall the compensation of the committee members exceed the fee paid by the applicant under Section 91.105.4.7.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.4.6.&#xA0; Self-insurance by the City for Committee Members.&#xA0; The provisions of Sections 11.36 through 11.44, inclusive, of the Los Angeles Administrative Code shall apply to each Sign Advisory Committee member while the member is acting as such, and committee members shall be deemed to be fully covered by the provisions of said sections even though each committee member is retained as an independent person and not as an officer or employee of the city.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.4.7.&#xA0; Fees.&#xA0; When a matter is referred to the committee as provided in this section, the applicant in said matter shall pay a referral fee of $300.00.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.5.&#xA0; Disabled Access &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Appeals&lt;/span&gt; Commission.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.5.1.&#xA0; Creation of the Commission.&#xA0; There is hereby established a commission known as the Disabled Access &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Appeals&lt;/span&gt; Commission.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.5.2.&#xA0; Membership of the Commission.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 173,238, Eff. 6/19/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)&#xA0; The Disabled Access &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Appeals&lt;/span&gt; Commission shall be composed of five qualified persons.&#xA0; Two members of the commission shall be physically disabled persons, and two members shall be persons experienced in construction. The fifth member may be any resident of the City of Los Angeles. Commission members shall be appointed by the Mayor, subject to Council approval, and may be removed by the Mayor.&#xA0; In the case of a vacancy during the term of office of any member, the same shall be filled by appointment by the mayor for the period of the unexpired term subject to the approval of the council by a majority vote. The members of the commission shall be exempt from all Civil Service provisions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.5.3.&#xA0; Compensation and Term of Office.&#xA0; Each member of the commission shall be paid $50.00 per meeting attended, but not to exceed $250.00 in any one calendar month.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	The term of office of the members of the commission shall be five years beginning with the first day of July of the respective years, except that the terms of office of the original five members of the commission appointed pursuant to this subsection shall be such that one term shall expire on the first June 30, one term shall expire on the second June 30, one term shall expire on the third June 30, one term shall expire on the fourth June 30, and one term shall expire on the fifth June 30 next following the effective date of the appointment of the original five members. Thereafter, the terms of the succeeding members shall be so designated that the term of office of one member shall expire each year. The period of term of each member shall be designated in the appointment.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	Each member of the commission shall have the power to administer &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;oaths&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.5.4.&#xA0; Authority of the Commission.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. 181,758, Eff. 8/8/11.)&#xA0; The commission shall have and exercise the following powers:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	To hear and determine written &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeals&lt;/span&gt; brought by any person from actions taken by the Department of Building and Safety (department) in the enforcement of the requirements of Section 19955, et seq., of the California Health and Safety Code, the provisions of state &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;law&lt;/span&gt; dealing with access to public accommodations by physically disabled persons.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	To hear and determine written &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeals&lt;/span&gt; brought by any person from the rulings, decisions and determinations of the department granting or denying applications for exceptions pursuant to Health and Safety Code Section 19957.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	To hear and determine written &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeals&lt;/span&gt; brought by any persons where it is alleged that there is error or abuse of discretion in any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt;, requirement, decision, interpretation or other determination made by the department in the enforcement or administration of Section 1.8 et seq., Chapter 1, Division I of California Building Code and any other federal, state or municipal handicapped access and adaptability requirements.&#xA0;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	All &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeals&lt;/span&gt; shall be reviewed by the department.&#xA0; The department may &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;reverse&lt;/span&gt; or modify the action appealed from at any time prior to final action by the commission.&#xA0; Any such new action may then be appealed to the commission.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	4.	To respond to the department&#x2019;s request for advice on any matter within the department&#x2019;s &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;jurisdiction&lt;/span&gt; relating to access to public accommodations and housing by the physically disabled.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	5.	To exercise the authority granted in Section 91.105.6.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.5.5.&#xA0; &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Appeals&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.5.5.1.&#xA0; Procedures.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 172,592, Eff. 6/28/99, Oper. 7/1/99.)&#xA0; An &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; to the commission may be filed by any person aggrieved, or by an officer, Board, Department or Bureau of the City. An &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; shall be in writing and shall be filed in the Office of the Board of Building and Safety Commissioners upon appropriate forms provided by the Department. An &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; shall set forth specifically the points at &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;issue&lt;/span&gt;, the reasons for the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt;, and wherein the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appellant&lt;/span&gt; believes there was an error or an abuse of discretion by the Department.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	When considering an &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; from an action by the Department, the commission shall make its determination within 30 days from the filing of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt;. This time limit may be extended by mutual written consent of the applicant and the commission.&#xA0; Upon receipt of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt;, the commission shall set the matter for &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; and give notice by mail of the time, place and purpose thereof to the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appellant&lt;/span&gt;, to the applicant, to the owner or owners of the property involved, and to any interested &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;party&lt;/span&gt; who has requested in writing to be so notified.&#xA0; Such notice shall be in writing and mailed at least 10 days prior to said &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; No other notice thereof need be given except in those cases hereinafter mentioned.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	The commission may grant, conditionally grant, or deny any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; All actions of the commission shall be final.&#xA0; Any action within the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;jurisdiction&lt;/span&gt; of the commission shall be final and conclusive as to the Department in the absence of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;fraud&lt;/span&gt; or abuse of discretion.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	A separate &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; shall be filed for each single building as described in Section 98.0403.2 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code. &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Appeals&lt;/span&gt; to the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Appeals&lt;/span&gt; Commission shall be accompanied by a filing fee as set forth in Table 4-A of Division 4 of Article 8, Chapter IX, of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	If the commission fails to act on any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; within the time limit specified in this section, then the action of the Department on the matter shall be final.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.5.5.2.&#xA0; Decision.&#xA0; The decision upon an &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; shall be concurred in by at least three members of the commission. The commission may modify or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;reverse&lt;/span&gt; a ruling, decision or determination appealed from only upon making written &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;findings&lt;/span&gt; setting forth specifically wherein the action of the department was in error or constituted an abuse of discretion. The commission shall make specific written &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;findings&lt;/span&gt; supporting any modification or reversal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	Upon making a decision, a copy of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;findings&lt;/span&gt; and determination shall be furnished the applicant, the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appellant&lt;/span&gt; and the Department of Building and Safety.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.5.5.3.&#xA0; Special &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Findings&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; Before granting or affirming the grant of an exception pursuant to Health and Safety Code Section 19957, the commission must find that the application involves a case of practical difficulty, unnecessary hardship, or extreme differences, and that it is clearly evident that equivalent facilitation and protection will be secured.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.5.5.4.&#xA0; &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Revocation&lt;/span&gt; of Approvals.&#xA0; The commission shall revoke or rescind any determination, including the grant of an &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; or&#xA0; exception, if made in error in violation of any provision of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;law&lt;/span&gt;, or in reliance on any false statement or misrepresentation as to a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;material&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;fact&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.5.5.5.&#xA0; Time Limits.&#xA0; The rights and &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;privileges&lt;/span&gt; granted by the commission pursuant to any decision, determination, approval, &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; or exception shall be void if all required building permits are not secured within one year of the effective date of such action, or if the permit expires under any of the conditions specified in Section 98.0602 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	However, the commission, and the superintendent acting on behalf of the commission, may grant extensions of time if the applicant submits in writing substantial &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;evidence&lt;/span&gt; that unusual conditions or circumstances either precluded the securing of all required permits within the allocated time or caused the permit to expire as specified in Section 98.0602 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	Requests for extensions of time shall be made not later than 30 days after the expiration times specified in this section.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.5.5.6.&#xA0; Additional Authority.&#xA0; In considering &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeals&lt;/span&gt;, the commission may exercise the following powers:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	To appoint one or more &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; officers to conduct &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearings&lt;/span&gt; and make recommendations to the same extent and in the same manner as the Superintendent of Building acting pursuant to LAMC Section 98.0601 (a).&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 180,619, Eff. 5/12/09.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	To request the attendance of witnesses and the production of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;evidence&lt;/span&gt; before it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	To request the city attorney, or an assistant or deputy designated by the city attorney to appear at any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; before the commission.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	4.	To adopt rules regarding the filing of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeals&lt;/span&gt;, the conduct of its &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearings&lt;/span&gt; and any other procedural rules in keeping with the provisions of this Division.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.5.5.7.&#xA0; Limitations on &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Jurisdiction&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, the commission&#x2019;s &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;jurisdiction&lt;/span&gt; shall not include the right to hear and determine an &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; from a department determination, &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; or action if such &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeal&lt;/span&gt; is filed:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	On or after the date a criminal &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;citation&lt;/span&gt; is issued, charging the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appellant&lt;/span&gt; with a violation of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;law&lt;/span&gt; based on the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;facts&lt;/span&gt; underlying such determination, &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; or action; or&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	On or after the date a criminal complaint is filed, charging the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appellant&lt;/span&gt; with a violation of state &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;laws&lt;/span&gt; based on such determination, &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; or action.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	Further, the commission&#x2019;s &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;jurisdiction&lt;/span&gt; shall not include the right to hear &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;appeals&lt;/span&gt; from or otherwise review any action, &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; or determination of the Board of Building and Safety Commissioners.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.6.&#xA0; Administrative Penalties for Disabled Access Violations.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.6.1.&#xA0; &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Order&lt;/span&gt; of Abatement and Notice of Proposed &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Penalty&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; If the superintendent determines that a person has violated or failed to comply with any requirement of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;law&lt;/span&gt; relating to access to public accommodations and housing by the physically disabled, then the superintendent may &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;issue&lt;/span&gt; an &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; of abatement and notice of proposed &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt; to that person.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	The &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; and notice shall be in writing and shall describe with particularity the nature of the violation, including a reference to the provision of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;law&lt;/span&gt; that has been violated. The &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; shall fix a reasonable time for correction of the violation, and the notice of proposed &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt; shall set forth the amount of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	The &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; of abatement and notice of proposed &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt; shall be served upon the person either personally, or by deposit in the United States mail in a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;sealed&lt;/span&gt; envelope, postage prepaid to the person&#x2019;s last known address.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	The &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; and notice shall also set forth the person&#x2019;s right to a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; as described in Section 91.105.6.2.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.6.2.&#xA0; Right to &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Hearing&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; Any person served with an &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; of abatement or notice of proposed &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt;, may apply in writing to the Disabled Access &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Appeals&lt;/span&gt; Commission for a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; with respect to the violation alleged, the abatement period, and the amount of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt;. This request shall be filed within 15 days after the date of service.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	If the person does not request a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; within the prescribed time, then the notice of proposed &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt; shall be final, and the amount of any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt; included in the notice shall immediately be due and owing to the City of Los Angeles. The city then shall have the right to bring an action in any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;court&lt;/span&gt; of competent &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;jurisdiction&lt;/span&gt; to enforce the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; and collect the amount of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	If the department determines that there has been compliance with the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; of abatement within the time for correction, then the department may rescind the notice of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.6.3.&#xA0; Time of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Hearing&lt;/span&gt;; Notice.&#xA0; If the person requests a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt;, the superintendent shall cause the matter to be set for &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; before the Disabled Access &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Appeals&lt;/span&gt; Commission. The &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt; shall be scheduled not later than 30 days after the date of the application for &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;hearing&lt;/span&gt;. This time limit may be extended with the mutual consent of the person and the commission. It shall be a defense to the affirmation of any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt; that the person complied with the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; of abatement within the time for correction.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	The decision of the commission on the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; of abatement and notice of proposed &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt; shall be final, and the amount of any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;affirmed&lt;/span&gt; by the commission shall immediately be due and owing to the City of Los Angeles. The city then shall have the right to bring an action in any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;court&lt;/span&gt; of competent &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;jurisdiction&lt;/span&gt; to enforce the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; and collect the amount of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.6.4&#xA0; Civil Penalties.&#xA0; Any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt; required to be paid under the provisions of this section is a debt owed to the City of Los Angeles. Any person owing a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt; due under the provisions of this section shall be liable in an action brought in the name of the City of Los Angeles in any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;court&lt;/span&gt; of competent &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;jurisdiction&lt;/span&gt; for recovery of any such amount.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	The &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;conviction&lt;/span&gt; of any person for violating any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;law&lt;/span&gt; shall not relieve the person from the obligation to pay any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt; that the person may owe the city, nor shall such payment prevent a &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;prosecution&lt;/span&gt; under appropriate provisions of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;law&lt;/span&gt; for any violation of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;law&lt;/span&gt;. The remedies provided in this section are cumulative. The use of one or more of the remedies prescribed in this section shall not bar the use of any other remedy provided for the enforcement of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;law&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;91.105.6.5.&#xA0; Fee &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;Schedules&lt;/span&gt;.&#xA0; The Superintendent shall submit a schedule for the assessment of civil penalties under this section to council for the approval by &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;ordinance&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	This schedule shall give due consideration to the appropriateness of the &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt; with respect to the following factors:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	The gravity of the violation;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	The good faith of the violator being charged; and&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	The history of previous violations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</html><text><unit id="2309" prefix=""><text>&#xA0; APPEALS.91.105.1.&#xA0; General.&#xA0; or requests for slight modifications in individual cases from the requirements of this Code shall be made in accordance with the procedure established in Section 98.0403.2 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.91.105.2.&#xA0; Building Advisory Appeal Board.&#xA0; The Building Advisory Appeal Board is hereby abolished. Any duties assigned to the Building Advisory Appeal Board by any provision of law shall be performed as determined by the Superintendent of Building.91.105.3.&#xA0; Engineering Geology Advisory Committee.91.105.3.1.&#xA0; Function of the Committee.&#xA0; It shall be the function of the Engineering Geology Advisory Committee to advise and counsel the board on appeals involving technical questions of soils engineering, geology, geology/seismology and related matters.91.105.3.2.&#xA0; Establishment of the Committee Member List.&#xA0; The Board of Building and Safety Commissioners shall establish an Engineering Geology Advisory Committee member list (hereinafter in this section referred to as the &#x201C;committee member list&#x201D;) which shall consist of not less than 10 soils engineers and engineering geologists who are available to serve as members of the Engineering Geology Advisory Committee.&#xA0; At least two of the engineering geologist members and two of the soils engineer members shall have experience in the field of seismic design and safety. Members of said committee shall be exempt from all Civil Service provisions.91.105.3.3.&#xA0; Procedure.&#xA0; When an appeal is made to the Board, and the Board determines that the subject of the appeal involves a problem of soils engineering, geology, geology/seismology or a related matter on which it desires further technical advice before it renders a decision thereon, the Board may select three or more persons from the Engineering Geology Advisory Committee member list to serve on a committee for the purpose of assisting the Board in seeking a solution to said problem, and may refer the matter to such committee members for report and recommendation. At least one member of the committee so designated shall be a soils engineer and one shall be an engineering geologist. The members of the committee so meeting shall review the matter and shall then submit to the board a recommendation. When a matter is referred to the committee as in this section provided, the board shall consider, but is not bound to accept, the recommendation of the committee.91.105.3.4.&#xA0; Compensation of Members.&#xA0; Each member of the committee who is in actual attendance at a meeting requested by the board shall be compensated at the rate of $50.00 for each four hours or fraction thereof of service. However, in no case shall the compensation of the committee members exceed the fee paid by the appellant under Section 91.105.3.6 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.91.105.3.5.&#xA0; Self insurance by the City for Committee Members.&#xA0; The provisions of Sections 11.36 through 11.44, inclusive, City of Los Angeles Administrative Code, entitled &#x201C;Self Insurance by the City for Officers and Employees of Said City&#x201D;, shall apply to each Engineering Geology Advisory Committee member while the member is acting as such, and committee members shall be deemed to be fully covered by the provisions of said sections even though each committee member is retained as an independent person and not as an officer or employee of the city.91.105.3.6.&#xA0; Fees.&#xA0; When a matter is referred to the committee as provided in this section, the appellant in said matter shall pay a referral fee of $50.00 and shall also pay a fee as follows:	1.	Where no more than two lots are involved in the appeal, $150.00;	2.	Where not less than three or more than 10 lots are involved in the appeal, $300.00;	3.	Where more than 10 lots are involved in the appeal, $600.00.91.105.4.&#xA0; Sign Advisory Committee.91.105.4.1.&#xA0; Function of the Committee.&#xA0; It shall be the function of a Sign Advisory Committee to advise, counsel and provide recommendations to the Board of Building and Safety Commissioners on matters involving sign regulations.91.105.4.2.&#xA0; Establishment of the Committee Member List.&#xA0; The Board of Building and Safety Commissioners shall establish a Sign Advisory Committee member list representing the various required fields of interest of persons who are available to serve as members of a Sign Advisory Committee. Persons selected for the Sign Advisory Committee list shall possess experience in the design, fabrication, the use or application of signs, or shall have demonstrated a background in the social and environment impacts of signs or the development of sign regulations. Members of said committee shall be exempt from all civil service requirements.91.105.4.3.&#xA0; Procedure.&#xA0; When the board determines that a matter is significant in nature, the board may refer the matter to a Sign Advisory Committee for evaluation and recommendation before it renders a decision thereon. When the matter is referred to a Sign Advisory Committee, the board shall consider, but is not bound to accept, the recommendation of the committee.91.105.4.4.&#xA0; Composition of the Committee.&#xA0; The board shall select five persons from the Sign Advisory Committee member list to serve on a committee. The committee shall be composed of one member from each of the following interests:	1.	One member of or designated by the Board of Building and Safety Commissioners;	2.	One member of or designated by the City Planning Commission; and	3.	Three public members, one each from the following interests: architecture, sign industry and community groups.91.105.4.5.&#xA0; Compensation of Members.&#xA0; Each member of the committee who is in actual attendance at a meeting requested by the board shall be compensated at the rate of $50.00 for each four hours or fraction thereof of service. However, in no case shall the compensation of the committee members exceed the fee paid by the applicant under Section 91.105.4.7.91.105.4.6.&#xA0; Self-insurance by the City for Committee Members.&#xA0; The provisions of Sections 11.36 through 11.44, inclusive, of the Los Angeles Administrative Code shall apply to each Sign Advisory Committee member while the member is acting as such, and committee members shall be deemed to be fully covered by the provisions of said sections even though each committee member is retained as an independent person and not as an officer or employee of the city.91.105.4.7.&#xA0; Fees.&#xA0; When a matter is referred to the committee as provided in this section, the applicant in said matter shall pay a referral fee of $300.00.91.105.5.&#xA0; Disabled Access Appeals Commission.91.105.5.1.&#xA0; Creation of the Commission.&#xA0; There is hereby established a commission known as the Disabled Access Appeals Commission.91.105.5.2.&#xA0; Membership of the Commission.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 173,238, Eff. 6/19/00, Oper. 7/1/00.)&#xA0; The Disabled Access Appeals Commission shall be composed of five qualified persons.&#xA0; Two members of the commission shall be physically disabled persons, and two members shall be persons experienced in construction. The fifth member may be any resident of the City of Los Angeles. Commission members shall be appointed by the Mayor, subject to Council approval, and may be removed by the Mayor.&#xA0; In the case of a vacancy during the term of office of any member, the same shall be filled by appointment by the mayor for the period of the unexpired term subject to the approval of the council by a majority vote. The members of the commission shall be exempt from all Civil Service provisions.91.105.5.3.&#xA0; Compensation and Term of Office.&#xA0; Each member of the commission shall be paid $50.00 per meeting attended, but not to exceed $250.00 in any one calendar month.	The term of office of the members of the commission shall be five years beginning with the first day of July of the respective years, except that the terms of office of the original five members of the commission appointed pursuant to this subsection shall be such that one term shall expire on the first June 30, one term shall expire on the second June 30, one term shall expire on the third June 30, one term shall expire on the fourth June 30, and one term shall expire on the fifth June 30 next following the effective date of the appointment of the original five members. Thereafter, the terms of the succeeding members shall be so designated that the term of office of one member shall expire each year. The period of term of each member shall be designated in the appointment.	Each member of the commission shall have the power to administer oaths.91.105.5.4.&#xA0; Authority of the Commission.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. 181,758, Eff. 8/8/11.)&#xA0; The commission shall have and exercise the following powers:	1.	To hear and determine written appeals brought by any person from actions taken by the Department of Building and Safety (department) in the enforcement of the requirements of Section 19955, et seq., of the California Health and Safety Code, the provisions of state law dealing with access to public accommodations by physically disabled persons.	2.	To hear and determine written appeals brought by any person from the rulings, decisions and determinations of the department granting or denying applications for exceptions pursuant to Health and Safety Code Section 19957.	3.	To hear and determine written appeals brought by any persons where it is alleged that there is error or abuse of discretion in any order, requirement, decision, interpretation or other determination made by the department in the enforcement or administration of Section 1.8 et seq., Chapter 1, Division I of California Building Code and any other federal, state or municipal handicapped access and adaptability requirements.&#xA0;	All appeals shall be reviewed by the department.&#xA0; The department may reverse or modify the action appealed from at any time prior to final action by the commission.&#xA0; Any such new action may then be appealed to the commission.	4.	To respond to the department&#x2019;s request for advice on any matter within the department&#x2019;s jurisdiction relating to access to public accommodations and housing by the physically disabled.	5.	To exercise the authority granted in Section 91.105.6.91.105.5.5.&#xA0; Appeals.91.105.5.5.1.&#xA0; Procedures.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 172,592, Eff. 6/28/99, Oper. 7/1/99.)&#xA0; An appeal to the commission may be filed by any person aggrieved, or by an officer, Board, Department or Bureau of the City. An appeal shall be in writing and shall be filed in the Office of the Board of Building and Safety Commissioners upon appropriate forms provided by the Department. An appeal shall set forth specifically the points at issue, the reasons for the appeal, and wherein the appellant believes there was an error or an abuse of discretion by the Department.	When considering an appeal from an action by the Department, the commission shall make its determination within 30 days from the filing of the appeal. This time limit may be extended by mutual written consent of the applicant and the commission.&#xA0; Upon receipt of the appeal, the commission shall set the matter for hearing and give notice by mail of the time, place and purpose thereof to the appellant, to the applicant, to the owner or owners of the property involved, and to any interested party who has requested in writing to be so notified.&#xA0; Such notice shall be in writing and mailed at least 10 days prior to said hearing.&#xA0; No other notice thereof need be given except in those cases hereinafter mentioned.	The commission may grant, conditionally grant, or deny any appeal.&#xA0; All actions of the commission shall be final.&#xA0; Any action within the jurisdiction of the commission shall be final and conclusive as to the Department in the absence of fraud or abuse of discretion.	A separate appeal shall be filed for each single building as described in Section 98.0403.2 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code. Appeals to the Appeals Commission shall be accompanied by a filing fee as set forth in Table 4-A of Division 4 of Article 8, Chapter IX, of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.	If the commission fails to act on any appeal within the time limit specified in this section, then the action of the Department on the matter shall be final.91.105.5.5.2.&#xA0; Decision.&#xA0; The decision upon an appeal shall be concurred in by at least three members of the commission. The commission may modify or reverse a ruling, decision or determination appealed from only upon making written findings setting forth specifically wherein the action of the department was in error or constituted an abuse of discretion. The commission shall make specific written findings supporting any modification or reversal.	Upon making a decision, a copy of the findings and determination shall be furnished the applicant, the appellant and the Department of Building and Safety.91.105.5.5.3.&#xA0; Special Findings.&#xA0; Before granting or affirming the grant of an exception pursuant to Health and Safety Code Section 19957, the commission must find that the application involves a case of practical difficulty, unnecessary hardship, or extreme differences, and that it is clearly evident that equivalent facilitation and protection will be secured.91.105.5.5.4.&#xA0; Revocation of Approvals.&#xA0; The commission shall revoke or rescind any determination, including the grant of an appeal or&#xA0; exception, if made in error in violation of any provision of law, or in reliance on any false statement or misrepresentation as to a material fact.91.105.5.5.5.&#xA0; Time Limits.&#xA0; The rights and privileges granted by the commission pursuant to any decision, determination, approval, appeal or exception shall be void if all required building permits are not secured within one year of the effective date of such action, or if the permit expires under any of the conditions specified in Section 98.0602 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.	However, the commission, and the superintendent acting on behalf of the commission, may grant extensions of time if the applicant submits in writing substantial evidence that unusual conditions or circumstances either precluded the securing of all required permits within the allocated time or caused the permit to expire as specified in Section 98.0602 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.	Requests for extensions of time shall be made not later than 30 days after the expiration times specified in this section.91.105.5.5.6.&#xA0; Additional Authority.&#xA0; In considering appeals, the commission may exercise the following powers:	1.	To appoint one or more hearing officers to conduct hearings and make recommendations to the same extent and in the same manner as the Superintendent of Building acting pursuant to LAMC Section 98.0601 (a).&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 180,619, Eff. 5/12/09.)	2.	To request the attendance of witnesses and the production of evidence before it.	3.	To request the city attorney, or an assistant or deputy designated by the city attorney to appear at any hearing before the commission.	4.	To adopt rules regarding the filing of appeals, the conduct of its hearings and any other procedural rules in keeping with the provisions of this Division.91.105.5.5.7.&#xA0; Limitations on Jurisdiction.&#xA0; Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, the commission&#x2019;s jurisdiction shall not include the right to hear and determine an appeal from a department determination, order or action if such appeal is filed:	1.	On or after the date a criminal citation is issued, charging the appellant with a violation of law based on the facts underlying such determination, order or action; or	2.	On or after the date a criminal complaint is filed, charging the appellant with a violation of state laws based on such determination, order or action.	Further, the commission&#x2019;s jurisdiction shall not include the right to hear appeals from or otherwise review any action, order or determination of the Board of Building and Safety Commissioners.91.105.6.&#xA0; Administrative Penalties for Disabled Access Violations.91.105.6.1.&#xA0; Order of Abatement and Notice of Proposed Penalty.&#xA0; If the superintendent determines that a person has violated or failed to comply with any requirement of the law relating to access to public accommodations and housing by the physically disabled, then the superintendent may issue an order of abatement and notice of proposed penalty to that person.	The order and notice shall be in writing and shall describe with particularity the nature of the violation, including a reference to the provision of law that has been violated. The order shall fix a reasonable time for correction of the violation, and the notice of proposed penalty shall set forth the amount of the penalty.	The order of abatement and notice of proposed penalty shall be served upon the person either personally, or by deposit in the United States mail in a sealed envelope, postage prepaid to the person&#x2019;s last known address.	The order and notice shall also set forth the person&#x2019;s right to a hearing as described in Section 91.105.6.2.91.105.6.2.&#xA0; Right to Hearing.&#xA0; Any person served with an order of abatement or notice of proposed penalty, may apply in writing to the Disabled Access Appeals Commission for a hearing with respect to the violation alleged, the abatement period, and the amount of the penalty. This request shall be filed within 15 days after the date of service.	If the person does not request a hearing within the prescribed time, then the notice of proposed penalty shall be final, and the amount of any penalty included in the notice shall immediately be due and owing to the City of Los Angeles. The city then shall have the right to bring an action in any court of competent jurisdiction to enforce the order and collect the amount of the penalty.	If the department determines that there has been compliance with the order of abatement within the time for correction, then the department may rescind the notice of penalty.91.105.6.3.&#xA0; Time of Hearing; Notice.&#xA0; If the person requests a hearing, the superintendent shall cause the matter to be set for hearing before the Disabled Access Appeals Commission. The hearing shall be scheduled not later than 30 days after the date of the application for hearing. This time limit may be extended with the mutual consent of the person and the commission. It shall be a defense to the affirmation of any penalty that the person complied with the order of abatement within the time for correction.	The decision of the commission on the order of abatement and notice of proposed penalty shall be final, and the amount of any penalty affirmed by the commission shall immediately be due and owing to the City of Los Angeles. The city then shall have the right to bring an action in any court of competent jurisdiction to enforce the order and collect the amount of penalty.91.105.6.4&#xA0; Civil Penalties.&#xA0; Any penalty required to be paid under the provisions of this section is a debt owed to the City of Los Angeles. Any person owing a penalty due under the provisions of this section shall be liable in an action brought in the name of the City of Los Angeles in any court of competent jurisdiction for recovery of any such amount.	The conviction of any person for violating any law shall not relieve the person from the obligation to pay any penalty that the person may owe the city, nor shall such payment prevent a prosecution under appropriate provisions of law for any violation of the law. The remedies provided in this section are cumulative. The use of one or more of the remedies prescribed in this section shall not bar the use of any other remedy provided for the enforcement of law.91.105.6.5.&#xA0; Fee Schedules.&#xA0; The Superintendent shall submit a schedule for the assessment of civil penalties under this section to council for the approval by ordinance.	This schedule shall give due consideration to the appropriateness of the penalty with respect to the following factors:	1.	The gravity of the violation;	2.	The good faith of the violator being charged; and	3.	The history of previous violations.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><unit></unit></prefixes><entire_prefix></entire_prefix><prefix_anchor></prefix_anchor><level>1</level></unit></text></law>
