<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><section_number>95.115</section_number><edition_id>1</edition_id><section_id>2820</section_id><structure_id>73</structure_id><catch_line>Permit Fees.</catch_line><history></history><full_text>&#xA0; PERMIT FEES.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 172,595, Eff. 6/28/99, Oper. 7/1/99.)

95.115.1.&#xA0; PERMIT FEES.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 180,868, Eff. 10/22/09.)&#xA0; Before any permit required by this Code is issued, the applicant shall pay to the Department the following fees:

PERMIT FEE SCHEDULE FOR HEATING, VENTILATING, AIR-CONDITIONING AND REFRIGERATION EQUIPMENT AND MISCELLANEOUS HEAT-PRODUCING APPLIANCES


  
    
      
        Permit
      
      
        Fee
      
    
    
      
        1.
      
      
        a.&#xA0; &#xA0; For issuing permit	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.&#xA0; &#xA0; 	For issuing a supplementary permit (the fee for which shall be the difference between the fee paid for the&#xA0; original permit and the fee which would have been&#xA0; required had the original permit included the entire installation, repair, relocation or alteration plus	
      
      
        $20.00
      
    
    
      
        2.
      
      
        For the installation or relocation of each fuel-burning heating appliance regulated by this Code	
      
      
        $19.00
      
    
    
      
        3.
      
      
        For&#xA0; each&#xA0; air&#xA0; inlet&#xA0; and&#xA0; air&#xA0; outlet&#xA0; served&#xA0; by any&#xA0; heating,&#xA0; air-conditioning&#xA0; or&#xA0; ventilation&#xA0; system	
      
      
        $5.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        or for each 1,000 square feet (92.9 m2) or fraction thereof of conditioned area for any heating or air-conditioning system using perforated building material in lieu of conventional air inlets and outlets	
      
      
        $38.00
      
    
    
      
        4.
      
      
        a.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each appliance vent system, factory-built chimney and each absorption unit vent system regulated by this Code	
      
      
        $12.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each unlisted single-wall metal chimney (smokestack)	
      
      
        $57.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; Note:&#xA0; This fee shall not apply to a vent system which is an integral part of an appliance or an absorption unit, which is listed for outdoor installation.
      
      
        
      
    
    
      
        5.
      
      
        For the repair of, alteration of or addition to each refrigeration system, fuel- burning heating appliance, comfort-cooling unit, absorption unit, or each comfort-heating, cooling, absorption, ventilation or evaporative cooling system, including the installation of controls regulated by this Code	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        6.
      
      
        a.&#xA0; &#xA0; For each ventilation system which is serving a commercial cooking hood	
      
      
        $33.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For each environmental air and commercial-type clothes dryer ventilation system regulated by this Code	
      
      
        $12.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        c.&#xA0; &#xA0; For each product-conveying duct system regulated by this Code	
      
      
        $59.00
      
    
    
      
        7.
      
      
        For the installation of each hood	
      
      
        $33.00
      
    
    
      
        8.
      
      
        a.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each comfort-cooling compressor of 25-horsepower (87.9 k/W) rating or less and each absorption unit having an input capacity of 500,000 Btu/h (2299.3 L/W) or less	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each refrigeration compressor of 25-horsepower rating (87.9 k/W) or less, other than a compressor for a unit refrigeration system	
      
      
        $38.00
      
    
    
      
        9.
      
      
        a.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each comfort-cooling compressor over 25-horsepower (87.9 K/W) rating and under 50-horsepower (175.8 k/W) rating, and each absorption unit having an input capacity over 500,000 Btu/h (2299.3 L/W) and under 1,000,000 Btu/h (4598.6 L/W)	
      
      
        $59.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each refrigeration compressor over 25-horsepower (87.9 k/W) rating and under 50-horsepower (175.8 k/W) rating	
      
      
        $77.00
      
    
    
      
        10.
      
      
        a.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each comfort-cooling compressor of 50-horsepower (175.8 k/W) rating and over, and each absorption unit having an input capacity of 1,000,000 Btu/h (4598.6 L/W) and over	
      
      
        $116.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each refrigeration compressor of 50-horsepower (175.8 k/W) rating and over	
      
      
        $158.00
      
    
    
      
        11.
      
      
        For&#xA0; the&#xA0; installation&#xA0; of&#xA0; each&#xA0; air-handling&#xA0; unit&#xA0; used&#xA0; for&#xA0; the&#xA0; distribution&#xA0; of&#xA0; conditioned&#xA0; air supply	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        Note:&#xA0; This fee shall not apply to an air-handling unit which is a portion of a factory-assembled appliance, comfort-cooling unit, evaporative cooler or absorption unit for which a permit is required elsewhere in this Code.	
      
      
        
      
    
    
      
        12.
      
      
        For the installation of each evaporative cooler which is not classified as a portable evaporative cooler	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        13.
      
      
        When it shall be necessary to make an extra inspection trip due to the applicant having given an incorrect address or wrong location for any permit when obtaining a permit required by this Code, a fee shall be paid by the applicant for correcting the address or location given in such permit	
      
      
        $36.00
      
    
    
      
        14.
      
      
        For the installation of incidental gas piping for each&#xA0; existing&#xA0; individual&#xA0; metered&#xA0; system&#xA0; up&#xA0; to and&#xA0; including&#xA0; five&#xA0; outlets&#xA0; (see&#xA0; Section 95.112.4)	
      
      
        $25.00
      
    
    
      
        &#xA0;&#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0;
      
      
        For each outlet over five	
      
      
        $7.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        Note:&#xA0; For the purpose of this fee, incidental gas piping shall mean any addition made to an existing low-pressure gas piping system to accommodate gas-burning equipment regulated by this Code.&#xA0; This fee shall not apply if such piping is less than six feet (1.8 m) in length and connects to an existing gas outlet.
      
      
        
      
    
    
      
        15.
      
      
        For the installation of each fire damper	
      
      
        $12.00
      
    
    
      
        16.
      
      
        For the installation of each smoke-control damper which is a portion of a smoke- control system that is required by the Los Angeles Municipal Code	
      
      
        $12.00
      
    
    
      
        17.
      
      
        For each smoke detector which is required by the Los Angeles Mechanical Code	
      
      
        $10.00
      
    
    
      
        18.
      
      
        For witnessing the performance test of any emergency mechanical smoke-control system, stair shaft pressurization system, smoke detector or smoke damper which is a portion of that system.&#xA0; For each hour or fraction thereof	
      
      
        $108.00
      
    
    
      
        19.
      
      
        For witnessing the performance test of any heating or cooling equipment for automatic shutoff.&#xA0; For each hour or fraction thereof	
      
      
        $108.00
      
    
    
      
        20.
      
      
        For witnessing the performance test of any ventilating system serving commercial food heat-processing equipment.&#xA0; For each hour or fraction thereof	
      
      
        $108.00
      
    
    
      
        21.
      
      
        For the minimum inspection	
      
      
        $93.00
      
    
    
      
        22.
      
      
        For each additional inspection	
      
      
        $93.00
      
    
    
      
        23.
      
      
        Minimum inspection fee.&#xA0; Los Angeles Municipal Code Section 98.0412.1 and 98.0412.1.1:
      
      
        
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        a.&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of a single fixture described in this section	
      
      
        $57.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.&#xA0; &#xA0; 	Where the cumulative fees described in this section total less than the minimum fee required by the Los Angeles Mechanical Code	
      
      
        $93.00
      
    
    
      
        24.
      
      
        For transfer of a permit	
      
      
        $50.00
      
    
    
      
        Note:&#xA0; Items 18, 19 and 20.&#xA0; For the purpose of witness fee requirements, more than one system of the same category can be inspected in the same building spaces if completed within the same hour.&#xA0; For each additional category or additional hour or fraction thereof a fee of $75.00 is required.&#xA0; These fees are not to be included in determining plan check fee.
      
    
  

	
95.115.2.&#xA0; PLAN CHECK FEES.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 180,868, Eff. 10/22/09.)

	(a)	Before formally accepting a set of plans and specifications for checking, the Department shall collect a plan check fee.

	A complete schedule of the permit fees due shall be included with each set of plans submitted to the Department.

	The plan check fees required by the provisions of this section are in addition to the inspection fees required by Sections 95.115.5 and 95.115.8 of this Code.

	A fee as specified in Item 10 of Section 95.115.2 shall be collected by the Department prior to approval for each set of plans submitted beyond the two required by this Code containing more than 10 sheets including calculations and documentation.

	Plan check fee shall be as follows:

	1.	All projects


  
    
      
        Type of Installation
      
      
        Standard Design
      
      
        Additional Fee for Checking Analysis of Annual Energy Budget
      
    
    
      
        Installation of equipment as listed in Section 95.115.1
      
      
        70% of permit fee
$93.00 minimum; plus a surcharge of 10% of permit fee, $72.00 minimum, for checking compliance with State Energy Standards
NOTE: For conditioned areas where the number of air inlets and air outlets is unknown, $12.00 for each 1000 sq. ft. or fraction thereof.
      
      
        60% of permit fee,
$144.00 minimum, 
$4,037.00 maximum
      
    
  


	2.	In addition to the above fee, a plan checking fee shall be assessed for checking the following systems:

	a.	Commercial cooking ventilation systems, serving type I hoods, each  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $216.00

	b.	Commercial cooking ventilation systems, serving type II hoods each  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $144.00

	c.	Type&#xA0; I,&#xA0; Type&#xA0; II&#xA0; or&#xA0; fume&#xA0; hoods,&#xA0; each  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $72.00

	d.	Product&#xA0; conveying&#xA0; ventilation systems  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $216.00

	e.	Engineering calculations of smoke control systems, each  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $1,081.00

	f.	Engineering calculations of stair shaft pressurization systems, each  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $216.00

	g.	Engineered and/or proprietary duct joints,&#xA0; each&#xA0; HVAC&#xA0; system, minimum  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $144.00

	h.	The Department may collect a plan check fee as specified in Section 98.0415(e) of the Los Angeles Municipal Code for the following plan check services:

	1.	Specially engineered systems;

	2.	Engineered systems not listed in Section 95.115.1;

	3.	Review of expired plans provided that the original approved plans are submitted along with the new plans, and the new plans have no changes other than those required to comply with the current code;

	4.	Review of plans revised for reasons other than to comply with plan check corrections;

	5.	Review of &#x201C;As Built&#x201D; plans provided that the original approved plans are submitted along with the new plans;

	6.	Any time not included in the original plan check fee.

	(b)	Off-hour Plan Check.&#xA0; Upon request by an applicant and accepted by the Department, an off-hour plan check fee per Section 98.0422 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code may be collected.


95.115.3.&#xA0; EXPIRATION OF PLAN CHECK.&#xA0; Plan check approval shall expire as provided for in Section 98.0603 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.

95.115.4.&#xA0; MINIMUM INSPECTION FEE.

	1.	A minimum fee as specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code shall be paid to the Department for each mechanical installation for which a permit is required by this Code.

	2.	When the cumulative fees and the issuing fee set forth in this Code are less than the minimum fee, the minimum fee shall be paid, which shall include the issuing fee.

	3.	The fee for single fixture shall apply to the installation of only one mechanical fixture/equipment and shall include the issuing fee.&#xA0; Where the fee for a single fixture exceeds the minimum fee for single fixtures, this fee shall not apply.

95.115.5.&#xA0; FEES FOR MISCELLANEOUS PERMITS.

	1.	When permission has been obtained from the Department, a permit may be issued for that portion of equipment to be concealed if the permit cannot be issued until required plans have been approved.&#xA0; The miscellaneous permit shall not be an authorization for the installation of any other equipment.

	The permittee shall submit plans along with this permit application which shall clearly designate the equipment to be concealed and the building area involved.&#xA0; If the work done on the miscellaneous permit is not in accordance with the final approved plans, the permittee shall be responsible for making all necessary corrections for compliance with the Code.

	A fee as specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code shall be paid for the inspection of this installation and shall be limited to one inspection trip and one reinspection trip.&#xA0; This fee is in addition to the permit-issuing fee specified in Section 95.115.1.

	2.	A miscellaneous permit fee as specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code shall be paid for inspection of the installation of equipment regulated by this Code which requires an inspection for determination of Code compliance and where such installation inspection is not provided for in the permit fee schedule specified in Section 95.115.1.&#xA0; This fee is in addition to the permit issuing fee specified in Section 95.115.1.

95.115.6.&#xA0; INVESTIGATION FEE.&#xA0; Except as provided in Section 95.112.1, whenever any work for which a permit is required under the provisions of this Code has been commenced without the authorization of a permit, a special investigation shall be made before a permit may be issued for the work.&#xA0; In addition to the permit fee, an investigation fee shall be collected as provided for in Section 98.0402 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.

95.115.7.&#xA0; TRANSFER OF PERMITS AND PLAN CHECKS.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 172,595, Eff. 6/28/99, Oper. 7/1/99.)&#xA0; No permit shall be transferable from the original permittee to any other person, unless the property owner authorizes the transfer in writing.&#xA0; Upon authorization, the new permittee shall file with the Department a new permit and pay to the Department a fee as specified in Section LAMC 98.0415 for issuing the new permit.&#xA0; This fee includes the issuing permit fee specified in the fee schedule set forth in LAMC Section 95.115.1.

	NOTE:&#xA0; No plan check shall be transferable from one contractor to another unless the original plans were prepared and signed by a state-licensed engineer in the proper classification.

95.115.8.&#xA0; FEES FOR ADDITIONAL INSPECTIONS.

	1.	Each permit shall be entitled to three inspection trips when the job is of a type requiring an inspection before covering or concealing the work.&#xA0; On jobs which may be completely inspected on one inspection trip, two inspection trips will be allowed.

	EXCEPTION:&#xA0; The number of inspection trips will not be limited on progress jobs, provided, however, that only one inspection will be permitted for checking a correction.&#xA0; For the purpose of this section, progress jobs are those in which circumstances beyond the control of the applicant make it impossible for the installation to be completed at any specific time.

	2.	If more inspection trips than are specified in Subsection 1 of this section are required due to the fault or error on the part of the applicant or the applicant&#x2019;s employees, an additional fee as specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code shall be paid by the applicant for each additional inspection trip.

	3.	The Department may recheck installations at intervals of 30 days or more, where violations continue to exist, until either the violations are cleared or a total of three rechecks are made.&#xA0; The fees specified in Subsection 2 of this section shall apply for each recheck inspection.

	4.	The fees charged under this section are in addition to any other fees shown and the payment of the fees required by this section shall not exempt any person from compliance with other provisions of this Code nor from any penalty prescribed by law.

	5.	Whenever special enforcement procedures are required to obtain compliance with properly executed Department notices or orders, a fee, as specified in Section 98.0407 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code, shall be assessed in addition to the added trip fee specified in Subsection 2 of this section.

95.115.9.&#xA0; INSPECTION FEES FOR OFF-HOURS INSPECTIONS.&#xA0; The Department may, at its discretion, make emergency inspections at other than normal working hours upon the request of a permittee, provided that additional fees are paid as specified in Section 98.0406 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.

95.115.10.&#xA0; FEES FOR OFF-SITE INSPECTIONS.&#xA0; Upon written request, the Department may, at its discretion, make inspections at locations other than the site upon which a building will be located, provided that location is within 60 miles (96.56 km) of the Los Angeles City Hall.

	A fee, in addition to fees charged elsewhere in this Code, at the rate specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code per hour shall be charged for such inspections, time to include travel to and from the place of inspection, with the minimum fee as specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.</full_text><order_by>115</order_by><ancestry><unit id="73" label="article"><name>Mechanical Code</name><identifier>5</identifier><url>/9/5/</url></unit><unit id="3" label="chapter"><name>Building Regulations</name><identifier>9</identifier><url>/9/</url></unit></ancestry><structure_contents><unit id="361"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.101</section_number><catch_line>Title.</catch_line><url>/95.101/</url><token>95.101</token></unit><unit id="266"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.102</section_number><catch_line>Purpose.</catch_line><url>/95.102/</url><token>95.102</token></unit><unit id="3770"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.103</section_number><catch_line>Scope.</catch_line><url>/95.103/</url><token>95.103</token></unit><unit id="1894"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.104</section_number><catch_line>Application To Existing Mechanical Systems.</catch_line><url>/95.104/</url><token>95.104</token></unit><unit id="3181"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.105</section_number><catch_line>Alternate Materials And Methods Of Construction.</catch_line><url>/95.105/</url><token>95.105</token></unit><unit id="4187"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.106</section_number><catch_line>Modifications.</catch_line><url>/95.106/</url><token>95.106</token></unit><unit id="3533"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.107</section_number><catch_line>Tests.</catch_line><url>/95.107/</url><token>95.107</token></unit><unit id="3910"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.108</section_number><catch_line>Powers And Duties Of The Department.</catch_line><url>/95.108/</url><token>95.108</token></unit><unit id="1431"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.109</section_number><catch_line>Unsafe Equipment.</catch_line><url>/95.109/</url><token>95.109</token></unit><unit id="3067"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.110</section_number><catch_line>Appeals.</catch_line><url>/95.110/</url><token>95.110</token></unit><unit id="3023"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.111</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited Acts.</catch_line><url>/95.111/</url><token>95.111</token></unit><unit id="1702"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.112</section_number><catch_line>Permits.</catch_line><url>/95.112/</url><token>95.112</token></unit><unit id="446"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.113</section_number><catch_line>Application For Permit.</catch_line><url>/95.113/</url><token>95.113</token></unit><unit id="1506"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.114</section_number><catch_line>Permit Issuance.</catch_line><url>/95.114/</url><token>95.114</token></unit><unit id="2820"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.115</section_number><catch_line>Permit Fees.</catch_line><url>/95.115/</url><token>95.115</token></unit><unit id="4077"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.116</section_number><catch_line>Inspections.</catch_line><url>/95.116/</url><token>95.116</token></unit><unit id="1522"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.117</section_number><catch_line>Connection Approval.</catch_line><url>/95.117/</url><token>95.117</token></unit><unit id="2137"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.118</section_number><catch_line>Registration.</catch_line><url>/95.118/</url><token>95.118</token></unit><unit id="3673"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.119</section_number><catch_line>Format.</catch_line><url>/95.119/</url><token>95.119</token></unit><unit id="515"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.120</section_number><catch_line>Validity.</catch_line><url>/95.120/</url><token>95.120</token></unit><unit id="471"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.121</section_number><catch_line>Standard Reference Documents.</catch_line><url>/95.121/</url><token>95.121</token></unit><unit id="1801"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.201</section_number><catch_line>General.</catch_line><url>/95.201/</url><token>95.201</token></unit><unit id="1896"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.202</section_number><catch_line>Accepted Meanings.</catch_line><url>/95.202/</url><token>95.202</token></unit><unit id="3871"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.203.0</section_number><catch_line>A.</catch_line><url>/95.203.0/</url><token>95.203.0</token></unit><unit id="1744"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.204.0</section_number><catch_line>B.</catch_line><url>/95.204.0/</url><token>95.204.0</token></unit><unit id="1469"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.205.0</section_number><catch_line>C.</catch_line><url>/95.205.0/</url><token>95.205.0</token></unit><unit id="540"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.206.0</section_number><catch_line>D.</catch_line><url>/95.206.0/</url><token>95.206.0</token></unit><unit id="3626"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.207.0</section_number><catch_line>E.</catch_line><url>/95.207.0/</url><token>95.207.0</token></unit><unit id="619"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.208.0</section_number><catch_line>F.</catch_line><url>/95.208.0/</url><token>95.208.0</token></unit><unit id="4132"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.209.0</section_number><catch_line>G.</catch_line><url>/95.209.0/</url><token>95.209.0</token></unit><unit id="3291"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.210.0</section_number><catch_line>H.</catch_line><url>/95.210.0/</url><token>95.210.0</token></unit><unit id="344"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.211.0</section_number><catch_line>I.</catch_line><url>/95.211.0/</url><token>95.211.0</token></unit><unit id="849"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.212.0</section_number><catch_line>J.</catch_line><url>/95.212.0/</url><token>95.212.0</token></unit><unit id="3992"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.213.0</section_number><catch_line>K.</catch_line><url>/95.213.0/</url><token>95.213.0</token></unit><unit id="879"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.214.0</section_number><catch_line>L.</catch_line><url>/95.214.0/</url><token>95.214.0</token></unit><unit id="3353"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.215.0</section_number><catch_line>M.</catch_line><url>/95.215.0/</url><token>95.215.0</token></unit><unit id="1349"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.216.0</section_number><catch_line>N.</catch_line><url>/95.216.0/</url><token>95.216.0</token></unit><unit id="3595"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.217.0</section_number><catch_line>O.</catch_line><url>/95.217.0/</url><token>95.217.0</token></unit><unit id="2243"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.218.0</section_number><catch_line>P.</catch_line><url>/95.218.0/</url><token>95.218.0</token></unit><unit id="3788"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.219.0</section_number><catch_line>Q.</catch_line><url>/95.219.0/</url><token>95.219.0</token></unit><unit id="2347"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.220.0</section_number><catch_line>R.</catch_line><url>/95.220.0/</url><token>95.220.0</token></unit><unit id="3141"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.221.0</section_number><catch_line>S.</catch_line><url>/95.221.0/</url><token>95.221.0</token></unit><unit id="4159"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.222.0</section_number><catch_line>T.</catch_line><url>/95.222.0/</url><token>95.222.0</token></unit><unit id="561"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.223.0</section_number><catch_line>U.</catch_line><url>/95.223.0/</url><token>95.223.0</token></unit><unit id="624"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.224.0</section_number><catch_line>V.</catch_line><url>/95.224.0/</url><token>95.224.0</token></unit><unit id="1719"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.225.0</section_number><catch_line>W.</catch_line><url>/95.225.0/</url><token>95.225.0</token></unit><unit id="3858"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.226.0</section_number><catch_line>X.</catch_line><url>/95.226.0/</url><token>95.226.0</token></unit><unit id="2935"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.227.0</section_number><catch_line>Y.</catch_line><url>/95.227.0/</url><token>95.227.0</token></unit><unit id="955"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.228.0</section_number><catch_line>Z.</catch_line><url>/95.228.0/</url><token>95.228.0</token></unit><unit id="3644"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.300</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/95.300/</url><token>95.300</token></unit><unit id="2894"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.312</section_number><catch_line>Water Supply.</catch_line><url>/95.312/</url><token>95.312</token></unit><unit id="883"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.400</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/95.400/</url><token>95.400</token></unit><unit id="423"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.500</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/95.500/</url><token>95.500</token></unit><unit id="3524"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.600</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/95.600/</url><token>95.600</token></unit><unit id="2330"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.700</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/95.700/</url><token>95.700</token></unit><unit id="2795"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.800</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/95.800/</url><token>95.800</token></unit><unit id="2081"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.900</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/95.900/</url><token>95.900</token></unit><unit id="2141"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.1000</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/95.1000/</url><token>95.1000</token></unit><unit id="1634"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.1100</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/95.1100/</url><token>95.1100</token></unit><unit id="1424"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.1200</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/95.1200/</url><token>95.1200</token></unit><unit id="703"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.1300</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/95.1300/</url><token>95.1300</token></unit><unit id="3818"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.1400</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/95.1400/</url><token>95.1400</token></unit><unit id="2018"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.1500</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/95.1500/</url><token>95.1500</token></unit><unit id="1574"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.1600</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/95.1600/</url><token>95.1600</token></unit><unit id="598"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.1700</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/95.1700/</url><token>95.1700</token></unit><unit id="3197"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.1800</section_number><catch_line>Basic Provisions.</catch_line><url>/95.1800/</url><token>95.1800</token></unit></structure_contents><previous_section id="1506"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.114</section_number><catch_line>Permit Issuance.</catch_line><url>/95.114/</url><token>95.114</token></previous_section><next_section id="4077"><structure_id>73</structure_id><section_number>95.116</section_number><catch_line>Inspections.</catch_line><url>/95.116/</url><token>95.116</token></next_section><metadata></metadata><references></references><url>/95.115/</url><token>95.115</token><formats><txt>/95.115.txt</txt><json>/95.115.xml</json></formats><dublin_core><Title>Permit Fees.</Title><Type>Text</Type><Format>text/html</Format><Identifier>&#xA7; 95.115</Identifier><Relation>Los Angeles Municipal Code</Relation></dublin_core><plain_text>                            LOS ANGELES MUNICIPAL CODE

PERMIT FEES. (&#xA7; 95.115)

&#xA0; PERMIT FEES.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 172,595, Eff. 6/28/99, Oper. 7/1/99.)95.115.1.&#xA0; PERMIT
FEES.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 180,868, Eff. 10/22/09.)&#xA0; Before any permit
required by this Code is issued, the applicant shall pay to the Department the
following fees:PERMIT FEE SCHEDULE FOR HEATING, VENTILATING, AIR-CONDITIONING
AND REFRIGERATION EQUIPMENT AND MISCELLANEOUS HEAT-PRODUCING APPLIANCES
  
    
      
        Permit
      
      
        Fee
      
    
    
      
        1.
      
      
        a.&#xA0; &#xA0; For issuing permit	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.&#xA0; &#xA0; 	For issuing a supplementary permit (the fee for which shall be
the difference between the fee paid for the&#xA0; original permit and the fee which
would have been&#xA0; required had the original permit included the entire
installation, repair, relocation or alteration plus	
      
      
        $20.00
      
    
    
      
        2.
      
      
        For the installation or relocation of each fuel-burning heating
appliance regulated by this Code	
      
      
        $19.00
      
    
    
      
        3.
      
      
        For&#xA0; each&#xA0; air&#xA0; inlet&#xA0; and&#xA0; air&#xA0; outlet&#xA0; served&#xA0; by any&#xA0;
heating,&#xA0; air-conditioning&#xA0; or&#xA0; ventilation&#xA0; system	
      
      
        $5.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        or for each 1,000 square feet (92.9 m2) or fraction thereof of
conditioned area for any heating or air-conditioning system using perforated
building material in lieu of conventional air inlets and outlets	
      
      
        $38.00
      
    
    
      
        4.
      
      
        a.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each appliance vent system,
factory-built chimney and each absorption unit vent system regulated by this
Code	
      
      
        $12.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each unlisted single-wall metal chimney
(smokestack)	
      
      
        $57.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; Note:&#xA0; This fee shall not apply to a vent system which is an
integral part of an appliance or an absorption unit, which is listed for outdoor
installation.
      
      
        
      
    
    
      
        5.
      
      
        For the repair of, alteration of or addition to each refrigeration
system, fuel- burning heating appliance, comfort-cooling unit, absorption unit,
or each comfort-heating, cooling, absorption, ventilation or evaporative cooling
system, including the installation of controls regulated by this Code	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        6.
      
      
        a.&#xA0; &#xA0; For each ventilation system which is serving a commercial
cooking hood	
      
      
        $33.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For each environmental air and commercial-type clothes dryer
ventilation system regulated by this Code	
      
      
        $12.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        c.&#xA0; &#xA0; For each product-conveying duct system regulated by this Code	
      
      
        $59.00
      
    
    
      
        7.
      
      
        For the installation of each hood	
      
      
        $33.00
      
    
    
      
        8.
      
      
        a.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each comfort-cooling compressor of
25-horsepower (87.9 k/W) rating or less and each absorption unit having an input
capacity of 500,000 Btu/h (2299.3 L/W) or less	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each refrigeration compressor of
25-horsepower rating (87.9 k/W) or less, other than a compressor for a unit
refrigeration system	
      
      
        $38.00
      
    
    
      
        9.
      
      
        a.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each comfort-cooling compressor over
25-horsepower (87.9 K/W) rating and under 50-horsepower (175.8 k/W) rating, and
each absorption unit having an input capacity over 500,000 Btu/h (2299.3 L/W)
and under 1,000,000 Btu/h (4598.6 L/W)	
      
      
        $59.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each refrigeration compressor over
25-horsepower (87.9 k/W) rating and under 50-horsepower (175.8 k/W) rating	
      
      
        $77.00
      
    
    
      
        10.
      
      
        a.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each comfort-cooling compressor of
50-horsepower (175.8 k/W) rating and over, and each absorption unit having an
input capacity of 1,000,000 Btu/h (4598.6 L/W) and over	
      
      
        $116.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each refrigeration compressor of
50-horsepower (175.8 k/W) rating and over	
      
      
        $158.00
      
    
    
      
        11.
      
      
        For&#xA0; the&#xA0; installation&#xA0; of&#xA0; each&#xA0; air-handling&#xA0; unit&#xA0; used&#xA0;
for&#xA0; the&#xA0; distribution&#xA0; of&#xA0; conditioned&#xA0; air supply	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        Note:&#xA0; This fee shall not apply to an air-handling unit which is a
portion of a factory-assembled appliance, comfort-cooling unit, evaporative
cooler or absorption unit for which a permit is required elsewhere in this
Code.	
      
      
        
      
    
    
      
        12.
      
      
        For the installation of each evaporative cooler which is not classified
as a portable evaporative cooler	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        13.
      
      
        When it shall be necessary to make an extra inspection trip due to the
applicant having given an incorrect address or wrong location for any permit
when obtaining a permit required by this Code, a fee shall be paid by the
applicant for correcting the address or location given in such permit	
      
      
        $36.00
      
    
    
      
        14.
      
      
        For the installation of incidental gas piping for each&#xA0; existing&#xA0;
individual&#xA0; metered&#xA0; system&#xA0; up&#xA0; to and&#xA0; including&#xA0; five&#xA0; outlets&#xA0;
(see&#xA0; Section 95.112.4)	
      
      
        $25.00
      
    
    
      
        &#xA0;&#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0;
      
      
        For each outlet over five	
      
      
        $7.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        Note:&#xA0; For the purpose of this fee, incidental gas piping shall mean
any addition made to an existing low-pressure gas piping system to accommodate
gas-burning equipment regulated by this Code.&#xA0; This fee shall not apply if such
piping is less than six feet (1.8 m) in length and connects to an existing gas
outlet.
      
      
        
      
    
    
      
        15.
      
      
        For the installation of each fire damper	
      
      
        $12.00
      
    
    
      
        16.
      
      
        For the installation of each smoke-control damper which is a portion of
a smoke- control system that is required by the Los Angeles Municipal Code	
      
      
        $12.00
      
    
    
      
        17.
      
      
        For each smoke detector which is required by the Los Angeles Mechanical
Code	
      
      
        $10.00
      
    
    
      
        18.
      
      
        For witnessing the performance test of any emergency mechanical
smoke-control system, stair shaft pressurization system, smoke detector or smoke
damper which is a portion of that system.&#xA0; For each hour or fraction thereof	
      
      
        $108.00
      
    
    
      
        19.
      
      
        For witnessing the performance test of any heating or cooling equipment
for automatic shutoff.&#xA0; For each hour or fraction thereof	
      
      
        $108.00
      
    
    
      
        20.
      
      
        For witnessing the performance test of any ventilating system serving
commercial food heat-processing equipment.&#xA0; For each hour or fraction thereof	
      
      
        $108.00
      
    
    
      
        21.
      
      
        For the minimum inspection	
      
      
        $93.00
      
    
    
      
        22.
      
      
        For each additional inspection	
      
      
        $93.00
      
    
    
      
        23.
      
      
        Minimum inspection fee.&#xA0; Los Angeles Municipal Code Section 98.0412.1
and 98.0412.1.1:
      
      
        
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        a.&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of a single fixture described in this
section	
      
      
        $57.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.&#xA0; &#xA0; 	Where the cumulative fees described in this section total less
than the minimum fee required by the Los Angeles Mechanical Code	
      
      
        $93.00
      
    
    
      
        24.
      
      
        For transfer of a permit	
      
      
        $50.00
      
    
    
      
        Note:&#xA0; Items 18, 19 and 20.&#xA0; For the purpose of witness fee
requirements, more than one system of the same category can be inspected in the
same building spaces if completed within the same hour.&#xA0; For each additional
category or additional hour or fraction thereof a fee of $75.00 is required.&#xA0;
These fees are not to be included in determining plan check fee.
      
    
  	
95.115.2.&#xA0; PLAN CHECK FEES.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 180,868, Eff.
10/22/09.)	(a)	Before formally accepting a set of plans and specifications for
checking, the Department shall collect a plan check fee.	A complete schedule of
the permit fees due shall be included with each set of plans submitted to the
Department.	The plan check fees required by the provisions of this section are
in addition to the inspection fees required by Sections 95.115.5 and 95.115.8 of
this Code.	A fee as specified in Item 10 of Section 95.115.2 shall be collected
by the Department prior to approval for each set of plans submitted beyond the
two required by this Code containing more than 10 sheets including calculations
and documentation.	Plan check fee shall be as follows:	1.	All projects
  
    
      
        Type of Installation
      
      
        Standard Design
      
      
        Additional Fee for Checking Analysis of Annual Energy Budget
      
    
    
      
        Installation of equipment as listed in Section 95.115.1
      
      
        70% of permit fee
$93.00 minimum; plus a surcharge of 10% of permit fee, $72.00 minimum, for
checking compliance with State Energy Standards
NOTE: For conditioned areas where the number of air inlets and air outlets is
unknown, $12.00 for each 1000 sq. ft. or fraction thereof.
      
      
        60% of permit fee,
$144.00 minimum, 
$4,037.00 maximum
      
    
  
	2.	In addition to the above fee, a plan checking fee shall be assessed for
checking the following systems:	a.	Commercial cooking ventilation systems,
serving type I hoods, each  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. 
.&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $216.00	b.	Commercial cooking ventilation systems, serving
type II hoods each  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. 
.&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $144.00	c.	Type&#xA0; I,&#xA0; Type&#xA0; II&#xA0; or&#xA0; fume&#xA0; hoods,&#xA0;
each  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. .
$72.00	d.	Product&#xA0; conveying&#xA0; ventilation systems  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. 
.&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $216.00	e.	Engineering calculations
of smoke control systems, each  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. 
.&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $1,081.00	f.	Engineering calculations of stair shaft
pressurization systems, each  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. 
.&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $216.00	g.	Engineered and/or proprietary duct joints,&#xA0;
each&#xA0; HVAC&#xA0; system, minimum  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. 
.&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $144.00	h.	The Department may collect a plan check fee as
specified in Section 98.0415(e) of the Los Angeles Municipal Code for the
following plan check services:	1.	Specially engineered systems;	2.	Engineered
systems not listed in Section 95.115.1;	3.	Review of expired plans provided that
the original approved plans are submitted along with the new plans, and the new
plans have no changes other than those required to comply with the current
code;	4.	Review of plans revised for reasons other than to comply with plan
check corrections;	5.	Review of &#x201C;As Built&#x201D; plans provided that the original
approved plans are submitted along with the new plans;	6.	Any time not included
in the original plan check fee.	(b)	Off-hour Plan Check.&#xA0; Upon request by an
applicant and accepted by the Department, an off-hour plan check fee per Section
98.0422 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code may be collected.
95.115.3.&#xA0; EXPIRATION OF PLAN CHECK.&#xA0; Plan check approval shall expire as
provided for in Section 98.0603 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.95.115.4.&#xA0;
MINIMUM INSPECTION FEE.	1.	A minimum fee as specified in Section 98.0412 of the
Los Angeles Municipal Code shall be paid to the Department for each mechanical
installation for which a permit is required by this Code.	2.	When the cumulative
fees and the issuing fee set forth in this Code are less than the minimum fee,
the minimum fee shall be paid, which shall include the issuing fee.	3.	The fee
for single fixture shall apply to the installation of only one mechanical
fixture/equipment and shall include the issuing fee.&#xA0; Where the fee for a
single fixture exceeds the minimum fee for single fixtures, this fee shall not
apply.95.115.5.&#xA0; FEES FOR MISCELLANEOUS PERMITS.	1.	When permission has been
obtained from the Department, a permit may be issued for that portion of
equipment to be concealed if the permit cannot be issued until required plans
have been approved.&#xA0; The miscellaneous permit shall not be an authorization for
the installation of any other equipment.	The permittee shall submit plans along
with this permit application which shall clearly designate the equipment to be
concealed and the building area involved.&#xA0; If the work done on the
miscellaneous permit is not in accordance with the final approved plans, the
permittee shall be responsible for making all necessary corrections for
compliance with the Code.	A fee as specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los
Angeles Municipal Code shall be paid for the inspection of this installation and
shall be limited to one inspection trip and one reinspection trip.&#xA0; This fee is
in addition to the permit-issuing fee specified in Section 95.115.1.	2.	A
miscellaneous permit fee as specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles
Municipal Code shall be paid for inspection of the installation of equipment
regulated by this Code which requires an inspection for determination of Code
compliance and where such installation inspection is not provided for in the
permit fee schedule specified in Section 95.115.1.&#xA0; This fee is in addition to
the permit issuing fee specified in Section 95.115.1.95.115.6.&#xA0; INVESTIGATION
FEE.&#xA0; Except as provided in Section 95.112.1, whenever any work for which a
permit is required under the provisions of this Code has been commenced without
the authorization of a permit, a special investigation shall be made before a
permit may be issued for the work.&#xA0; In addition to the permit fee, an
investigation fee shall be collected as provided for in Section 98.0402 of the
Los Angeles Municipal Code.95.115.7.&#xA0; TRANSFER OF PERMITS AND PLAN CHECKS.&#xA0;
(Amended by Ord. No. 172,595, Eff. 6/28/99, Oper. 7/1/99.)&#xA0; No permit shall be
transferable from the original permittee to any other person, unless the
property owner authorizes the transfer in writing.&#xA0; Upon authorization, the new
permittee shall file with the Department a new permit and pay to the Department
a fee as specified in Section LAMC 98.0415 for issuing the new permit.&#xA0; This
fee includes the issuing permit fee specified in the fee schedule set forth in
LAMC Section 95.115.1.	NOTE:&#xA0; No plan check shall be transferable from one
contractor to another unless the original plans were prepared and signed by a
state-licensed engineer in the proper classification.95.115.8.&#xA0; FEES FOR
ADDITIONAL INSPECTIONS.	1.	Each permit shall be entitled to three inspection
trips when the job is of a type requiring an inspection before covering or
concealing the work.&#xA0; On jobs which may be completely inspected on one
inspection trip, two inspection trips will be allowed.	EXCEPTION:&#xA0; The number
of inspection trips will not be limited on progress jobs, provided, however,
that only one inspection will be permitted for checking a correction.&#xA0; For the
purpose of this section, progress jobs are those in which circumstances beyond
the control of the applicant make it impossible for the installation to be
completed at any specific time.	2.	If more inspection trips than are specified
in Subsection 1 of this section are required due to the fault or error on the
part of the applicant or the applicant&#x2019;s employees, an additional fee as
specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code shall be paid by
the applicant for each additional inspection trip.	3.	The Department may recheck
installations at intervals of 30 days or more, where violations continue to
exist, until either the violations are cleared or a total of three rechecks are
made.&#xA0; The fees specified in Subsection 2 of this section shall apply for each
recheck inspection.	4.	The fees charged under this section are in addition to
any other fees shown and the payment of the fees required by this section shall
not exempt any person from compliance with other provisions of this Code nor
from any penalty prescribed by law.	5.	Whenever special enforcement procedures
are required to obtain compliance with properly executed Department notices or
orders, a fee, as specified in Section 98.0407 of the Los Angeles Municipal
Code, shall be assessed in addition to the added trip fee specified in
Subsection 2 of this section.95.115.9.&#xA0; INSPECTION FEES FOR OFF-HOURS
INSPECTIONS.&#xA0; The Department may, at its discretion, make emergency inspections
at other than normal working hours upon the request of a permittee, provided
that additional fees are paid as specified in Section 98.0406 of the Los Angeles
Municipal Code.95.115.10.&#xA0; FEES FOR OFF-SITE INSPECTIONS.&#xA0; Upon written
request, the Department may, at its discretion, make inspections at locations
other than the site upon which a building will be located, provided that
location is within 60 miles (96.56 km) of the Los Angeles City Hall.	A fee, in
addition to fees charged elsewhere in this Code, at the rate specified in
Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code per hour shall be charged for
such inspections, time to include travel to and from the place of inspection,
with the minimum fee as specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles
Municipal Code.
</plain_text><html>
					&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#xA0; PERMIT FEES.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 172,595, Eff. 6/28/99, Oper. 7/1/99.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;95.115.1.&#xA0; PERMIT FEES.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 180,868, Eff. 10/22/09.)&#xA0; Before any permit required by this Code is issued, the applicant shall pay to the Department the following fees:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;PERMIT FEE SCHEDULE FOR HEATING, VENTILATING, AIR-CONDITIONING AND REFRIGERATION EQUIPMENT AND MISCELLANEOUS HEAT-PRODUCING APPLIANCES&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  
    
      
        Permit
      
      
        Fee
      
    
    
      
        1.
      
      
        a.&#xA0; &#xA0; For issuing permit	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.&#xA0; &#xA0; 	For issuing a supplementary permit (the fee for which shall be the difference between the fee paid for the&#xA0; original permit and the fee which would have been&#xA0; required had the original permit included the entire installation, repair, relocation or alteration plus	
      
      
        $20.00
      
    
    
      
        2.
      
      
        For the installation or relocation of each fuel-burning heating appliance regulated by this Code	
      
      
        $19.00
      
    
    
      
        3.
      
      
        For&#xA0; each&#xA0; air&#xA0; inlet&#xA0; and&#xA0; air&#xA0; outlet&#xA0; served&#xA0; by any&#xA0; heating,&#xA0; air-conditioning&#xA0; or&#xA0; ventilation&#xA0; system	
      
      
        $5.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        or for each 1,000 square feet (92.9 m2) or fraction thereof of conditioned area for any heating or air-conditioning system using perforated building &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;material&lt;/span&gt; in lieu of conventional air inlets and outlets	
      
      
        $38.00
      
    
    
      
        4.
      
      
        a.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each appliance vent system, factory-built chimney and each absorption unit vent system regulated by this Code	
      
      
        $12.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each unlisted single-wall metal chimney (smokestack)	
      
      
        $57.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; Note:&#xA0; This fee shall not apply to a vent system which is an integral part of an appliance or an absorption unit, which is listed for outdoor installation.
      
      
        
      
    
    
      
        5.
      
      
        For the repair of, alteration of or addition to each refrigeration system, fuel- burning heating appliance, comfort-cooling unit, absorption unit, or each comfort-heating, cooling, absorption, ventilation or evaporative cooling system, including the installation of controls regulated by this Code	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        6.
      
      
        a.&#xA0; &#xA0; For each ventilation system which is serving a commercial cooking hood	
      
      
        $33.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For each environmental air and commercial-type clothes dryer ventilation system regulated by this Code	
      
      
        $12.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        c.&#xA0; &#xA0; For each product-conveying duct system regulated by this Code	
      
      
        $59.00
      
    
    
      
        7.
      
      
        For the installation of each hood	
      
      
        $33.00
      
    
    
      
        8.
      
      
        a.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each comfort-cooling compressor of 25-horsepower (87.9 k/W) rating or less and each absorption unit having an input capacity of 500,000 Btu/h (2299.3 L/W) or less	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each refrigeration compressor of 25-horsepower rating (87.9 k/W) or less, other than a compressor for a unit refrigeration system	
      
      
        $38.00
      
    
    
      
        9.
      
      
        a.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each comfort-cooling compressor over 25-horsepower (87.9 K/W) rating and under 50-horsepower (175.8 k/W) rating, and each absorption unit having an input capacity over 500,000 Btu/h (2299.3 L/W) and under 1,000,000 Btu/h (4598.6 L/W)	
      
      
        $59.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each refrigeration compressor over 25-horsepower (87.9 k/W) rating and under 50-horsepower (175.8 k/W) rating	
      
      
        $77.00
      
    
    
      
        10.
      
      
        a.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each comfort-cooling compressor of 50-horsepower (175.8 k/W) rating and over, and each absorption unit having an input capacity of 1,000,000 Btu/h (4598.6 L/W) and over	
      
      
        $116.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each refrigeration compressor of 50-horsepower (175.8 k/W) rating and over	
      
      
        $158.00
      
    
    
      
        11.
      
      
        For&#xA0; the&#xA0; installation&#xA0; of&#xA0; each&#xA0; air-handling&#xA0; unit&#xA0; used&#xA0; for&#xA0; the&#xA0; distribution&#xA0; of&#xA0; conditioned&#xA0; air supply	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        Note:&#xA0; This fee shall not apply to an air-handling unit which is a portion of a factory-assembled appliance, comfort-cooling unit, evaporative cooler or absorption unit for which a permit is required elsewhere in this Code.	
      
      
        
      
    
    
      
        12.
      
      
        For the installation of each evaporative cooler which is not classified as a portable evaporative cooler	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        13.
      
      
        When it shall be necessary to make an extra inspection trip due to the applicant having given an incorrect address or wrong location for any permit when obtaining a permit required by this Code, a fee shall be paid by the applicant for correcting the address or location given in such permit	
      
      
        $36.00
      
    
    
      
        14.
      
      
        For the installation of incidental gas piping for each&#xA0; existing&#xA0; individual&#xA0; metered&#xA0; system&#xA0; up&#xA0; to and&#xA0; including&#xA0; five&#xA0; outlets&#xA0; (see&#xA0; Section 95.112.4)	
      
      
        $25.00
      
    
    
      
        &#xA0;&#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0;
      
      
        For each outlet over five	
      
      
        $7.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        Note:&#xA0; For the purpose of this fee, incidental gas piping shall mean any addition made to an existing low-pressure gas piping system to accommodate gas-burning equipment regulated by this Code.&#xA0; This fee shall not apply if such piping is less than six feet (1.8 m) in length and connects to an existing gas outlet.
      
      
        
      
    
    
      
        15.
      
      
        For the installation of each fire damper	
      
      
        $12.00
      
    
    
      
        16.
      
      
        For the installation of each smoke-control damper which is a portion of a smoke- control system that is required by the Los Angeles Municipal Code	
      
      
        $12.00
      
    
    
      
        17.
      
      
        For each smoke detector which is required by the Los Angeles Mechanical Code	
      
      
        $10.00
      
    
    
      
        18.
      
      
        For witnessing the performance test of any emergency mechanical smoke-control system, stair shaft pressurization system, smoke detector or smoke damper which is a portion of that system.&#xA0; For each hour or fraction thereof	
      
      
        $108.00
      
    
    
      
        19.
      
      
        For witnessing the performance test of any heating or cooling equipment for automatic shutoff.&#xA0; For each hour or fraction thereof	
      
      
        $108.00
      
    
    
      
        20.
      
      
        For witnessing the performance test of any ventilating system serving commercial food heat-processing equipment.&#xA0; For each hour or fraction thereof	
      
      
        $108.00
      
    
    
      
        21.
      
      
        For the minimum inspection	
      
      
        $93.00
      
    
    
      
        22.
      
      
        For each additional inspection	
      
      
        $93.00
      
    
    
      
        23.
      
      
        Minimum inspection fee.&#xA0; Los Angeles Municipal Code Section 98.0412.1 and 98.0412.1.1:
      
      
        
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        a.&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of a single fixture described in this section	
      
      
        $57.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.&#xA0; &#xA0; 	Where the cumulative fees described in this section total less than the minimum fee required by the Los Angeles Mechanical Code	
      
      
        $93.00
      
    
    
      
        24.
      
      
        For transfer of a permit	
      
      
        $50.00
      
    
    
      
        Note:&#xA0; Items 18, 19 and 20.&#xA0; For the purpose of &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;witness&lt;/span&gt; fee requirements, more than one system of the same category can be inspected in the same building spaces if completed within the same hour.&#xA0; For each additional category or additional hour or fraction thereof a fee of $75.00 is required.&#xA0; These fees are not to be included in determining plan check fee.
      
    
  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	
95.115.2.&#xA0; PLAN CHECK FEES.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 180,868, Eff. 10/22/09.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(a)	Before formally accepting a set of plans and specifications for checking, the Department shall collect a plan check fee.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	A complete schedule of the permit fees due shall be included with each set of plans submitted to the Department.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	The plan check fees required by the provisions of this section are in addition to the inspection fees required by Sections 95.115.5 and 95.115.8 of this Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	A fee as specified in Item 10 of Section 95.115.2 shall be collected by the Department prior to approval for each set of plans submitted beyond the two required by this Code containing more than 10 sheets including calculations and documentation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	Plan check fee shall be as follows:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	All projects&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  
    
      
        Type of Installation
      
      
        Standard Design
      
      
        Additional Fee for Checking Analysis of Annual Energy Budget
      
    
    
      
        Installation of equipment as listed in Section 95.115.1
      
      
        70% of permit fee
$93.00 minimum; plus a surcharge of 10% of permit fee, $72.00 minimum, for checking compliance with State Energy Standards
NOTE: For conditioned areas where the number of air inlets and air outlets is unknown, $12.00 for each 1000 sq. ft. or fraction thereof.
      
      
        60% of permit fee,
$144.00 minimum, 
$4,037.00 maximum
      
    
  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	2.	In addition to the above fee, a plan checking fee shall be assessed for checking the following systems:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	a.	Commercial cooking ventilation systems, serving type I hoods, each  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;.  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;.  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;. . $216.00&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	b.	Commercial cooking ventilation systems, serving type II hoods each  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;.  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;.  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;. . $144.00&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	c.	Type&#xA0; I,&#xA0; Type&#xA0; II&#xA0; or&#xA0; fume&#xA0; hoods,&#xA0; each  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;.  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;.  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;. . $72.00&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	d.	Product&#xA0; conveying&#xA0; ventilation systems  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;.  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;.  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;. . $216.00&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	e.	Engineering calculations of smoke control systems, each  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;.  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;.  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;. . $1,081.00&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	f.	Engineering calculations of stair shaft pressurization systems, each  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;.  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;.  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;. . $216.00&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	g.	Engineered and/or proprietary duct joints,&#xA0; each&#xA0; HVAC&#xA0; system, minimum  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;.  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;.  .&#x2009;.&#x2009;. . $144.00&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	h.	The Department may collect a plan check fee as specified in Section 98.0415(e) of the Los Angeles Municipal Code for the following plan check services:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	Specially engineered systems;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	Engineered systems not listed in Section 95.115.1;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	Review of expired plans provided that the original approved plans are submitted along with the new plans, and the new plans have no changes other than those required to comply with the current code;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	4.	Review of plans revised for reasons other than to comply with plan check corrections;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	5.	Review of &#x201C;As Built&#x201D; plans provided that the original approved plans are submitted along with the new plans;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	6.	Any time not included in the original plan check fee.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	(b)	Off-hour Plan Check.&#xA0; Upon request by an applicant and accepted by the Department, an off-hour plan check fee per Section 98.0422 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code may be collected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
95.115.3.&#xA0; EXPIRATION OF PLAN CHECK.&#xA0; Plan check approval shall expire as provided for in Section 98.0603 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;95.115.4.&#xA0; MINIMUM INSPECTION FEE.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	A minimum fee as specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code shall be paid to the Department for each mechanical installation for which a permit is required by this Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	When the cumulative fees and the issuing fee set forth in this Code are less than the minimum fee, the minimum fee shall be paid, which shall include the issuing fee.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	The fee for single fixture shall apply to the installation of only one mechanical fixture/equipment and shall include the issuing fee.&#xA0; Where the fee for a single fixture exceeds the minimum fee for single fixtures, this fee shall not apply.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;95.115.5.&#xA0; FEES FOR MISCELLANEOUS PERMITS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	When permission has been obtained from the Department, a permit may be issued for that portion of equipment to be concealed if the permit cannot be issued until required plans have been approved.&#xA0; The miscellaneous permit shall not be an authorization for the installation of any other equipment.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	The permittee shall submit plans along with this permit application which shall clearly designate the equipment to be concealed and the building area involved.&#xA0; If the work done on the miscellaneous permit is not in accordance with the final approved plans, the permittee shall be responsible for making all necessary corrections for compliance with the Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	A fee as specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code shall be paid for the inspection of this installation and shall be limited to one inspection trip and one reinspection trip.&#xA0; This fee is in addition to the permit-issuing fee specified in Section 95.115.1.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	A miscellaneous permit fee as specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code shall be paid for inspection of the installation of equipment regulated by this Code which requires an inspection for determination of Code compliance and where such installation inspection is not provided for in the permit fee schedule specified in Section 95.115.1.&#xA0; This fee is in addition to the permit issuing fee specified in Section 95.115.1.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;95.115.6.&#xA0; INVESTIGATION FEE.&#xA0; Except as provided in Section 95.112.1, whenever any work for which a permit is required under the provisions of this Code has been commenced without the authorization of a permit, a special investigation shall be made before a permit may be issued for the work.&#xA0; In addition to the permit fee, an investigation fee shall be collected as provided for in Section 98.0402 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;95.115.7.&#xA0; TRANSFER OF PERMITS AND PLAN CHECKS.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 172,595, Eff. 6/28/99, Oper. 7/1/99.)&#xA0; No permit shall be transferable from the original permittee to any other person, unless the property owner authorizes the transfer in writing.&#xA0; Upon authorization, the new permittee shall file with the Department a new permit and pay to the Department a fee as specified in Section LAMC 98.0415 for issuing the new permit.&#xA0; This fee includes the issuing permit fee specified in the fee schedule set forth in LAMC Section 95.115.1.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	NOTE:&#xA0; No plan check shall be transferable from one contractor to another unless the original plans were prepared and signed by a state-licensed engineer in the proper classification.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;95.115.8.&#xA0; FEES FOR ADDITIONAL INSPECTIONS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	1.	Each permit shall be entitled to three inspection trips when the job is of a type requiring an inspection before covering or concealing the work.&#xA0; On jobs which may be completely inspected on one inspection trip, two inspection trips will be allowed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	EXCEPTION:&#xA0; The number of inspection trips will not be limited on progress jobs, provided, however, that only one inspection will be permitted for checking a correction.&#xA0; For the purpose of this section, progress jobs are those in which circumstances beyond the control of the applicant make it impossible for the installation to be completed at any specific time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	2.	If more inspection trips than are specified in Subsection 1 of this section are required due to the fault or error on the part of the applicant or the applicant&#x2019;s employees, an additional fee as specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code shall be paid by the applicant for each additional inspection trip.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	3.	The Department may recheck installations at intervals of 30 days or more, where violations continue to exist, until either the violations are cleared or a total of three rechecks are made.&#xA0; The fees specified in Subsection 2 of this section shall apply for each recheck inspection.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	4.	The fees charged under this section are in addition to any other fees shown and the payment of the fees required by this section shall not exempt any person from compliance with other provisions of this Code nor from any &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;penalty&lt;/span&gt; prescribed by &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;law&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	5.	Whenever special enforcement procedures are required to obtain compliance with properly executed Department notices or &lt;span class="dictionary"&gt;orders&lt;/span&gt;, a fee, as specified in Section 98.0407 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code, shall be assessed in addition to the added trip fee specified in Subsection 2 of this section.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;95.115.9.&#xA0; INSPECTION FEES FOR OFF-HOURS INSPECTIONS.&#xA0; The Department may, at its discretion, make emergency inspections at other than normal working hours upon the request of a permittee, provided that additional fees are paid as specified in Section 98.0406 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;95.115.10.&#xA0; FEES FOR OFF-SITE INSPECTIONS.&#xA0; Upon written request, the Department may, at its discretion, make inspections at locations other than the site upon which a building will be located, provided that location is within 60 miles (96.56 km) of the Los Angeles City Hall.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	A fee, in addition to fees charged elsewhere in this Code, at the rate specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code per hour shall be charged for such inspections, time to include travel to and from the place of inspection, with the minimum fee as specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</html><text><unit id="2795" prefix=""><text>&#xA0; PERMIT FEES.
	(Amended by Ord. No. 172,595, Eff. 6/28/99, Oper. 7/1/99.)95.115.1.&#xA0; PERMIT FEES.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 180,868, Eff. 10/22/09.)&#xA0; Before any permit required by this Code is issued, the applicant shall pay to the Department the following fees:PERMIT FEE SCHEDULE FOR HEATING, VENTILATING, AIR-CONDITIONING AND REFRIGERATION EQUIPMENT AND MISCELLANEOUS HEAT-PRODUCING APPLIANCES
  
    
      
        Permit
      
      
        Fee
      
    
    
      
        1.
      
      
        a.&#xA0; &#xA0; For issuing permit	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.&#xA0; &#xA0; 	For issuing a supplementary permit (the fee for which shall be the difference between the fee paid for the&#xA0; original permit and the fee which would have been&#xA0; required had the original permit included the entire installation, repair, relocation or alteration plus	
      
      
        $20.00
      
    
    
      
        2.
      
      
        For the installation or relocation of each fuel-burning heating appliance regulated by this Code	
      
      
        $19.00
      
    
    
      
        3.
      
      
        For&#xA0; each&#xA0; air&#xA0; inlet&#xA0; and&#xA0; air&#xA0; outlet&#xA0; served&#xA0; by any&#xA0; heating,&#xA0; air-conditioning&#xA0; or&#xA0; ventilation&#xA0; system	
      
      
        $5.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        or for each 1,000 square feet (92.9 m2) or fraction thereof of conditioned area for any heating or air-conditioning system using perforated building material in lieu of conventional air inlets and outlets	
      
      
        $38.00
      
    
    
      
        4.
      
      
        a.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each appliance vent system, factory-built chimney and each absorption unit vent system regulated by this Code	
      
      
        $12.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each unlisted single-wall metal chimney (smokestack)	
      
      
        $57.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; Note:&#xA0; This fee shall not apply to a vent system which is an integral part of an appliance or an absorption unit, which is listed for outdoor installation.
      
      
        
      
    
    
      
        5.
      
      
        For the repair of, alteration of or addition to each refrigeration system, fuel- burning heating appliance, comfort-cooling unit, absorption unit, or each comfort-heating, cooling, absorption, ventilation or evaporative cooling system, including the installation of controls regulated by this Code	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        6.
      
      
        a.&#xA0; &#xA0; For each ventilation system which is serving a commercial cooking hood	
      
      
        $33.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For each environmental air and commercial-type clothes dryer ventilation system regulated by this Code	
      
      
        $12.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        c.&#xA0; &#xA0; For each product-conveying duct system regulated by this Code	
      
      
        $59.00
      
    
    
      
        7.
      
      
        For the installation of each hood	
      
      
        $33.00
      
    
    
      
        8.
      
      
        a.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each comfort-cooling compressor of 25-horsepower (87.9 k/W) rating or less and each absorption unit having an input capacity of 500,000 Btu/h (2299.3 L/W) or less	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each refrigeration compressor of 25-horsepower rating (87.9 k/W) or less, other than a compressor for a unit refrigeration system	
      
      
        $38.00
      
    
    
      
        9.
      
      
        a.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each comfort-cooling compressor over 25-horsepower (87.9 K/W) rating and under 50-horsepower (175.8 k/W) rating, and each absorption unit having an input capacity over 500,000 Btu/h (2299.3 L/W) and under 1,000,000 Btu/h (4598.6 L/W)	
      
      
        $59.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each refrigeration compressor over 25-horsepower (87.9 k/W) rating and under 50-horsepower (175.8 k/W) rating	
      
      
        $77.00
      
    
    
      
        10.
      
      
        a.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each comfort-cooling compressor of 50-horsepower (175.8 k/W) rating and over, and each absorption unit having an input capacity of 1,000,000 Btu/h (4598.6 L/W) and over	
      
      
        $116.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.	&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of each refrigeration compressor of 50-horsepower (175.8 k/W) rating and over	
      
      
        $158.00
      
    
    
      
        11.
      
      
        For&#xA0; the&#xA0; installation&#xA0; of&#xA0; each&#xA0; air-handling&#xA0; unit&#xA0; used&#xA0; for&#xA0; the&#xA0; distribution&#xA0; of&#xA0; conditioned&#xA0; air supply	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        Note:&#xA0; This fee shall not apply to an air-handling unit which is a portion of a factory-assembled appliance, comfort-cooling unit, evaporative cooler or absorption unit for which a permit is required elsewhere in this Code.	
      
      
        
      
    
    
      
        12.
      
      
        For the installation of each evaporative cooler which is not classified as a portable evaporative cooler	
      
      
        $24.00
      
    
    
      
        13.
      
      
        When it shall be necessary to make an extra inspection trip due to the applicant having given an incorrect address or wrong location for any permit when obtaining a permit required by this Code, a fee shall be paid by the applicant for correcting the address or location given in such permit	
      
      
        $36.00
      
    
    
      
        14.
      
      
        For the installation of incidental gas piping for each&#xA0; existing&#xA0; individual&#xA0; metered&#xA0; system&#xA0; up&#xA0; to and&#xA0; including&#xA0; five&#xA0; outlets&#xA0; (see&#xA0; Section 95.112.4)	
      
      
        $25.00
      
    
    
      
        &#xA0;&#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0;
      
      
        For each outlet over five	
      
      
        $7.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        Note:&#xA0; For the purpose of this fee, incidental gas piping shall mean any addition made to an existing low-pressure gas piping system to accommodate gas-burning equipment regulated by this Code.&#xA0; This fee shall not apply if such piping is less than six feet (1.8 m) in length and connects to an existing gas outlet.
      
      
        
      
    
    
      
        15.
      
      
        For the installation of each fire damper	
      
      
        $12.00
      
    
    
      
        16.
      
      
        For the installation of each smoke-control damper which is a portion of a smoke- control system that is required by the Los Angeles Municipal Code	
      
      
        $12.00
      
    
    
      
        17.
      
      
        For each smoke detector which is required by the Los Angeles Mechanical Code	
      
      
        $10.00
      
    
    
      
        18.
      
      
        For witnessing the performance test of any emergency mechanical smoke-control system, stair shaft pressurization system, smoke detector or smoke damper which is a portion of that system.&#xA0; For each hour or fraction thereof	
      
      
        $108.00
      
    
    
      
        19.
      
      
        For witnessing the performance test of any heating or cooling equipment for automatic shutoff.&#xA0; For each hour or fraction thereof	
      
      
        $108.00
      
    
    
      
        20.
      
      
        For witnessing the performance test of any ventilating system serving commercial food heat-processing equipment.&#xA0; For each hour or fraction thereof	
      
      
        $108.00
      
    
    
      
        21.
      
      
        For the minimum inspection	
      
      
        $93.00
      
    
    
      
        22.
      
      
        For each additional inspection	
      
      
        $93.00
      
    
    
      
        23.
      
      
        Minimum inspection fee.&#xA0; Los Angeles Municipal Code Section 98.0412.1 and 98.0412.1.1:
      
      
        
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        a.&#xA0; &#xA0; For the installation of a single fixture described in this section	
      
      
        $57.00
      
    
    
      
        
      
      
        b.&#xA0; &#xA0; 	Where the cumulative fees described in this section total less than the minimum fee required by the Los Angeles Mechanical Code	
      
      
        $93.00
      
    
    
      
        24.
      
      
        For transfer of a permit	
      
      
        $50.00
      
    
    
      
        Note:&#xA0; Items 18, 19 and 20.&#xA0; For the purpose of witness fee requirements, more than one system of the same category can be inspected in the same building spaces if completed within the same hour.&#xA0; For each additional category or additional hour or fraction thereof a fee of $75.00 is required.&#xA0; These fees are not to be included in determining plan check fee.
      
    
  	
95.115.2.&#xA0; PLAN CHECK FEES.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 180,868, Eff. 10/22/09.)	(a)	Before formally accepting a set of plans and specifications for checking, the Department shall collect a plan check fee.	A complete schedule of the permit fees due shall be included with each set of plans submitted to the Department.	The plan check fees required by the provisions of this section are in addition to the inspection fees required by Sections 95.115.5 and 95.115.8 of this Code.	A fee as specified in Item 10 of Section 95.115.2 shall be collected by the Department prior to approval for each set of plans submitted beyond the two required by this Code containing more than 10 sheets including calculations and documentation.	Plan check fee shall be as follows:	1.	All projects
  
    
      
        Type of Installation
      
      
        Standard Design
      
      
        Additional Fee for Checking Analysis of Annual Energy Budget
      
    
    
      
        Installation of equipment as listed in Section 95.115.1
      
      
        70% of permit fee
$93.00 minimum; plus a surcharge of 10% of permit fee, $72.00 minimum, for checking compliance with State Energy Standards
NOTE: For conditioned areas where the number of air inlets and air outlets is unknown, $12.00 for each 1000 sq. ft. or fraction thereof.
      
      
        60% of permit fee,
$144.00 minimum, 
$4,037.00 maximum
      
    
  
	2.	In addition to the above fee, a plan checking fee shall be assessed for checking the following systems:	a.	Commercial cooking ventilation systems, serving type I hoods, each  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $216.00	b.	Commercial cooking ventilation systems, serving type II hoods each  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $144.00	c.	Type&#xA0; I,&#xA0; Type&#xA0; II&#xA0; or&#xA0; fume&#xA0; hoods,&#xA0; each  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $72.00	d.	Product&#xA0; conveying&#xA0; ventilation systems  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $216.00	e.	Engineering calculations of smoke control systems, each  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $1,081.00	f.	Engineering calculations of stair shaft pressurization systems, each  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $216.00	g.	Engineered and/or proprietary duct joints,&#xA0; each&#xA0; HVAC&#xA0; system, minimum  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;.  .&thinsp;.&thinsp;. . $144.00	h.	The Department may collect a plan check fee as specified in Section 98.0415(e) of the Los Angeles Municipal Code for the following plan check services:	1.	Specially engineered systems;	2.	Engineered systems not listed in Section 95.115.1;	3.	Review of expired plans provided that the original approved plans are submitted along with the new plans, and the new plans have no changes other than those required to comply with the current code;	4.	Review of plans revised for reasons other than to comply with plan check corrections;	5.	Review of &#x201C;As Built&#x201D; plans provided that the original approved plans are submitted along with the new plans;	6.	Any time not included in the original plan check fee.	(b)	Off-hour Plan Check.&#xA0; Upon request by an applicant and accepted by the Department, an off-hour plan check fee per Section 98.0422 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code may be collected.
95.115.3.&#xA0; EXPIRATION OF PLAN CHECK.&#xA0; Plan check approval shall expire as provided for in Section 98.0603 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.95.115.4.&#xA0; MINIMUM INSPECTION FEE.	1.	A minimum fee as specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code shall be paid to the Department for each mechanical installation for which a permit is required by this Code.	2.	When the cumulative fees and the issuing fee set forth in this Code are less than the minimum fee, the minimum fee shall be paid, which shall include the issuing fee.	3.	The fee for single fixture shall apply to the installation of only one mechanical fixture/equipment and shall include the issuing fee.&#xA0; Where the fee for a single fixture exceeds the minimum fee for single fixtures, this fee shall not apply.95.115.5.&#xA0; FEES FOR MISCELLANEOUS PERMITS.	1.	When permission has been obtained from the Department, a permit may be issued for that portion of equipment to be concealed if the permit cannot be issued until required plans have been approved.&#xA0; The miscellaneous permit shall not be an authorization for the installation of any other equipment.	The permittee shall submit plans along with this permit application which shall clearly designate the equipment to be concealed and the building area involved.&#xA0; If the work done on the miscellaneous permit is not in accordance with the final approved plans, the permittee shall be responsible for making all necessary corrections for compliance with the Code.	A fee as specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code shall be paid for the inspection of this installation and shall be limited to one inspection trip and one reinspection trip.&#xA0; This fee is in addition to the permit-issuing fee specified in Section 95.115.1.	2.	A miscellaneous permit fee as specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code shall be paid for inspection of the installation of equipment regulated by this Code which requires an inspection for determination of Code compliance and where such installation inspection is not provided for in the permit fee schedule specified in Section 95.115.1.&#xA0; This fee is in addition to the permit issuing fee specified in Section 95.115.1.95.115.6.&#xA0; INVESTIGATION FEE.&#xA0; Except as provided in Section 95.112.1, whenever any work for which a permit is required under the provisions of this Code has been commenced without the authorization of a permit, a special investigation shall be made before a permit may be issued for the work.&#xA0; In addition to the permit fee, an investigation fee shall be collected as provided for in Section 98.0402 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.95.115.7.&#xA0; TRANSFER OF PERMITS AND PLAN CHECKS.&#xA0; (Amended by Ord. No. 172,595, Eff. 6/28/99, Oper. 7/1/99.)&#xA0; No permit shall be transferable from the original permittee to any other person, unless the property owner authorizes the transfer in writing.&#xA0; Upon authorization, the new permittee shall file with the Department a new permit and pay to the Department a fee as specified in Section LAMC 98.0415 for issuing the new permit.&#xA0; This fee includes the issuing permit fee specified in the fee schedule set forth in LAMC Section 95.115.1.	NOTE:&#xA0; No plan check shall be transferable from one contractor to another unless the original plans were prepared and signed by a state-licensed engineer in the proper classification.95.115.8.&#xA0; FEES FOR ADDITIONAL INSPECTIONS.	1.	Each permit shall be entitled to three inspection trips when the job is of a type requiring an inspection before covering or concealing the work.&#xA0; On jobs which may be completely inspected on one inspection trip, two inspection trips will be allowed.	EXCEPTION:&#xA0; The number of inspection trips will not be limited on progress jobs, provided, however, that only one inspection will be permitted for checking a correction.&#xA0; For the purpose of this section, progress jobs are those in which circumstances beyond the control of the applicant make it impossible for the installation to be completed at any specific time.	2.	If more inspection trips than are specified in Subsection 1 of this section are required due to the fault or error on the part of the applicant or the applicant&#x2019;s employees, an additional fee as specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code shall be paid by the applicant for each additional inspection trip.	3.	The Department may recheck installations at intervals of 30 days or more, where violations continue to exist, until either the violations are cleared or a total of three rechecks are made.&#xA0; The fees specified in Subsection 2 of this section shall apply for each recheck inspection.	4.	The fees charged under this section are in addition to any other fees shown and the payment of the fees required by this section shall not exempt any person from compliance with other provisions of this Code nor from any penalty prescribed by law.	5.	Whenever special enforcement procedures are required to obtain compliance with properly executed Department notices or orders, a fee, as specified in Section 98.0407 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code, shall be assessed in addition to the added trip fee specified in Subsection 2 of this section.95.115.9.&#xA0; INSPECTION FEES FOR OFF-HOURS INSPECTIONS.&#xA0; The Department may, at its discretion, make emergency inspections at other than normal working hours upon the request of a permittee, provided that additional fees are paid as specified in Section 98.0406 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.95.115.10.&#xA0; FEES FOR OFF-SITE INSPECTIONS.&#xA0; Upon written request, the Department may, at its discretion, make inspections at locations other than the site upon which a building will be located, provided that location is within 60 miles (96.56 km) of the Los Angeles City Hall.	A fee, in addition to fees charged elsewhere in this Code, at the rate specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code per hour shall be charged for such inspections, time to include travel to and from the place of inspection, with the minimum fee as specified in Section 98.0412 of the Los Angeles Municipal Code.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><unit></unit></prefixes><entire_prefix></entire_prefix><prefix_anchor></prefix_anchor><level>1</level></unit></text></law>
